<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/compilation.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-24T14:37:46-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/compilation.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Compilation</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Post 44: Dharma</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0719" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 44: Dharma" /><published>2023-07-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post44_CCT_Dharma</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0719"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There have been several Incarnations on this Earth who have always said to know your Spirit because without finding his Spirit a human being cannot find God. Just as without eyes we cannot identify colors, similarly without knowing the Spirit, through arguments, we cannot obtain God. Through brains we cannot know God. It is through the Spirit only we can know God. <font color="DarkRed">Till now everybody has said that, "You rise in your dharma and find your Spirit. Know the Spirit which is within you."</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Spirit from The Life Eternal, 1980 Issue, Page 55</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Today, Sahaja Yoga has reached the state of Mahā Yoga, which is en masse evolution manifested through it. <font color="DarkRed">It is this day's Yuga Dharma.</font> It is the way the Last Judgment is taking place. Announce it to all the Seekers of Truth, to all the nations of the world, so that nobody misses the blessings of the Divine to achieve their meaning, their Absolute, their Spirit."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote, Message from Maha Avatar, Issue 1 (July-September 1980), Page 1</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Carbon has four valencies, gold has the property that it is untarnishable.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Similarly, dharma is the sterling quality which is sustenance of mankind. Man has evolved from an amoeba to this stage, through his dharma, which is the code of law of evolution. This code of life protects and nourishes our spiritual growth. It gives us balance and a state to ascend in our evolutionary process.</font><br />
Without balance how can we ascend?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Dharma from the book Gita Enlightened (2014) by Yogi Mahajan, Page 38</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The central channel begins at the Mūlādhāra and passes straight up into the highest chakra of Sahasrāra. <font color="DarkRed">Only partly active up to the human stage, it expresses the evolutionary power of the Virāṭa (sattvaguṇa), virtue and righteousness (dharma) and the Power of Awareness (Jñāna Śhakti).</font><br />
......<br />
The Suṣhumṇā is the central channel for our evolution. It is through this channel that we become collectively conscious and all the disparate factors of our being are integrated in one whole. It makes the connection between our conscious mind and the 'auto' of the autonomic nervous system, the Spirit, which is the reflection of God. <font color="DarkRed">Suṣhumṇā is the Way of Dharma, the straight and narrow path by which we pass through the gate of the Āgñyā chakra to enter into the Kingdom of God in the Sahasrāra.</font><br />
So with the Sahasrāra open and the connection with Suṣhumṇā established, we are open to the source of all awareness where all knowledge dwells, and is sustained by the Primordial Source of All Power (Ādi Śhakti). Meditation in thoughtless awareness is the key to the development of a strong Suṣhumṇā. <font color="DarkRed">Another basic requirement is to enjoy a virtuous and dhārmik life. After Realization, try to keep in thoughtless awareness as much as possible, with attention centered in Suṣhumṇā nāḍī, the channel of the eternal present, where the only time is 'now'. In this way, with Kuṇḍalinī awakening, we transcend time and space.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes from the book Sahaja Yoga the Divine Path by Dr. Hari Shankar Sharma, Part I, Pages 62--64</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There is a difference between innocence and ignorance. Innocence understands and responds to love without expectations or sense of gaining something out of love. He has no sense of gaining anything out of love. <font color="DarkRed">Without innocence you cannot be dhārmik. Unless innocence is embedded in dharma it has no meaning.<br />
......<br />
You may be adhārmik but after Kuṇḍalinī awakening you become dhārmik.</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 A List of Quotes</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"No names can describe Him. He cannot be grasped, and He is beyond praise. <font color="DarkRed">"Whenever dharma declines and evil prevails, I incarnate Myself."</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa from Akashwani, Volume I, Issue VIII (August 2000), Page 3</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"How much hold is there in your mind! <font color="DarkRed">Dharma is itself a big hold on you.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote, Navarātri Pūjā, from the book Sahaja Yoga, An Experiential Treatise (Sahaja Yoga Anubhavāche Bola) by Venu Narayan Phaḍake, Chapter 19, Pages 248 and 249</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The void is kept clean by people who follow a life of human sustainence (Dharma)[.]<br />
After enlightenment the Dharma is awakened and then there [is] no need to know about do's and don'ts.</font> All bad habits drop out spontaneously."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Void</b>

&lt;/p&gt;

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Vishwa Nirmala Dharma has been established. We need to be alert to protect its dignity. Ones who will venture outside its boundaries, may get possessed with evil. The reason is that all around ignorance and evil are ruling.</font><br />
The one who stays within the boundaries (maryādās), is the one who will rise higher. Otherwise he may disintegrate and get destroyed completely."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Vishwa Nirmala Dharma (Hindi)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Her third power is of Mahalaxmi. This is the power that renders sustenance (Dharma) to Her Creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Powers of the Primordial Mother related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"x <font color="DarkRed">Sustenance (Dharma) in the creation is the essence that expresses character.</font> For example Gold has the sustenance that it does tarnish. Anything that is yellow or glittering is not gold. In the same way water has the quality of sustenance that it cleanses or dissolves many things and does not dissolve some things. <font color="DarkRed">The human sustenance expressed in a nutshell as ten commandments. That was the time to let human beings know the essence of their quality. What they do and what they do not.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Dharma likely related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The chakras that are governed are aho [who] created according to the nature, functionand [function and] the sustenence (Dharma) of the Deities."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Chakras Created According to the Deities</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The Divine Power (Pranava[)] is the integrated one power of Adishakti. Though it manifests its activitating [activating] capacity as material power in the matter it resides in every particle of the matter. <font color="DarkRed">Though dormant as existence it is felt as electromagnetic power and as sustenance (Dharma) is expressed in giving character to every element + [plus] to every form and every shape of its crystals. In the living beings existence is expressed as life and susten[an]ce individual character.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Praṇava</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"For example human beings are evolved and have sense of dirt[,] filth and untidiness but animals are not aware of it. <font color="DarkRed">The sense of laws that govern us also comes from the evolved state of our sustainence [sustenance] (Dharma).</font> We know that balanced life is very important and that unlike animals we have freedom to go to any absurd extremes.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Hence sex without marriage fidelity has no help for wellbeing as it creates a problematic personality. As all other sex has no collective sanction as is against human sustainence [sustenence] (Dharma).</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Sex related to the book Ascent</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then the third one, I said, was Swāhā -- the Nābhī, is the consumption. Swadhā ... is the, that is the fire thing, fire, Fire Principle is the consumption part. <font color="DarkRed">Swadhā is the sustenance, Swadhā.</font> There are two things in the Nābhī chakra. <font color="DarkRed">Swadhā is the one by which you sustain the dharma. So, that's the two essences -- one is Swāhā, by which you consume everything, like the Agni Tattwa means like the Fire Principle, and Swadhā, is the Principle of the Water, which is sustenance.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1905-0000 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On the Essences of Elements</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Kuṇḍalinī awakening is an event such that this power rises above from within your triangular bone, pierces through six plexuses [chakras] and comes out from Brahmarandhra [hole in fontanel bone].<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Until this event takes place within you, sometimes it's fruitless to talk about dharma [religion].</font> Because talks may perhaps make you a good human being but one cannot get Self-realization.<br />
Unless Self-realization is achieved, all powers within us cannot be expressed. Understand that it is final and ultimate goal of our evolution. When Kuṇḍalinī is awakened, It pierces the Brahmarandhra but post this connection, the Yoga has to be established. Not for too long but meditation for a short while has to be practiced every day.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Another big change that happens is sense of righteousness (dharma) is awakened within us, it's within and not without.</font><br />
For example, any Hindi, Muslim or Christian can commit any sin or do wrong deeds, his religion has no binding upon him. <font color="DarkRed">But it's such a thing that once dharma is awakened within, you cannot commit anything illicit.</font><br />
Compassion, mercy, etc. are awakened within you and despite this you become extremely energetic and dynamic. Whatever you keep doing, you won't feel tired. You do your work in very loving and peaceful way.<br />
With this, you attain peace with you, become absolutely peaceful. A person who has very angry temperament becomes absolutely calm. Because whatever angularities you have within, become all right. All deformities within us are due to problems in plexuses [chakras] and once these chakras become all right, they get all right.<br />
......<br />
This work is going on in seven[ty] countries. Thousands of people get together, but never ever there is any tussle. All live-in harmony together. Yes, sometimes they do tease each other but jokingly, in a friendly manner. You would not have seen such friendships otherwise. Whether this person is from Russia, England, Japan or anywhere they build a collective love amongst themselves.<br />
 <font color="DarkRed">Because of this, when true religion (dharma) is awakened within, they understand that all religions are one, understand totality of all religions. You don't criticize any religion and worship all Dharma Pravartaka [Founder(s) of Religion].</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1907-0000 Interview (Hindi) with a Lady for a TV Program Directed by Ashok Agarwal, Ardhamātrā Volume 2, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1972-0409 Public Program (Marathi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>
</font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Dharma" /><category term="crimson @ Yuga Dharma" /><category term="crimson @ Vishwa Nirmala Dharma" /><category term="crimson @ Way of Dharma" /><category term="crimson @ Dharma Pravartaka" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 43: Joys or Types of Joy</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0712" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 43: Joys or Types of Joy" /><published>2023-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post43_CCT_Types_Joy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0712"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"To manage all these [problems of the world], until you get Paramānand, without the power to connect to the source, you can never get joy and you can never be satisfied. Man can get happiness at the Feet of Paramātma."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0326 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"What is called salvation? Why have we come into this world? Why did human being originate? Why was human made in a special form? Why did God give so many powers to this beautiful organism through a special artwork (kalākṛiti)?<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Only after understanding this you will get to know that your whole astitva, your entire existence is to drown [drench] you in Atyanta Ānanda [endless/profound joy].</font><br />
For that God has made this creation with great labor [hard work]."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0216 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Śhārīrika Bīmāri-yāṃ Chaitanya se Ṭhīka Ho Sakatī Hai (Physical Ailments Can Be Cured with Vibrations), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Last time, I told you what is Ātmā, how it becomes Sachchidānanda, and how humans achieve all three things only after Self-realization. Without Self-realization you cannot know the Truth, you cannot get joy. Self-realization is very important."</font><br />
<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Last time I told you about the Ātmā, what it is and how it becomes Sachchidānand, and how only after Realization a human can achieve all three. Without Self-realization you cannot know Ātmā, you cannot receive happiness. Realizing Ātmā is very necessary."</font><br />
<br />
<b>Variant 3:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"I had told you the last time what is Ātmā, how it is Sachchidānand, and how after being made aware of the Ātmā only humans can achieve these three things. Without Self-realization, you cannot know the Truth. You cannot achieve bliss. You should have the sensitivity of the Ātmā."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-1228 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Ātmā ki Anubhūti, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Sachchidānand State is what? We have to achieve that."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0201 Public Program (Hindi), Brahma kā Gyān (Knowledge of Brahma) or Mūlādhāra to Viśhuddhi, Āgñyā, and Sahasrāra, 9 Raisina Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />
"<font color="DarkRed">Yesterday I told you that today I will tell you about Śhiva's Nature of Truth, Attention and Joy Spirit (Śhiva Swarūp Sachchidānanda Ātmā), residing in the heart.</font> But [I] think I will tell you in the end only, after telling about all the chakras. That will be good."<br />
<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />
"<font color="DarkRed">Yesterday I told you that I will be telling you about Sachchidānanda who is the same as Śhiva and who resides in our heart</font>, but today I am thinking that I should tell you that after I finish talking about all the chakras, in the end. That will be good."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0316 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Viśhuddhi Chakra, Śhāmiyānā, Garden, Pataudi House, 10 Ashoka Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I don't know how far he is been able to tell you about the Kuṇḍalinī. <font color="DarkRed">Today, it looks like Sachchidānanda and everything.</font> And Grégoire already has written a book called <i>Advent</i>, which is very knowledgeable also.<br />
......<br />
But it's all uh absolutely blasphemous to say that, 'You don't drink!' So I don't say that either.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">You will just not do it, because you really get drunk with the joy of the Spirit, Sachchidānand.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1020 Public Program, Day 8, East West Center, 141 5th Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And you ... you won't die either. Means you will achieve your Spirit.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And the, "Sākṣhātkāri santvara śhabdakāri ka sant," the realized Souls, the Saints who are realized, the Brahmānanda, the joy of the Brahma, by this new Yoga.</font><br />
And they won't have to go into Samādhi."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0130 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Age of Active Divinity (Prophecies of Āchārya Kākā Bhujander, Jacqueline Murray, Cheiro, Ann Bailey and Śhrī Gyāneśhwara), Sholapur, Maharashtra, India (other date 0127)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The joy at the Sahasrāra is called as Nirānand, since long. Since ancient times is called Nirānanda or Nirmalānanda. So many call it as Nirmalānand or Nirānand. That joy is the joy that you enjoy even when you get crucified. That joy you enjoy even when you are poisoned. Even on your deathbed, you enjoy that joy. That joy is Nirānand."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0731 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Dedication through Meditation (Complete Dedication Is the Only Way or Meditation Is Nothing but Surrendering), Seminar, Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Cowley Manor, Cheltenham, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">But the most important is that, "The form of the Spirit is of Sachchidānand." "The form of the Spirit is of Sachchidānand," is what it is said.</font> But what does this mean? Everyone keeps saying that, "The form of the Spirit is of Sachchidānand."<br />
But what is the meaning of Sachchidānand? First of all this is the Truth. Now we keep saying that, 'This is the Truth,' 'That is Truth,' 'We saw that this is the Truth.' Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has said that, "Only Brahma is the Truth, all others are false." 'Rest all is illusion,' what is the meaning of this? 'This is the Truth and everything else is illusion,' means what?<br />
The meaning of this is that whatever vyavahār [conduct, behavior] we are doing [having] today, whatever we are vyavahār [performimg, practicing] today, we are doing it blindly, and when we get to know the form of the Spirit, at that time our practice becomes sighted (ḍoḷas), the truth can be seen."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0104 Public Talk (Marathi + English), Rotary Club, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India}\label{1983-0104 Public Talk (Marathi + English), Rotary Club, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0309 Talkback Live Interview with Barry Everingham for the 'Forum' Program of the Radio Station 'RSN Racing and Sport' (ACMA callsign 3UZ), after 2nd Public Program, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So He had to create this creation in such a way, that He could create His own image, reflect it, and make it enjoy itself. It's a very mutual appreciation, as we call it, āndolan. Whatever He does for us, is for His own pleasures. But the beauty of it is that: your pleasure is His pleasure. And the other way round is: His pleasure should be your pleasure, too.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Once that becomes the fact that the pleasure of God becomes your pleasure, you enter into that beautiful arena of Heavenly Joy: Swargīya Ānand.</font><br />
Only if it is one-sided enterprise or one-sided effort, it gets lost. Human efforts are one-sided. But God's efforts are such that they cannot be enjoyed then unless and until they are reflected back."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0330 Birthday Pūjā and Havan (English + Marathi), Birla Matushri Sabhagar, New Marine Lines, Churchgate, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1010 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (5th Day of Navarātri and Canadian Thanksgiving Day), Garden, 1386 Lincoln Avenue, Toronto, ON, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This Spirit is like Sachchidānand, means Truth, Attention and Joy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0216 Public Program (Hindi), Day 5, Sahasrāra and Ātmā, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In Sahaja Yoga, as you grow from one to another, there are different types of ānandas.<br />
Like we can say, the Spirit, when you see the Spirit, you get an ānand, called Swānanda. That means you feel your Spirit yourself, and you feel very happy. Then you give Realization to others, you get Parānanda, joy of others. But when you get the enjoyment of well-being, in health and materially all right and everything all right, everything in saṃtoṣha, in complete satisfaction, then it's Brahmānanda. And like that you start feeling higher and higher joys within yourself. Because your nerves start opening to new dimensions.<br />
So you can say that at the Kṛiṣhṇa level, you get Kṛiṣhṇānanda, where you get the sweetness, the mādhurya. And when you see your generosity, then you get Śhivānanda. And when you are with children, you get Gaṇeśhānanda. And that can be described, all those can be described, but Nirānand cannot be described, because it's Mahāmāyā's Joy. All these joys put together is Nirānanda. So there is no place for ego and superego at all. The complete Sahasrāra is opened out, and nothing but the complete rapport is established with the Divine.<br />
And there is a pouring of light all the time in the head and the light going back, that you have seen in My Photograph. As if the Sahasrāra becomes like a sucking child from the Universal Mother, sucking the joy inside, and it is again reflecting back. It would be like the waves reach the shores and then they are again repleted, they go back and then they form a pattern.<br />
Now the joy out of that pattern, how can you describe? The only thing about Nirānanda is, that you have Mahāmāyā so close and so far away, that's the speciality.<br />
Completely thoughtless, silence there, complete silence, you don't think. It's just silence you cannot put into words any more, because the words break with the force of the Ānanda. They cannot hold it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0502 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirānanda, Āśhram, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But the first nihi means without, devoid, and nira means sheer. <font color="DarkRed">Like when you say Nirānanda, Nirātma: Sheer Ātmā, Sheer Joy. Kevalam, the only. There's nothing but Joy. But this one is used, nira or nihi, used in two forms as I told you: one for saying of ... without or devoid of, the another form is [for saying] the only, absolute, the absolute.<br />
So here the joy becomes Nirānanda: Absolute Joy, nothing but joy. It's complete freedom. So you have all kinds of joys, as I told you before: you have Swānanda, the joy of the Spirit, then you have got Brahmānand, the joy of well-being, you've got Līlānanda, Kṛiṣhṇānand, where you have the joy of the play. But when you reach the State of Sahasrāra it is Nirānand: means Sheer, Absolute Joy.<br />
Though the name Nirā is My name, it means Absolute. So, when you put such an adjective before anything else, it becomes absolute. Thus you become absolute. And when you are at that State of Absolute, then there is no place for anything else to be there but your Self.<br />
......<br />
 So this is what, at Sahasrāra you get Nirānanda.<br />
In different stages of Sahaja Yoga we had to start from Śharīrānanda, means the ā... ānand of the body, Mānasānanda, the joy of the mānasa, is the psyche. Then you can say Ahaṅkārānanda, where you have to have the satisfaction of the ego. But the state has now to be established within us is of Nirānanda.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, State of Absolute (Nirānanda Absolute Joy, Absolute Love, Absolute Compassion, Absolute Power), Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"After listening to all these beautiful words of My children, Mother cannot know what to say, it's very difficult to express My feeling of complete joy -- Kevalānand."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0329 Public Program with Birthday Felicitations (English + Hindi), Sir Shankarlal Concert Hall, Modern School, Bara Khamba Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You must know today that I have been working in Bombay [Mumbai] for about seventeen years and still I find that pettiness is in so many people. Although we may say that there are many Sahaja Yogis, and many do My Pūjā, and many attend programs and also meditate and do Pūjā at home. But what do they achieve in this Pūjā? <font color="DarkRed">"My sister has become all right," "My brother has got the blessings," but did you get Śhivānand [Joy of the Spirit]? Have you been able to establish yourself in this ānand [bliss]? Have you achieved the joy been got of Nirānand? That is what the Mother wishes, that you get the joy of the Sahasrāra.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0214 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi + English), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"And you will be just witnessing that joy within yourself. And you will enjoy it because there is no ... there are no words to describe it. As they say, 'At Sahasrāra, you get Nirānanda,' means only joy, Kevalānanda, Absolute Joy. There's nothing second to it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0607 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On Arrival, Āśhram, Josef Melichar Gasse 20, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I am happy in situations which give comfort to the soul and the Spirit. <font color="DarkRed">And the joy which My Spirit experiences is dependent upon all of you. If you reach the state of Ātmānand, My Heart will be filled with joy.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1227 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (English + Hindi), How We Should Behave, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">And when your entire life becomes cleansed with this Oṃkār, then you get the joy, which is called Ātmānand. You get that.</font> And even in Ātmā, the energy that is there, that is also the Śhakti of Oṃkāra."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1225 Christmas Pūjā (English + Hindi), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So's today we are here to enjoy our joy. Our Ātmānanda, Nirānand and Paramānanda, all these we are here to enjoy, which are of eternal value."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Joy and Happiness, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"About the Ātmā many things have been said, that you get Ātmānand, Brahmānand and Nirānand, which means you go into complete bliss. That joy and [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], does not mean that you turn away from reality, [but] rather you understand reality."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0205 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sahajayog kā Arth (Meaning of Sahaja Yoga), Netaji Indoor Stadium, Kolkata Police Safe House, Eden Gardens, Strand Rd, Maidan, B.B.D. Bagh, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Today while singing the praises of Lord Śhiva the same feeling comes. This Śhakti has been given by Lord Śhiva that is why He is called Ānand Dāyak. There are several constituents of this joy like, Nirānand, Ātmānand, Āhlād ... these resonate with our emotions as a flower resonates with fragrance. In the same way the pure, beautiful, noble feelings in our hearts towards something is āhlād by which we are enthralled. Then there is no desire for anything else."</font><br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"The joy felt by singing Śhrī Śhiva Stuti earlier today, that is because of Śhrī Śhiva. Śhrī Śhiva gives us this ability to be joyous. That is why He is called 'Joy Giver'. The pure joy felt in joy, just joy, there are many types of joy, Ātmānand and Āhlād. This joy is related to our feelings. The feelings in our heart, the good, generous, beautiful loving pure ones of beauty, love, etc. spread fragrance like a flower spreads its fragrance. This is pure joy. In such a joy we are happy and joyous. And as a result we do not need anything else."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0219 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Kyukī Mānava kā Aṃtima Lakṣhya yahī hai kī Vo Śhiva Tattwa ko Prāpta Kare (The Ultimate Aim of Human Beings Is to Attain that Śhiva Tattwa), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Realized Souls have to ascend gradually in their surrender to the innocence of Śhrī Gaṇeśha. People who are simple and chaste like small children, those who are not dominated by dogmatic or fanatical minds, achieve their spontaneous Self-realization (Sahaja Yoga) almost immediately in the mere proximity of highly evolved and God-realized personalities (<i>Avatāras</i>). They feel the sensation of joy on their central nervous system, and as the light of its awareness gradually increases, they experience very unique sensations of bliss. These sensations can be differentiated and also recognized by practice. <font color="DarkRed">In Sanskrit there are four names given to the four kinds of joy experienced by the development of these four types of rippled identities:<br />
<br />
1. <i>Paramānanda</i><br />
<br />
2. <i>Sahajānanda</i><br />
<br />
3. <i>Vīrānanda</i><br />
<br />
4. <i>Yogānanda</i><br />
<br />
They are created by the four petals, which generate Four Powers called <i>Gupta}</i>, <i>Prakasa</i>, <i>Karala</i> and <i>Vikarala</i>.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Types of Joy" /><category term="crimson @ Ahankaranand" /><category term="crimson @ Atmananda" /><category term="crimson @ Atyanta Ananda" /><category term="crimson @ Brahmananda" /><category term="crimson @ Ganeshananda" /><category term="crimson @ Kevalananda" /><category term="crimson @ Krishnananda" /><category term="crimson @ Lilananda" /><category term="crimson @ Manasananda" /><category term="crimson @ Nirananda" /><category term="crimson @ Nirmalananda" /><category term="crimson @ Nityananda" /><category term="crimson @ Parananda" /><category term="crimson @ Paramananda" /><category term="crimson @ Sachchidananda" /><category term="crimson @ Sahajananda" /><category term="crimson @ Sharirananda" /><category term="crimson @ Shivananda" /><category term="crimson @ Swananda" /><category term="crimson @ Swargiya Anand" /><category term="crimson @ Virananda" /><category term="crimson @ Yogananda" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 42: Revolution</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0705" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 42: Revolution" /><published>2023-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post42_CCT_Revolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0705"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">The New Revolution in your awareness has to take place otherwise all human achievements have no meaning.</font> It would be like arranging all the electrical decorations for the marriage without the electrical current But when the light be on, you will see the Bridegroom and the Bride."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes from the book The Advent (2002 edition) by Grégoire de Kalbermatten</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[It's a very simple method, has to be simple because it is very vital. <font color="DarkRed">You are now joining a big revolution in the whole world, which has to bring forth the spirituality into the whole humanity transforming.</font>]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1904-0000 Public Program</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">In the path of revolution such has been happening, that any person who goes into the expertise of anything he sinks, and finishes off.</font><br />
In the same way it is happening to humans. There is so much competition and opposition going on, that man has made his brain so specialist that his brain is bursting.<br />
Now a new type of man is needed that can know this Power beyond the mind. This Power which moves this mind also makes the heart beat. To know that Power you can talk all you want, or try all you want, you cannot reach there. This is without any doubt. It is not written anywhere about which I am talking. I am not saying anything very special."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0715 Guru Pūjā (Hindi) (Guru Pūrṇimā), Sahaja Yoga is a New Discovery, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"If someone is vindictive, or tries to be overbearing, just say, 'I don't care. Where do I have the time for talking to such beggars? Where do I have time for talking to such affluent people or such useless people?'
<font color="DarkRed">Only when this happens, Sahaja Yoga can get established, because Sahaja Yoga is a Revolutionary Path in the center.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0213 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Seminar, Second Floor Hall, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Regarding money, the same thing: if you go to the temple, give the temple priest a rupee and a quarter. There they have kept potbellied people on hire to worship. 'Once these people come and take money, then religion is fulfilled.' People boast that they have contributed so many lākhs of rupees, this is done, then havan and pūjan [worship], etc.<br />
This has no meaning. Because you have no right. Not only havan and pūjan, [but] you have no right even to mention them.<br />
So why this havan, pūjan?<br />
Once you do havan and pūjan then again there is corruption.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Therefore in our country many revolutions took place. They call them religious but I will say these are intellectual revolutions.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0527 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Sahaja Yoga Baddal Sarvānna Sangaychee Hi Sahajayogyānchi Jababdari Āhe (Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"[After 16 seconds:] For example, during war, people lost their values, because they lost faith in God. [After 12 seconds:] Chaste women, who believed in chastity, were brutally assaulted. [After 11 seconds:] Very religious people were persecuted, families were broken, many men were killed, and children, women, and old people, were scattered. A very horrible atmosphere of insecurity, overpowered all these nations. Then came the concentration camps, you see, also, which shattered human beings. Because human beings are very delicate instruments. They are the coveted creations, they are the highest, and they were dominated by things like bombs, which are matter. [After 14 seconds:] Thus the Spirit in man died out. People lost faith in righteousness, in love.<br />
[After 15 seconds:] Then a new pattern of securities were built up.<br />
[After 10 seconds:] <font color="DarkRed">The industrial revolution followed it, as a result.</font> [After 12 seconds:] And the artificial sense of joy, of security, of love, was accepted by the society.<br />
This is what man did with his freedom. Because wars are created by man, this is not God's doing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0400 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Only through Sahaja Kuṇḍalinī Yoga Human Beings Are Going to Evolve (on Nābhī Chakra and its hurdles), (likely) Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK (month and location not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
"<font color="DarkRed">There is a huge revolution taking place in Sahaja: the dharma is getting completely getting established in people in its true form.</font><br />
And due to that people are realizing that there is no point in entertaining such fake gurus who keep robbing them. There is no point in sticking to traditions that make you stupid and bring you down.<br />
Traditions which make you ascend, which take you to higher, which establish you in the Realm of Spirituality, only those traditions are supposed to be regarded as genuine ones."<br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
"<font color="DarkRed">There is a huge revolution taking place in Sahaja Yoga: as the true nature of religion has come to the fore, the dharma is getting completely established.</font><br />
People are now realizing that the unnecessary intermediaries keep robbing them and they will no longer pay alms to them.<br />
Traditions which make fool of you are of no use. Traditions which make you wise, which take you to a higher level, which really enlighten you spiritually, only those traditions should be considered genuine."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">In the same way, Rāhurī's Mister [Madhukar] Dhumāḷ who was giving a lecture in front of you, he has brought about a revolution in villages and posts.</font> Many Sahaja Yogis from Rāhurī have come with him and each one of them is a Sahaja Yogi like a polished diamond. If you would like to know how knowledgeable he is and if you would like to see an understanding about God Almighty, then you should have some discussion with him."<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Similarly, Mister Dhumāḷ from Rāhurī who was giving the lecture before us, he has also created a revolution in the villages.</font> There are quite a few Sahaja Yogis who have come along with him from Rāhurī, and each one of them is a beautiful Sahaja Yogi, chiseled like a diamond. To understand how knowledgeable they are and how deep their knowledge of the Divine Principle is, one must have discussion with them."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0227 Public Program (Marathi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The concept of Form and Formless should be explained so that these conflicts get resolved.<br />
When our right channel was being created, the five elements had to be awakened. You know these five elements, all of this creation was made with them. So, these five elements had to be awakened with Yagñyas from the Vedas, and prayers and praises were recited. The five elements were awakened with Yagñyas. It was necessary to awaken these five elements, the fire, the water. It was only after they were awakened that human beings could have put them to use. Agriculture started after that as did the idea of science.<br />
If our Piṅgalā nāḍī hadn't been awakened we wouldn't have researched into science nor known how to use these five elements, how to make electricity and how to use fire. We wouldn't have known fire let alone how to make it!<br />
So that we become capable of making all this, that's why the right side had to be worshipped. That's why Yagñyas were performed. And because all these energies are formless, that's why the Formless was worshipped at that time.<br />
Once these were awakened, people wondered what to do next.<br />
Then meditation started and people came to the Central Path.<br />
Once they started progressing on the Suṣhumṇā, they could see where the Deities were seated and that the bodies of the chakras were made of these five elements. When they studied the elements, they realized that they were governed by Deities. After that, they got to know these Deities one after the other, through meditation.<br />
Then they claimed that they had Forms so the focus shifted from the Formless to Form. Those whose awareness evolved came to the Form.<br />
Then you know what happened to the ones who started believing in the Forms. `Worship this!', `Worship that!' Ritualism came into being. Blind faith and religious fanaticism came into being and things were in a miserable state.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Then there was a great revolution, and not only that, Muhammad Sāheb took His birth. Christ came into this world. These people said that the Formless is to be worshipped and to do away with the Form.</font>"<br />
There was a lot of secrecy in this matter at that time.<br />
However, the Bible says that, `All that is made by the Earth and the Sky should not be replicated and worshipped.' If Christians could understand this and apply this understanding to the practice of idol worship.<br />
What has the Earth made? The Earth has made all the swayambhus.<br />
Now tell the Christians that the Earth has made the swayambhus Herself and if you make their replicas, they are not worthy of worship because they're imperfect.<br />
These things have a coefficient, too. Forms have a coefficient because of which there is a flow of the Chaitanya.<br />
It is impossible to replicate those forms in exactly the same way. Also, the one who makes them should be a realized Soul who should not put his creation up for sale. Keeping this in mind, mostly all the idols that we worship are of zero value."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0304 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Session 2 (evening), Town Hall, Dehradun, Uttarakhand, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0311 Public Program (English + Hindi), Day 2, Session 2 (evening), On Gāndhī and Collective Consciousness, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today our country needs a big spiritual revolution.}"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1011 Public Program (Hindi) (8th Day of Navarātri), Sahajyog ke Anubhav (Experience of Sahaja Yoga), Ice Skating Ring, Kolkata, West Bengal, India (place and date not sure)}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Modern democracies began to emerge in the eighteenth century, but at around the same time, with the advancement of science, the industrial revolution began to manifest itself. What we call industrial and commercial values were also generated by the advent of the industrial or technological society.</font> As it is, science is absolutely amoral. It does not conform to the rules and regulations laid down for the human value system. Science is the knowledge of matter and matter has its own internal regulations. Unlike human beings, matter does not have free will with which to establish any ethical value system for itself. In pure science, which is amoral, this quality has been carried over, almost without anyone noticing, into the practical and applied field through technology. Thus, industry and (in close association with it) commerce have become absolutely amoral.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">There is a tendency, built up in the West since the time of Enlightenment and the democratic revolutions of the 18th century, that we should be free to absorb all the unrighteous, unholy, inauspicious and destructive ideas that we can find in every film, every book, and every newspaper, whatever the source. Somehow people want to take up the challenge to become the evil force themselves. People have now to decide if they want to stop this democratic derailment by understanding what must be done. The progress that the West is proud of is towards complete destruction, as human beings have the freedom to achieve heaven or go to hell and also they have the tremendous power of rationality to justify their doom.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 3: Democracy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Revolution" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 41: Love</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0628" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 41: Love" /><published>2023-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post41_CCT_Love</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0628"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"... the Kuṇḍalinī, the residual Divine Power, resides in the triangular bone at the base of the spine. It is the germinating power of the seed of your being. This seed sprouts through Sahaja Yoga. I am like the gardener who pours some water on the seeds which he has planted in his garden. At first, only a few flowers come up, but at the time of the blossoming the phenomenon of en masse Self-realization is manifested. <font color="red">This Divine Love that I pour is your own right for this is the culminating point of the human evolution which has been promised by the Scriptures.</font>
......
<font color="red">Can you conceive of an energy which thinks, organizes, feels and love?</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="red">If love cannot blossom in the optimum conditions of marriage how can it blossom out of it? How can the whole world know love?</font><br />
......<br />
They [husband and wife] are not similar but both are equal, no doubt! One is the right and the other the left wheel of the chariot. If one wheel is bigger than the other, the chariot cannot move properly. Both must be respected. The husband-wife relationship has to be absolutely informal; all artificiality must be dropped. <font color="red">They must love and also sometimes quarrel to show their concern. This is the sign of a healthy relationship. But a woman has to behave like a woman and man has to be like a man. Spontaneous fidelity, love and mutual sharing are the only way one can give and receive the joy of married life.</font> The slightest deviation from conjugal fidelity must be absolutely avoided, and if committed, openly confessed. A person who does not believe in a one-woman one-man relationship should not marry at all; why make another person unhappy? The effects of secret infidelity are of the worst kind and can ruin the whole society?<br />
......<br />
What sin can you commit that I cannot devour? <font color="red">You know, the Devī's Love is like the bottom of the ocean; no matter how big the ocean is, its bottom is always bigger.</font><br />
......<br />
[Related to the seekers that come to public programs and then they fizzle out due to the escapism that, 'Śhrī Mātājī is too pure and too great':] <font color="red">The ocean of sin cannot be greater than the heart of your Lord who loves you.</font> He can drink all the poison. Come back.<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">I think your childhood must have been very harsh, that is why you do not know the art of love.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="red">Love is much more powerful than all the hatred of the world.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes from the book The Advent (2002 edition) by Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Pages 51, 69, 120, 123, 226, 234, 265, 267</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There is no need to think about others' wrong. <font color="red">Satisfaction is the boat and love is the oar.</font> Why to make our life's hard‽<br />
......<br />
Does Gaṅgā measure the value of your pitcher? ...... Gaṅgā has accepted you and came to your house. <font color="red">She washes your feet, so that you can accept this pure love and fill others' pitcher.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes from Various Letters (likely Hindi) from Anant Jeevan, Issue 2, Inside Front Cover</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This is the era of Enlightenment. One can see and feel the bubbling of new idioms in our creative world of art, music and all that is beautiful and joy-giving. Integration is the key note of this new regeneration of universal tones. These tones are ripples of the harmonic, dynamic undercurrent music of the Universal Divine Love.</font><br />
<font color="red">Is there a possibility of this love expressed in the unity of human beings with God Almighty giving a new vision to the apparent diversities?</font><br />
Is it possible that this unique happening is accessible to many, that they may see their own creative world revolving in the great universe of All-pervading Power?<br />
My only answer is, 'Yes.'<br />
My only question is, 'Why not?' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from The Life Eternal, 1980 Issue, Pages 46, 48 and 50, from a 1984 Pamphlet, Brighton, East Sussex, UK, and from the Back Cover of The Advent (2002 edition)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Never forget that your Mother is very powerful, that She knows everything and that She loves you very much."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 1 (January-February 1981), Page 11</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"You cannot love Me, if you don't love your sister and your brother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from Nirmala Yoga, Issue Issue 9 (May-June 1982), Page 22</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Magnanimity of mind is very pleasing and it attracts others. This magnanimity lies within human being and is awakened by Kuṇḍalinī. But how can those people have this joy of spontaneity who are living in artificial atmosphere? Although Kuṇḍalinī has been awakened and She has pierced Brahmarandhra yet heart must be pierced. <font color="red">But some Sahaja Yogis have hearts like stones, absolutely devoid of love; they use sarcastic words while talking to others and want to show that they are great. On many occasions I have seen, people push others or shout at others even in My presence. Particularly, when you shout at the children, I feel pain in My heart. At least Sahaja Yogis should have deep love for each other. When you know that you are the children of the same Mother, why do you look down upon some people? Are you perfect? Are there no faults in you? We only talk of Universal Love. If you have no love for each other amongst you, then in which mankind will it be seen? All I want to tell you is to clean your minds of venomous thoughts that you have for other Sahaja Yogis.</font><br />
If a Sahaja Yogi visits your town, invite him, look after him, as if he is your brother. His happiness will purify your homes. I cannot understand how there can be groups among the Sahaja Yogis, because every moment your condition is improving or going down.<br />
Know that making such groups is disastrous. <font color="red">Look at the good qualities of others and enjoy their love.</font> Don't worry about their bad qualities. Leave them for Me. You will realize in meditation that this is the only way of opening the fountains of bliss."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 13 (January-February 1983), Pages 23 and 25</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Sahaja Yogi parents have great responsibility towards their realized children. <font color="red">They have to be protected, disciplined and brought up in proper atmosphere of love.</font> Realized children cannot tolerate negativity. They fight with it."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Two Quotes from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 13 (January-February 1983), Page 25</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">When you start feeling love, respect and awe towards God Almighty, it's a sign that your faith and belief, that God Almighty is all-powerful and also that He takes care of us, has established.</font> God Almighty is always showering us with blessings and His Grace. God Almighty is ever compassionate. You cannot imagine how much compassionate God Almighty is. <font color="red">He is extremely compassionate but equally merciless. It is impossible to survive His wrath. Nothing can stop Him, not even My Love.</font> God Almighty will say that I have given a lot of freedom, lenience to all My children. And that's why they have spoilt. That's why I ask that you do not get into any wrong doings and do not discredit your Mother. I remind you again not to lose your precious time in wasteful activities but completely imbibe Sahaja Yoga."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Four Quotes from Nirmala Yoga (Hindi), Issue 22 (November-December 1985), Back Cover</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Concerned listener:</b> Mother, how will other people understand Your message?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">Everyone understands love, don't they?</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Three Quotes from the booklet H. H. Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī, a life dedicated to humanity</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The greatest mistake is to close one's heart. However hurt one may be, remember that within there is someone who always loves you. She is your individual mother, your Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
She is connected to the All-pervading Power of Divine Love, which never abandons you.<br />
In Her Love, there are no expectations. There is only a tender glow that takes us to Her presence."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from the booklet Sahaja Yoga the true meditation</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Human love means possession and determination.<br />
Divine Love soothes you, It raises you to a new awareness. It is something that's just flowing. Not rationality, nothing. It is to feel, feeling for the pain of others. Feeling for their longing and feeling for their aspirations. Just feel within.</font><br />
With Yoga [Self-realization] we become collectively conscious. We can feel our centers and that of others on the fingertips. As Muhammad Sāhib had said, ``At the Time of Resurrection, your fingers will speak."<br />
The Namāz has the real ritual to know the Spirit.<br />
The Pūjās and worship all pour joy on our central nervous system. We feel the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost, the Chaitanya Laharī in living experience. We become one with the Divine and the rapport is established. The Divine Vibrations indicate and the coding if we know them, we know their meanings. <font color="red">Love has its own bondage -- very sweet and beautiful. We have to know the waves of the Divine Ocean of Grace and enjoy them.</font><br />
If a child comes and spoils our house then we should enjoy the fun of spoiling. If our freedom is challenged by a little child's crying, we are not a wise person. It's abandonment, it's loneliness, it's cutting off from the Primordial One that we are not being able to tolerate other people's freedom. We have to be truly free. When a little child cannot cry in its own home, what kind of freedom is that? If a child cannot eat what he wants in his own home what kind of freedom is that? <font color="red">Of course, this freedom is to be pruned, nourished and developed in the Correct Way of Love.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from the book Gita Enlightened (2014) by Yogi Mahajan, Pages 56 and 57</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"It [Kuṇḍalinī] organizes and plans everything, and above all loves you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from the book Gita Enlightened (2014) by Yogi Mahajan, Page 322</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Kuṇḍalinī gives Self-knowledge, that is She points out problems on chakras. She is the pure desire, meaning chaste desire. There is no lust, greed, anything and She is your own individual mother. She knows everything about you and is absolutely the knowledge.<br />
<font color="red">She is the pure light of knowledge, love, compassion and attention. She is the tremendous force within, the storehouse of compassion, love and knowledge and Ocean of Forgiveness. She is the power which is Absolute Purity, auspiciousness, pure love, detachment, concern, enlightened attention and joy.</font> She gives Witness State, peace, security, and wisdom ..."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from the 1997 book Music and Sahaja Yoga by Arun Apte, Pages 167 and 168</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Dear Sahaja Yogis, lots of love to all of you!<br />
You all lovingly came to Santa Cruz [Airport in Mumbai] in the rain but we could only meet for a moment. You showered so much love on Me that I was completely overwhelmed. I was so delighted by it that vibrations from different chakras continuously started flowing through every pore of My body. Many chakras that were dormant until now became active. I was witnessing a miracle of your love. Keep sending such pure love. I bless you that you all will achieve all the infinite that is beyond this mahāmāyā.<br />
This love is not the regular human love and is like Ambrosia. It is like a drizzle but there are waves of the ocean behind it. That ocean has decided to drench you. You should remember that the actions of Me going away from you or Me running towards you, are the two ropes used for churning. I enjoy this as a witness. My chakras are the churner that are churning you and the butter of love comes up. I am standing just like a pole -- immovable and inevitable.<br />
You are worthy of this love. You should stay immersed in that love and share it with others.</font> And distributing this Nectar is the only condition. That Kṛiṣhṇa who stole the butter to share with others should be awakened in you. Somehow you must acquire that butter. As the plane was delayed, I was thinking that you all must be waiting and how it will all work out, and I would have thanked God if you had gone back. I am your innocent Mother. <font color="red">Sometimes I get angry at you when you make a mistake but you should remember that I have come on this Earth because I love you immensely.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-0000 Letter (Marathi) to Sahaja Yogis</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And what security of understanding. That everywhere in the whole world we have brothers and sisters who are on their Inner Being, on their Divine, and how we are bound together with that love.<br />
When I talk of love, people think that I am trying to make you weak people. Because people think those who l... love are weak. But the most dynamic power in this world is that of love. Is the most aggressive power, is that of love. Even we, when suffer in love, it is out of our strength that we suffer and not out of our weakness.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="red">The Love that I am talking about, the Divine Love, makes you not only strong but dynamic. It is the Greatest Luminous Power that we can think of. Only when Love is surrounded by gross, and is lost in the gross, it looks as if it is weak and under chains. The time it is released, the Dynamic Power of Love can transcend all the evil powers of the world.</font><br />
......<br />
But it is not now for the realized to sit down and to wonder and laugh at the foolishness of the people who are not yet realized. Not even to take pity on them, but to come out. <font color="red">'Come out with the sword of love to win the whole world,' it is very, very essential.</font> If the creation has to be saved, then you are not to keep mum about it.<br />
<font color="red">All the wrong ideas about love, all the falsehood about love, has to be given up.</font><br />
......"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0828 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Most Dynamic Power of Love, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Love" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Miscellaneous Post 2: Linktree</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0418" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Miscellaneous Post 2: Linktree" /><published>2023-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Misc_Post2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0418"><![CDATA[<p>
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
At the suggestion of Uncle John Noyce back in October 2021, we are pleased to let you know that 
the team has a Linktree account <a href="https://linktr.ee/comprehensivecompilationsteam">CCT</a> that stores the links of all the main pages of websites we manage. It can be used to have all these links handy (for personal usage or sharing). The subscribers would also be notified whenever new links are added to the account.<br />
Please kindly share the link with all our brothers and sisters.<br />

<br />
The Comprehensive Compilations Team (CCT)<br />
sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="violet @ Miscellaneous" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, Jay Śhrī Mātājī! At the suggestion of Uncle John Noyce back in October 2021, we are pleased to let you know that the team has a Linktree account CCT that stores the links of all the main pages of websites we manage. It can be used to have all these links handy (for personal usage or sharing). The subscribers would also be notified whenever new links are added to the account. Please kindly share the link with all our brothers and sisters.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 40: Oṃ and Auṃ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0412" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 40: Oṃ and Auṃ" /><published>2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post40_CCT_Aum_Om</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0412"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"mixture of seven sounds when heard together create a beautiful sound like OM or when broken it sounds like A, oo, MA. This sound is without percussion and hence is known as Anahata[.] It is written and heard as ॐ ie Devnagri [Devanāgarī] script for OM. Later on Anahata passing through the different centers of the Kund[a]lini becomes the word."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Om related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[Both right/left treatment needed, paper burning helps depression, maṭakā, look through candle flame at Bindhi, do not meditate with eyes closed, only close eyes when thinking stops, right Āgñyā ice, Auṃ Ham Kṣham.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advices Given to Dr. Madhur Rai, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had only one Son who was Praṇava incarnate. <font color="red">Think of it, He was Auṃ incarnate. He incarnated on this Earth.</font> His name was Jesus Christ. Mary was His Mother. He was placed on the Āgñyā chakra."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now She is in this form. So the beginning of the Auṃ starts. Parabola, first of all, gets converted into Auṃ. Then She pushes Herself down and settles down for a while to meditate and to find out how She is going to work it out, we can say like this."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0220 Public Program, Creation and Evolution, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"For example the Word, what is the Word? Is it Logos or something? What is that? What is it comprising of, what does that mean, how it starts, from where it has come? It is Auṃ. Auṃ comes from three words uh, ooh, muh. Uh, ooh, muh.<br />
Uh stands for the first creation of the left-hand side, what we call the Mahākālī Power. First only in the world manifestation of the superego took place, so we can say that uh stand for the beginning when only up to the stage when life was not created.<br />
Ooh stands for the other stage, where, now sound is the same. Sound is the same, manifestation is different. The voice is the same, My sound is the same, for example whatever is My sound, you can make it out wherever I speak, this is Mātājī speaking.<br />
Maybe the manifestation is different in uh, ooh, muh, so first uh starts, then comes to ooh, which is Mahāsaraswatī Power. We can say the three notes which we have as, I don't know in English what you say to the notes but we say sah, uh sah [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], the basic three notes, so the second note is that of Mahāsaraswatī by which the life -- sun life -- started working.<br />
And the third one is the muh through which evolution started taking its place. So that is the Mahālakṣhmī stage.<br />
So you have got these Three Powers working together, and that is, in a very short form, we say it is Auṃ.<br />
But it is not only that human beings have said it. When you meditate you have seen that Auṃ. I'm saying that these Three Powers have a third, these three sounds, and that's how this word is created, of Auṃ.<br />
For a realized Soul, Auṃ is a most powerful thing. For example, if you want to protect yourself, the word Auṃ itself can protect, and when these Three Powers combine as Auṃ we say that this only the Child or the Son God represents in its purest form Auṃ. That's why in the life of Christ, or we can say in the life of a personality that represented the Son of God, Auṃ is very important because He embodies that Auṃ within Himself. All these Three Powers are in Him, and in the most innocent form.<br />
......<br />
In this sound of Oṃkāra, the complete sounds of the worlds are there. All the permutations and combinations, the complete melody of this universities within these three sounds uh, ooh, muh. It is based on Auṃ.<br />
When the Kuṇḍalinī moves also, it moves in three ways uh, ooh, muh, because in the lower portion it is the uh. In the center portion it is the ooh, and here it is the muh. Meaning that at the lower portion of the human being we are what was created as dead matter. In the center we are what is creation, means creativity, and in the third is the evolutionary, so even we are divided in three ways -- is, we are, our upper part is muh, central part is ooh and the lower part is uh. That is how we are, and when you say Auṃ in a proper way, you find the Kuṇḍalinī rises.<br />
......<br />
Auṃ works like anything. Now you may say that where is the word Auṃ in the Christian religion? It is in Amen. Amen is nothing but Auṃ, because muh means a nasal sound, and end of a nasal sound, and nuh also means nasal sound, because in the Arabic language it's written like a nee, you see, and nee with My name, you say, nuh, with My name starts nuh, also written with a dot, all of them have got a dot. It's a dot which shows that it's a nuh. And in the Sanskrit language, dot means nuh. And that is why it is muh and nuh. Amen is the same as Auṃ.<br />
Now the problem is everything, as evolution goes up, changes and that's why Auṃ was brought to the level of Amen. Uh became Ah and Ooh became Muh, and Muh became Nuh. As I told you that Christ came as a human being, but He was Gaṇeśha. And the Swastika became the cross. The same way, Auṃ is Amen.<br />
So after every prayer, you are supposed to say Amen. Why not Amen? What does that mean? From there the word Auṃ ends in English language.<br />
......<br />
Now the same word Auṃ is used by negative forces also. How do they use it? They will give this name to some devil, normally they do not, because this is one of the purest words which cannot be Contaminated. Normally they will not, normally they will not. I have not met anyone so far who has got a devil on him with the name Auṃ, and nobody so far has given this name to anyone, but I have seen.<br />
......<br />
He [person giving names] can use, but he cannot use the name of Auṃ, and he cannot use the name of Jesus. He cannot give the name of Śhrī Gaṇeśh. These names are beyond their [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. You see because they are terrible. ...... They might say all kinds of Auṃs and everything. But with all of these they can attack someone, like this, they say Auṃ namo Śhivaya, it's all right. Auṃ namo Śhiva, now, Auṃ you have put it, in that it neutralizes, they perhaps do not know it neutralizes a little bit. Auṃ namo Śhivaya.<br />
And it means so great, means you bow to Śhiva. That aspect of God which is eternal. But they will say that you take the name Auṃ namo Śhivaya because with that the thing you see, it's overpowered by Śhiva, and that's how they will put Auṃ with that, but they'll never give a single word as Auṃ at [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] point, because no devil will own that name, it's too great. And these are the tricks these people play with the word Auṃ, and you should play with the same. Whenever you feel like that, you just say Auṃ. Don't say anything else, say Auṃ. For you, every sentence has an end. Even if you say Auṃ namo Śhivaya [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. But even if you say Auṃ Jesus, it's enough. Now in a circle, if you say the complete universe into a circle, then you make three portions of that, you get three arches. Say one is uh, another ooh, another muh. When you try to reconstruct them, then you get uh ooh and muh, there are three arches, you reconstruct them. First arch is bent like this ... uh, ooh, second one like that, and the third one is muh. And the dot on that is the center point Is the center point of the circle, dot on that. Now you have seen how Auṃ is written down, and that is how it is, the three arches are described like that, so the whole creation and the center dot, which is the God Himself, all put together makes the Auṃ, and that is how it is being named. I think I have told you now first of all when the creation too, place, how first the Auṃ was formed. Did I tell you with the parabola, with the drawing, so the first sound, the first sound that started because of the separation, the first separation when it too, place between the two identities, God and His Power, that was the time the sound started, and that sound is nothing else but Auṃ. That sound will be there and will work out till these two identities become one, then there is no relativity left and so there is nothing, so people think the world has come out of nothing, because there is no relativity, when they become two then there is something, otherwise they are one and absolute, and so there is nothing, when the sound merges or finishes or, as we say, disappears [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] That is the time when the whole creation merges into one action. So that is the point where one has to go.<br />
Now, in your own being it happens. First you feel the Auṃ, you feel it sometimes the sound coming, sometimes you feel some sort of tingling going on, because there are seven sounds, which are easily discernible out of this Auṃ. Easily. But there are many, but I am saying at least seven you can easily find out. If you sit down sometimes you might hear some sort of a bell ringing, sometimes you'll hear as if there is a waterfall, and sometimes you'll hear as if in the night, the small crickets are singing. You see all kinds of sounds are coming, you see you feel that they are there, something is happening, in the night, you see, that sort of a feeling you'll get, all different types of sounds there are, but seven sounds you can easily find out, and all of them put together make the Auṃ. So, if you play all of them in a proper manner, in a melodious manner, well we can say in a harmonious manner, then you'll hear the sound Auṃ.<br />
......<br />
So this Auṃ is, is a sound that understands, that talks, hat organizes, that informs, and that is the sound of the Divine Love. This is the electrical feeling that you get on your hand. But this is the sound.<br />
......<br />
So we have got also five very subtle type of expression of five elements, and those are this fine sound of Auṃ, the vibrations are the electrical, there is a magnet in that sound, or in that powered, for a person who is, who is realized. The person who is blessed by God has a magnetic power. That person attracts. That person might not even speak about, but people know about these things. They know that he's a man who's realized, there's something special about him. Immediately you can find it out, what he is. It is because of this sound and the magnet. You must have heard that sound when we converted into matter. In the same way, all these things are converted, the sound becomes a magnet, the magnet becomes the vibrations, the vibrations can become the Spirit. So these are all convertible, and part and parcel of the same thing, the same energy which is the Divine Love, which is Love. Love has a sound, and love has electricity, it has got magnetism. And it has got the power. When all these subtle powers are poured on to any human being, it acts, it acts, and people start improving in their health. You must have heard of experiments where people have tried music on some people who are hot well, and they have been cured. And what happens is that they, the subtler, subtler powers of the sound that we are manifesting, that behind it, the power that is manifesting it, comes into play. Which is a very small thing there, but with you people, when you put you hand this is the sound of Auṃ which is vibrating, it is so micro, microwaved, vibrations, that you cannot see with a magnifying glass, you will not see My finger shaking at all, you'll say they are very steady, but they're very microwaves. And the microwaves, when they pass into the body of the human beings, or anything, there they awaken the microwaves that are sleeping in the body of the human beings, or whatever things you use, and they start generating the second, what you call, phase as the [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] of the outside [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
......<br />
Now, when you people say Auṃ, realized people, when You say Auṃ, the sound waves of Auṃ, you just try on a person who is. Just now you are having some pain there. All right. Now, just now you put your hand there and say Auṃ. Try it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0400 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Auṃ, (likely) Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK (month and location not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Today as Yogi has asked Me to speak about Auṃ, I would like to tell you about the great word called Auṃ: what it is, what it represents, and how it came into being.<br />
......<br />
Auṃ is a word people don't understand because it is at the very beginning of this creation that the energy of God, energy of His Love separated from His identity. He pushed Her, called it as Lāsya, He pushed Her to create, and He became the spectator and She had to create. At that time when She was pushed -- we don't have here something to show you how it worked -- but when He tried to push Her, Her movements went into a kind of a word which is [draws with the right index finger in the air]: written as like this three, A, U and M. So there are three words in it. At the time of that pushing, when the separation took place, there was a sound, this the first sound and that sound is called as Auṃ.<br /> 
So many people call it as Logos, but to understand it you have to go deeper into it to und[erstand] what it is was.<br />
So Her power got divided into three: A, U and M. And that's how She became Auṃ. So Auṃ is the sound which is emitted when She creates, which acts as the basis of the essence of Her Love.<br />
Then how She started creating is a very long story which I won't be able to tell you today, but this Auṃ is the one that She first used to create the innocence on this Earth. So this Auṃ was the innocence with which She filled the whole universe. So Auṃ is nothing but the innocence that you see in children, in so many people, in Saints and in most of the Incarnations, that they are empowered by Their innocence. And this innocence first filled the whole space. Even before creating the space the innocence was there. That was the first creation of element and that was the innocence. So Auṃ is innocence which does all the living work on this Earth.<br />"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0929 Public Program, Day 2, Auṃ, Cultural Integration Fellowship, 260 Fulton Street, San Francisco, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"<font size="+1">The Sound of Praṇava</font><br />
Praṇava's sound is known as <i>Anāhat</i>. It is generated when the Primordial Cell breaks like the hatching of an egg. It is audible with the departure of the nucleus from the ellipse.<br />
<br />
* The first linear movement of Ādi Śhakti makes the First Primordial Sound -- 'Ā'.<br />
* The push of Sadāśhiva causes the Second Primordial Sound -- 'Ū'.<br />
* The Third Sound -- 'MA' -- is caused by the pause stage, which follows the breathing in and breathing out of the Primordial Zygote.<br />
<br />
Praṇava is therefore the All-pervading Divine Power of Ādi Śhakti, and Anāhat is the sound created, without any percussion, by this Power. It can be understood better by describing Anāhat as the sound announcement of Praṇava.<br />
These three Primordial Syllables 'Ā', 'Ū' and 'MA', represent the Three Powers of the Primordial Mother:<br />
<br />
* 'Ā' represents the existence and Destructive Power of Mahākālī<br />
* 'Ū' represents the Creative Power of Mahāsaraswatī<br />
* 'MA' represents the Sustenance or Evolutionary Power of Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
<br />
These three Primordial Syllables, later on, form the Primordial Words (<i>Bīja Mantras</i>) 'Aim', 'Hrīm' and 'Klīm'. All together these comprise the phonetic words of the Devanāgarī script (Sanskrit), and will be examined in greater detail in the chapter on chakras.<br />
Much before the hatching of the Primordial Egg, the Primordial Zygote reaches the embryonic stage. It starts breathing and creates the Primordial Sound (<i>Anāhata</i>) that fills the entire embryo, which encircles the central point. The breathing of Ādi Śhakti is the Praṇava or Divine Power, while its sound is called Anāhata. This sound is without percussion and is heard on the heart as a pulsation. This sound is a mixture of seven component sounds (<i>Nādabrahman</i>), which when heard together creates the beautiful Word, 'Auṃ'. When it is broken into its component parts it sounds like 'Ā', 'Ū' and 'MA'. It later ascends through the different subtle centers on the path of Kuṇḍalinī (the residual power of Praṇava) and becomes the Word.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Pages 9 and 10</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Om" /><category term="crimson @ Aum" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 39: Jaundice</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0405" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 39: Jaundice" /><published>2023-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post39_CCT_Jaundice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0405"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Treatment for jaundice is as follows. Boil young radish leaves in water, add rock candy to that water and drink it continuously. Do not drink any other water. Vibrate the water before drinking.<br />
Second treatment is to put some mustard oil in a brass or a bronze bowl and rotate it (oil) in a clockwise direction with either nābhī [finger] or all the fingers. One of the hands -- left or right -- should be towards the photo. Watch both hands, and whichever hand feels lighter should be kept towards the photo. The oil will slowly become thick and yellow. Do not throw this oil in water but take it far away and burn it. You will feel better if you do this two-three times. Do not eat any oil or ghee at all. Give vibration[s] to Nābhī and liver while keeping the other hand towards the photo."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-1029 Letter (Marathi) to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[1. Drink every morning and evening one glass of radish leaf juice.]<br /> 
[2. Drink in the morning one glass of kokum syrup.]<br />
[3. Holding an ice pack with the left hand, place it on the liver, with the right hand toward the picture of Śhrī Mātājī and meditate without any candle light or diya (lamp) in front of the picture.]<br />
[4. You can eat Bengali sweets.]<br />
[5. No fried food, red meat or fat under any circumstances.]<br />
[6. No fish or dairy products at all except buttermilk in which butter has been skimmed off.]<br />
[7. No cheese at all.]<br />
[8. Liv 52 tablets: 3-4 tablets per day for two months.]<br />
[9. All citrus fruits are OK (no mango, apple, banana, papaya or chīkū).]<br />
[10. Sugar cane juice or sugar cane is very good.]<br />
[11. No butter at all.]<br />
[12. No uṛada dāl (arhar/tuar).]<br />
[13. Boiled rice, all vegetables, moong dāl are OK.]<br />
[14. No chilies in food.]<br />
[15. Ginger, potato, onion, and cucumber are OK.]<br />
[16. Regular intake of lemon juice with vibrated sugar is OK.]<br />
[17. No ice cream.]<br />
[18. Amalā kā murabbā is good and can be taken with both meals.]<br />
[19. Silver varak on food is good.]<br />
[20. All vegetables fruits grown under the earth are OK.]<br />
[21. No groundnuts, no ground nut oil. Groundnut oil is very bad for liver. Sunflower oil in little quantity is all right.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advice (Diet) for Jaundice, Hepatitis, and Overheated Liver from Divine Cool Breeze (India), Volume 4, Issues 8 and 9 (August--September 1992), Page 22</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, this Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra is to be looked after.<br />
In Delhi, Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra is the first problem. Firstly, because you think too much. Secondly, you think you are running the show. Thirdly, the water of Delhi is not good.<br />
I've requested all the people, all the Sahaja Yogis to boil their foo... water and drink it. And never wat... drink water outside. At the most if you have to drink then you can drink something bottled. But try to boil the water all the time to keep your Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra all right.<br />
<font color="red">It [unboiled water] causes jaundice and all kinds of problems, because water is the basis of Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra.</font><br />
So if you try to spoil the Nābhī, by ... Nābhī is the basis, and N... if Nābhī gets spoiled, then Swādhiṣhṭhāna also gets spoiled. Because from Nābhī the Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra has arisen.<br />
Moreover, one has to know how to give balance to oneself, ah-ah ... when the Swādhiṣhṭhāna is out."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0206 Public Program, Day 2, Swādhiṣhṭhāna Chakra, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Sahaja Yoga diabetes is absolutely curable. <font color="red">Jaundice and all these diseases of the liver are also absolutely curable in Sahaja Yoga.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0303 Public Program, Day 2, God Has Created Us with a Purpose, Town Hall, Hay Street and Barrack Street, Perth, WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">Now, this kind of a hand, if you see, yellowish color, all right, ...</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> It's liver!<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">... itself, it means liver. This is a liver patient: definitely a liver patient, this one.<br />
Now, for such a hand, what should you do: is to take uh-uh-uh the water that I've given you, and boil it with radish leaves. And take radish leaves and sugar with it. That water you have to take for some time.<br />
Specially when you have this flood water. After that you should be careful, because people can get jaundice.</font><br />
You see, this flood is not such a disaster: the aftereffects of floods are.<br /> 
This water is not good, you should not take any other water but spring water. Spring water you should drink. <font color="red">And, as far as possible, be careful about jaundice.</font><br />
<font color="red">If jaundice sets in, the only solution is that you should take radish leaves, eat lot of radish, and boil it in that water that I give you, today, and put some sugar in it, and just take that water, nothing else.</font><br />
Because that's one thing one has to be careful: when such a flood comes in, the aftereffects of the floods can be felt. All right?<br />
......<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>  [Taping on the palm of the lady with jaundice:] <font color="red">Jaundice!<br />
Do you get jaundice in this country?</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> Oh, yes!<br />
<b>Gentleman:</b> Yes.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font> <font color="red">Do you get jaundice in this country?</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> Very much.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font> <font color="red">So one should know how to treat jaundice and look after yourself.<br />
Jaundice is really, could be fatal and is very dangerous because it spoils your uh liver very badly.<br />
So, to be on safe side, eat lot of radish, and the uh also take that water as I told you, for your jaundice.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0306 Workshop, Mother Are You the Holy Ghost, Park on the Bank of River Torrens, Adelaide, SA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, all other such diseases, specially the worst of all, that is the result. Of course, liver is horrifyingly bad.<br />
And liver can be cured through Sahaj Yog only. It cannot be cured up.<br />
Actually I have seen that people develop cirrhosis of liver or cancer of liver, only then we realize that the fellow has a liver trouble.<br />
<font color="red">But liver starts at a very early age in ... specially in the Western countries. Because the mothers are always thinking, the fathers are always planning, the poor child is born with jaundice, is born with jaundice.<br />
And jaundice is so easily curable. But so many people die of this little thing called jaundice, children specially.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0131 Public Talk to Doctors (English mixed with Marathi), Dr. Vaishampayan Memorial Government Medical College, Jawaharlal Housing Society, Opp. District Court, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Children need sugar so give it. But not in such a form that it sticks to teeth but which goes in the stomach.<br />
Secondly, in summers a fruit named kokum is found in Maharashtra. Soak it overnight, and boil it next day, add some sugar and give it to the child during day.<br />
<font color="red">If one suffers from jaundice, then boil radish leaves, mix vibrated sugar and give to the child. Child can be cured of jaundice in one day.</font><br />
In summers give juice of radish. Give radish to children, it is good for them.<br />
We give lot of fried this to children, it should not be done."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0325 Chaitra Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Sahajyogiyo Keliye Bhartiya Sanskṛiti ka Mahatva (Importance of Indian Culture for Sahaja Yogis), Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So I concluded that a drunkard's child is born with a damaged liver. <font color="red">So, you have given your child a damaged liver from the beginning, and as soon as a child is born, he will get jaundice.</font> If the father's or mother's liver is damaged, then the child also is born with a damaged liver."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0219 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Session 1 (evening), A Sahaja Yogi Will Reflect on the Outside His Inner Quality, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then I have also seen that a some children have very uh uh thin body, very low weight, some children have. So you must immediately find out if the child has got liver.<br />
<font color="red">Could be the child could have got this liver in the hospital. Because they are born realized children, and in the hospital when the child is born there might be hepatitis going on or something, children will catch this, and they get jaundice and things.<br />
Now for all these children there's a very good medicine is: to boil the radish leaves, put some uh-uh-uah candy sugar in it, and give that as a medicine and don't give water, to little babies, up to a point, you see, say about uh, say about when they are about six months or so. In the water you can give that radish leaves. Is ... uhv ... even earlier you can do it. You warm it up [a] little bit and give it. You can mix it up with candy sugar. The taste may not be so good, but it's the medicine for the children, for small children.<br />
Because if you do not give them proper liver in childhood, basically they'll always have this trouble later.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0709 Talk to Sahaj Yogis, Advice on Small Children, Āśhram, Josef Melichar Gasse 20, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I find: at least fifty percent people, in the West, are suffering from liver trouble. They are not aware of it! Till they get to cirrhosis, to skin troubles, this, that, they will not know that they have a bad liver. <font color="red">Till they have jaundice or a ... other diseases which are caused by liver problems.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0723 Public Program, Day 2, The Diamond in Our Heart, Outdoor Spreckels Organ Pavilion, Balboa Park, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Another thing: they have no immunity for anything. <font color="red">Like if there's any jaundice, they are the first to get it.</font> If there's malaria, they are the first to get it. If there's typhoid, they are first to get it. While Indian children have that immunity.<br />
Because, I have seen here also, everybody is carrying the child!<br />
Don't touch the child all the time! Keep the child away from: your body has that warmth which goes to the child also."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0305 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before Departure, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[Treatment for Jaundice:] [A lot of tender radish leaves should be boiled in two cups of water. Boil the mixture down until less than one cup of liquid remains. Mix this with vibrated sugar or candy sugar. Drink only this water for three days.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-07xx Advices on Health, Āśhram, Montpellier Road 14A, Ealing, London W5, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], <font color="red">you see, all allergies are due to bad liver. All allergies are. Skin is looked after by the liver. That's the basic thing.<br />
Now when, you see, a child is born, if the mother is eating food or something which is bad for the liver, or when the child is born mostly they get jaundice, I've seen, at a young age. Because of the hospital perhaps, maybe, they catch.</font><br />
<font color="red">Now when uh-uh-uh, uh when ehh, you see, a child is born, if the mother is eating food or something which is bad for the liver, or when the child is born, mostly they will get jaundice, I have seen, in young age. Because of the hospital perhaps, maybe they catch.</font><br />
So, such a person gets allergies.<br />
So you must treat the liver. By treating the liver, perfected it.<br />
Anand, you see, had some allergies -- My grandson.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi doctor:</b> Jī.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So I told him, "Anand, put some ice on her [it]." Finished!<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi doctor:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> He has no allergies left.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-092x Conversation with Sahaja Yogis Doctors, Questions and Answers, Āśhram, Montpellier Road, Ealing, London, UK (other month 10)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="peru @ Medical" /><category term="peru @ jaundice" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Miscellaneous Post 1: Few details about CCT</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0309" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Miscellaneous Post 1: Few details about CCT" /><published>2023-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Misc_Post1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0309"><![CDATA[<p>
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
In this email we would like to say a few things about our team, Comprehensive Compilations Team, such as how it is structured, how it works, how it hopes to evolve, etc. Through this we hope you will know us even better and also would like to help us more or give us more elaborate feedback.<br />
The team was created in 2014 with the idea of having four members covering the main areas of the database minus websites: English, Hindi, Marathi, and technical aspects such as files, etc.<br />
In July 2017, after Guru Puja, one Sahaja Yogi visited a member of our team and he was so impressed with the CCT database that he envisioned websites for it. In due time (Sep. 2018) he created the Eternal Moments which is now maintained by CCT.<br />
So, since Sep. 2018 we envision a fifth member of the team covering websites.<br />
Well, so far we have not reached five members. As such, the current three members are often covering several of the five main areas.<br />
Since its creation, the team has always been independent, nonaligned, fully involved at all levels of the database, dedicated to quality, comprehensiveness, accuracy, nonediting, sharing, crediting all sources, and aiming to share everything in due time on dedicated, independent, nonaligned, well-dedicated, self-promoted websites.<br />
It operates under very strict and clear-cut unwritten rules. For instance, the team, regardless of what its individual members might think, respects all listed and unlisted video links (as at the time of sharing). Also, the team does not upload any video/audio/pdf files (of documents/publications) unless it has the appropriate permission to do it (such as materials scanned by or received by the team, video digitized by or received by the team, etc.). In particular, it makes no sense to our team to in any way download and reupload a video/audio/pdf unless it has the permission to do it, as giving credit is very important and as it is so easy to embed in a website a video/audio/pdf in a manner in which all original sources are neatly traceable. Moreover, among pdf files of publications, only once we came across one which had a wrong title, so there is relatively little or next to nothing to offer in terms of accuracy to pdf files.<br />
The rules for Photos are a bit different as usually Photos are not titled, do not come from known sources, and have multiple versions; so, as long as we can offer substantial contribution to titles or in exceptional cases start an empty gallery or help to make a sequence of Photos of an evident more complete, few Photos might be uploaded without a clear-cut permission.<br />
To begin with, basic independent teams have been formed (such as the Yearly Topics Team, Scriptures Team, CCT, etc.). You can see them posting, and the posts implicitly define subteams whether they are named as such or not.<br />
The team views public growth as one step at a time. So far we reached Step 3, and there are so many more steps that one would not even like to count them. But of course, from its inception, the team has a well-defined picture of the whole database such as how it ought to look once it is essentially completed, etc.<br />
Step 1, the very foundation of the database, is the database of transcripts/quotes, <font color="blue"><b>Divine Message</b></font>, and we are very fortunate to have a website for it since 2019 due to volunteers helping the team. The link <a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/divine/">Divine Message</a> is part of the website where all the posts of the teams are shared.<br />
Step 2 is the website <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/">Eternal Moments</a> of Photographs of Shri Mataji and of photos Moments of Joy.<br />
Step 3 is the archives at the link <a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/archives/">Archives</a>, which, among other things, contains one single table that will gradually contain the whole archives' data.<br />
We are looking forward to the next steps. Your kind contribution, help, support and sharing has been and it will always be very much appreciated.<br />
The team would benefit a lot from being joined by one or two members who would like to take active roles in websites or Hindi.<br />
<br />
The Comprehensive Compilations Team (CCT)<br />
sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="violet @ Miscellaneous" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, Jay Śhrī Mātājī! In this email we would like to say a few things about our team, Comprehensive Compilations Team, such as how it is structured, how it works, how it hopes to evolve, etc. Through this we hope you will know us even better and also would like to help us more or give us more elaborate feedback. The team was created in 2014 with the idea of having four members covering the main areas of the database minus websites: English, Hindi, Marathi, and technical aspects such as files, etc. In July 2017, after Guru Puja, one Sahaja Yogi visited a member of our team and he was so impressed with the CCT database that he envisioned websites for it. In due time (Sep. 2018) he created the Eternal Moments which is now maintained by CCT. So, since Sep. 2018 we envision a fifth member of the team covering websites. Well, so far we have not reached five members. As such, the current three members are often covering several of the five main areas. Since its creation, the team has always been independent, nonaligned, fully involved at all levels of the database, dedicated to quality, comprehensiveness, accuracy, nonediting, sharing, crediting all sources, and aiming to share everything in due time on dedicated, independent, nonaligned, well-dedicated, self-promoted websites. It operates under very strict and clear-cut unwritten rules. For instance, the team, regardless of what its individual members might think, respects all listed and unlisted video links (as at the time of sharing). Also, the team does not upload any video/audio/pdf files (of documents/publications) unless it has the appropriate permission to do it (such as materials scanned by or received by the team, video digitized by or received by the team, etc.). In particular, it makes no sense to our team to in any way download and reupload a video/audio/pdf unless it has the permission to do it, as giving credit is very important and as it is so easy to embed in a website a video/audio/pdf in a manner in which all original sources are neatly traceable. Moreover, among pdf files of publications, only once we came across one which had a wrong title, so there is relatively little or next to nothing to offer in terms of accuracy to pdf files. The rules for Photos are a bit different as usually Photos are not titled, do not come from known sources, and have multiple versions; so, as long as we can offer substantial contribution to titles or in exceptional cases start an empty gallery or help to make a sequence of Photos of an evident more complete, few Photos might be uploaded without a clear-cut permission. To begin with, basic independent teams have been formed (such as the Yearly Topics Team, Scriptures Team, CCT, etc.). You can see them posting, and the posts implicitly define subteams whether they are named as such or not. The team views public growth as one step at a time. So far we reached Step 3, and there are so many more steps that one would not even like to count them. But of course, from its inception, the team has a well-defined picture of the whole database such as how it ought to look once it is essentially completed, etc. Step 1, the very foundation of the database, is the database of transcripts/quotes, Divine Message, and we are very fortunate to have a website for it since 2019 due to volunteers helping the team. The link Divine Message is part of the website where all the posts of the teams are shared. Step 2 is the website Eternal Moments of Photographs of Shri Mataji and of photos Moments of Joy. Step 3 is the archives at the link Archives, which, among other things, contains one single table that will gradually contain the whole archives' data. We are looking forward to the next steps. Your kind contribution, help, support and sharing has been and it will always be very much appreciated. The team would benefit a lot from being joined by one or two members who would like to take active roles in websites or Hindi. The Comprehensive Compilations Team (CCT) sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 38: Color, Frequency, Wavelength</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0308" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 38: Color, Frequency, Wavelength" /><published>2023-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post38_CCT_Color_Frequency_Wavelength</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0308"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There have been several Incarnations on this Earth who have always said to know your Spirit because without finding his Spirit a human being cannot find God. <font color="DarkRed">Just as without eyes we cannot identify colors, similarly without knowing the Spirit, through arguments, we cannot obtain God.</font> Through brains we cannot know God. It is through the Spirit only we can know God. Till now everybody has said that, "You rise in your dharma and find your Spirit; know the Spirit which is within you." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Spirit from The Life Eternal, 1980 Issue, Page 55</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"[Due to an Āgñyā chakra problem, Douglas Fry used to see different colors, this beautiful rainbow green and this beautiful rainbow, flashing from Śhrī Mātājī. He mentions this to Her.]<br />
You shouldn't see that. One color is power [red] and one is purity [green]. If you can actually see those colors, it means you are not in the center. You are off to one side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Seeing Colors, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Ādi Viṣhṇu protects and evolves the path of evolution. His Incarnations are like milestones in the progress of spiritual awareness, and develop, one by one, new dimensions of human perception. They show the light in the darkness of ignorance, and each Avatāra adds a new boundless perception, a new fragrance, and a new color to the beauty of creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Realized Souls are able to see the Kuṇḍalinī as twisted, coiled identities in the atmosphere. They can also see good and bad souls as round bodies, their colors expressing their quality.</font> They do not see the body of the souls, but possessed people can see such bodies as they belong to the subconscious strata themselves.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Spirits are of different colors, ranging from jet black to smokey black, or patchy golden if they are egoistical. By contrast, realized Souls appear like clear crystals, and sometimes shine like stars. Their face and body are of the same appearance as their body in life.</font><br />
......<br />
In India they use also the dead spirits which are devoid of Kuṇḍalinī ... [<font color="orange">missing</font>] and Divine Spirit (<i>Ātmā</i>). They enter into the fetus about the same time. At their entry we can feel the pulse of the fetus.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Realized Souls can see them in the atmosphere. Not in human form or colors but only as Kuṇḍalinī and Spirit engulfed by soul. Sometimes one sees bunches or sometimes loops of Kuṇḍalinī, and also in the forms of black or white dots. These souls carry the Spirit and the body of the Kuṇḍalinī as small coiled structures. These are the chakras, and to some are visible as different varieties of light.</font> The only one which is one with the Kuṇḍalinī is the Spirit (<i>Ātmā</i>) which is the light of the heart.<br />
It should be quite clear what one means by the word 'soul'. The soul, is the subtle body (<i>sūkṣhma śharīra</i>), the subtle form of the subject's body without the water element and the earth element. The soul consists of five sheaths. Two of these disintegrate on the physical plane at the time of death. They form the chromosomes. The rest of the bodies (<i>śharīra</i>) depart into the Collective Subconscious. <font color="DarkRed">This soul-body can vary in color from black, blackish violet, through green, light blue, and golden crystal to white.</font> These bodies dissipate in the atmosphere around an individual according to his unfulfilled desires. Those spirits which have spontaneously dropped all material desires rise effortlessly to great heights, beyond the atmospheric realm and human vision. They can sometimes descend to Earth, though, to appear as apparitions, or communicate certain revelations."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 5: The Subconscious and the Collective Subconscious}\label{The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 5: The Subconscious and the Collective Subconscious</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">In a Divine Incarnation this [Mūlādhāra] chakra has the color of clay, and it shines.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In realized Souls the Mūlādhāra chakra shines like a neon misty or orange light. It appears as if the wicks of the Swastika are illumined with beautiful radiant lights. They look like four pinkish-orange colored tongues of flame which are silent yet living. The whole vision is of a four-petalled lotus with silent flames for petals. The lotus has a center which is deep blue or misty gray depending on Śhrī Gaṇeśha's mood. Realized Souls can peep into this ocean of deep color and visualize the melting of deep blue into light blue, and see sudden flashes appear like clouds and lightning. This vision spreads beautiful clouds of joy around the seeker.</font> The lightning is followed by the trunk of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, and after some time the elephant-headed Deity appears as a small child. At first He looks static to most realized Souls, but later on expresses a great deal of movement. Each movement creates a new wave of joy and tranquility. At a later stage, Śhrī Gaṇeśha becomes a living personality to such souls.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In ordinary human beings (<i>Asahaja</i>) this chakra appears as coral color, and looks like four threads or wicks joined in the shape of a Swastika.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In the case of misguided seekers (sādhakas) this subtle center appears red. In a clairvoyant, who is misguided because of misuse of his sympathetic nervous system, it appears deep red. Sometimes one sees only the wheel-like chakra rotating in a colored circular pattern of various shades of deep red and blue-black. This happens when Śhrī Gaṇeśha expresses His temper against the clairvoyant <i>sādhaka</i>.</font> Clairvoyance is only achieved with the help of 'dead spirits' by non-realized souls working through the sympathetic nervous system, and is an unauthorized disturbance to Him.<br />
......<br />
Any effort at obstinate abstinence or overindulgence excites the sympathetic nervous system. With the pressure of overactivity, the subject's attention starts moving along the Iḍā or Piṅgalā nāḍī as the case may be. <font color="DarkRed">At first, a vision of the Mūlādhāra chakra as a deep red, multicolored kaleidoscopic wheel becomes visible to the individual. The deep red color is the result of Śhrī Gaṇeśha's anger due to unauthorized probing in His Realm. This unceremonious approach is insulting to Him and His Mother Kuṇḍalinī. Inside the very center of this wheel one can even see the angered and inflamed Śhrī Gaṇeśha if one attempts to force the probe further.</font> A misguided seeker may even get a shock, or feel terrible heat in his body and suffer inexplicable restlessness. Particularly horrible experiences of the past, known as 'flashbacks', may occur. Some people howl and jump around like wild animals; others who are impotent and exhibitionistic often end up taking off all their clothes.<br />
......<br />
So the seeker who insults the Primordial Mother is greatly punished by Śhrī Gaṇeśha. No one can harm Him as He is inviolable under the Holy Aura of love of His Mother. His indestructibility is proved in the Resurrection of Christ. Seekers trying hard to reach Him can only work through the sympathetic nervous system, and their attention moves through the right or left channels as the central parasympathetic nervous system is beyond their reach. Eventually, by such stupid persistence, such misguided seekers are dangerously sidetracked and become clairvoyant. Their attention only goes onto the fringes of His chakra without any control and rotates on the outermost border. <font color="DarkRed">Sometimes such individuals describe their vision of this chakra. It seems like the wrath of Śhrī Gaṇeśha bubbles as a red and blue colored fire which rotates at the surface of the chakra.</font> It does not make any sense to these ignorant people. In reality, the chakra is like a bulbous bloom in the shape of a morning glory flower. <font color="DarkRed">If the misguided seeker persists in his obstinate pursuits, then Śhrī Gaṇeśha appears in red hot hues, and warns the seeker to stop the unauthorized probing.</font> At this stage, if the seeker does not give up he is punished by Śhrī Gaṇeśha's anger expressed as tremendous heat or a burning sensation. Sometimes blisters may appear in an elliptical line, starting from the navel and going around the neck. This can occur without any advance warning. The seeker may jump like a scalded cat, or experience agonizing burning sensations. All these symptoms are due to the insult the misguided seeker bestows on Śhrī Gaṇeśha and His Mother, and not to Kuṇḍalinī awakening, which many stupid people identify it with. This kind of physical resistance is apparent only in people who do not mentally accept the sin (<i>adharma</i>). But those who by their previous karmas or weaknesses accept sin, feel as if their responsibility is over. They feel relaxed and the entities working through them enjoy the pleasures, while they themselves feel pure. Actually, such a subject is dominated completely by these entities, and turns into a slave and an insensitive person."<br />"
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The earth element created the Swādhiṣhṭhān chakra and gave it its yellow color. It thus appears as six yellow-colored threads in most people when it comes into vision in meditation. The color ranges between pale yellow to mustard from person to person, depending on their state of mind as far as their creativity is concerned. In a realized Soul the color is golden, and in an Incarnation it looks like a brilliant Sun. In its center there is a round deep hollow, bluish-yellow in color. In the wrong type of seeker (<i>Asahaja</i>) this appears as a deep blue-black coloration. For a Yogi, though, who is able to peep into this hollow, the form of Brahmadeva in pale yellow colors is clearly visible.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Animals have no sense of beauty; only human beings can feel the esthetics of a composition of different colors, or the movement of lines and the melting of forms.</font> The feelings of joy acquired through this esthetic sense create a <i>Rasa</i> (a secretion of the essence or juice of a feeling). This Rasa gives one a stimulative feeling that sets in motion waves of esthetic joy within the Inner Self. These joys are of different frequencies and vibrations. One does not need to dissect them but as I look at the different petals of this chakra, I shall try to explain the kinds of joys present in the realm of creativity expressed through divine enlightenment.<br />
......<br />
I know a gentleman from Africa who possessed a huge piece of jade. After getting his Self-realization he felt that the stone was emitting vibrations. <font color="DarkRed">He sensed that jade had three colors: green, pink and white in circular layers. He made a unique flowerpot out of that piece of jade which was white in color with a pattern of green leaves and pink flowers. Quite ordinary stones can be transformed through esthetic sensitivity into such priceless works of art through the Grace of the Power of Saraswatī.</font><br />
There are no temples to Brahmadeva because He is never there to attend any pūjā or worship. He is too busy looking after the creation which represents Him, and is His witnessing power in human evolution. <font color="DarkRed">But the main activity of this Deity is to create absolute beauty, beauty emitted through a variety of textures, colors, lines and forms in matter.</font> Variety is the essence of beauty, and the harmony of those varieties creates a bliss which is felt by an awakened mind. It is also felt, much more, as joy. The artist produces a work to express the joy he felt glimpsing the beauty of creation. Many artists who are great Souls and worshipers of Saraswatī have added to Brahmadeva's material creation, establishing a new community of subtler human beings called artists. <font color="DarkRed">The joy poured into nature by the Primordial Mother is enjoyed by artists, and is revealed in the universal language of colors, lines and forms they use to express it.</font> They fill human lives with exquisite creations of music, art, dance and other art forms. All this is the blessing of the Goddess Saraswatī who is in the image of Mahāsaraswatī, Deity of the Piṅgalā nāḍī. This channel is responsible for supplying Praṇava for the creation of all human endeavors. "<br />"
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 13: Swādhiṣhṭhān Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The power of sustenance is the expression of the revelatory mood of Ādi Śhakti, the sattvaguṇa, in Her aspect as Mahālakṣhmī. She gives character and form to matter by Her loving care and affection. It is as if Her assuring love asserts matter to hold all its aspects together through its sustenance, like a nugget of gold, which is yellow and shines and has a peculiar character all of its own. <font color="DarkRed">All that is yellow or shines is not necessarily gold, but real gold is gold because it is yellow in color, shines and does not tarnish.</font> Its quality of not tarnishing is gold's sustenance (<i>dharma</i>).<br />
......<br />
When a seeker gets his Self-realization, Praṇava manifests the existence of the five elements. A Sahaja Yogi feels an energy like electricity oozing out of his extremities (<i>Chaitanya Laharī</i>). These are the Divine Vibrations of Praṇava but they also express the electrical part of his nature. These vibrations are also magnetic, and emit radiance or light. <font color="DarkRed">When this happens one can hear the sounds of the heart, and see different forms of light and colors.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 14: The Powers of Ādi Śhakti and the Three Guṇas</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">In the collective all must transcend the false barriers of race, color, creed, nationality and fundamentalism.</font> The foundation of the collective is Divine Love and respect."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0700 Book 'Sahaja Yoga', Chapter 2: Vishwa Nirmala Dharma</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In these centuries, rationality at its height, worked through the medium of the white-skinned races who elaborated a linear area derived from rational thinking that all other skin colors were somehow not made by God, who, it was tacitly assumed, was certainly White and most probably Anglo-Saxon, and had bestowed a different color upon other races as a kind of divine punishment. This sort of ignorance may appear very funny to us, but armed with this special kind of rationality, or rather with the rationalizations of imperialism and colonialism, they actually killed thousands and even millions of people, plundering their land and making slaves of the population. As a result, one cannot find a single Red Indian in North America living freely and naturally in the traditional way, because they are all locked up in reservations "generously" given to them by the invaders. One has to go to the museum to see their pictures painted with the head dressed as of Red Indians but, strangely, with the faces of Anglo-Saxons.</font><br />
Thank God some divine providence took Columbus to America and kept him there, instead of to India where he thought he was heading. <font color="DarkRed">Otherwise, the "colored" people of India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Tibet, Nepal, Afghanistan and all other "stans" with their ancient and sophisticated cultures, would have also been completely devastated and destroyed by the superiority complex of the Conquistadors, those bull fighters of Spain, whose great contribution to civilization was creating the "peace" and the "calm" of the Catholic churchyard.</font> But to make up for Columbus' neglect, the great Anglo-Saxons came to India from England, did their best to neutralize the heritage and deep wisdom of India, and then gracefully left after 300 years of respectable hospitality from their unasked hosts. They left India peacefully, but with this great country disastrously divided into two different parts into which the seeds of violent destruction were already sown.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">When the Anglo-Saxons were busily plundering those "inferior" cultures of the "colored" races (especially in America), their ego developed to the extent that they were thoroughly blinded to reality and they began to think that their arrogance and their inhuman behavior was perfectly normal and quite all right. They found, according to all the rules and logic of rationality and to their great satisfaction, that they had nicely plundered the whole world, crushed all the "inferior" races into submission and had now settled down comfortably to enjoy the fruits of their arrogance.</font> Of course, polarity started manifesting itself. America, particularly, began to prosper and, despite the great idealism of the American Revolution against colonialism, the people gradually became slaves to luxury, and the victims of their own egoism. As time passed, they began to treat the non Anglo-Saxons, all the Jews, Hispanics, Italians and Russians, as inferior races and they tormented them as foreigners in that land of the Red Indians, which now they assumed was their own. Many, perhaps fired by religious zeal, claimed that it was their birthright and that they had been chosen and blessed by God to do the great work of destroying the Red Indians, who were "primitive" and did not have white skin, as God Almighty most certainly had.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Recently it was shocking to hear that the top priest of the Catholic Church in Austria has been charged with the offense of abusing children. His dress was all red in color. I wish he could enter into the arena of bull fights with a very deadly bull facing him. Even the children themselves might feel it preferable to die than to live a life of such devastation.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 1: Modernism and Rationality</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"These handmade things are a reflection of their enjoyment of life and they give us, if we know how to appreciate them, a deep feeling of harmony and joy. <font color="DarkRed">These simple artists feel that whatever beauty God has created around them has nourished their minds with that beauty, and the natural world -- the flowers, leaves and colors that they see around them -- goes into the cloth which will be covering and enhancing the beauty of lovely ladies.</font> They know that the body is created by God and that its beauty is to be clad and set off by the beauty of human creation. It is surprising how poetically these simple people describe their work when they talk about it.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">It is a well-known fact that on a ship people get very bored because everything is decorated with the same color and texture. The curtains are the same all over, and even the food is much the same every day. All these repetitions very quickly bore the unfortunate passengers.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 2: Choices</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 4: Racialism</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Color" /><category term="crimson @ Frequency" /><category term="crimson @ Wavelength" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 37: Photograph</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0301" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 37: Photograph" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post37_CCT_Photograph</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0301"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This Photo was taken after I opened the Collective Sahasrāra Chakra. I even look a bit sad.<br />
I look very serious in this Photo. At that time I even stopped eating and became a little thin.<br />
From birth I knew I was the Goddess, and My job was to save and raise up this doomed humanity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on a Photo Taken in 1970 on the Terrace, Flat with View towards the Sea, A1 Jeevan Jyot, Nepean Sea Road (now Lady Laxmibai Jagmohandas Mārg), Setalvad Lane, Breach Candy, Cumballa Hill, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"... Teach them not to put their back and their feet to the Photo ... "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes on Children from the book Raising Children in Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">[Śhrī Mātājī further on says that there will be a day when She will not be there and even Her Photograph will not be there, but Sahaja Yoga will be there.]</font> "...... that Sahaja Yoga cannot be destroyed because it is a living thing. It is an energy."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Poetry and Sahaja Yoga, India from the book The Breeze of Sahasrara, Pages 200 and 201</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Do you differentiate Me, the physical Form and My Photograph in My nirākār Form? At times I Myself wonder how it works out, but it works out even at times better that My own physical presence before You.<br />
May be you need to stabilize your wandering thoughts and seek Mother in your heart, you really do not need to come near Me to meet Me to get your all problems solved. My Photograph ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Personal Attention</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[In early eighties Śhrī Mātājī discovers that catches from removed ex-leaders have passed on to new Sahaja Yogis who have received Realization from them.]<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Asking these new Sahaja Yogis:] <font color="DarkRed">Did he [removed ex-leader] give you Realization before My Photograph or without it?</font><br />
<b>New Sahaja Yogis:</b> Before Your Photograph.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Then it is I who gave you Realization, so there is no reason to feel indebted to him. Forget him.</font> [With that, catches fled.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī instructs that Realization should be given before Her Photo, then the catches do not transfer from one to another. Moreover, one does not absorb the catches of the seekers.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Catches and Photograph from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 6, Page 20 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Behind every element is a Deity, when you put the elements before My Photograph they get vibrated."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Elements, Photograph, and Vibrations from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 14, Page 39 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[Arriving in a city for a Public Program, Śhrī Mātājī observes there are no posters anywhere.]
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Why there are no posters?</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogis:</b> Śhrī Mātājī, we were worried about the protocol of Your Photograph. People might tear or trample on them.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"> The city gets vibrated with My Photograph, and that is how the Paramachaitanya informs the seekers through their unconsciousness. When I went to Russia, the Russian seekers had never known about Me but the Unconscious informed them and they came in thousands. When I asked them, "How did you recognize Me?" They answered, "From your Photograph of course Mother." I have given permission for putting My Photograph on posters, you don't have to worry about the protocol.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Posters from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 22, Pages 64 and 65 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
""<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-1029 Letter (Marathi) to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In meditation try to stop your thoughts. <font color="DarkRed">Watch My Photograph with open eyes and see that you stop your thoughts.</font> You should stop your thoughts, then you go into meditation. The simple thing to stop your thoughts is the Lord's Prayer, because that's the Āgñyā state. So in the morning you remember Lord's Prayer or Gaṇeśha's mantra. It's just the same. Or you even say 'I forgive'. So you can start with Gaṇeśha's mantra, say Lord's Prayer and then say ]I forgive'. It works out."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1905-0000 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On Meditation</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[<font color="DarkRed">Poor eyesight: looking through candle flame on Mother's hands Photograph, Devī Kavach: Śhrī Śhaṅkhinī mantra.</font> Mahāgaṇeśha, Mahābhairava, Hiraṇyagarbha. Viśhuddhi and back Āgñyā treatment. Massage wrists/Viśhuddhi with ghee camphor. Cover Viśhuddhi. Ghee camphor in nose.]<br />
.....<br />
[Cancer: skin tumor. Śhrī Mātājī has said that at initial stages, Sahaj will help. In advanced stage you need medical help. Remove tumor and continue Sahaj methods. Don't worry, surrender to Mother. <font color="DarkRed">Speak to Photograph.</font> Be innocent and surrender.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advices Given to Dr. Madhur Rai, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, there is another question which was asked - of course, they ... they thought it was very wise, and I think it is a great help - that, "When we put hands to You, we burn. But when Your disciples put hands to us, they burn. Now, who is the positive, who is the negative?" It's a complicated question.<br />
So, for that, we have to use a person who is lunatic: absolute accepted lunatic or psychologically affected person. <font color="DarkRed">Ask that person to put the hands to Me or to My Photograph, and raise the Kuṇḍalinī, he'll start shaking too much.</font> Now, you ask a realized person to put his hand and go into meditation, while a person who is suffering from negativity will start shaking and burning.<br />
The one who is a certified person and a negative personality, the one who suffers from inferiority complexes and the fear and all these symptoms of negativity, should be used as a measuring rod.<br />
One gentleman wanted to take full advantage of My raising things. <font color="DarkRed">He took My Photograph and put it and all that thing.</font> And he also said he was My disciple, [laughing:] very openly. Of course, I accepted that, "You be my Guru. You can give me something sensible." And then I got something also, [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] he said, "You must tell people that, 'I am your guru.' " I said, "All this thing if you want I will tell them. But I don't think you have done anything unique." But even now he is been too much. He is telling people that he's doing My work."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0325 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Seminar, Day 3, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then you take a big, nice Photo of Mine, frame it nicely, and sit in front of it after lighting a lamp, in meditation. Meet Me after two or three days."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0xxx Public Program, Day 22, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Whosoever will come in front of you should dissolve in your love. And if he does not dissolve, then he will run away. A day will come and that day you will not need this protection.<br />
You people have found many ways of protection. These people can tell you about some of the ways if you want. You can ask them. <font color="DarkRed">Like taking vibrations on the Photo.</font> Taking out [vibrations] with feet or taking out with water. How to put your own bandhan, etc. Taking different names, etc. There are many types. If you want to know about them then you can talk to these people, then these people can tell you all this.<br />
......<br />
You have to do no business whatsoever.<br />
You have not to collect money in any way. For nothing at all.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">One person said to Me that he will sell My Photos and then that money he will give to the Āśhram. I said, "Which Āśhram? What money? Who said so? Why do you listen to others?"</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0903 Pūjā (Hindi), Ātma-sākṣhātkār ka Arth (Meaning of Self-realization), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0910 Public Program (Hindi), Bholāpan (Innocence), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (place not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photograph" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>