<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/compilation.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-05-17T10:53:52-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/compilation.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Compilation</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Miscellaneous Post 2: Linktree</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0418" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Miscellaneous Post 2: Linktree" /><published>2023-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Misc_Post2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0418"><![CDATA[<p>
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
At the suggestion of Uncle John Noyce back in October 2021, we are pleased to let you know that 
the team has a Linktree account <a href="https://linktr.ee/comprehensivecompilationsteam">CCT</a> that stores the links of all the main pages of websites we manage. It can be used to have all these links handy (for personal usage or sharing). The subscribers would also be notified whenever new links are added to the account.<br />
Please kindly share the link with all our brothers and sisters.<br />

<br />
The Comprehensive Compilations Team (CCT)<br />
sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="violet @ Miscellaneous" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, Jay Śhrī Mātājī! At the suggestion of Uncle John Noyce back in October 2021, we are pleased to let you know that the team has a Linktree account CCT that stores the links of all the main pages of websites we manage. It can be used to have all these links handy (for personal usage or sharing). The subscribers would also be notified whenever new links are added to the account. Please kindly share the link with all our brothers and sisters.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 40: Oṃ and Auṃ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0412" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 40: Oṃ and Auṃ" /><published>2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post40_CCT_Aum_Om</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0412"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"mixture of seven sounds when heard together create a beautiful sound like OM or when broken it sounds like A, oo, MA. This sound is without percussion and hence is known as Anahata[.] It is written and heard as ॐ ie Devnagri [Devanāgarī] script for OM. Later on Anahata passing through the different centers of the Kund[a]lini becomes the word."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Om related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[Both right/left treatment needed, paper burning helps depression, maṭakā, look through candle flame at Bindhi, do not meditate with eyes closed, only close eyes when thinking stops, right Āgñyā ice, Auṃ Ham Kṣham.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advices Given to Dr. Madhur Rai, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had only one Son who was Praṇava incarnate. <font color="red">Think of it, He was Auṃ incarnate. He incarnated on this Earth.</font> His name was Jesus Christ. Mary was His Mother. He was placed on the Āgñyā chakra."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now She is in this form. So the beginning of the Auṃ starts. Parabola, first of all, gets converted into Auṃ. Then She pushes Herself down and settles down for a while to meditate and to find out how She is going to work it out, we can say like this."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0220 Public Program, Creation and Evolution, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"For example the Word, what is the Word? Is it Logos or something? What is that? What is it comprising of, what does that mean, how it starts, from where it has come? It is Auṃ. Auṃ comes from three words uh, ooh, muh. Uh, ooh, muh.<br />
Uh stands for the first creation of the left-hand side, what we call the Mahākālī Power. First only in the world manifestation of the superego took place, so we can say that uh stand for the beginning when only up to the stage when life was not created.<br />
Ooh stands for the other stage, where, now sound is the same. Sound is the same, manifestation is different. The voice is the same, My sound is the same, for example whatever is My sound, you can make it out wherever I speak, this is Mātājī speaking.<br />
Maybe the manifestation is different in uh, ooh, muh, so first uh starts, then comes to ooh, which is Mahāsaraswatī Power. We can say the three notes which we have as, I don't know in English what you say to the notes but we say sah, uh sah [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], the basic three notes, so the second note is that of Mahāsaraswatī by which the life -- sun life -- started working.<br />
And the third one is the muh through which evolution started taking its place. So that is the Mahālakṣhmī stage.<br />
So you have got these Three Powers working together, and that is, in a very short form, we say it is Auṃ.<br />
But it is not only that human beings have said it. When you meditate you have seen that Auṃ. I'm saying that these Three Powers have a third, these three sounds, and that's how this word is created, of Auṃ.<br />
For a realized Soul, Auṃ is a most powerful thing. For example, if you want to protect yourself, the word Auṃ itself can protect, and when these Three Powers combine as Auṃ we say that this only the Child or the Son God represents in its purest form Auṃ. That's why in the life of Christ, or we can say in the life of a personality that represented the Son of God, Auṃ is very important because He embodies that Auṃ within Himself. All these Three Powers are in Him, and in the most innocent form.<br />
......<br />
In this sound of Oṃkāra, the complete sounds of the worlds are there. All the permutations and combinations, the complete melody of this universities within these three sounds uh, ooh, muh. It is based on Auṃ.<br />
When the Kuṇḍalinī moves also, it moves in three ways uh, ooh, muh, because in the lower portion it is the uh. In the center portion it is the ooh, and here it is the muh. Meaning that at the lower portion of the human being we are what was created as dead matter. In the center we are what is creation, means creativity, and in the third is the evolutionary, so even we are divided in three ways -- is, we are, our upper part is muh, central part is ooh and the lower part is uh. That is how we are, and when you say Auṃ in a proper way, you find the Kuṇḍalinī rises.<br />
......<br />
Auṃ works like anything. Now you may say that where is the word Auṃ in the Christian religion? It is in Amen. Amen is nothing but Auṃ, because muh means a nasal sound, and end of a nasal sound, and nuh also means nasal sound, because in the Arabic language it's written like a nee, you see, and nee with My name, you say, nuh, with My name starts nuh, also written with a dot, all of them have got a dot. It's a dot which shows that it's a nuh. And in the Sanskrit language, dot means nuh. And that is why it is muh and nuh. Amen is the same as Auṃ.<br />
Now the problem is everything, as evolution goes up, changes and that's why Auṃ was brought to the level of Amen. Uh became Ah and Ooh became Muh, and Muh became Nuh. As I told you that Christ came as a human being, but He was Gaṇeśha. And the Swastika became the cross. The same way, Auṃ is Amen.<br />
So after every prayer, you are supposed to say Amen. Why not Amen? What does that mean? From there the word Auṃ ends in English language.<br />
......<br />
Now the same word Auṃ is used by negative forces also. How do they use it? They will give this name to some devil, normally they do not, because this is one of the purest words which cannot be Contaminated. Normally they will not, normally they will not. I have not met anyone so far who has got a devil on him with the name Auṃ, and nobody so far has given this name to anyone, but I have seen.<br />
......<br />
He [person giving names] can use, but he cannot use the name of Auṃ, and he cannot use the name of Jesus. He cannot give the name of Śhrī Gaṇeśh. These names are beyond their [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. You see because they are terrible. ...... They might say all kinds of Auṃs and everything. But with all of these they can attack someone, like this, they say Auṃ namo Śhivaya, it's all right. Auṃ namo Śhiva, now, Auṃ you have put it, in that it neutralizes, they perhaps do not know it neutralizes a little bit. Auṃ namo Śhivaya.<br />
And it means so great, means you bow to Śhiva. That aspect of God which is eternal. But they will say that you take the name Auṃ namo Śhivaya because with that the thing you see, it's overpowered by Śhiva, and that's how they will put Auṃ with that, but they'll never give a single word as Auṃ at [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] point, because no devil will own that name, it's too great. And these are the tricks these people play with the word Auṃ, and you should play with the same. Whenever you feel like that, you just say Auṃ. Don't say anything else, say Auṃ. For you, every sentence has an end. Even if you say Auṃ namo Śhivaya [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. But even if you say Auṃ Jesus, it's enough. Now in a circle, if you say the complete universe into a circle, then you make three portions of that, you get three arches. Say one is uh, another ooh, another muh. When you try to reconstruct them, then you get uh ooh and muh, there are three arches, you reconstruct them. First arch is bent like this ... uh, ooh, second one like that, and the third one is muh. And the dot on that is the center point Is the center point of the circle, dot on that. Now you have seen how Auṃ is written down, and that is how it is, the three arches are described like that, so the whole creation and the center dot, which is the God Himself, all put together makes the Auṃ, and that is how it is being named. I think I have told you now first of all when the creation too, place, how first the Auṃ was formed. Did I tell you with the parabola, with the drawing, so the first sound, the first sound that started because of the separation, the first separation when it too, place between the two identities, God and His Power, that was the time the sound started, and that sound is nothing else but Auṃ. That sound will be there and will work out till these two identities become one, then there is no relativity left and so there is nothing, so people think the world has come out of nothing, because there is no relativity, when they become two then there is something, otherwise they are one and absolute, and so there is nothing, when the sound merges or finishes or, as we say, disappears [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] That is the time when the whole creation merges into one action. So that is the point where one has to go.<br />
Now, in your own being it happens. First you feel the Auṃ, you feel it sometimes the sound coming, sometimes you feel some sort of tingling going on, because there are seven sounds, which are easily discernible out of this Auṃ. Easily. But there are many, but I am saying at least seven you can easily find out. If you sit down sometimes you might hear some sort of a bell ringing, sometimes you'll hear as if there is a waterfall, and sometimes you'll hear as if in the night, the small crickets are singing. You see all kinds of sounds are coming, you see you feel that they are there, something is happening, in the night, you see, that sort of a feeling you'll get, all different types of sounds there are, but seven sounds you can easily find out, and all of them put together make the Auṃ. So, if you play all of them in a proper manner, in a melodious manner, well we can say in a harmonious manner, then you'll hear the sound Auṃ.<br />
......<br />
So this Auṃ is, is a sound that understands, that talks, hat organizes, that informs, and that is the sound of the Divine Love. This is the electrical feeling that you get on your hand. But this is the sound.<br />
......<br />
So we have got also five very subtle type of expression of five elements, and those are this fine sound of Auṃ, the vibrations are the electrical, there is a magnet in that sound, or in that powered, for a person who is, who is realized. The person who is blessed by God has a magnetic power. That person attracts. That person might not even speak about, but people know about these things. They know that he's a man who's realized, there's something special about him. Immediately you can find it out, what he is. It is because of this sound and the magnet. You must have heard that sound when we converted into matter. In the same way, all these things are converted, the sound becomes a magnet, the magnet becomes the vibrations, the vibrations can become the Spirit. So these are all convertible, and part and parcel of the same thing, the same energy which is the Divine Love, which is Love. Love has a sound, and love has electricity, it has got magnetism. And it has got the power. When all these subtle powers are poured on to any human being, it acts, it acts, and people start improving in their health. You must have heard of experiments where people have tried music on some people who are hot well, and they have been cured. And what happens is that they, the subtler, subtler powers of the sound that we are manifesting, that behind it, the power that is manifesting it, comes into play. Which is a very small thing there, but with you people, when you put you hand this is the sound of Auṃ which is vibrating, it is so micro, microwaved, vibrations, that you cannot see with a magnifying glass, you will not see My finger shaking at all, you'll say they are very steady, but they're very microwaves. And the microwaves, when they pass into the body of the human beings, or anything, there they awaken the microwaves that are sleeping in the body of the human beings, or whatever things you use, and they start generating the second, what you call, phase as the [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] of the outside [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
......<br />
Now, when you people say Auṃ, realized people, when You say Auṃ, the sound waves of Auṃ, you just try on a person who is. Just now you are having some pain there. All right. Now, just now you put your hand there and say Auṃ. Try it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0400 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Auṃ, (likely) Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK (month and location not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Today as Yogi has asked Me to speak about Auṃ, I would like to tell you about the great word called Auṃ: what it is, what it represents, and how it came into being.<br />
......<br />
Auṃ is a word people don't understand because it is at the very beginning of this creation that the energy of God, energy of His Love separated from His identity. He pushed Her, called it as Lāsya, He pushed Her to create, and He became the spectator and She had to create. At that time when She was pushed -- we don't have here something to show you how it worked -- but when He tried to push Her, Her movements went into a kind of a word which is [draws with the right index finger in the air]: written as like this three, A, U and M. So there are three words in it. At the time of that pushing, when the separation took place, there was a sound, this the first sound and that sound is called as Auṃ.<br /> 
So many people call it as Logos, but to understand it you have to go deeper into it to und[erstand] what it is was.<br />
So Her power got divided into three: A, U and M. And that's how She became Auṃ. So Auṃ is the sound which is emitted when She creates, which acts as the basis of the essence of Her Love.<br />
Then how She started creating is a very long story which I won't be able to tell you today, but this Auṃ is the one that She first used to create the innocence on this Earth. So this Auṃ was the innocence with which She filled the whole universe. So Auṃ is nothing but the innocence that you see in children, in so many people, in Saints and in most of the Incarnations, that they are empowered by Their innocence. And this innocence first filled the whole space. Even before creating the space the innocence was there. That was the first creation of element and that was the innocence. So Auṃ is innocence which does all the living work on this Earth.<br />"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0929 Public Program, Day 2, Auṃ, Cultural Integration Fellowship, 260 Fulton Street, San Francisco, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"<font size="+1">The Sound of Praṇava</font><br />
Praṇava's sound is known as <i>Anāhat</i>. It is generated when the Primordial Cell breaks like the hatching of an egg. It is audible with the departure of the nucleus from the ellipse.<br />
<br />
* The first linear movement of Ādi Śhakti makes the First Primordial Sound -- 'Ā'.<br />
* The push of Sadāśhiva causes the Second Primordial Sound -- 'Ū'.<br />
* The Third Sound -- 'MA' -- is caused by the pause stage, which follows the breathing in and breathing out of the Primordial Zygote.<br />
<br />
Praṇava is therefore the All-pervading Divine Power of Ādi Śhakti, and Anāhat is the sound created, without any percussion, by this Power. It can be understood better by describing Anāhat as the sound announcement of Praṇava.<br />
These three Primordial Syllables 'Ā', 'Ū' and 'MA', represent the Three Powers of the Primordial Mother:<br />
<br />
* 'Ā' represents the existence and Destructive Power of Mahākālī<br />
* 'Ū' represents the Creative Power of Mahāsaraswatī<br />
* 'MA' represents the Sustenance or Evolutionary Power of Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
<br />
These three Primordial Syllables, later on, form the Primordial Words (<i>Bīja Mantras</i>) 'Aim', 'Hrīm' and 'Klīm'. All together these comprise the phonetic words of the Devanāgarī script (Sanskrit), and will be examined in greater detail in the chapter on chakras.<br />
Much before the hatching of the Primordial Egg, the Primordial Zygote reaches the embryonic stage. It starts breathing and creates the Primordial Sound (<i>Anāhata</i>) that fills the entire embryo, which encircles the central point. The breathing of Ādi Śhakti is the Praṇava or Divine Power, while its sound is called Anāhata. This sound is without percussion and is heard on the heart as a pulsation. This sound is a mixture of seven component sounds (<i>Nādabrahman</i>), which when heard together creates the beautiful Word, 'Auṃ'. When it is broken into its component parts it sounds like 'Ā', 'Ū' and 'MA'. It later ascends through the different subtle centers on the path of Kuṇḍalinī (the residual power of Praṇava) and becomes the Word.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Pages 9 and 10</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Om" /><category term="crimson @ Aum" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 39: Jaundice</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0405" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 39: Jaundice" /><published>2023-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post39_CCT_Jaundice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0405"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Treatment for jaundice is as follows. Boil young radish leaves in water, add rock candy to that water and drink it continuously. Do not drink any other water. Vibrate the water before drinking.<br />
Second treatment is to put some mustard oil in a brass or a bronze bowl and rotate it (oil) in a clockwise direction with either nābhī [finger] or all the fingers. One of the hands -- left or right -- should be towards the photo. Watch both hands, and whichever hand feels lighter should be kept towards the photo. The oil will slowly become thick and yellow. Do not throw this oil in water but take it far away and burn it. You will feel better if you do this two-three times. Do not eat any oil or ghee at all. Give vibration[s] to Nābhī and liver while keeping the other hand towards the photo."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-1029 Letter (Marathi) to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[1. Drink every morning and evening one glass of radish leaf juice.]<br /> 
[2. Drink in the morning one glass of kokum syrup.]<br />
[3. Holding an ice pack with the left hand, place it on the liver, with the right hand toward the picture of Śhrī Mātājī and meditate without any candle light or diya (lamp) in front of the picture.]<br />
[4. You can eat Bengali sweets.]<br />
[5. No fried food, red meat or fat under any circumstances.]<br />
[6. No fish or dairy products at all except buttermilk in which butter has been skimmed off.]<br />
[7. No cheese at all.]<br />
[8. Liv 52 tablets: 3-4 tablets per day for two months.]<br />
[9. All citrus fruits are OK (no mango, apple, banana, papaya or chīkū).]<br />
[10. Sugar cane juice or sugar cane is very good.]<br />
[11. No butter at all.]<br />
[12. No uṛada dāl (arhar/tuar).]<br />
[13. Boiled rice, all vegetables, moong dāl are OK.]<br />
[14. No chilies in food.]<br />
[15. Ginger, potato, onion, and cucumber are OK.]<br />
[16. Regular intake of lemon juice with vibrated sugar is OK.]<br />
[17. No ice cream.]<br />
[18. Amalā kā murabbā is good and can be taken with both meals.]<br />
[19. Silver varak on food is good.]<br />
[20. All vegetables fruits grown under the earth are OK.]<br />
[21. No groundnuts, no ground nut oil. Groundnut oil is very bad for liver. Sunflower oil in little quantity is all right.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advice (Diet) for Jaundice, Hepatitis, and Overheated Liver from Divine Cool Breeze (India), Volume 4, Issues 8 and 9 (August--September 1992), Page 22</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, this Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra is to be looked after.<br />
In Delhi, Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra is the first problem. Firstly, because you think too much. Secondly, you think you are running the show. Thirdly, the water of Delhi is not good.<br />
I've requested all the people, all the Sahaja Yogis to boil their foo... water and drink it. And never wat... drink water outside. At the most if you have to drink then you can drink something bottled. But try to boil the water all the time to keep your Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra all right.<br />
<font color="red">It [unboiled water] causes jaundice and all kinds of problems, because water is the basis of Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra.</font><br />
So if you try to spoil the Nābhī, by ... Nābhī is the basis, and N... if Nābhī gets spoiled, then Swādhiṣhṭhāna also gets spoiled. Because from Nābhī the Swādhiṣhṭhāna chakra has arisen.<br />
Moreover, one has to know how to give balance to oneself, ah-ah ... when the Swādhiṣhṭhāna is out."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0206 Public Program, Day 2, Swādhiṣhṭhāna Chakra, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Sahaja Yoga diabetes is absolutely curable. <font color="red">Jaundice and all these diseases of the liver are also absolutely curable in Sahaja Yoga.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0303 Public Program, Day 2, God Has Created Us with a Purpose, Town Hall, Hay Street and Barrack Street, Perth, WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">Now, this kind of a hand, if you see, yellowish color, all right, ...</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> It's liver!<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">... itself, it means liver. This is a liver patient: definitely a liver patient, this one.<br />
Now, for such a hand, what should you do: is to take uh-uh-uh the water that I've given you, and boil it with radish leaves. And take radish leaves and sugar with it. That water you have to take for some time.<br />
Specially when you have this flood water. After that you should be careful, because people can get jaundice.</font><br />
You see, this flood is not such a disaster: the aftereffects of floods are.<br /> 
This water is not good, you should not take any other water but spring water. Spring water you should drink. <font color="red">And, as far as possible, be careful about jaundice.</font><br />
<font color="red">If jaundice sets in, the only solution is that you should take radish leaves, eat lot of radish, and boil it in that water that I give you, today, and put some sugar in it, and just take that water, nothing else.</font><br />
Because that's one thing one has to be careful: when such a flood comes in, the aftereffects of the floods can be felt. All right?<br />
......<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>  [Taping on the palm of the lady with jaundice:] <font color="red">Jaundice!<br />
Do you get jaundice in this country?</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> Oh, yes!<br />
<b>Gentleman:</b> Yes.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font> <font color="red">Do you get jaundice in this country?</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> Very much.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font> <font color="red">So one should know how to treat jaundice and look after yourself.<br />
Jaundice is really, could be fatal and is very dangerous because it spoils your uh liver very badly.<br />
So, to be on safe side, eat lot of radish, and the uh also take that water as I told you, for your jaundice.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0306 Workshop, Mother Are You the Holy Ghost, Park on the Bank of River Torrens, Adelaide, SA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, all other such diseases, specially the worst of all, that is the result. Of course, liver is horrifyingly bad.<br />
And liver can be cured through Sahaj Yog only. It cannot be cured up.<br />
Actually I have seen that people develop cirrhosis of liver or cancer of liver, only then we realize that the fellow has a liver trouble.<br />
<font color="red">But liver starts at a very early age in ... specially in the Western countries. Because the mothers are always thinking, the fathers are always planning, the poor child is born with jaundice, is born with jaundice.<br />
And jaundice is so easily curable. But so many people die of this little thing called jaundice, children specially.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0131 Public Talk to Doctors (English mixed with Marathi), Dr. Vaishampayan Memorial Government Medical College, Jawaharlal Housing Society, Opp. District Court, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Children need sugar so give it. But not in such a form that it sticks to teeth but which goes in the stomach.<br />
Secondly, in summers a fruit named kokum is found in Maharashtra. Soak it overnight, and boil it next day, add some sugar and give it to the child during day.<br />
<font color="red">If one suffers from jaundice, then boil radish leaves, mix vibrated sugar and give to the child. Child can be cured of jaundice in one day.</font><br />
In summers give juice of radish. Give radish to children, it is good for them.<br />
We give lot of fried this to children, it should not be done."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0325 Chaitra Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Sahajyogiyo Keliye Bhartiya Sanskṛiti ka Mahatva (Importance of Indian Culture for Sahaja Yogis), Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So I concluded that a drunkard's child is born with a damaged liver. <font color="red">So, you have given your child a damaged liver from the beginning, and as soon as a child is born, he will get jaundice.</font> If the father's or mother's liver is damaged, then the child also is born with a damaged liver."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0219 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Session 1 (evening), A Sahaja Yogi Will Reflect on the Outside His Inner Quality, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then I have also seen that a some children have very uh uh thin body, very low weight, some children have. So you must immediately find out if the child has got liver.<br />
<font color="red">Could be the child could have got this liver in the hospital. Because they are born realized children, and in the hospital when the child is born there might be hepatitis going on or something, children will catch this, and they get jaundice and things.<br />
Now for all these children there's a very good medicine is: to boil the radish leaves, put some uh-uh-uah candy sugar in it, and give that as a medicine and don't give water, to little babies, up to a point, you see, say about uh, say about when they are about six months or so. In the water you can give that radish leaves. Is ... uhv ... even earlier you can do it. You warm it up [a] little bit and give it. You can mix it up with candy sugar. The taste may not be so good, but it's the medicine for the children, for small children.<br />
Because if you do not give them proper liver in childhood, basically they'll always have this trouble later.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0709 Talk to Sahaj Yogis, Advice on Small Children, Āśhram, Josef Melichar Gasse 20, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I find: at least fifty percent people, in the West, are suffering from liver trouble. They are not aware of it! Till they get to cirrhosis, to skin troubles, this, that, they will not know that they have a bad liver. <font color="red">Till they have jaundice or a ... other diseases which are caused by liver problems.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0723 Public Program, Day 2, The Diamond in Our Heart, Outdoor Spreckels Organ Pavilion, Balboa Park, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Another thing: they have no immunity for anything. <font color="red">Like if there's any jaundice, they are the first to get it.</font> If there's malaria, they are the first to get it. If there's typhoid, they are first to get it. While Indian children have that immunity.<br />
Because, I have seen here also, everybody is carrying the child!<br />
Don't touch the child all the time! Keep the child away from: your body has that warmth which goes to the child also."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0305 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before Departure, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[Treatment for Jaundice:] [A lot of tender radish leaves should be boiled in two cups of water. Boil the mixture down until less than one cup of liquid remains. Mix this with vibrated sugar or candy sugar. Drink only this water for three days.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-07xx Advices on Health, Āśhram, Montpellier Road 14A, Ealing, London W5, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], <font color="red">you see, all allergies are due to bad liver. All allergies are. Skin is looked after by the liver. That's the basic thing.<br />
Now when, you see, a child is born, if the mother is eating food or something which is bad for the liver, or when the child is born mostly they get jaundice, I've seen, at a young age. Because of the hospital perhaps, maybe, they catch.</font><br />
<font color="red">Now when uh-uh-uh, uh when ehh, you see, a child is born, if the mother is eating food or something which is bad for the liver, or when the child is born, mostly they will get jaundice, I have seen, in young age. Because of the hospital perhaps, maybe they catch.</font><br />
So, such a person gets allergies.<br />
So you must treat the liver. By treating the liver, perfected it.<br />
Anand, you see, had some allergies -- My grandson.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi doctor:</b> Jī.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So I told him, "Anand, put some ice on her [it]." Finished!<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi doctor:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> He has no allergies left.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-092x Conversation with Sahaja Yogis Doctors, Questions and Answers, Āśhram, Montpellier Road, Ealing, London, UK (other month 10)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="peru @ Medical" /><category term="peru @ jaundice" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Miscellaneous Post 1: Few details about CCT</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0309" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Miscellaneous Post 1: Few details about CCT" /><published>2023-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Misc_Post1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0309"><![CDATA[<p>
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
In this email we would like to say a few things about our team, Comprehensive Compilations Team, such as how it is structured, how it works, how it hopes to evolve, etc. Through this we hope you will know us even better and also would like to help us more or give us more elaborate feedback.<br />
The team was created in 2014 with the idea of having four members covering the main areas of the database minus websites: English, Hindi, Marathi, and technical aspects such as files, etc.<br />
In July 2017, after Guru Puja, one Sahaja Yogi visited a member of our team and he was so impressed with the CCT database that he envisioned websites for it. In due time (Sep. 2018) he created the Eternal Moments which is now maintained by CCT.<br />
So, since Sep. 2018 we envision a fifth member of the team covering websites.<br />
Well, so far we have not reached five members. As such, the current three members are often covering several of the five main areas.<br />
Since its creation, the team has always been independent, nonaligned, fully involved at all levels of the database, dedicated to quality, comprehensiveness, accuracy, nonediting, sharing, crediting all sources, and aiming to share everything in due time on dedicated, independent, nonaligned, well-dedicated, self-promoted websites.<br />
It operates under very strict and clear-cut unwritten rules. For instance, the team, regardless of what its individual members might think, respects all listed and unlisted video links (as at the time of sharing). Also, the team does not upload any video/audio/pdf files (of documents/publications) unless it has the appropriate permission to do it (such as materials scanned by or received by the team, video digitized by or received by the team, etc.). In particular, it makes no sense to our team to in any way download and reupload a video/audio/pdf unless it has the permission to do it, as giving credit is very important and as it is so easy to embed in a website a video/audio/pdf in a manner in which all original sources are neatly traceable. Moreover, among pdf files of publications, only once we came across one which had a wrong title, so there is relatively little or next to nothing to offer in terms of accuracy to pdf files.<br />
The rules for Photos are a bit different as usually Photos are not titled, do not come from known sources, and have multiple versions; so, as long as we can offer substantial contribution to titles or in exceptional cases start an empty gallery or help to make a sequence of Photos of an evident more complete, few Photos might be uploaded without a clear-cut permission.<br />
To begin with, basic independent teams have been formed (such as the Yearly Topics Team, Scriptures Team, CCT, etc.). You can see them posting, and the posts implicitly define subteams whether they are named as such or not.<br />
The team views public growth as one step at a time. So far we reached Step 3, and there are so many more steps that one would not even like to count them. But of course, from its inception, the team has a well-defined picture of the whole database such as how it ought to look once it is essentially completed, etc.<br />
Step 1, the very foundation of the database, is the database of transcripts/quotes, <font color="blue"><b>Divine Message</b></font>, and we are very fortunate to have a website for it since 2019 due to volunteers helping the team. The link <a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/divine/">Divine Message</a> is part of the website where all the posts of the teams are shared.<br />
Step 2 is the website <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/">Eternal Moments</a> of Photographs of Shri Mataji and of photos Moments of Joy.<br />
Step 3 is the archives at the link <a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/archives/">Archives</a>, which, among other things, contains one single table that will gradually contain the whole archives' data.<br />
We are looking forward to the next steps. Your kind contribution, help, support and sharing has been and it will always be very much appreciated.<br />
The team would benefit a lot from being joined by one or two members who would like to take active roles in websites or Hindi.<br />
<br />
The Comprehensive Compilations Team (CCT)<br />
sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="violet @ Miscellaneous" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, Jay Śhrī Mātājī! In this email we would like to say a few things about our team, Comprehensive Compilations Team, such as how it is structured, how it works, how it hopes to evolve, etc. Through this we hope you will know us even better and also would like to help us more or give us more elaborate feedback. The team was created in 2014 with the idea of having four members covering the main areas of the database minus websites: English, Hindi, Marathi, and technical aspects such as files, etc. In July 2017, after Guru Puja, one Sahaja Yogi visited a member of our team and he was so impressed with the CCT database that he envisioned websites for it. In due time (Sep. 2018) he created the Eternal Moments which is now maintained by CCT. So, since Sep. 2018 we envision a fifth member of the team covering websites. Well, so far we have not reached five members. As such, the current three members are often covering several of the five main areas. Since its creation, the team has always been independent, nonaligned, fully involved at all levels of the database, dedicated to quality, comprehensiveness, accuracy, nonediting, sharing, crediting all sources, and aiming to share everything in due time on dedicated, independent, nonaligned, well-dedicated, self-promoted websites. It operates under very strict and clear-cut unwritten rules. For instance, the team, regardless of what its individual members might think, respects all listed and unlisted video links (as at the time of sharing). Also, the team does not upload any video/audio/pdf files (of documents/publications) unless it has the appropriate permission to do it (such as materials scanned by or received by the team, video digitized by or received by the team, etc.). In particular, it makes no sense to our team to in any way download and reupload a video/audio/pdf unless it has the permission to do it, as giving credit is very important and as it is so easy to embed in a website a video/audio/pdf in a manner in which all original sources are neatly traceable. Moreover, among pdf files of publications, only once we came across one which had a wrong title, so there is relatively little or next to nothing to offer in terms of accuracy to pdf files. The rules for Photos are a bit different as usually Photos are not titled, do not come from known sources, and have multiple versions; so, as long as we can offer substantial contribution to titles or in exceptional cases start an empty gallery or help to make a sequence of Photos of an evident more complete, few Photos might be uploaded without a clear-cut permission. To begin with, basic independent teams have been formed (such as the Yearly Topics Team, Scriptures Team, CCT, etc.). You can see them posting, and the posts implicitly define subteams whether they are named as such or not. The team views public growth as one step at a time. So far we reached Step 3, and there are so many more steps that one would not even like to count them. But of course, from its inception, the team has a well-defined picture of the whole database such as how it ought to look once it is essentially completed, etc. Step 1, the very foundation of the database, is the database of transcripts/quotes, Divine Message, and we are very fortunate to have a website for it since 2019 due to volunteers helping the team. The link Divine Message is part of the website where all the posts of the teams are shared. Step 2 is the website Eternal Moments of Photographs of Shri Mataji and of photos Moments of Joy. Step 3 is the archives at the link Archives, which, among other things, contains one single table that will gradually contain the whole archives' data. We are looking forward to the next steps. Your kind contribution, help, support and sharing has been and it will always be very much appreciated. The team would benefit a lot from being joined by one or two members who would like to take active roles in websites or Hindi. The Comprehensive Compilations Team (CCT) sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 38: Color, Frequency, Wavelength</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0308" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 38: Color, Frequency, Wavelength" /><published>2023-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post38_CCT_Color_Frequency_Wavelength</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0308"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There have been several Incarnations on this Earth who have always said to know your Spirit because without finding his Spirit a human being cannot find God. <font color="DarkRed">Just as without eyes we cannot identify colors, similarly without knowing the Spirit, through arguments, we cannot obtain God.</font> Through brains we cannot know God. It is through the Spirit only we can know God. Till now everybody has said that, "You rise in your dharma and find your Spirit; know the Spirit which is within you." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Spirit from The Life Eternal, 1980 Issue, Page 55</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"[Due to an Āgñyā chakra problem, Douglas Fry used to see different colors, this beautiful rainbow green and this beautiful rainbow, flashing from Śhrī Mātājī. He mentions this to Her.]<br />
You shouldn't see that. One color is power [red] and one is purity [green]. If you can actually see those colors, it means you are not in the center. You are off to one side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Seeing Colors, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Ādi Viṣhṇu protects and evolves the path of evolution. His Incarnations are like milestones in the progress of spiritual awareness, and develop, one by one, new dimensions of human perception. They show the light in the darkness of ignorance, and each Avatāra adds a new boundless perception, a new fragrance, and a new color to the beauty of creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Realized Souls are able to see the Kuṇḍalinī as twisted, coiled identities in the atmosphere. They can also see good and bad souls as round bodies, their colors expressing their quality.</font> They do not see the body of the souls, but possessed people can see such bodies as they belong to the subconscious strata themselves.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Spirits are of different colors, ranging from jet black to smokey black, or patchy golden if they are egoistical. By contrast, realized Souls appear like clear crystals, and sometimes shine like stars. Their face and body are of the same appearance as their body in life.</font><br />
......<br />
In India they use also the dead spirits which are devoid of Kuṇḍalinī ... [<font color="orange">missing</font>] and Divine Spirit (<i>Ātmā</i>). They enter into the fetus about the same time. At their entry we can feel the pulse of the fetus.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Realized Souls can see them in the atmosphere. Not in human form or colors but only as Kuṇḍalinī and Spirit engulfed by soul. Sometimes one sees bunches or sometimes loops of Kuṇḍalinī, and also in the forms of black or white dots. These souls carry the Spirit and the body of the Kuṇḍalinī as small coiled structures. These are the chakras, and to some are visible as different varieties of light.</font> The only one which is one with the Kuṇḍalinī is the Spirit (<i>Ātmā</i>) which is the light of the heart.<br />
It should be quite clear what one means by the word 'soul'. The soul, is the subtle body (<i>sūkṣhma śharīra</i>), the subtle form of the subject's body without the water element and the earth element. The soul consists of five sheaths. Two of these disintegrate on the physical plane at the time of death. They form the chromosomes. The rest of the bodies (<i>śharīra</i>) depart into the Collective Subconscious. <font color="DarkRed">This soul-body can vary in color from black, blackish violet, through green, light blue, and golden crystal to white.</font> These bodies dissipate in the atmosphere around an individual according to his unfulfilled desires. Those spirits which have spontaneously dropped all material desires rise effortlessly to great heights, beyond the atmospheric realm and human vision. They can sometimes descend to Earth, though, to appear as apparitions, or communicate certain revelations."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 5: The Subconscious and the Collective Subconscious}\label{The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 5: The Subconscious and the Collective Subconscious</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">In a Divine Incarnation this [Mūlādhāra] chakra has the color of clay, and it shines.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In realized Souls the Mūlādhāra chakra shines like a neon misty or orange light. It appears as if the wicks of the Swastika are illumined with beautiful radiant lights. They look like four pinkish-orange colored tongues of flame which are silent yet living. The whole vision is of a four-petalled lotus with silent flames for petals. The lotus has a center which is deep blue or misty gray depending on Śhrī Gaṇeśha's mood. Realized Souls can peep into this ocean of deep color and visualize the melting of deep blue into light blue, and see sudden flashes appear like clouds and lightning. This vision spreads beautiful clouds of joy around the seeker.</font> The lightning is followed by the trunk of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, and after some time the elephant-headed Deity appears as a small child. At first He looks static to most realized Souls, but later on expresses a great deal of movement. Each movement creates a new wave of joy and tranquility. At a later stage, Śhrī Gaṇeśha becomes a living personality to such souls.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In ordinary human beings (<i>Asahaja</i>) this chakra appears as coral color, and looks like four threads or wicks joined in the shape of a Swastika.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In the case of misguided seekers (sādhakas) this subtle center appears red. In a clairvoyant, who is misguided because of misuse of his sympathetic nervous system, it appears deep red. Sometimes one sees only the wheel-like chakra rotating in a colored circular pattern of various shades of deep red and blue-black. This happens when Śhrī Gaṇeśha expresses His temper against the clairvoyant <i>sādhaka</i>.</font> Clairvoyance is only achieved with the help of 'dead spirits' by non-realized souls working through the sympathetic nervous system, and is an unauthorized disturbance to Him.<br />
......<br />
Any effort at obstinate abstinence or overindulgence excites the sympathetic nervous system. With the pressure of overactivity, the subject's attention starts moving along the Iḍā or Piṅgalā nāḍī as the case may be. <font color="DarkRed">At first, a vision of the Mūlādhāra chakra as a deep red, multicolored kaleidoscopic wheel becomes visible to the individual. The deep red color is the result of Śhrī Gaṇeśha's anger due to unauthorized probing in His Realm. This unceremonious approach is insulting to Him and His Mother Kuṇḍalinī. Inside the very center of this wheel one can even see the angered and inflamed Śhrī Gaṇeśha if one attempts to force the probe further.</font> A misguided seeker may even get a shock, or feel terrible heat in his body and suffer inexplicable restlessness. Particularly horrible experiences of the past, known as 'flashbacks', may occur. Some people howl and jump around like wild animals; others who are impotent and exhibitionistic often end up taking off all their clothes.<br />
......<br />
So the seeker who insults the Primordial Mother is greatly punished by Śhrī Gaṇeśha. No one can harm Him as He is inviolable under the Holy Aura of love of His Mother. His indestructibility is proved in the Resurrection of Christ. Seekers trying hard to reach Him can only work through the sympathetic nervous system, and their attention moves through the right or left channels as the central parasympathetic nervous system is beyond their reach. Eventually, by such stupid persistence, such misguided seekers are dangerously sidetracked and become clairvoyant. Their attention only goes onto the fringes of His chakra without any control and rotates on the outermost border. <font color="DarkRed">Sometimes such individuals describe their vision of this chakra. It seems like the wrath of Śhrī Gaṇeśha bubbles as a red and blue colored fire which rotates at the surface of the chakra.</font> It does not make any sense to these ignorant people. In reality, the chakra is like a bulbous bloom in the shape of a morning glory flower. <font color="DarkRed">If the misguided seeker persists in his obstinate pursuits, then Śhrī Gaṇeśha appears in red hot hues, and warns the seeker to stop the unauthorized probing.</font> At this stage, if the seeker does not give up he is punished by Śhrī Gaṇeśha's anger expressed as tremendous heat or a burning sensation. Sometimes blisters may appear in an elliptical line, starting from the navel and going around the neck. This can occur without any advance warning. The seeker may jump like a scalded cat, or experience agonizing burning sensations. All these symptoms are due to the insult the misguided seeker bestows on Śhrī Gaṇeśha and His Mother, and not to Kuṇḍalinī awakening, which many stupid people identify it with. This kind of physical resistance is apparent only in people who do not mentally accept the sin (<i>adharma</i>). But those who by their previous karmas or weaknesses accept sin, feel as if their responsibility is over. They feel relaxed and the entities working through them enjoy the pleasures, while they themselves feel pure. Actually, such a subject is dominated completely by these entities, and turns into a slave and an insensitive person."<br />"
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The earth element created the Swādhiṣhṭhān chakra and gave it its yellow color. It thus appears as six yellow-colored threads in most people when it comes into vision in meditation. The color ranges between pale yellow to mustard from person to person, depending on their state of mind as far as their creativity is concerned. In a realized Soul the color is golden, and in an Incarnation it looks like a brilliant Sun. In its center there is a round deep hollow, bluish-yellow in color. In the wrong type of seeker (<i>Asahaja</i>) this appears as a deep blue-black coloration. For a Yogi, though, who is able to peep into this hollow, the form of Brahmadeva in pale yellow colors is clearly visible.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Animals have no sense of beauty; only human beings can feel the esthetics of a composition of different colors, or the movement of lines and the melting of forms.</font> The feelings of joy acquired through this esthetic sense create a <i>Rasa</i> (a secretion of the essence or juice of a feeling). This Rasa gives one a stimulative feeling that sets in motion waves of esthetic joy within the Inner Self. These joys are of different frequencies and vibrations. One does not need to dissect them but as I look at the different petals of this chakra, I shall try to explain the kinds of joys present in the realm of creativity expressed through divine enlightenment.<br />
......<br />
I know a gentleman from Africa who possessed a huge piece of jade. After getting his Self-realization he felt that the stone was emitting vibrations. <font color="DarkRed">He sensed that jade had three colors: green, pink and white in circular layers. He made a unique flowerpot out of that piece of jade which was white in color with a pattern of green leaves and pink flowers. Quite ordinary stones can be transformed through esthetic sensitivity into such priceless works of art through the Grace of the Power of Saraswatī.</font><br />
There are no temples to Brahmadeva because He is never there to attend any pūjā or worship. He is too busy looking after the creation which represents Him, and is His witnessing power in human evolution. <font color="DarkRed">But the main activity of this Deity is to create absolute beauty, beauty emitted through a variety of textures, colors, lines and forms in matter.</font> Variety is the essence of beauty, and the harmony of those varieties creates a bliss which is felt by an awakened mind. It is also felt, much more, as joy. The artist produces a work to express the joy he felt glimpsing the beauty of creation. Many artists who are great Souls and worshipers of Saraswatī have added to Brahmadeva's material creation, establishing a new community of subtler human beings called artists. <font color="DarkRed">The joy poured into nature by the Primordial Mother is enjoyed by artists, and is revealed in the universal language of colors, lines and forms they use to express it.</font> They fill human lives with exquisite creations of music, art, dance and other art forms. All this is the blessing of the Goddess Saraswatī who is in the image of Mahāsaraswatī, Deity of the Piṅgalā nāḍī. This channel is responsible for supplying Praṇava for the creation of all human endeavors. "<br />"
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 13: Swādhiṣhṭhān Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The power of sustenance is the expression of the revelatory mood of Ādi Śhakti, the sattvaguṇa, in Her aspect as Mahālakṣhmī. She gives character and form to matter by Her loving care and affection. It is as if Her assuring love asserts matter to hold all its aspects together through its sustenance, like a nugget of gold, which is yellow and shines and has a peculiar character all of its own. <font color="DarkRed">All that is yellow or shines is not necessarily gold, but real gold is gold because it is yellow in color, shines and does not tarnish.</font> Its quality of not tarnishing is gold's sustenance (<i>dharma</i>).<br />
......<br />
When a seeker gets his Self-realization, Praṇava manifests the existence of the five elements. A Sahaja Yogi feels an energy like electricity oozing out of his extremities (<i>Chaitanya Laharī</i>). These are the Divine Vibrations of Praṇava but they also express the electrical part of his nature. These vibrations are also magnetic, and emit radiance or light. <font color="DarkRed">When this happens one can hear the sounds of the heart, and see different forms of light and colors.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 14: The Powers of Ādi Śhakti and the Three Guṇas</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">In the collective all must transcend the false barriers of race, color, creed, nationality and fundamentalism.</font> The foundation of the collective is Divine Love and respect."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0700 Book 'Sahaja Yoga', Chapter 2: Vishwa Nirmala Dharma</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In these centuries, rationality at its height, worked through the medium of the white-skinned races who elaborated a linear area derived from rational thinking that all other skin colors were somehow not made by God, who, it was tacitly assumed, was certainly White and most probably Anglo-Saxon, and had bestowed a different color upon other races as a kind of divine punishment. This sort of ignorance may appear very funny to us, but armed with this special kind of rationality, or rather with the rationalizations of imperialism and colonialism, they actually killed thousands and even millions of people, plundering their land and making slaves of the population. As a result, one cannot find a single Red Indian in North America living freely and naturally in the traditional way, because they are all locked up in reservations "generously" given to them by the invaders. One has to go to the museum to see their pictures painted with the head dressed as of Red Indians but, strangely, with the faces of Anglo-Saxons.</font><br />
Thank God some divine providence took Columbus to America and kept him there, instead of to India where he thought he was heading. <font color="DarkRed">Otherwise, the "colored" people of India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Tibet, Nepal, Afghanistan and all other "stans" with their ancient and sophisticated cultures, would have also been completely devastated and destroyed by the superiority complex of the Conquistadors, those bull fighters of Spain, whose great contribution to civilization was creating the "peace" and the "calm" of the Catholic churchyard.</font> But to make up for Columbus' neglect, the great Anglo-Saxons came to India from England, did their best to neutralize the heritage and deep wisdom of India, and then gracefully left after 300 years of respectable hospitality from their unasked hosts. They left India peacefully, but with this great country disastrously divided into two different parts into which the seeds of violent destruction were already sown.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">When the Anglo-Saxons were busily plundering those "inferior" cultures of the "colored" races (especially in America), their ego developed to the extent that they were thoroughly blinded to reality and they began to think that their arrogance and their inhuman behavior was perfectly normal and quite all right. They found, according to all the rules and logic of rationality and to their great satisfaction, that they had nicely plundered the whole world, crushed all the "inferior" races into submission and had now settled down comfortably to enjoy the fruits of their arrogance.</font> Of course, polarity started manifesting itself. America, particularly, began to prosper and, despite the great idealism of the American Revolution against colonialism, the people gradually became slaves to luxury, and the victims of their own egoism. As time passed, they began to treat the non Anglo-Saxons, all the Jews, Hispanics, Italians and Russians, as inferior races and they tormented them as foreigners in that land of the Red Indians, which now they assumed was their own. Many, perhaps fired by religious zeal, claimed that it was their birthright and that they had been chosen and blessed by God to do the great work of destroying the Red Indians, who were "primitive" and did not have white skin, as God Almighty most certainly had.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Recently it was shocking to hear that the top priest of the Catholic Church in Austria has been charged with the offense of abusing children. His dress was all red in color. I wish he could enter into the arena of bull fights with a very deadly bull facing him. Even the children themselves might feel it preferable to die than to live a life of such devastation.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 1: Modernism and Rationality</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"These handmade things are a reflection of their enjoyment of life and they give us, if we know how to appreciate them, a deep feeling of harmony and joy. <font color="DarkRed">These simple artists feel that whatever beauty God has created around them has nourished their minds with that beauty, and the natural world -- the flowers, leaves and colors that they see around them -- goes into the cloth which will be covering and enhancing the beauty of lovely ladies.</font> They know that the body is created by God and that its beauty is to be clad and set off by the beauty of human creation. It is surprising how poetically these simple people describe their work when they talk about it.<br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">It is a well-known fact that on a ship people get very bored because everything is decorated with the same color and texture. The curtains are the same all over, and even the food is much the same every day. All these repetitions very quickly bore the unfortunate passengers.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 2: Choices</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 4: Racialism</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Color" /><category term="crimson @ Frequency" /><category term="crimson @ Wavelength" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 37: Photograph</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0301" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 37: Photograph" /><published>2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post37_CCT_Photograph</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0301"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This Photo was taken after I opened the Collective Sahasrāra Chakra. I even look a bit sad.<br />
I look very serious in this Photo. At that time I even stopped eating and became a little thin.<br />
From birth I knew I was the Goddess, and My job was to save and raise up this doomed humanity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on a Photo Taken in 1970 on the Terrace, Flat with View towards the Sea, A1 Jeevan Jyot, Nepean Sea Road (now Lady Laxmibai Jagmohandas Mārg), Setalvad Lane, Breach Candy, Cumballa Hill, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"... Teach them not to put their back and their feet to the Photo ... "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes on Children from the book Raising Children in Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">[Śhrī Mātājī further on says that there will be a day when She will not be there and even Her Photograph will not be there, but Sahaja Yoga will be there.]</font> "...... that Sahaja Yoga cannot be destroyed because it is a living thing. It is an energy."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Poetry and Sahaja Yoga, India from the book The Breeze of Sahasrara, Pages 200 and 201</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Do you differentiate Me, the physical Form and My Photograph in My nirākār Form? At times I Myself wonder how it works out, but it works out even at times better that My own physical presence before You.<br />
May be you need to stabilize your wandering thoughts and seek Mother in your heart, you really do not need to come near Me to meet Me to get your all problems solved. My Photograph ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Personal Attention</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[In early eighties Śhrī Mātājī discovers that catches from removed ex-leaders have passed on to new Sahaja Yogis who have received Realization from them.]<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Asking these new Sahaja Yogis:] <font color="DarkRed">Did he [removed ex-leader] give you Realization before My Photograph or without it?</font><br />
<b>New Sahaja Yogis:</b> Before Your Photograph.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Then it is I who gave you Realization, so there is no reason to feel indebted to him. Forget him.</font> [With that, catches fled.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī instructs that Realization should be given before Her Photo, then the catches do not transfer from one to another. Moreover, one does not absorb the catches of the seekers.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Catches and Photograph from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 6, Page 20 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Behind every element is a Deity, when you put the elements before My Photograph they get vibrated."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Elements, Photograph, and Vibrations from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 14, Page 39 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[Arriving in a city for a Public Program, Śhrī Mātājī observes there are no posters anywhere.]
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Why there are no posters?</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogis:</b> Śhrī Mātājī, we were worried about the protocol of Your Photograph. People might tear or trample on them.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"> The city gets vibrated with My Photograph, and that is how the Paramachaitanya informs the seekers through their unconsciousness. When I went to Russia, the Russian seekers had never known about Me but the Unconscious informed them and they came in thousands. When I asked them, "How did you recognize Me?" They answered, "From your Photograph of course Mother." I have given permission for putting My Photograph on posters, you don't have to worry about the protocol.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Posters from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 22, Pages 64 and 65 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
""<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-1029 Letter (Marathi) to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In meditation try to stop your thoughts. <font color="DarkRed">Watch My Photograph with open eyes and see that you stop your thoughts.</font> You should stop your thoughts, then you go into meditation. The simple thing to stop your thoughts is the Lord's Prayer, because that's the Āgñyā state. So in the morning you remember Lord's Prayer or Gaṇeśha's mantra. It's just the same. Or you even say 'I forgive'. So you can start with Gaṇeśha's mantra, say Lord's Prayer and then say ]I forgive'. It works out."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1905-0000 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On Meditation</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[<font color="DarkRed">Poor eyesight: looking through candle flame on Mother's hands Photograph, Devī Kavach: Śhrī Śhaṅkhinī mantra.</font> Mahāgaṇeśha, Mahābhairava, Hiraṇyagarbha. Viśhuddhi and back Āgñyā treatment. Massage wrists/Viśhuddhi with ghee camphor. Cover Viśhuddhi. Ghee camphor in nose.]<br />
.....<br />
[Cancer: skin tumor. Śhrī Mātājī has said that at initial stages, Sahaj will help. In advanced stage you need medical help. Remove tumor and continue Sahaj methods. Don't worry, surrender to Mother. <font color="DarkRed">Speak to Photograph.</font> Be innocent and surrender.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advices Given to Dr. Madhur Rai, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, there is another question which was asked - of course, they ... they thought it was very wise, and I think it is a great help - that, "When we put hands to You, we burn. But when Your disciples put hands to us, they burn. Now, who is the positive, who is the negative?" It's a complicated question.<br />
So, for that, we have to use a person who is lunatic: absolute accepted lunatic or psychologically affected person. <font color="DarkRed">Ask that person to put the hands to Me or to My Photograph, and raise the Kuṇḍalinī, he'll start shaking too much.</font> Now, you ask a realized person to put his hand and go into meditation, while a person who is suffering from negativity will start shaking and burning.<br />
The one who is a certified person and a negative personality, the one who suffers from inferiority complexes and the fear and all these symptoms of negativity, should be used as a measuring rod.<br />
One gentleman wanted to take full advantage of My raising things. <font color="DarkRed">He took My Photograph and put it and all that thing.</font> And he also said he was My disciple, [laughing:] very openly. Of course, I accepted that, "You be my Guru. You can give me something sensible." And then I got something also, [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] he said, "You must tell people that, 'I am your guru.' " I said, "All this thing if you want I will tell them. But I don't think you have done anything unique." But even now he is been too much. He is telling people that he's doing My work."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0325 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Seminar, Day 3, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then you take a big, nice Photo of Mine, frame it nicely, and sit in front of it after lighting a lamp, in meditation. Meet Me after two or three days."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0xxx Public Program, Day 22, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Whosoever will come in front of you should dissolve in your love. And if he does not dissolve, then he will run away. A day will come and that day you will not need this protection.<br />
You people have found many ways of protection. These people can tell you about some of the ways if you want. You can ask them. <font color="DarkRed">Like taking vibrations on the Photo.</font> Taking out [vibrations] with feet or taking out with water. How to put your own bandhan, etc. Taking different names, etc. There are many types. If you want to know about them then you can talk to these people, then these people can tell you all this.<br />
......<br />
You have to do no business whatsoever.<br />
You have not to collect money in any way. For nothing at all.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">One person said to Me that he will sell My Photos and then that money he will give to the Āśhram. I said, "Which Āśhram? What money? Who said so? Why do you listen to others?"</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0903 Pūjā (Hindi), Ātma-sākṣhātkār ka Arth (Meaning of Self-realization), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0910 Public Program (Hindi), Bholāpan (Innocence), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (place not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photograph" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 36: Culture</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0222" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 36: Culture" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post36_CCT_Culture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0222"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Without spirituality science has no culture. Does science know on what love feeds on? The meaning of love, or how a living thing works, science is not able to tell about it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Progress, Science and Spirituality, Sahasrāra Pūjā, from the book Sahaja Yoga, An Experiential Treatise (Sahaja Yoga Anubhavāche Bola) by Venu Narayan Phaḍake, Chapter 10, Page 130 (possible year 1998)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In the democratic country there is a wild race for creating new wants and new problems to make the machines work for twenty four [twenty-four] hours. The house hold [household] is filled with all junk showing the relics of the dead desires. <font color="DarkRed">To counterbalance we have movements of anti-culture who take to other desires of drugs[,] ect. [etc.]</font> In the communist countries the desires are controlled by force and regimentation but once these bounded people get to the so-called free countries they become wild like primitive people.[,] worse than the free people[.]"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Economics</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In guiding the creation of an atom into this complex universe and in planning the evolution of a single cell into this wonderful human being, there is a hidden hand of a very great Artist-artist because through his creation He expresses Himself, He sings, He dances, He paints, He acts and above all, He compels the spectators to reflect. Yes, He created this world because He wanted to reflect Himself, His Truths, His Beauty, His Grace, His Compassion, His Sweetness, His Righteousness, all that can be termed as culture."
......<br />
Artists have to raise the taste of public eye to their standards of taste and not to stoop down to the cheap demands of the public and thus surrendering their freedom. This can be done by contacting educational and social institutions by the enlightened artists. Through articles in magazines and newspapers, the idea[s] of such artists can be propagated. Through dramas, films and radio talks, people can be educated for the understanding of real art. Thus the dignity of art can be maintained.<br />
By coming in contact with the public at large through these societies, the social self of an artist will develop into a keener and a [more] sensitive being. It will react to the slightest unrest in the nation, to the slightest imbalance in the society. If he sees a leper on the street, his heart will pour out with such sympathy through his art that he can create an atmosphere by which social workers, doctors, scientists and the people in charge of the state will be forced to think of some solution to the problems of leprosy. If an artist finds his countrymen being unpatriotic or cowardly, he can through his art inspire them and can serve the role of a brave soldier. Thus he can serve the society through other by creating a deep impact on their minds. Such is the motivating power of an artist. They are the loveliest flowers of the creation, the sweetest dreams of the Creator and the dearest parts of the human society. Perhaps, they do not know how they are loved, worshiped and followed by their spectators.
This is my humble concept of art, culture and artist. In my honest efforts, I have tried to suggest certain ways and means by which artists can get united and give a lead to further the cause of art.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1961-1000 Article 'Art Culture and Artist' published in the souvenir 'Dignity of Art' brought out to commemorate the Inauguration of the 'Youth Society For Films' by the Union Home Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri on 1961-1008, the function presided over by the Chief Minister of Maharashtra Y. B. Chevam, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"12. To improve the esthetics of behavior and beauty by holding exhibitions of art, culture and music and through all activities which speak the universal language of love and beauty by developing the inner sense known as "Atīndriya", that enlightens the subtle sensitivities."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1972-0308 Annexure I of The Life Eternal Trust Deed, Charity Commissioner, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"As if don't know what is this thing which came from God, which is to be given to this world ... And the Truth is that, 'It is!' No doubt about it.<br />
But even after knowing this Truth, I won't call it their fault but the reason for their shortcoming is that they did not get birth in Yoga Bhūmi [Land of Yoga] of India. Don't know why God gave birth to such great people on that bhoga bhūmi [land of materialism] and you people have got birth on this Yoga Bhūmi. <font color="DarkRed">That bhoga bhūmi where they have no culture.</font> They don't even know if they have to wear sindūr [kumkum] on the forehead or on the nose. They don't know the protocols of Pūjā, they don't know the protocol of praying, they have no knowledge about God. They don't know even how to sit on the ground. They don't know anything, they don't even know how to give claps while performing the Āratī.<br />
And such great Souls, so innate they are, so loving.<br />
They love Me so much, such respect they have towards Me that I am surprised. Whenever they walk in front of Me, in fact they don't, but whenever they pass they bow and pass with their head bent down. They love Me so much that anything in this whole world has no meaning for them in front of Me. They have such deep feeling for Me that they don't know how should they respect Me, in what way. I am surprised that how they have so much understanding of all this about Me."<br />
......<br />
Your baiṭhak [sitting capacity] should be perfect. It should be strong.<br />
I can't even tell them about baiṭhak. They don't even know this word. English language is useless. They don't have any culture of that sort, no talks like this. So unfortunate they are.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1221 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Apanī aur Dṛuṣhṭi Rakhe (Keep the Attention on Yourself), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, you are seeing that in this world there are people chanting 'Hare Rāma, hare Kṛiṣhṇa'. In London, so many of their disciples come to Me and they have cancer here.<br />
This is a fact that I am sharing with you. I am your Mother and I have to tell you what is false.<br />
They have cancer here.<br />
You will be surprised that in this throat resides Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. When anyone faces a problem in the throat or in the cervical plexus then the name of Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa has to be taken in the science of Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
Now look at their Kuṇḍalinīs which are not awakened and Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is sitting angrily at this point. He has disappeared from there. What is the reason? <font color="DarkRed">We think, 'Oh, they are spreading our culture!,' though they don't spread any culture. I have seen their ponytails falling off, their dhotīs [lower garment worn traditionally in India] falling off and it looks so ugly.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now to say of Indian culture and Hindu culture and Muslim culture and other cultures, it is most surprising that Kuṇḍalinī, or we can say the Primordial Kuṇḍalinī of the Virāṭa, has got all these Great Incarnations -- whether they were Muslims, whether they were Christians, whether they were Indians -- seated on the chakras."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"What a great thing of Sahaja Yoga! I have talked about it a day before yesterday, that the power of Sahaja Yoga is tremendous.<br />
Once you receive this Power of God Almighty, then you enter into new Kingdom, and God is the King of that Kingdom Himself.<br />
You don't have to say this later that, 'Don't speak in Marathi, don't speak in Hindi, don't speak in ten languages.' You only speak one language, have one Kingdom. Unify the whole country!<br />
There should be only one United Nations.<br />
It happens that way because you all are one, that you have only taken in a way that, 'We are different,' or you think, 'It's given by this form by God.'<br />
We are different, you are different, and you are all one from inside. That is, it has the power to connect, it is inside to connect.<br />
Even the word connected is not right. You are one from inside.<br />
You are the only one in infinity, means the Power to show that you all are one is awakened. It means Sahaja Yoga is unified and bringing everyone together. This means it integrates everyone, it brings integration to each other.<br />
Everyone seems to be doing well. 'It's good in this culture,' 'It's good in that culture.' 
Someone is better in that, and the other one is better in another.'"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0531 Public Program (Marathi), Sahajyog Sgalyāṃnā Samagra Karto (Sahaja Yoga Makes Everyone Holistic), Matunga, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I am not in opposition for English language, but the language of Ātmā is Sanskrit.<br />
They have never bothered about the Spirit.<br />
You see, so we have to use some common language with [which] speaks about Ātmā. English language is not sufficient enough, I must tell you.<br />
They do not have those experiences because this is so far they have not gone deep into it, and we are very old people, ancient people. <font color="DarkRed">Our culture has been to know God, and everything has come in Sanskrit because Sanskrit is really a Devavāṇi [language of the Gods].</font><br />
Apart from that, when the Kuṇḍalinī moves, She makes sounds, She makes different sounds, which we -- they are really Devanāgarī sounds, all of them are, on all different chakras they are. If I have time I might tell you all those sounds that It makes.<br />
So our Sanskrit is really a Devavāṇi, and even when you say mantras, then, through the Sanskrit language or Devanāgarī pronunciations only, you can excite them better."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi+English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0223 Public Program, Day 2, The Normal Human Consciousness and Beyond Human Awareness, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 35: Alternative</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0215" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 35: Alternative" /><published>2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post35_Alternative</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0215"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"We aim to hold a conference where representatives from different religions around the world will come together to discuss how organized religions are lacking. The aim is to take the concept of a universal, 'pure' religion and to offer as an alternative a 'Universal Religion of the Spirit'."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Two Quotes from an article by Catherine Kelly (a writer and broadcaster who lives in London) Reproduced in a 2001-1200 article 'Age of the Truth' by Audrey Hopes in a Local Newspaper from Los Angeles Area</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
"You must say the mantras during Pūjā, but with complete śhraddhā. <font color="DarkRed">There is no alternative to śhraddhā.</font> When your śhraddhā is exquisite [profound], then only you should sit for a Pūjā. That way the Pūjā is done by heart. That time waves after waves of joy start flowing because when Ātmā Tattwa is the focal point there can not be any thoughts. The way people fill wine in a glass, same is with you performing Pūjā, your śhraddhā is the wine and the glass is nothing but the recitation of mantras and sādhana. While drinking this wine you are completely engrossed, with no thoughts, and you swim in this joy. How to express that joy in thoughts [words]? The wine which is inside the stomach, who is going to pour it back into a glass? And that too in an inferior glass made of thoughts. Joy after drinking this wine is eternal. It is your wealth. Many Pūjās like this have happened in front of Me and every time a big wave comes and takes you to a new shore. Those experiences from different shores become your own. They give grandness to your personality and open new doors of joy.<br />
It is best to do a Pūjā in the heart. If you can look at the Photo and then bring it into your heart, or after a Pūjā if you can bring that scene into your heart, then the joy of that moment can become permanent and will last for a long time. Read this letter to all Sahaja Yogis and send them copies of this letter."<br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
"You should say the Mantras in Pūjā but with great faith (śhraddhā). <font color="DarkRed">There is no alternative to śhraddhā.</font> You should perform the Pūjā when śhraddhā grows deep, so that heart itself gets all Pūjā performed. At that time waves of bliss start flowing because it is the Spirit that is saying, how can any thought come at that time? People pour their wine in the glass. Your Pūjā is like that. In that, wine is your faith and the glass is the recitation of Mantras and the worshiping. When you are drinking that wine forgetting everything, how can a thought come! Then only bathing in the Ocean of Bliss! How can that joy be expressed in thoughts? Who will pour that wine, back in the glass, which is to be drunk and that too in the inferior glass of thoughts? However, the joy that you get after drinking the wine is eternal and ever-present. It becomes your asset. Many such Pūjās have been performed in My presence. Every time a big wave comes and take you to a new land. Experiences of many such lands become your own. They give vastness to personality and open new gates of joy.<br />
Best is worshiping in the heart. If, the Photo by looking at it, can be placed in heart or, after the Pūjā, its view goes to heart, then the joy which you get only at that time, can become everlasting and ever-present. Show this letter, to all Sahaja Yogis and send its copies."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1012 Letter to Nirmalā (sister of Rājabhāī Modi) (Marathi), On Pūjā, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br /><br />
"Now instead of thinking and planning, if they realize the planning of the Almighty, then they don't have to take that headache upon themselves. First understand God. Meaning, His All-pervading Power is doing all the planning by Itself. If you abide by that planning then all your tasks will work out beautifully. <font color="DarkRed">If instead you take it upon yourself, then you will always encounter some hindrances and obstacles.</font> You can see for yourself the state of our country due to the existing planning. "
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br /><br />
"Now instead of thinking and planning themselves, if they understand the planning of the Almighty, then they don't have to take that trouble upon themselves. First understand God. Meaning, His All-pervading Power is doing all the planning by Itself. If you abide by that planning, then all your tasks will work out properly and beautifully. <font color="DarkRed">If instead you take it upon yourself, then you will plan, evaluate alternatives and work out the solutions where there will always be obstacles.</font>"
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"There is no alternative to this. It is a very subtle. Only one or two strands of the Kuṇḍalinī rise from inside of it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0318 Public Program (Hindi), Day 9, Sahasrāra Chakra, Śhāmiyānā, Garden, Pataudi House, 10 Ashoka Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then there can be only two possibilities. Either you recognize the Self-realization within you, and rise up to its greatness and go deep in it, or leave it altogether. There cannot be a third alternative.<br />
As someone asked, "How many turns are there in London?" "Only two: left and right." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0818 Public Program (Hindi), Ātmā and Paramātma, Saradār Patel Vidyalaya (School), Lodi Estate, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"There were some people who came to Me whom I called druggist or chemist. Means they used to be in state of coma. Such high consumption of drugs. But they got out of drugs from next day itself. Liquor, cigarette everything. Ninety-nine percent [99%].<br />
But one percent [1%] may still be stuck. Some are stubborn, but they should strive hard, and they do strive else one gets catches. Then you realize that there is a catch on the left Viśhuddhi, this and that. Then it pains. There is no alternative except removing the catch."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1209 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Day 1, Sane Gurujī Vidyālaya (English Medium) School, Bhikoba Waman Pathare Mārg, Near Dadar Catering College, Shivaji Park, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">How there are ... there is no alternative for Sahaj Yog, no alternative, one must know. Everything that is living has no alternatives.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed">For example, if a mango tree says that, 'I will create a pomegranate,' it cannot. There is no alternative.</font><br />
Whatever is there it has to see and enjoy. But not to force its way on [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
......<br />
Look at the little ones: how they came forward to give Me flowers, every step, every movement was so joyous, was creating such a beautiful delicate ripple in My heart. And it's written as history for Me to see these little, little sweet, innocent Gaṇeśhas coming forward.<br />
That in wisdom becomes so [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] that you know the Source of Love as Gaṇeśha [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. <font color="DarkRed">For He did not know anything else but one that which is the Source of Love. Never questioned. Never argued, no alternative. No new ideas came into head, He's just steadying in.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Wisdom, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now if you say: 'Which is the way a flower has to become a fruit?' There's only one way! [Laughing:] There have no two ways. <font color="DarkRed">Living things do not have two ways and five alternatives.</font> These are all for human beings to take lots of decisions and [laughs] do all these things. But for any living thing, it's only one way it works out.<br />
And that's how it is the germination within you, which is a living force of the Living God, is the only way: is the Kuṇḍalinī awakening. <font color="DarkRed">And that's why we can say, Sahaja is the only way! It is! There's no other way out!</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0331 Talkback Live Interview with a Gentleman for the 'Forum' Program of 'Macquarie Sports Radio' Station (call sign 2UE), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So-o, to become closer to God, you have to be closer to God. That's as simple as that.<br />
I mean somebody would say: `How do I know that I know that ... what ... how to drive a car?' When you know. `How do I know I [laughing:] can drive a bike?' Say, for example somebody says, `How can I use a bike?' I mean when you are that you are that! I mean is there any other way out? `How will I say I've got eyes?' When you can see! Finished! I mean it's so simple as that.<br />
So, how can you say you are nearer to God? You yourself will know you are nearer to God. Because the joy of being that tells you.<br />
You need not be close to Me, you need not be touching My Feet, you could be anywhere in the forest, you could be very close to Me, and those who thing [] they are close to Me because they can make a little face and, you know, behave in a very artificial way or some dramatic styles, you see, they are very far away.<br />
And those who cannot understand the commands of the brain are useless things!<br />
Now supposing one nail starts growing big, all right, and piercing inside the skin, we'll take it out, isn't it? There's not listening to the brain!<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> We'll have to throw it out!<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Any malignant growth is that growth which goes beyond the control of the brain, of the central nervous system. If the parasympathetic cannot control a growth of a particular cell, that is a malignant cell!<br />
So, if you become malignant in Sahaja Yoga, you may think you are a very great person or very some thing. You may think, you will be thrown out. Because you are a disease! You are a diseased person. You'll be thrown out.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">So to be reluh ... relevant, is to be relevant! There's no alternative for that.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed">Paryāy (alternative)</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Paryāy (alternative)</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> No compromise in it.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">No compromise.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0206 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Action and Desire, Research Station, Niphad, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Like Blake has said, that, "Men of God will become Prophets, and the ... these Prophets will have powers to make others Prophets."<br />
He said it so clearly for you English people, but I don't think you people like Him very much. [Laughing:] Because ... because the way peo... few people I have seen, who really appreciate Blake. And some of them have said that, ``He is mad!" Naturally, among all the mad people, a sane person may look mad also. But He is the one who has so clearly said.<br />
And in this country, this great man should be born, and should talk about Jerusalem, is remarkable!<br />
Because you cannot think, in England, where people just believe in dominating other countries and using the ... their power to dominate others, you could get Jerusalem established!<br />
But what He said was of these days, when those false ideas have dropped off, when people do not think of domination, they do not think of materialism, they are fed up with all these things, and they are seeking today.<br /> 
And who are these seekers? These seekers are the men of God.<br />
So, recognize yourself. First of all, you must recognize your Self before recognizing anybody else, that you are seekers and that you are men of God.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Unless and until you have found God, you are not going to be happy by all these nonsensical ... uh-uh-uh ... alternatives people are giving.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0515 Public Program, Day 3, The Creative Power, Central Channel, Brighton Pavillion, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I mean, you may, in your myth, you see, hallucination, think it is different, and fight.<br />
It's, I ... I sometimes feel you are just fighting your shadows! This is the, you have created shadows, and the shadows are fighting. And just to make the shadows fight, you fight, otherwise shadows won't fight. [Some laughter.] It's all a shadow! There's no truth in it!<br />
To Me, it looks like that. It's all madness. What is there to fight?<br />
This is One World. Everybody is blessed by God. They all should enjoy His blessings: to enter into the Kingdom of God. He is the King. He is the One who is the Ruler.<br />
In His Kingdom, there is nothing like a state.<br />
So, that's a very different world you are entering into.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">There are no alternatives there! It's only one Absolute State of Mind, where you become the Spirit. That's all.</font><br />
......<br />
Foods also, natural food you must eat, more natural food, than artificial. All that will give you a better living.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And that is called as alternative, all right. That's alternative is important.</font><br />
But that doesn't mean you go on a bullock cart.<br />
You can export your trains to India, or your cars to India and get khādī from there. All right?<br />
Mu... mutual understanding. Because we are part and parcel of one Whole.<br />
And we just cannot exist by our only growth because then we become malignant, you see. One cells eats another. They ... you have to!<br />
If you have a machinery, you have to eat other! Because you produce so much, you must find markets for them, you must supply them, you must send over. Then you must have other countries to exploit them!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0607 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Ego and Humility or You Must Improve Yourself, Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0614 Public Program, You Are All Bound by One Thread (We All Are Expecting Something Great to Happen), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="gold @ Alternative" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 34: Aims, Destinations, Goals, and Purposes</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0208" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 34: Aims, Destinations, Goals, and Purposes" /><published>2023-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post34_CCT_Aims_Destinations_Goals_Purposes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0208"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You can attain any destination that you fix. All your autosuggestions will materialize.</font> The remedy that is to be used is: your attention should be on Me and you should make the following conditioning of thoughts on your Āgñyā "How fortunate we are to have been realized! We are Sahaja Yogis. God has chosen us. How can we work if we remain weak? Ādi Śhakti has given us the power to redeem the whole mankind. We can do it and we will do it." On heart you should criticize with these thoughts "How deep is God's love for us! He has given us the Realization. He is the Ocean of Mercy. Ignoring all our mistakes, He is working hard day and night for our welfare and, instead of praying for His forgiveness of our mistakes, we are making complaints against Him and blaming Him!" The following thoughts will please your hearts, "O God, please give us the Power of Your Love. May I be the drop in the Ocean of Your Love that is enveloping the whole universe, so that its loving pulsation is vibrated through My life and I remain engrossed in that bliss." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-0000 Letter (Marathi) from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 14 (March-April 1983), Page 11, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To emerge out victoriously of these two dangerous jaws of destruction is only possible if the leaders of the nations get self realization through sahaja yoga and are enlightened by Self Knowledge and the Knowledge of the collective. (This would manifest on their central nervous system). <font color="DarkRed">Thus appearing on the stage of reality as Lotuses of Divinity spreading the fragrance of human ascent into its glorious destination. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Democracy, Communism, and Religion related to the book Ascent</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"It is thus that the human beings constitute the best reflectors of the Creator. <font color="DarkRed">Some of them as sages, like Lord Buddha, Jesus Christ, Lord Mahavir, mark the destination of human progress, others as scientist discover the mighty forces of creation which are being constantly harnessed in the service of man.</font> Similarly, some others gifted with extraordinary faculties of perception and understanding play the role of "Artists". They have not only an extra-ordinary "eye" but also an ability to communicate with others through the medium of art. They have an extremely sensitive heart and an equally eloquent medium by which they can touch the hearts of their fellowmen. This factor assumes a social importance and thus an artist plays a vital role, as member of a society."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1961-1000 Article 'Art Culture and Artist' published in the souvenir 'Dignity of Art' brought out to commemorate the Inauguration of the 'Youth Society For Films' by the Union Home Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri on 1961-1008, the function presided over by the Chief Minister of Maharashtra Y. B. Chevam, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Mister Phaḍake, chakras and their colors don't mean everything. You have to go further ahead than that. These colors mean only a particle of the sea or sand. We have to reach to the complete sand as a whole.</font> These colors are like the scenes we pass while traveling by train. We don't remember the scenes and get involved in them. We just have a destination to reach. We forget all that we pass on the way, in between. In the same way attention should not go to the colors you pass on the way to Sahasrāra. How the thoughtless awareness comes. How it should be established for long time. This should be observed. Only looking at the colors will reduce the attention at Sahasrāra and it will be spoiled." [<b> Variant:</b> "<font color="DarkRed">Aho Phaḍake, colors of the chakras is not everything. You still have a long way to go. These colors are only like a drop of water in the ocean. We have to cross all these.</font> When we are traveling in a train, several scenes cross before our eyes, do we remember all of them? Our attention is on our destination. We forget what happens in between. Similarly, do not bother about the colors. Your attention should be on the Sahasrār. How will thoughtlessness come? How can we make it stay for a long time? Your attention should be on these things. If you keep seeing colors, you will only end up doing trāṭak on the Āgñyā chakra and it will get spoilt."]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0000 Quote (Marathi), on Seeing Colors, Part 1, Public Program, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But today you are those chosen flowers, chosen over the ages, to blossom so that today your vibrations and your fragrance should spread across the world, cleanse its sludge and eliminate the filth of this Ocean of Illusion.<br />
When looking at it, one may wonder, 'How it is possible, Mātājī is making a big statement?' <font color="DarkRed">But this is a continuation (silasilā) and, when the Destination has arrived in front you, then thinking, 'Why it has arrived? How has it come? How can this happen? When you were walking, did the destination not arrive? When you were seeking, will you not get your place?'!</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">The Destination has arrived. You all have reached courtyard. How easy and sahaja is all this.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0120 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi+Marathi), Day 1, Session 1 (morning), Tīn Śhaktiyān (Three Powers), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As Christ had said, "I am the Light, I am the Path," same is My statement, "I am the Destination, not only the Path."<br />
I did not say this to you because I had very bad experiences. This is the only reason. You people have to come to My refuge (śharaṇāgat). You have to accept Me as Mother and live like My sons. Without that your work will not be done.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0329 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Vigyān Manuṣhya kī Rachanā Nahīṃ Khoja Hai (Science Is Human's Discovery, Not Creation), Sweet Home, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Have I to say like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, "Leave all religions and surrender to Me" or as Śhrī Jesus, "I am the way, I am the door."<br />
I want to tell that I am that Man̄jil (Destination). But will you people accept it? Will this fact go to your hearts?"</font><br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Will I have to say like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa said, "Give up all other duties and surrender only to me," or like Jesus Christ said, "I am the path and I am the entrance."<br />
What I want to tell you is that, 'I am your final aim.' But will you all accept this? Will this message of mine enter your hearts?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1021 Letter to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Diwālī from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 13 (January-February 1983), Page 22, 2, Parklands, Ice House Wood, Hurst Green, Oxted, Surrey, UK}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0619 Public Program, The Difference Between East and West, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Aims" /><category term="crimson @ Destinations" /><category term="crimson @ Goals" /><category term="crimson @ Purposes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 33: Commitments, Oaths, Pledges, Promises, and Vows</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0201" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 33: Commitments, Oaths, Pledges, Promises, and Vows" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post33_CCT_Commitments_Oaths_Pledges_Promises_Vows</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0201"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"A couple of days ago, I asked people to promise that they would no longer consume alcohol, and half of them got up and left. Just a promise -- it was not like I asked them to make any payments!"</font><br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"A couple of days ago, I asked people to promise that they would no longer consume alcohol, and half of them got up and left. I then said that, "Just take the oath," I did not say that you will have to pay for that. But the moment I said this, half the people got up and left."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, at this place in Bordi, you all take an oath in your mind that, 'This is our aim that each person will save at least thousand more people.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0325 Pūjā (Hindi+English), Chit ke Gaharai (Depth of Your Attention), Seminar, Day 2, Camp, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now we have got, astrologically there are three and a half auspicious days where you don't have to consultant any uh ... any books of astrology, which are called as Pañchāṅg, to find out whether it is an auspicious time or not. For any Pūjā, for any [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] good work you have to do, people consultant, in India, the Pañchāṅg, is the book to find out which date is auspicious [and] which is not.<br />
One of them is today. Is a day you can do anything good, you decide anything good. <font color="DarkRed">Today is the day to take an oath, to think of something great, to visualize something big, to ask a boon, to do a big Pūjā, is one of the greatest uh day.</font> One of the, we call them muhūrtas, which where you do not consultant these books.<br />
And that's why rājyābhiṣhek of, I mean the crowning ceremony of Śhrī Rāma took place on this day."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, in the Presence of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, you have to take an oath, that, 'Whatever is the past of my country, I will get opposite to that!'<br />
......<br />
So, the second oath we have to take before Śhrī Gaṇeśha is: that, 'I will be honest to myself. I will not deceive myself, for anybody's sake!'<br />
......<br />
So, with the third oath you have to take: that, 'For us, our Mother is so powerful, why should we be afraid of anything‽ If She is going to give us the wisdom, why should we try to seek it anywhere else‽'<br />
......<br />
The another oath we have to take today: that, 'We'll respect every Sahaja Yogi from our heart, because they are made in the form of Śhrī Gaṇeśha. We'll not make fun of them. We'll not laugh at them.'<br />
As long as they are in Sahaja Yoga, we have to respect [them]. But they can be thrown away, they can get out of it.<br />
But unless and until this happens, do not put your ego on other people. Don't think that you understand everything. Don't think that you know everything.<br />
Respect each and every person. N... not to what he has read or for what he has learnt, but because he is a Great Soul."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0902 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Buffet Area, Hotel Riffelberg, Zermatt, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0316 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Marriages Ceremony, Tent, Back Garden, Āśhram, 1267 Burke Road, Kew, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So everybody should take an oath that, 'We will marry in any caste, creed, religion, country, nation.' There is no reason to outcast you as they are not your relatives and you have seen how they behave.<br />
......<br />
So on this auspicious day take an oath and decide that, 'I am a Sahaja Yogi and till death I will remain a Sahaja Yogi. After death also I will remain a Sahaja Yogi. We have earned this from infinity.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1230 Pūjā (English+Marathi), In Ten Years We Can Change the World and Purity Is the Main Point, Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, the ... celebration of Diwālī should be that we carry the light all over the world and enlighten people, as many as we can. None of our private things, no... none of our own problems are important. So the, that what it is: that we have to realize that we have got a certain position, which no one has in this world. So, once you understand, your own esteem goes up, and you see for yourself what you have to do!<br />
<font color="DarkRed">So then, everybody should, today, decide and take an oath, that, 'We'll do everything to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility.'</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You have to meditate. With that you go deeper and deeper.<br />
Today I want you to give Me a promise, a present to Me: that, you take oath that you will now take up jobs and you will meditate and become deeper Sahaja Yogis. And also, that you'll spread Sahaja Yoga.<br />
Everyone can get thousands Sahaja Yogis.<br />
Because you do not meditate, you do not have the depth to show that you are great peo... people."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0904 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Laziness, Hotel Sofitel Victoria, Warsaw, Poland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"So on this Day of Resurrection you have to take a vow that you will transform into a very high level and become very deep Sahaja Yogis."</font>
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"That is why, today on the Day of Resurrection take an oath in your mind that, 'We will become deep Sahaja Yogis of the highest order, Sahaja Yogis who have depth.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0414 Easter Pūjā (English+Hindi), You have to Crucify Your Ego, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Commitments" /><category term="crimson @ Oaths" /><category term="crimson @ Pledges" /><category term="crimson @ Promises" /><category term="crimson @ Vows" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>