<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/compilation.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-02-24T17:59:40-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/compilation.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Compilation</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Post 36: Culture</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0222" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 36: Culture" /><published>2023-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post36_CCT_Culture</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0222"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Without spirituality science has no culture. Does science know on what love feeds on? The meaning of love, or how a living thing works, science is not able to tell about it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Progress, Science and Spirituality, Sahasrāra Pūjā, from the book Sahaja Yoga, An Experiential Treatise (Sahaja Yoga Anubhavāche Bola) by Venu Narayan Phaḍake, Chapter 10, Page 130 (possible year 1998)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In the democratic country there is a wild race for creating new wants and new problems to make the machines work for twenty four [twenty-four] hours. The house hold [household] is filled with all junk showing the relics of the dead desires. <font color="DarkRed">To counterbalance we have movements of anti-culture who take to other desires of drugs[,] ect. [etc.]</font> In the communist countries the desires are controlled by force and regimentation but once these bounded people get to the so-called free countries they become wild like primitive people.[,] worse than the free people[.]"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Economics</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In guiding the creation of an atom into this complex universe and in planning the evolution of a single cell into this wonderful human being, there is a hidden hand of a very great Artist-artist because through his creation He expresses Himself, He sings, He dances, He paints, He acts and above all, He compels the spectators to reflect. Yes, He created this world because He wanted to reflect Himself, His Truths, His Beauty, His Grace, His Compassion, His Sweetness, His Righteousness, all that can be termed as culture."
......<br />
Artists have to raise the taste of public eye to their standards of taste and not to stoop down to the cheap demands of the public and thus surrendering their freedom. This can be done by contacting educational and social institutions by the enlightened artists. Through articles in magazines and newspapers, the idea[s] of such artists can be propagated. Through dramas, films and radio talks, people can be educated for the understanding of real art. Thus the dignity of art can be maintained.<br />
By coming in contact with the public at large through these societies, the social self of an artist will develop into a keener and a [more] sensitive being. It will react to the slightest unrest in the nation, to the slightest imbalance in the society. If he sees a leper on the street, his heart will pour out with such sympathy through his art that he can create an atmosphere by which social workers, doctors, scientists and the people in charge of the state will be forced to think of some solution to the problems of leprosy. If an artist finds his countrymen being unpatriotic or cowardly, he can through his art inspire them and can serve the role of a brave soldier. Thus he can serve the society through other by creating a deep impact on their minds. Such is the motivating power of an artist. They are the loveliest flowers of the creation, the sweetest dreams of the Creator and the dearest parts of the human society. Perhaps, they do not know how they are loved, worshiped and followed by their spectators.
This is my humble concept of art, culture and artist. In my honest efforts, I have tried to suggest certain ways and means by which artists can get united and give a lead to further the cause of art.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1961-1000 Article 'Art Culture and Artist' published in the souvenir 'Dignity of Art' brought out to commemorate the Inauguration of the 'Youth Society For Films' by the Union Home Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri on 1961-1008, the function presided over by the Chief Minister of Maharashtra Y. B. Chevam, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"12. To improve the esthetics of behavior and beauty by holding exhibitions of art, culture and music and through all activities which speak the universal language of love and beauty by developing the inner sense known as "Atīndriya", that enlightens the subtle sensitivities."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1972-0308 Annexure I of The Life Eternal Trust Deed, Charity Commissioner, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"As if don't know what is this thing which came from God, which is to be given to this world ... And the Truth is that, 'It is!' No doubt about it.<br />
But even after knowing this Truth, I won't call it their fault but the reason for their shortcoming is that they did not get birth in Yoga Bhūmi [Land of Yoga] of India. Don't know why God gave birth to such great people on that bhoga bhūmi [land of materialism] and you people have got birth on this Yoga Bhūmi. <font color="DarkRed">That bhoga bhūmi where they have no culture.</font> They don't even know if they have to wear sindūr [kumkum] on the forehead or on the nose. They don't know the protocols of Pūjā, they don't know the protocol of praying, they have no knowledge about God. They don't know even how to sit on the ground. They don't know anything, they don't even know how to give claps while performing the Āratī.<br />
And such great Souls, so innate they are, so loving.<br />
They love Me so much, such respect they have towards Me that I am surprised. Whenever they walk in front of Me, in fact they don't, but whenever they pass they bow and pass with their head bent down. They love Me so much that anything in this whole world has no meaning for them in front of Me. They have such deep feeling for Me that they don't know how should they respect Me, in what way. I am surprised that how they have so much understanding of all this about Me."<br />
......<br />
Your baiṭhak [sitting capacity] should be perfect. It should be strong.<br />
I can't even tell them about baiṭhak. They don't even know this word. English language is useless. They don't have any culture of that sort, no talks like this. So unfortunate they are.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1221 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Apanī aur Dṛuṣhṭi Rakhe (Keep the Attention on Yourself), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, you are seeing that in this world there are people chanting 'Hare Rāma, hare Kṛiṣhṇa'. In London, so many of their disciples come to Me and they have cancer here.<br />
This is a fact that I am sharing with you. I am your Mother and I have to tell you what is false.<br />
They have cancer here.<br />
You will be surprised that in this throat resides Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. When anyone faces a problem in the throat or in the cervical plexus then the name of Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa has to be taken in the science of Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
Now look at their Kuṇḍalinīs which are not awakened and Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is sitting angrily at this point. He has disappeared from there. What is the reason? <font color="DarkRed">We think, 'Oh, they are spreading our culture!,' though they don't spread any culture. I have seen their ponytails falling off, their dhotīs [lower garment worn traditionally in India] falling off and it looks so ugly.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now to say of Indian culture and Hindu culture and Muslim culture and other cultures, it is most surprising that Kuṇḍalinī, or we can say the Primordial Kuṇḍalinī of the Virāṭa, has got all these Great Incarnations -- whether they were Muslims, whether they were Christians, whether they were Indians -- seated on the chakras."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"What a great thing of Sahaja Yoga! I have talked about it a day before yesterday, that the power of Sahaja Yoga is tremendous.<br />
Once you receive this Power of God Almighty, then you enter into new Kingdom, and God is the King of that Kingdom Himself.<br />
You don't have to say this later that, 'Don't speak in Marathi, don't speak in Hindi, don't speak in ten languages.' You only speak one language, have one Kingdom. Unify the whole country!<br />
There should be only one United Nations.<br />
It happens that way because you all are one, that you have only taken in a way that, 'We are different,' or you think, 'It's given by this form by God.'<br />
We are different, you are different, and you are all one from inside. That is, it has the power to connect, it is inside to connect.<br />
Even the word connected is not right. You are one from inside.<br />
You are the only one in infinity, means the Power to show that you all are one is awakened. It means Sahaja Yoga is unified and bringing everyone together. This means it integrates everyone, it brings integration to each other.<br />
Everyone seems to be doing well. 'It's good in this culture,' 'It's good in that culture.' 
Someone is better in that, and the other one is better in another.'"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0531 Public Program (Marathi), Sahajyog Sgalyāṃnā Samagra Karto (Sahaja Yoga Makes Everyone Holistic), Matunga, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I am not in opposition for English language, but the language of Ātmā is Sanskrit.<br />
They have never bothered about the Spirit.<br />
You see, so we have to use some common language with [which] speaks about Ātmā. English language is not sufficient enough, I must tell you.<br />
They do not have those experiences because this is so far they have not gone deep into it, and we are very old people, ancient people. <font color="DarkRed">Our culture has been to know God, and everything has come in Sanskrit because Sanskrit is really a Devavāṇi [language of the Gods].</font><br />
Apart from that, when the Kuṇḍalinī moves, She makes sounds, She makes different sounds, which we -- they are really Devanāgarī sounds, all of them are, on all different chakras they are. If I have time I might tell you all those sounds that It makes.<br />
So our Sanskrit is really a Devavāṇi, and even when you say mantras, then, through the Sanskrit language or Devanāgarī pronunciations only, you can excite them better."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi+English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0223 Public Program, Day 2, The Normal Human Consciousness and Beyond Human Awareness, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 35: Alternative</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0215" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 35: Alternative" /><published>2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post35_Alternative</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0215"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"We aim to hold a conference where representatives from different religions around the world will come together to discuss how organized religions are lacking. The aim is to take the concept of a universal, 'pure' religion and to offer as an alternative a 'Universal Religion of the Spirit'."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Two Quotes from an article by Catherine Kelly (a writer and broadcaster who lives in London) Reproduced in a 2001-1200 article 'Age of the Truth' by Audrey Hopes in a Local Newspaper from Los Angeles Area</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
"You must say the mantras during Pūjā, but with complete śhraddhā. <font color="DarkRed">There is no alternative to śhraddhā.</font> When your śhraddhā is exquisite [profound], then only you should sit for a Pūjā. That way the Pūjā is done by heart. That time waves after waves of joy start flowing because when Ātmā Tattwa is the focal point there can not be any thoughts. The way people fill wine in a glass, same is with you performing Pūjā, your śhraddhā is the wine and the glass is nothing but the recitation of mantras and sādhana. While drinking this wine you are completely engrossed, with no thoughts, and you swim in this joy. How to express that joy in thoughts [words]? The wine which is inside the stomach, who is going to pour it back into a glass? And that too in an inferior glass made of thoughts. Joy after drinking this wine is eternal. It is your wealth. Many Pūjās like this have happened in front of Me and every time a big wave comes and takes you to a new shore. Those experiences from different shores become your own. They give grandness to your personality and open new doors of joy.<br />
It is best to do a Pūjā in the heart. If you can look at the Photo and then bring it into your heart, or after a Pūjā if you can bring that scene into your heart, then the joy of that moment can become permanent and will last for a long time. Read this letter to all Sahaja Yogis and send them copies of this letter."<br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
"You should say the Mantras in Pūjā but with great faith (śhraddhā). <font color="DarkRed">There is no alternative to śhraddhā.</font> You should perform the Pūjā when śhraddhā grows deep, so that heart itself gets all Pūjā performed. At that time waves of bliss start flowing because it is the Spirit that is saying, how can any thought come at that time? People pour their wine in the glass. Your Pūjā is like that. In that, wine is your faith and the glass is the recitation of Mantras and the worshiping. When you are drinking that wine forgetting everything, how can a thought come! Then only bathing in the Ocean of Bliss! How can that joy be expressed in thoughts? Who will pour that wine, back in the glass, which is to be drunk and that too in the inferior glass of thoughts? However, the joy that you get after drinking the wine is eternal and ever-present. It becomes your asset. Many such Pūjās have been performed in My presence. Every time a big wave comes and take you to a new land. Experiences of many such lands become your own. They give vastness to personality and open new gates of joy.<br />
Best is worshiping in the heart. If, the Photo by looking at it, can be placed in heart or, after the Pūjā, its view goes to heart, then the joy which you get only at that time, can become everlasting and ever-present. Show this letter, to all Sahaja Yogis and send its copies."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1012 Letter to Nirmalā (sister of Rājabhāī Modi) (Marathi), On Pūjā, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br /><br />
"Now instead of thinking and planning, if they realize the planning of the Almighty, then they don't have to take that headache upon themselves. First understand God. Meaning, His All-pervading Power is doing all the planning by Itself. If you abide by that planning then all your tasks will work out beautifully. <font color="DarkRed">If instead you take it upon yourself, then you will always encounter some hindrances and obstacles.</font> You can see for yourself the state of our country due to the existing planning. "
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br /><br />
"Now instead of thinking and planning themselves, if they understand the planning of the Almighty, then they don't have to take that trouble upon themselves. First understand God. Meaning, His All-pervading Power is doing all the planning by Itself. If you abide by that planning, then all your tasks will work out properly and beautifully. <font color="DarkRed">If instead you take it upon yourself, then you will plan, evaluate alternatives and work out the solutions where there will always be obstacles.</font>"
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"There is no alternative to this. It is a very subtle. Only one or two strands of the Kuṇḍalinī rise from inside of it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0318 Public Program (Hindi), Day 9, Sahasrāra Chakra, Śhāmiyānā, Garden, Pataudi House, 10 Ashoka Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then there can be only two possibilities. Either you recognize the Self-realization within you, and rise up to its greatness and go deep in it, or leave it altogether. There cannot be a third alternative.<br />
As someone asked, "How many turns are there in London?" "Only two: left and right." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0818 Public Program (Hindi), Ātmā and Paramātma, Saradār Patel Vidyalaya (School), Lodi Estate, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"There were some people who came to Me whom I called druggist or chemist. Means they used to be in state of coma. Such high consumption of drugs. But they got out of drugs from next day itself. Liquor, cigarette everything. Ninety-nine percent [99%].<br />
But one percent [1%] may still be stuck. Some are stubborn, but they should strive hard, and they do strive else one gets catches. Then you realize that there is a catch on the left Viśhuddhi, this and that. Then it pains. There is no alternative except removing the catch."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1209 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Day 1, Sane Gurujī Vidyālaya (English Medium) School, Bhikoba Waman Pathare Mārg, Near Dadar Catering College, Shivaji Park, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">How there are ... there is no alternative for Sahaj Yog, no alternative, one must know. Everything that is living has no alternatives.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed">For example, if a mango tree says that, 'I will create a pomegranate,' it cannot. There is no alternative.</font><br />
Whatever is there it has to see and enjoy. But not to force its way on [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
......<br />
Look at the little ones: how they came forward to give Me flowers, every step, every movement was so joyous, was creating such a beautiful delicate ripple in My heart. And it's written as history for Me to see these little, little sweet, innocent Gaṇeśhas coming forward.<br />
That in wisdom becomes so [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] that you know the Source of Love as Gaṇeśha [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. <font color="DarkRed">For He did not know anything else but one that which is the Source of Love. Never questioned. Never argued, no alternative. No new ideas came into head, He's just steadying in.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Wisdom, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now if you say: 'Which is the way a flower has to become a fruit?' There's only one way! [Laughing:] There have no two ways. <font color="DarkRed">Living things do not have two ways and five alternatives.</font> These are all for human beings to take lots of decisions and [laughs] do all these things. But for any living thing, it's only one way it works out.<br />
And that's how it is the germination within you, which is a living force of the Living God, is the only way: is the Kuṇḍalinī awakening. <font color="DarkRed">And that's why we can say, Sahaja is the only way! It is! There's no other way out!</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0331 Talkback Live Interview with a Gentleman for the 'Forum' Program of 'Macquarie Sports Radio' Station (call sign 2UE), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So-o, to become closer to God, you have to be closer to God. That's as simple as that.<br />
I mean somebody would say: `How do I know that I know that ... what ... how to drive a car?' When you know. `How do I know I [laughing:] can drive a bike?' Say, for example somebody says, `How can I use a bike?' I mean when you are that you are that! I mean is there any other way out? `How will I say I've got eyes?' When you can see! Finished! I mean it's so simple as that.<br />
So, how can you say you are nearer to God? You yourself will know you are nearer to God. Because the joy of being that tells you.<br />
You need not be close to Me, you need not be touching My Feet, you could be anywhere in the forest, you could be very close to Me, and those who thing [] they are close to Me because they can make a little face and, you know, behave in a very artificial way or some dramatic styles, you see, they are very far away.<br />
And those who cannot understand the commands of the brain are useless things!<br />
Now supposing one nail starts growing big, all right, and piercing inside the skin, we'll take it out, isn't it? There's not listening to the brain!<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> We'll have to throw it out!<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Any malignant growth is that growth which goes beyond the control of the brain, of the central nervous system. If the parasympathetic cannot control a growth of a particular cell, that is a malignant cell!<br />
So, if you become malignant in Sahaja Yoga, you may think you are a very great person or very some thing. You may think, you will be thrown out. Because you are a disease! You are a diseased person. You'll be thrown out.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">So to be reluh ... relevant, is to be relevant! There's no alternative for that.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed">Paryāy (alternative)</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Paryāy (alternative)</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> No compromise in it.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">No compromise.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0206 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Action and Desire, Research Station, Niphad, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Like Blake has said, that, "Men of God will become Prophets, and the ... these Prophets will have powers to make others Prophets."<br />
He said it so clearly for you English people, but I don't think you people like Him very much. [Laughing:] Because ... because the way peo... few people I have seen, who really appreciate Blake. And some of them have said that, ``He is mad!" Naturally, among all the mad people, a sane person may look mad also. But He is the one who has so clearly said.<br />
And in this country, this great man should be born, and should talk about Jerusalem, is remarkable!<br />
Because you cannot think, in England, where people just believe in dominating other countries and using the ... their power to dominate others, you could get Jerusalem established!<br />
But what He said was of these days, when those false ideas have dropped off, when people do not think of domination, they do not think of materialism, they are fed up with all these things, and they are seeking today.<br /> 
And who are these seekers? These seekers are the men of God.<br />
So, recognize yourself. First of all, you must recognize your Self before recognizing anybody else, that you are seekers and that you are men of God.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Unless and until you have found God, you are not going to be happy by all these nonsensical ... uh-uh-uh ... alternatives people are giving.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0515 Public Program, Day 3, The Creative Power, Central Channel, Brighton Pavillion, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I mean, you may, in your myth, you see, hallucination, think it is different, and fight.<br />
It's, I ... I sometimes feel you are just fighting your shadows! This is the, you have created shadows, and the shadows are fighting. And just to make the shadows fight, you fight, otherwise shadows won't fight. [Some laughter.] It's all a shadow! There's no truth in it!<br />
To Me, it looks like that. It's all madness. What is there to fight?<br />
This is One World. Everybody is blessed by God. They all should enjoy His blessings: to enter into the Kingdom of God. He is the King. He is the One who is the Ruler.<br />
In His Kingdom, there is nothing like a state.<br />
So, that's a very different world you are entering into.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">There are no alternatives there! It's only one Absolute State of Mind, where you become the Spirit. That's all.</font><br />
......<br />
Foods also, natural food you must eat, more natural food, than artificial. All that will give you a better living.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And that is called as alternative, all right. That's alternative is important.</font><br />
But that doesn't mean you go on a bullock cart.<br />
You can export your trains to India, or your cars to India and get khādī from there. All right?<br />
Mu... mutual understanding. Because we are part and parcel of one Whole.<br />
And we just cannot exist by our only growth because then we become malignant, you see. One cells eats another. They ... you have to!<br />
If you have a machinery, you have to eat other! Because you produce so much, you must find markets for them, you must supply them, you must send over. Then you must have other countries to exploit them!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0607 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Ego and Humility or You Must Improve Yourself, Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0614 Public Program, You Are All Bound by One Thread (We All Are Expecting Something Great to Happen), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="gold @ Alternative" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 34: Aims, Destinations, Goals, and Purposes</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0208" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 34: Aims, Destinations, Goals, and Purposes" /><published>2023-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post34_CCT_Aims_Destinations_Goals_Purposes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0208"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You can attain any destination that you fix. All your autosuggestions will materialize.</font> The remedy that is to be used is: your attention should be on Me and you should make the following conditioning of thoughts on your Āgñyā "How fortunate we are to have been realized! We are Sahaja Yogis. God has chosen us. How can we work if we remain weak? Ādi Śhakti has given us the power to redeem the whole mankind. We can do it and we will do it." On heart you should criticize with these thoughts "How deep is God's love for us! He has given us the Realization. He is the Ocean of Mercy. Ignoring all our mistakes, He is working hard day and night for our welfare and, instead of praying for His forgiveness of our mistakes, we are making complaints against Him and blaming Him!" The following thoughts will please your hearts, "O God, please give us the Power of Your Love. May I be the drop in the Ocean of Your Love that is enveloping the whole universe, so that its loving pulsation is vibrated through My life and I remain engrossed in that bliss." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-0000 Letter (Marathi) from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 14 (March-April 1983), Page 11, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To emerge out victoriously of these two dangerous jaws of destruction is only possible if the leaders of the nations get self realization through sahaja yoga and are enlightened by Self Knowledge and the Knowledge of the collective. (This would manifest on their central nervous system). <font color="DarkRed">Thus appearing on the stage of reality as Lotuses of Divinity spreading the fragrance of human ascent into its glorious destination. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Democracy, Communism, and Religion related to the book Ascent</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"It is thus that the human beings constitute the best reflectors of the Creator. <font color="DarkRed">Some of them as sages, like Lord Buddha, Jesus Christ, Lord Mahavir, mark the destination of human progress, others as scientist discover the mighty forces of creation which are being constantly harnessed in the service of man.</font> Similarly, some others gifted with extraordinary faculties of perception and understanding play the role of "Artists". They have not only an extra-ordinary "eye" but also an ability to communicate with others through the medium of art. They have an extremely sensitive heart and an equally eloquent medium by which they can touch the hearts of their fellowmen. This factor assumes a social importance and thus an artist plays a vital role, as member of a society."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1961-1000 Article 'Art Culture and Artist' published in the souvenir 'Dignity of Art' brought out to commemorate the Inauguration of the 'Youth Society For Films' by the Union Home Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri on 1961-1008, the function presided over by the Chief Minister of Maharashtra Y. B. Chevam, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Mister Phaḍake, chakras and their colors don't mean everything. You have to go further ahead than that. These colors mean only a particle of the sea or sand. We have to reach to the complete sand as a whole.</font> These colors are like the scenes we pass while traveling by train. We don't remember the scenes and get involved in them. We just have a destination to reach. We forget all that we pass on the way, in between. In the same way attention should not go to the colors you pass on the way to Sahasrāra. How the thoughtless awareness comes. How it should be established for long time. This should be observed. Only looking at the colors will reduce the attention at Sahasrāra and it will be spoiled." [<b> Variant:</b> "<font color="DarkRed">Aho Phaḍake, colors of the chakras is not everything. You still have a long way to go. These colors are only like a drop of water in the ocean. We have to cross all these.</font> When we are traveling in a train, several scenes cross before our eyes, do we remember all of them? Our attention is on our destination. We forget what happens in between. Similarly, do not bother about the colors. Your attention should be on the Sahasrār. How will thoughtlessness come? How can we make it stay for a long time? Your attention should be on these things. If you keep seeing colors, you will only end up doing trāṭak on the Āgñyā chakra and it will get spoilt."]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0000 Quote (Marathi), on Seeing Colors, Part 1, Public Program, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But today you are those chosen flowers, chosen over the ages, to blossom so that today your vibrations and your fragrance should spread across the world, cleanse its sludge and eliminate the filth of this Ocean of Illusion.<br />
When looking at it, one may wonder, 'How it is possible, Mātājī is making a big statement?' <font color="DarkRed">But this is a continuation (silasilā) and, when the Destination has arrived in front you, then thinking, 'Why it has arrived? How has it come? How can this happen? When you were walking, did the destination not arrive? When you were seeking, will you not get your place?'!</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">The Destination has arrived. You all have reached courtyard. How easy and sahaja is all this.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0120 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi+Marathi), Day 1, Session 1 (morning), Tīn Śhaktiyān (Three Powers), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As Christ had said, "I am the Light, I am the Path," same is My statement, "I am the Destination, not only the Path."<br />
I did not say this to you because I had very bad experiences. This is the only reason. You people have to come to My refuge (śharaṇāgat). You have to accept Me as Mother and live like My sons. Without that your work will not be done.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0329 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Vigyān Manuṣhya kī Rachanā Nahīṃ Khoja Hai (Science Is Human's Discovery, Not Creation), Sweet Home, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Have I to say like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, "Leave all religions and surrender to Me" or as Śhrī Jesus, "I am the way, I am the door."<br />
I want to tell that I am that Man̄jil (Destination). But will you people accept it? Will this fact go to your hearts?"</font><br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Will I have to say like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa said, "Give up all other duties and surrender only to me," or like Jesus Christ said, "I am the path and I am the entrance."<br />
What I want to tell you is that, 'I am your final aim.' But will you all accept this? Will this message of mine enter your hearts?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1021 Letter to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Diwālī from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 13 (January-February 1983), Page 22, 2, Parklands, Ice House Wood, Hurst Green, Oxted, Surrey, UK}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0619 Public Program, The Difference Between East and West, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Aims" /><category term="crimson @ Destinations" /><category term="crimson @ Goals" /><category term="crimson @ Purposes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 33: Commitments, Oaths, Pledges, Promises, and Vows</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0201" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 33: Commitments, Oaths, Pledges, Promises, and Vows" /><published>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post33_CCT_Commitments_Oaths_Pledges_Promises_Vows</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0201"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"A couple of days ago, I asked people to promise that they would no longer consume alcohol, and half of them got up and left. Just a promise -- it was not like I asked them to make any payments!"</font><br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"A couple of days ago, I asked people to promise that they would no longer consume alcohol, and half of them got up and left. I then said that, "Just take the oath," I did not say that you will have to pay for that. But the moment I said this, half the people got up and left."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, at this place in Bordi, you all take an oath in your mind that, 'This is our aim that each person will save at least thousand more people.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0325 Pūjā (Hindi+English), Chit ke Gaharai (Depth of Your Attention), Seminar, Day 2, Camp, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now we have got, astrologically there are three and a half auspicious days where you don't have to consultant any uh ... any books of astrology, which are called as Pañchāṅg, to find out whether it is an auspicious time or not. For any Pūjā, for any [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] good work you have to do, people consultant, in India, the Pañchāṅg, is the book to find out which date is auspicious [and] which is not.<br />
One of them is today. Is a day you can do anything good, you decide anything good. <font color="DarkRed">Today is the day to take an oath, to think of something great, to visualize something big, to ask a boon, to do a big Pūjā, is one of the greatest uh day.</font> One of the, we call them muhūrtas, which where you do not consultant these books.<br />
And that's why rājyābhiṣhek of, I mean the crowning ceremony of Śhrī Rāma took place on this day."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, in the Presence of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, you have to take an oath, that, 'Whatever is the past of my country, I will get opposite to that!'<br />
......<br />
So, the second oath we have to take before Śhrī Gaṇeśha is: that, 'I will be honest to myself. I will not deceive myself, for anybody's sake!'<br />
......<br />
So, with the third oath you have to take: that, 'For us, our Mother is so powerful, why should we be afraid of anything‽ If She is going to give us the wisdom, why should we try to seek it anywhere else‽'<br />
......<br />
The another oath we have to take today: that, 'We'll respect every Sahaja Yogi from our heart, because they are made in the form of Śhrī Gaṇeśha. We'll not make fun of them. We'll not laugh at them.'<br />
As long as they are in Sahaja Yoga, we have to respect [them]. But they can be thrown away, they can get out of it.<br />
But unless and until this happens, do not put your ego on other people. Don't think that you understand everything. Don't think that you know everything.<br />
Respect each and every person. N... not to what he has read or for what he has learnt, but because he is a Great Soul."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0902 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Buffet Area, Hotel Riffelberg, Zermatt, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0316 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Marriages Ceremony, Tent, Back Garden, Āśhram, 1267 Burke Road, Kew, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So everybody should take an oath that, 'We will marry in any caste, creed, religion, country, nation.' There is no reason to outcast you as they are not your relatives and you have seen how they behave.<br />
......<br />
So on this auspicious day take an oath and decide that, 'I am a Sahaja Yogi and till death I will remain a Sahaja Yogi. After death also I will remain a Sahaja Yogi. We have earned this from infinity.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1230 Pūjā (English+Marathi), In Ten Years We Can Change the World and Purity Is the Main Point, Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, the ... celebration of Diwālī should be that we carry the light all over the world and enlighten people, as many as we can. None of our private things, no... none of our own problems are important. So the, that what it is: that we have to realize that we have got a certain position, which no one has in this world. So, once you understand, your own esteem goes up, and you see for yourself what you have to do!<br />
<font color="DarkRed">So then, everybody should, today, decide and take an oath, that, 'We'll do everything to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility.'</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You have to meditate. With that you go deeper and deeper.<br />
Today I want you to give Me a promise, a present to Me: that, you take oath that you will now take up jobs and you will meditate and become deeper Sahaja Yogis. And also, that you'll spread Sahaja Yoga.<br />
Everyone can get thousands Sahaja Yogis.<br />
Because you do not meditate, you do not have the depth to show that you are great peo... people."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0904 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Laziness, Hotel Sofitel Victoria, Warsaw, Poland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"So on this Day of Resurrection you have to take a vow that you will transform into a very high level and become very deep Sahaja Yogis."</font>
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"That is why, today on the Day of Resurrection take an oath in your mind that, 'We will become deep Sahaja Yogis of the highest order, Sahaja Yogis who have depth.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0414 Easter Pūjā (English+Hindi), You have to Crucify Your Ego, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Commitments" /><category term="crimson @ Oaths" /><category term="crimson @ Pledges" /><category term="crimson @ Promises" /><category term="crimson @ Vows" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 32: Vision</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0125" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 32: Vision" /><published>2023-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post32_CCT_Vision</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0125"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This is the era of Enlightenment. One can see and feel the bubbling of new idioms in our creative world of art, music and all that is beautiful and joy-giving. Integration is the key note of this new regeneration of universal tones. These tones are ripples of the harmonic, dynamic undercurrent music of the Universal Divine Love.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Is there a possibility of this love expressed in the unity of human beings with God Almighty giving a new vision to the apparent diversities?</font><br />
Is it possible that this unique happening is accessible to many, that they may see their own creative world revolving in the great universe of All-pervading Power?<br />
My only answer is, 'Yes.'<br />
My only question is, 'Why not?' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from The Life Eternal, 1980 Issue, Pages 46, 48 and 50, from a 1984 Pamphlet, Brighton, East Sussex, UK, and from the Back Cover of The Advent (2002 edition)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The music, and the art, the creativity, is all within us. We all have the ability within us, but we need to establish the technique. With poetry, drawing or music, we must have the technique or we cannot express it properly. The creativity is there, but it cannot be expressed properly without the knowledge of the technique. <font color="DarkRed">It is such a great gift to be able to paint or sculpt and create works of art that please the Spirit and bring joy to all who see them; to be able to express the joy of life and the vision of our ascent through poetry.</font> Such gifts we have been given. Let us use them to their fullest potential. Like our bodies, as temples for the Spirit, are looked after and decorated with beautiful things, our lives are enriched by the beauty of the arts and music. If we have the ability and the knowledge within us, then let's learn how to share it with the world. If the words are there but we cannot speak and share them, what is the point of it? We can learn how to express and share these gifts we have been given."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Two Quotes on Music and Art from the book Divine Knowledge through Vibrations (1992) by P.T. Rajasekharan and R. Venkatesan, Pages 148 and 149</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"An institution for children of Sahaja Yogi families around the world, to provide for the protection of their innocence, for the development of their personality and for their academic advancement in a pure, ethical and spiritual environment, so that they grow up to be responsible members of the community striving for the vision of an enlightened, worldwide human family, owing allegiance to One Almighty God and living together in peace and harmony."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Dharmaśhālā School, Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"... have pure motherly love for every human, every animal, for nature and the whole Mother Earth. Develop inner balance and peace ... be collective, tolerant ... and respectful to everyone."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote related to the Vision for the Vishwa Nirmala Prem Āśhram in Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India from Blossom Time, Volume 2, Issue 5 (September-October 2008), Page 7</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"No one has experienced something like this before. And nowhere in the world has this experiment been successful anywhere before this because I too have come on this Earth many times before. I have thought of doing this many times before and this is the first time in this lifetime that this work has been successful.<br />
That is why whatever unfinished that is left you have to complete it. You have not come to belittle or pull down anyone. Whatever incompleteness has been left, you have to complete it. <font color="DarkRed">Just think that you are new persons in this modern world with an expanded vision, and you have to guide the whole world.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In everything, in your behavior, your talk, the way you talk, in your touch, your laughter, and your tears. In everything there should be such a vision of your heart. It is massive. This massiveness should show from within you. There should be a Vision of the Skies within you. The Purity of Water should reflect from within you. The Brilliance of the Sun should show from your face, the Coolness of the Moon should flow from within you. Flowing everywhere, you should be like the Wind.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0903 Pūjā (Hindi), Ātma-sākṣhātkār ka Arth (Meaning of Self-realization), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Peace and thoughtless awareness will be established in you: you are in antar maun [inner silence] but aware of all outside things. <font color="DarkRed">Your vision will have a State of Witness.</font> Your intelligence will become dynamic, it becomes unique. Such go up your measurement that you yourself become knowledge."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1219 Public Program (Hindi), Nagpur, Maharashtra, India (other date 1222)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"One should remain in Thoughtlessness. This is your place, your wealth, your strength (śhakti). This is your form. This is your beauty. This is your life. Thoughtless! As soon as you are thoughtless the outside methods, the whole of it starts moving in your hands. Live in thoughtlessness. Over there, there is no Time, no Direction, nor can anyone touch it. <font color="DarkRed">There is only a vision of the Living. There is only a vision of Life and how it blooms. There is vision of its Beauty, its Capability, its Prosperity and its Truth. Watch it from where the stream of life is flowing.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0125 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Har Śhwās Me Sahaja Yoga Ko Prasthāpit Karanā Hogā (Sahaja Yoga Must Be Established in Every Breath or Must Listen Every Day and Imbibe Sahaja Yoga), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So when you become all right, the world will also turn all right.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Everything is in [a] mess because you are not all right. You are not all right, meaning your vision is not all right.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0">1977-1218 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Chitta and Ātmā (Satyacha Prakāśh and Ātmā Itself in Form), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India<b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0220 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, What Is the Surrender (Surrender, Will, Spirit, Attention, Mind), Āśhram, 234A Regent's Park Road, Finchley, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Vision" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 31: Triśhaṅku</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0118" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 31: Triśhaṅku" /><published>2023-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/Compilation_Post31_CCT_Tri%C5%9Bha%E1%B9%85ku</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2023/0118"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Gentleman:</b> I mean will ... is Australia blessed?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Very much!<br />
<b>Gentleman:</b> With the upcoming wars and things?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Very much blessed. It's a very much blessed place, specially created. Australia was the first continent to be created.<br />
And the I, if I dare to answer this question, I hope you'll believe Me and not get into ego trips.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Australia is a place which is described in the ancient Purāṇas. That a great Saint was sent to Australia, and ther[e] another heaven was created. And that Saint is called as Triśhaṅku which is your South... uh what you call that? Is the ...</font><br />
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves:</b> Southern Cross.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">... Southern Cross.<br />
That shows the Southern Cross and you can only see Southern Cross from Australia.<br />
This is one of the Purāṇas, or the Vedas also have mentioned this.</font><br />
And, even before that, Australia is the place which has the Gaṇeśha. The first is the Mūlādhāra chakra, the first center is in Australia. How much wise you should be!<br />
Did you hear Me?<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0329 Workshop, Session 1 (morning), Garden, House of a Sahaja Yogi, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I went to Australia, and I was amazed the way miracles took place in that country.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">It is said that, in the Purāṇa, there was a Saint called Triśhaṅku, who committed some mistake, little mistake, and he was sent as the Southern Cross, hanging in the air, and was told that, "You must create your own heaven!" And really Australia is Heaven, no doubt, but it's Mūlādhāra! It is Mūlādhāra.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0504 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Dr. Warren Reeves</b> [summarizes a lady:] We live in a country here, which was inhabited by the aboriginal people, who, she says, understood these things. Uh do You have any knowledge or feelings about these people?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Very much!<br />
The names are like Paramātā. Paramātā means the Primordial Mother.<br />
Is so many words are ... your ... uh this ... uh the Rock of Ayers is nothing but Gaṇeśha Himself! You see, this is the land of Mūlādhāra chakra.<br />
You don't know what a land you are living in!<br />
Whatever you may try, you cannot lose your innocence in this country. Is a country of innocence. You'll keep it a bit of it, because is a country of innocence! You'll see all that!<br />
<b>Lady:</b> We ... [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] ...<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Is a very great country!<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Is described in the Purāṇas, in the ancient times, that there was one Great Saint, whom committed some mistake, and he was thrown out in the sky, and God said, "All right, now I'll allow you to go away from here, but I give you a boon again, because you are a great man, that you'll create your own heavens here," and that's the seventh cross." It's called Triśhaṅku in Sanskrit language.</font><br />
So you are great people, you don't know you are born on a very great soil.<br />
This is the Mūlādhāra itself, the first chakra, where Śhrī Gaṇeśha, the innocence, resides.<br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0301 Workshop, Āśhram, Crawley (7 kms SW of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> But uh marrying them in India is better. Is easier.<br />
Uh we had it in uh, what you call this place?<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Here.<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> Bordi.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Switzerland.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Switzerland. Is very difficult, it was. We managed! We did it! Very difficult. And you don't get such nice presents. [Laughter, some applause.]<br />
[As some laughter continues:] In India you got lot of nice things.<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yoginī</b> [laughing]: Yes.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> For a little amount that you pay, we can maneuver something very good.<br />
You'll be happy to know that Indians also paid lot of money, substantiated in. Of course, you people also paid some money, there. And, actually, if you see that the people who paid, all together, we calculated that. for every couple, even the people who attended the weddings, paid uh-uh-uh two dollar[s] each. [Laughs.]<br />
[Laughing:] [In the West] you cannot buy any present for two dollar[s] each.<br />
But in a collective way it [1985-0208 Marriages Ceremony, Bordi] was so beautiful. And worked out so well. It was such a time, I tell you, unforgettable. As if you were in the Vṛindāvan, beautiful time. <font color="DarkRed">And you saw Southern Cross coming down, both the times, Southern Cross. From Australia it came through that side. I mean, Southern Cross you'll never see in India. But we saw Southern Cross, in India, at the time of marriage. It's a miracle of miracles. All the stars, all the nakṣhatras were there.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0602 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On Music and Marriages, after the Evening Program after Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Tent, Backyard, House of Judy Gaddy, 442 Liberty Road, Englewood, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> What is the color, of your flag?<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Uh-uh-uh it's, well, it's got a Union Jack in the corner, and then it's blue, and it has four, the four starts of the Southern Cross on it.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Oh, I see. So it's ...<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> So it's, it's almost, ...<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> ... little blue?<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> ... is it as dark as that? It almost is, isn't it?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Yes.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Is that, sort of color?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Blue.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Was that, but the Union Jack has four stars.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Union Jack is still hanging.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Yes, I'm afraid we still have the Union Jack in the corner. [Śhrī Mātājī smiles.] Australia has the same uh stars, ...<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Yes.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> ... but they have five. Their Southern Cross is five stars.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Hāṃ [yes].<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> And ours in New Zealand is ...<br />
[To the Sahaja Yoginī who brings an insigne:] Ha! Thank you!<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Receiving the insigne:] Uh-uh-uh, a Union Jack, nice. And this is four ... beautiful.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Yes.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> The same deep color you have [on the Pūjā sāṛī]. The red you have, also there. [Using Her sāṛī to clean the insigne:] Near, very much near the red. Mhh.<br />
So because of Commonwealth countries. We are not, no more, Commonwealth now, [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. We were. We are not, no more.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Still out.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> We are not, ...<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Yeah.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> ... anymore, Commonwealth.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Mhh. We used to be.<br />
<b>Bāḷāsāheb:</b> Nineteen forty-seven [1947].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Hindi/Marathi.]<br />
I don't know, are we not there?<br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> We still are, Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> We still, we are still, [Hindi/Marathi]?<br />
<b>Bāḷāsāheb:</b> Yes.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> We are Commonwealth country, still. But we are not uh dominion or ...<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Oh, no, that side.<br />
Not, it's no longer empire, it's a ... it's uh-uh-uh a collection of alliets [allies] and friendly states. It's not a ... there is no sense of domination of one another.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> No, no, no. So now, this means the alliance part. So we don't have alliance, we don't have alliance in picture.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Perhaps the, that's the flag of the heart, Mother, [as Śhrī Mātājī laughs:] which, which is on the corner of many flags in the world.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Yeah. [Laughing:] All of the Āgñyā. [Laughter.] I don't know. Six, six is the Swādhiṣhṭhāna.<br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> Āṭha hai [there are eight], Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Huh?<br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> They have eight.<br /><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Āṭha hai. [Hindi]: eka, do, tīna, chāra, pāṃcha, cheha, sāta, āṭha.<br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> Mhh.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Right.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> There ... [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Is correct. They have done the right thing because they are the heart! Unconsciously, they have done it, you see, but so beautifully is done.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Four uh, the four stars are the stars in You never ... I've never seen in the Northern Hemisphere. It's a ... it's a uh a cross on four starts ... on five stars but only can be seen in the Southern Hemisphere.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> But we saw it! We saw when they got married in Bordi.<br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Ha‽<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Yes! With the, all the starts were there, and they saw the Southern Cross also, ...</font><br />
<b>Brian Bell:</b> Mhh.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">... and all the Australians came and saw that and said, "This is the same."</font> [Some laughter.]<br />
This was two years back. Or, when did you have the Bordi marriages? Three years back?<br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> Yes.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Three years, yes.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Three years back.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Three and a half.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">And all the starts, there were twenty-eight marriages, twenty-seven marriages and twenty-seven Nakṣhatras, that's [Hindi]?</font><br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> Constellations.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Simultaneously:] Constellations were there.<br />
[Pointing to the insigne of Southern Cross:] <font color="DarkRed">One of them was this.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0516 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Foundations, 41 Valley Road, Mount Eden, Auckland, New Zealand</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It was said that a Saint called Triśhaṅkar committed some mistakes and as a punishment he was given some land in the Bay of Bengal and was told to take that land away. As part of the rectification of that curse, he was told to take that land and make a heaven out of it. I have really seen that heaven where I went. Triśhaṅkar is nothing but your Southern Cross and in Sanskrit your Southern Cross is known as the Triśhaṅkar. The parallel between this account in the Purāṇas and history is startling. Geology has shown that Australia and India were joined as part of the original land mass known as Godwana Land. Australia was started as a penal colony where people were sent as punishment from England."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0300 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Of course, in It... uh .. Australia is a very God-blessed place, no doubt about it. [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] <font color="DarkRed">is Gaṇeśha's place firstly, and described in our uh-uh-uh Śhāstras in India, that a, one Saint who fell from his heights, so [he] was cursed and uh, this, the, what you call this Southern Cross. And God made him into a Southern Cross and threw him.</font> [Gestures the throwing with the right hand.]<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">In a ... He said, "You'll be hanging round like that, upside down here." It's called as Triśhaṅku. "And you will ... some part of the land will go with you there, which will be your own [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]." Then he said, "Also You must give me some blessings," He said, "I will bless that land." Is all described in the Śhāstras that Triśhaṅku comes here and there ... there's a land and this and that.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0213 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Questions and Answers during Picnic, Black Mountain Peninsula, Canberra, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"About Australia, there's a myth in India, that there was a big Saint, and he was very good, but somehow he made some mistakes, or maybe lots of mistakes. So, God cursed him, and said, "You better go away from India." It was connecting India and Africa.<br />
So the land was brought down, to this point. He gave him the land, God, and He said: "Now you resurrect this land, nd make something out of it."<br />
And this star is called as ... this-ss Triśhaṅku, which is your Southern Cross. This Southern Cross is called as Triśhaṅku, as is men... mentioned in our Purāṇas as this-s Saint who became like that, and God made him into a-eh-eh ... star which is hanging, Triśhaṅku is hanging, on top of this land, and is working out the building up of this country.<br />
He was told that: "You go there, and make a Heaven for the human beings."<br />
This has so many mythological and historical backgrounds. </font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0403 Easter Pūjā, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="indigo @ Personalities" /><category term="indigo @ Trishanku" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 30: Gout</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0622" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 30: Gout" /><published>2022-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/Compilation_Post30_Gout</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0622"><![CDATA[<p>
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
Please find below the pdf file of quotes on <font color="blue">gout</font> obtained by searching for all possible root combinations such as "<font color="red">gout</font>". If by chance extra such quotes, please kindly share them with all of us.<br />
Please kindly share the file with all our brothers and sisters.<br />
We would like to thank the Sahaja Yoginī who suggested this topic.<br />
<br />
The Comprehensive Compilations Team
</p>

<p><a href="https://bit.ly/3bf9Tbr">Instantly download the pdf here</a></p>

<iframe src="/pdf/#/files/Gout.pdf" width="1000px" height="1000px"></iframe>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="peru @ Medical" /><category term="peru @ gout" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Śhrī Mātājī! Please find below the pdf file of quotes on gout obtained by searching for all possible root combinations such as "gout". If by chance extra such quotes, please kindly share them with all of us. Please kindly share the file with all our brothers and sisters. We would like to thank the Sahaja Yoginī who suggested this topic. The Comprehensive Compilations Team]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 29: American Presidents, Part 10f (Abraham Lincoln)</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0418" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 29: American Presidents, Part 10f (Abraham Lincoln)" /><published>2022-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/Compilation_Post29_American_Presidents_Part_10f_Abraham_Lincoln</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0418"><![CDATA[<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Please find below the pdf file of quotes on <font color="blue">American Presidents, Part 10f (Abraham Lincoln)</font> obtained by searching for all possible root combinations such as “<font color="red">Lincoln</font>” and “<font color="red">Abraham</font>”. If by chance extra such quotes, please kindly share them with all of us.<br /></p>

<p>Please kindly share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10f_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of this Part 10f here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10e_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10e here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10d_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10d here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10c_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10c here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10b_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10b here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10a_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10a here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="indigo @ Personalities" /><category term="indigo @ American Presidents" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Śhrī Mātājī!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 28: American Presidents, Part 10e (Abraham Lincoln)</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0403" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 28: American Presidents, Part 10e (Abraham Lincoln)" /><published>2022-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/Compilation_Post28_American_Presidents_Part_10e_Abraham_Lincoln</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0403"><![CDATA[<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Please find below the pdf file of quotes on <font color="blue">American Presidents, Part 10e (Abraham Lincoln)</font> obtained by searching for all possible root combinations such as “<font color="red">Lincoln</font>” and “<font color="red">Abraham</font>”. If by chance extra such quotes are found out before 1997, please kindly share them with all of us.<br /></p>

<p>Please kindly share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10e_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of this Part 10e here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10d_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10d here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10c_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10c here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10b_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10b here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10a_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10a here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="indigo @ Personalities" /><category term="indigo @ American Presidents" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Śhrī Mātājī!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post 27: American Presidents, Part 10d (Abraham Lincoln)</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0221" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post 27: American Presidents, Part 10d (Abraham Lincoln)" /><published>2022-02-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-02-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/Compilation_Post27_American_Presidents_Part_10d_Abraham_Lincoln</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/compilation/2022/0221"><![CDATA[<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Please find below the pdf file of quotes on <font color="blue">American Presidents, Part 10d (Abraham Lincoln)</font> obtained by searching for all possible root combinations such as “<font color="red">Lincoln</font>” and “<font color="red">Abraham</font>”. If by chance extra such quotes are found out before July 1991, please kindly share them with all of us.<br /></p>

<p>Please kindly share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10d_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of this Part 10d here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10c_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10c here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10b_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10b here</a></p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/American_Presidents_Part_10a_Abraham_Lincoln.pdf">Download pdf of the prior Part 10a here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="indigo @ Personalities" /><category term="indigo @ American Presidents" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jay Śhrī Mātājī!]]></summary></entry></feed>