<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-30T09:37:33-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti: “He also has said that, ’It is the Primordial Mother who has created the Universe.’ “</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti: “He also has said that, ’It is the Primordial Mother who has created the Universe.’ “" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/2024_11_15_Shri_Guru_Nanak_Birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/15"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the birthday of Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka.</b> It is being celebrated throughout the world with so much of zeal that I have not seen in India. For the first time it has been advertised in so many papers and by different means.<br />
Guru Nāṇaka always talked of Sahaja Yoga. ``Everything else," He said, ``is just showing off." About religion He said that, ``Observing fasts, going on pilgrimage, etc., are just meant to show off. Now you have to discover the power that is within you and establish it." Guru Nāṇaka kept on repeating the same thing again and again.<br />
......<br />
<b>But Guru Nāṇaka always talked of the Spirit.&lt;'b&gt; He explained it very clearly, but no one heeded what he wrote. They will just put a finger on the couplet and read it out. Could we understand him this way? If we go through his writings properly and absorb it, then the whole śhabda jālam [web of words], in which most of the people are caught, will come to an end. See the condition of Sikhs!<br />
Without looking within and experiencing the innate energy, how could one follow Sikh religion? Only this is the teaching of Guru Nāṇaka, this is what is called `Sikh' [learning]. All the Saints of that age had the discretion to know who is a Saint and who is not. All the gurus incorporated their poems and experiences in Guru Grantha and that is why Guru Grantha is revered so much. Only the renowned gurus contributed to it. They were so spiritual that they did churning of all the religious Scriptures and put the substance in Guru Grantha."&lt;/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1123 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
&lt;/p&gt;

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0105.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Guru Nāṇak was not a human being, He was not only a Paigambar [Prophet] but He was the Reincarnation of Ādi Guru, the Primordial Master, He was a Divine Personality.</b><br />
Of course, the people who were there at His time were so useless and gross people that they actually tortured His life and nobody followed Him. After His death is a different point.<br />
<b>He also has said that, "It is the Primordial Mother who has created the Universe.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0222 Public Program (English + Hindi) (Śhivarātri Day), Day 5, Lord Śhiva, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Ikoaŉkār saṯ nām karṯā purakẖ nirbẖao nirvair akāl mūraṯ ajūnī saibẖaŉ gur parsāḏ.</b></font><br />
There is One and only One God who is transcendent as well as immanent.<br />
True and Eternal Name. Creator and Person. Without Fear and without Enmity.<br /> 
Timeless Form, Unborn, Self-existent.<br />
Realized by Divine Grace.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka's Mool Mantra</b>
&lt;/p&gt;

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a special day of Guru Nāṇaka's birthday.</b><br />
Uh we have celebrated one Guru Pūjā uh-uh-uh ... and the, as you know that <b>Guru Nāṇak was also the Incarnation of the Primordial Master, the same Spirit came on this Earth. And the He's the One who tried to re-establish the work of Muhammad.</b><br />
Muhammad was the Incarnation of the same Spirit, the Primordial Master. He came on this Earth to establish the religion.<br />
Islam is the name of that religion, is the religion of every Sahaja Yogi, of every Christian, of every Hindu. <b>We all belong to One Religion which believes in expanding our ourne ... awareness to the new perception of collectivity: from human level to the higher level, where you can perceive and manifest the Divine Power. This is the religion we are following.<br />
All the religions were established on this Earth to create the seekers. You are the seekers: you are the Men of God. Now, all of you have to become Prophets. And to become Prophets, today's Sahaja Yoga has taken the form of Mahā Yoga. All of you have to become Prophets.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0106.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"When you go to any guru, first of all see the disciples, how they are: how they behave, what powers they have got. Then you accept. That's the sign of a Sadguru. 

Nāṇaka has said clearly. <b>Guru Nāṇak was such an enlightened Soul, and He said that: ``The one who meets [makes] you meet ... meet God is the Sadguru." Everybody is not a guru.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0317 Public Program, Day 2, Swādhiṣhṭhān, Thinking, Illness, Hilton Hotel, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Love the saints of every faith<br />
Put away thy pride.<br />
Remember the essence of religion<br />
Is meekness and sympathy.<br />
Not fine clothes,<br />
Not the Yogi's garb and ashes,<br />
Not the blowing of the horns,<br />
Not long prayers,<br />
Not recitations and torturous,<br />
Not the ascetic way,<br />
But a life of goodness and purity,<br />
Amid the world's temptations.<br />
"Vahe Guru" is the Guru Mantra that God is the ultimate!<br />
"Vahe Guru"</b></font><br />
(A beautiful summary of Śhrī Guru Nāṇakjī's teachings in one of His hymns)
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The Prophets have two special qualities, as all the Prophets had: first of all, they have to talk about spiritual education.</b> All of Them did that: Muhammad Sāhab did it, Rāja Janaka did it, Nāṇaka did it, Moses did it, Abraham did it. All of Them prophesized and taught you how to lead yourself in the right path, by the right action, by leading a right life.<br />
You are going to be the Prophets of a little different nature. You are Prophets, you are Islamic, you are a Jews, you are Parsis. You are all those, but you are going to become Prophets which are called as Pīr in Islam, in Hindu Scriptures it's called as ātma-sākṣhātkāri, ātmajas. In the way Nāṇaka has described, He calls them Par. But you are endowed with a greater power, there's more power in you. There they had a bigger propensity. You have another delicate power by which you can raise the Kuṇḍalinī of people.<br />
You are going to be Prophets who are going to make others Prophets. Not only to establish religion but to make them Prophets. This is the most important thing. Not just to maintain a static state of righteous, religious, good people but that to evolve those seekers, those righteous, good, religious people into Prophets. And those Prophets whom you will evolve will also be the same type of Prophets but they will also have this additional power by which they will also evolve. That is why it is a Mahā Yoga.<br />
<b>This is the greatest work in the history of all spiritual history: that you are the Prophets who are looking after the Men of God, and you are going to transform them into Prophets.</b></font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0107.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It is the same thing, everybody has said: ``You should know about your Self."<br />
Guru Nāṇaka's thing I'll say:</font> <font color="DarkGreen">``Kāhe re bana khojan jāe, Sadā [Sarab] nivāsī sadā alepā tohī saṃga samāī, Puṣhpamadhya jo bāsa basata hai mukara māhī jaise chhāī, Taise hī harī base niraṃtara ghaṭa hī khojo bhāī, Kahe Nāṇaka bina āpā chīnai miṭai na bhrama kī khāī."</font> &lt;font color="DarkRed"He said, ``You must know your Self." ``Know thyself" Christ has said. Everybody has said, ``You should know your Self."<br />
Now what is that, knowing your Self? That is nothing but you are.<br />
The principle is this that the Truth is this that you are not this body, this mind, you are not these emotions, you are not this ego; you are not this conditionings, but you are the pure Spirit. All our Saints have said that."&lt;/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0406 Public Talk to Doctors, Conference ``The Art of Healing and `Sahaja Yoga' -- A Special Session on Alternative Medicine", Indian Medical Association, FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0108.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"May God bless you all!<br />
This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery, which you all should become the Great Prophets who are going to change all the men of God into Prophets.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Know that in every heart that beats<br />
The Lord of Life has His mansion.<br />
It is through the Guru’s teaching<br />
We merge in the Formless One.<br />
By the gentle path of Sahaja<br />
Attain God, Purest of the Pure.<br />
A disciple who serves his Guru and no other<br />
Will succeed, says Nāṇak, that is sure.</b><br />
<br />
<b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTEE</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTEE</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font> 
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1980-1123-guru-nanaks-birthday"> video</a><br />

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ (1993-0704 Guru Pūjā Cabella) </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nāṇak Mohammad</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a>
</p>
 
<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiya Tere Charano Ki (2008-1113 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, Noida)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/iOXcrlduLNM">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavil by Nirmal Sangeet Sarita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/I1nxKFe8QOU?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guruon kī Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarita Bhaiyakayataya (When we belong to God what is to fear) by Nirmal Sangeet Sarita (1990-0310 Australia)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/47fMsue7fs8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>
</font></p></b></font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Guru Nanaka Birthday" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Guru Dattatreya" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī:”brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/02" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī:”brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity”" /><published>2024-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-11-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/2024_10_29_Diwali_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/02"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Actually, only after Sahaja Yoga started, the real Diwālī is taking shape.</b> We had many beautiful lamps, and we had lot of oil to burn, but there was no spark, to enlighten the dīpas. And the wick, as you call it -- is called as bātī in Hindi language -- is like your Kuṇḍalinī, so the Kuṇḍalinī had to meet the spark. The beautiful lamps were all a waste, purposeless, pointless. And this is the great blessings in modern times, that so many lights are enlightened and we are having a dīpāwali of human hearts. When you become the light, you don't worry about the lamp, how it looks, how it is to be made, it's all done. You just have to worry about the flame, about the oil, because it's the oil that burns and gives light."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1117 Diwālī Pūjā (6th Day after Diwālī Day), Bagni di Tivoli (24 kms E of Rome), Lazio, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0101.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So this is the fifth day is Dvija [Bhāī Dūja]. So from thirteenth to the fifth day they celebrate Diwālī.</b><br />
For us Diwālī has a very great significance. That is: from one light many lights are awakened and they are put in a line. So they are called as diwālī, means the `lights put in a line'. So when you hold My hands together, all of us, through that the energy passes and the enlightened Rāsa is established. And the whole world has to become that beautiful dream of your Mother where nothing but the bliss of your Father and His enjoyment when He sees His own Creation dancing in that Ocean of Bliss.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"We have to be like a beautiful tower of light. Like a lighthouse. And everybody should work it out within and without. Within though you have worked out, without you must work now.<br />
And secondly there's a dīpāwali [row of lights], it is not only one light. <b>So we have to be all collective, try to get to collective life. Whenever it is possible, try to attend all that is collective; try to be there, where there is collective happenings. There, where it is collective, this source of energy flows better.</b><br />
May God bless you all!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then the second day is also very important: is the second day is the Moon. That is the Moon came out of the ...<br />
... Sea. According to this mythology, the Lakṣhmī came out of the Sea and with Her this Moon came out, which was only a two-day-old Moon, the New Moon but the two-day-old Moon. And this was regarded as the brother of Lakṣhmī, because they were born at the same time from the sea. So He is the brother of Lakṣhmī. It's all symbolic! This is very, very symbolic."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0102.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Pūrna chandr’ābhā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the radiance of the Full Moon! Salutations to You!<br />
</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, the last day is very important: is a very universal day, I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj. is the ... or they call it also in Marathi Bhāūbīj, the ... different names. Is the: brothers' and sisters' day.<br />
Now, the brothers' and sisters' relationship has to be very, very strong. And the purity of that relationship is to be maintained. Is not necessary that you should be born as brothers and sisters, not necessary. But you are born, because if you are realized Souls you are born as brothers and sisters. So that purity must be maintained in the society of Sahaja Yoga. Very important it is. That we should try to develop this situation that brothers and sisters are something very pure. Their relationships are very pure. And they should not be at all challenged.<br />
It is so much so that even if you call somebody your brother, he is your brother and the more you develop this relationship, the better your left Viśhuddhi will be. Because left Viśhuddhi is the relationship with God as a brother or with a Goddess as a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0103.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a day we celebrate in India where relationship between brothers and sisters have to be established.</b> They're very pure. Brothers and relationsh... sisters relationship is without any lust or greed. Is pure relationship, where the sister prays for the protection of the brother and brother play ... pray ... prays for the self-sufficiency of the kṣhema, well-being, of the sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But for a gṛuhalakṣhmī, the brother is very important.<br />
<b>And the brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaja Yoga collectivity.</b> If you understand that brotherhood and sisterhood is love which is very pure, there is no expectation, is just love: is giving love and taking love. And Absolute Purity within us should exist between our relationships when we call them as Sahaja Yogi brothers and sisters. And as there is understanding, complete understanding between the brother and sister, in a family, one has to know we are all part and parcel of a family, born out [of] the same Mother.<br />
Nobody has to shoot off, you know, nobody has to become something great, nobody has to correct others, nobody has to uh say that, 'I'm something unique.'<br />
All of you have to work it out together and find out the solution working out together, in complete friendship and unison.<br />
Anyone who cuts off himself and goes out or becomes anything else, goes out of circulation and useless for Sahaja Yoga. Such a person is completely useless: the one who tries to get out of the family.<br />
All of you have to be supporting as each other, helping to each other, not shouting at each other, [not] getting angry with each other, trusting each other, not finding faults, treating each other with respect [<font color="orange">unclear</font> and love].<br />
This is the most important thing, which Sahaj Yogis don't understand, that you are Saints and you have to respect each other."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0104.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This is the promise of Diwālī to you all, that you will reach highest and the noblest way of life.</b> Every word I say will be there to prove what I say is there. Whatever petty problems you have, they'll all be washed off. All these are the messages from the Divine, you don't have to worry about petty things, about money, about jobs, that's not your job. Your destiny will work it out. You have a promise that you'll be looked after. I hope you believe in that promise and are joyous in the highest way.<br />
I bless you all from My heart, all of you, for a very happy and prosperous Diwālī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (16th day after Diwālī Day), The Need for Sincerity, Holiday Inn Express and Suites, 1080 Navigator Drive, Ventura, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/194014361"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā - Rang De Jhini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuzhe Rupa Pāhuniyā Mi danga zhalo ai</b></font><br />
(Seeing Your serene and majestic look, we stand stunned and astonished))<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Awaz Uthayenge</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Bhai Duja Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “It’s the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/01" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “It’s the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā”" /><published>2024-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/2024_10_29_Diwali_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/11/01"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So, this is what it is. <b>One has to know that Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa is represented here as the light.</b> And, you see these lights when enlightened, even a small light, how it reacts and how it shows. And now, you have become the light, you see. Even this light can do it. You see, I put My hand to it and it recognizes and knows that because it is now enlightened. It is put before the Photograph, it's enlightened. It works that way.<br />
Now what about you? <b>You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.</b><br />
<b>Diwālī means the, the rows of lights. So, you are going to make this beautiful mansion of God full of Diwālī light. You have entered into the Kingdom of God and you have to enlighten it. So you are the decoration of God on one side, you are the glory of God</b> and also, on the other side you are the guide, guidelines -- you are like the torches ...... You have to become lighthouses."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0097.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>is the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā nights, not only of Lakṣhmī Pūjā</b>. There's a difference between the two.<br />
Mahālakṣhmī is one of the powers of the Three Powers, Main Powers, of Ādi Śhakti. As you know Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī.<br />
Now these powers have powers at a material level also, at a subtler level also. So Mahālakṣhmī Power is achieved after Lakṣhmī Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, for today's New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, why is it necessary to have a New Year Day in our life?<br />
While last year those who got Realization were very lucky people, but plodding through the path of Self-realization one loses all the enthusiasm and idealism that one has when you get Realization.<br />
You think of doing so many things about it. When you get Realization you are so much engrossed into it, you enjoy it so much that you think that, 'Now! The time has come for me to do this and that and that, and I'm going to contact these people and I'm going to give this to news to this one, and I'm going to do this work and show to Mother that what She has given me, I have made it many folds.' Because it was a new experience, great experience, the only experience that you have been waiting for.<br />
And that you also decide that, 'I am going to now become the torchbearer of this great light that has come into me, and I am going to form one of the lights of this Dīpawali.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then the day of the New Year comes in afterwards, because in India in the north, that's the time people finish their crops and they found that day was very good to celebrate the New Year. And, that is actually more, sort of, we can say is a social thing in India, we need not use that, what ever suits us. You can have your own New Year. Because in the south, say in Maharashtra they have another New Year, as I told you where Śhālivāhana in his dynasty started another calendar and they celebrate that.<br />
So all these things are nothing is rigid about anything, one must know. Nothing is rigid. Rigidity comes from ignorance.<br />
It's all for you, for your joy and happiness. The whole festival system is for your happiness and not for the happiness of the time or date. It's for you, so it should be adjustable according to your needs and understanding. And also according to your national way you live. They should be no addiction to any particular type of culture, a particular type of ideas. It's all for you. All these festivals are for you, not for Gods. They don't have these festivals. It's only for you people these festivals are there. And when you celebrate them, that's only for your joy and your happiness. And that's how you should celebrate in a way that gives you the greatest amount of happiness. And the festivals, all the festivals of the world must be celebrated. The more you are festive, the happier it is."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0098.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... [in] Sahaja Yoga we believe that the Lakṣhmī must became [become] Mahālakṣhmī. A man has to become greater man: mahā mānav. What does that mean? That She has to become the Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
<b>Mahālakṣhmī is a Deity which makes you absolutely satisfied with whatever you have. Complete satisfaction.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, She gives all kinds of benevolence and as a result, the Mahālakṣhmī Principle gets awakened in you. This Mahālakṣhmī Principle is nothing but the desire to be one with God.</b><br />
When you get the Mahālakṣhmī Principle you feel, "Mātājī, we have got everything and we have understood that God is with us and that we have come into the Kingdom of God but yet we feel that something is missing." What is missing? "We have not yet given anything to someone, we have not shared and eaten, we feel that we have eaten alone." At that point, the Mahālakṣhmī Principle gets awakened in you and when it gets awakened, if you slowly make your flame taller with balance, not with imbalance, but with balance, then She will sit in your Brahmarandhra and your whole life will get enlightened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + Marathi) (Diwālī Day), Puṣhpa Maṅgal Karyalaya, Mote Mangal Karyalay Road, Sheth Narayan Das Dugad Chowk, Bibwewadi, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... the <b>Mahālakṣhmī Principle is the principle where you start seeking the Truth and nothing else.</b><br />
But how can you seek the Truth without any light in your hand? It's not some sort of an abstract thing or just a drama. 'Oh, I'm seeking the truth with my eyes closed and with darkness in my hand, I'm seeking the truth!' How can you take to Mahālakṣhmī Principle unless and until the Lakṣhmī Principle is embedded in you? Unless and until you feel that love for each other, you have felt that love, you have expressed that love, you have been generous, you have been enjoying the generosity of your own. Then only you can rise up to that Principle of Mahālakṣhmī which is the Spiritual Principle."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia (50 kms S of Venice), Veneto, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0099.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now I have to take you to a very subtler side of life and that subtler side is that with the blessings of Śhrī Lakṣhmī or Mahālakṣhmī now you have achieved your Self-realization. The Mahālakṣhmī Principle has given you this ascent and the Mahālakṣhmī Principle is that you rise much above your mundane life into the Realm of Self-realization.<br />
So by Her blessings you become like lotuses yourselves.</b> Now you become another aspect of Diwālī which means the rows of lights.<br />
Śhrī Rāma's crowning or any other aspect of Śhrī Lakṣhmī here now becomes your own crowning, that is now you have entered into the Kingdom of God and once you are there then automatically as the citizens of God's Kingdom you are blessed and as you become the lotuses then you start spreading your fragrance all around. Now you do not keep this joy to yourself but you become generous about it and you go all out to give it to others."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So out of the Lakṣhmī Principle I hope you get all the tattwas, all the principles, satisfied in you fully, and also the Mahālakṣhmī Principle flows through your being.<br />
You have to be very satisfied and comfortable people. Not to find faults. If you are finding faults then know that you are not Sahaja Yogis. If you are trying to control others then know that you are not Sahaja Yogis.<br />
Even the leaders, I would say, should never try to control. They must know how the principle is working in the silence; see for themselves how it is working. It's a trick you must learn. Of course, little correction is needed. That time you correct the person. At that time, doesn't matter. But you must know how the whole principle of benevolence is working itself. The whole Paramachaitanya is doing the benevolence part; you must know that.<br />
As I've told you before also, you have to be like the sea which receives all the rivers into it. If you are on top of the hill you cannot receive anything. So you have to be like a sea to receive everything and you have to be at the height. As I told you the other day, the same way that very close to the sea there should be a personality which is above everything else. Such a beautiful personality you should have, is the depth of the sea and the height of the Kailāsa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Pāḍavā), Be Honest to Yourself, Auditorium, Gymnasium, Montecatini Terme, Tuscany, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0100.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>I bless you with all the Lakṣhmī Principle and Mahālakṣhmī Principle but above all the Principle of Love, the Pure Love without any expectations, nirvajya.</b> I bless you all on this auspicious day.<br />
May God bless you!<br />
Have wisdom and understand that Mother has said it out of Her heart, out of Her Love, out of Her feelings for us.<br />
May God bless you!</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia (50 kms S of Venice), Veneto, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"...... I wish you all a very Happy Diwālī and a prosperous whole year, after this New Year Day.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1106 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Apollon Camping, Delphi, Greece</b></font><br />
<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Jagan-mātā, Mahālakṣhmī sākṣhāt,
Śhri Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.</b></font><br />
Śhri Mātājī Nirmalā Devī, You are the Mother of this Universe and the Power of Evolution.
</p>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), What State You Have to Reach, Quinta do Mar, Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/78316274"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Shri Mahalakshmi Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parabrahma Rūpini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Ch-wz0NR08"> video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa, Music Of Joy</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tere hi Gun gate hai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Padava" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “This is the time of Thanksgiving. On this day we have to go to our elders and give thanks to them for whatever they have done for us”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/31" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “This is the time of Thanksgiving. On this day we have to go to our elders and give thanks to them for whatever they have done for us”" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_29_Diwali_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/31"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you have to enlighten many lights, we call it Dīpawali, Diwālī is dīpāwali, means the rows of lights, and by celebrating this Diwālī with so many of you I'm sure we'll have such a torch of light which will go around the whole world.</b><br />
Just remember you are not a small drop, now you have become the Ocean and you have to spread.<br />
Now you are sitting on your thrones and assume your powers. You have all the powers within you, you have to just manifest it. You have to just feel yourself, understand yourself what is your responsibility.<br />
You have been asking for light now you've got the light, you have become the light, now give light to others.<br />
So achieve a state where your light is on your head, on your Sahasrāra and that it is in your heart, you are not ordinary people, never think that way, actually in Sahaja Yoga only so-called ordinary people will come."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0093.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Sahaja Yogi is a special character of a soldier who fights for the Truth. That kind of a personality, when you will have, there will be lights all over.<br />
In this Diwālī Day, I bless you all from My heart and I want you to respect yourself and understand what is the position of your being in this l... something ... organization we can call or a, in this Movement of Sahaja Yoga, and how are we working it out. The attention should move from all this nonsensical, mundane things to your Self. It should be a very dynamic force that should work out. And I am sure next year it will be very different. We'll have all the beautiful blessings of the Divine. We must do it collectively, understandingly.<br />
May God bless you!"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1118 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Soldiers of Divine Power and Sahaja Yogi Is a Special Character of a Soldier Who Fights for the Truth, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="BlueViolet"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Lakṣhmī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
<b>O Divine Mother, You are verily Shri Lakshmi. Salutations to You!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now we have got, <b>astrologically there are three and a half auspicious days where you don't have to consultant</b> any uh ... any books of astrology, which are called as Pañchāṅg, ......<br />
<b>One of them is today. Is a day you can do anything good, you decide anything good. Today is the day to take an oath, to think of something great, to visualize something big, to ask a boon, to do a big Pūjā, is one of the greatest uh day. One of the, we call them muhūrtas, which where you do not consultant these books.<br />
And that's why rājyābhiṣhek of, I mean the crowning ceremony of Śhrī Rāma took place on this day.</b><br />
So there are so many aspects for this that, after Rāma had killed Rāvaṇa, another satanic force, this Diwālī was celebrated. Also, this was celebrated much earlier, when Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed. And this is how we express our joy and happiness, our gratitude to God that He has protected us always with His Power, with His Śhakti and has destroyed all the rākṣhasas and all the evil forces of this world.<br />
<b>This is the time of Thanksgiving. On this day we have to go to our elders and give thanks to them for whatever they have done for us. To all those people whom we have to give thanks, today is the day when we have to ask God to bless all these people.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā, Āśhram, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0094.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Lakṣhmī Pūjā, means the day they worship Lakṣhmī. I've told you many a times, the symbol of Lakṣhmī was created really beautifully. And it was so that She came out of the water. Through the water She came out so clean. And She has no pride. She doesn't assert Herself. She doesn't put Her pressure on others.</b><br />
......<br />
Because She stands only on a lotus. Can you imagine how light She must be to stand on a lotus? She has a big body, everything is there, but She stands on a lotus. That She takes all Her weight within Herself, She just sucks in Her weight as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa has described. That like a tortoise sucks in his legs inside his body, in the same way we have to suck in all the weight of money, weight of your positions, weight of your so-called education, weight of some aristocratic family you are born of. This is all nonsense which makes you a heavy person to go down very fast.<br />
So She stands, or floats in a way, on the lotus. And what a thing is beautiful, this lotus, that She doesn't disturb any petals of the lotus, nothing. She just stands, peacefully, in a balance. Unless and until you have balance you cannot stand on a lotus. So She is so balanced. Her center of gravity is so balanced that She cannot topple down.<br />
......<br />
<b>Now She has a hand, one hand like this, one hand like this, and there are two hands which have got again the lotuses, the pink ones.</b> Yesterday you saw the pink. Pink is Her fragrance, I think is spread on the sky. And She is pink, pink because that shows that Her house, Her nature is pink. Pink is inviting, is loving. She is a very fond hostess, that She wants everybody to come in, in Her house."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Pāḍavā), Be Honest to Yourself, Auditorium, Gymnasium, Montecatini Terme, Tuscany, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0095.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So there are two aspects of this thing we have understood is that Lakṣhmī fulfills all our monetary needs plus also she gives us all the balance, all the joy, all the bliss in the family.<br />
Now the problem is with us that unless and until we meditate, unless and until we reach that state of satisfaction we cannot see the work of this Divine Power."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>You are all, as I said, you are My light. And the light is there which is an eternal light.</b> These lights will be finished. We'll have to light them every year. Not you people. You have eternal light and this light is going to spread Joy. What's the problem of this world? The whole problem, you take it. There's no joy. Simple as that -- there's no joy. If they had joy, they would not have done all these nonsensical things. There's no joy. When you have joy, you don't want to fight, you don't want to do anything that is harmful. You don't want to say anything after anyone, not only that but you do not want to have something that will spoil this Mother Earth or which will bring ecological problem. No, you just don't want it, don't want to do anything because it harms harms others. People feel unhappy about it whether it is here, India, anywhere. You just feel that 'Why should I do such a thing which is not so congenial to others?' I mean, it's not joy-giving.<br />
So when you have joy, you have to be joy-giving. And if you are not joy-giving, that means there's something lacking in your Sahaja Yoga and that's why we have to come up now. We have to become Sahaja Yoginīs and Sahaja Yogis. That is joy-giving society. We can change our name, if you like, if not Sahaja Yoga is good: 'Joy-giving Association'."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So's today we are here to enjoy our joy. Our Ātmānanda, Nirānand and Paramānanda, all these we are here to enjoy, which are of eternal value.</b><br />
You have to understand that now believe that you are in the Kingdom of God and all the subtle beauties of your being are going to be opened out to you. You are going to see yourself all the beauty. But here, if your eyes are already closed, if your heart is already closed and you don't want to see something that's so beautiful, how can I say what a beautiful thing they have made? Is a very important thing in life, is to have a very positive attitude. For Sahaja Yoga also. In Sahaja Yoga we have to develop ourselves within."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0096.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Now, the ... celebration of Diwālī should be that we carry the light all over the world and enlighten people, as many as we can. None of our private things, no... none of our own problems are important. So the, that what it is: that we have to realize that we have got a certain position, which no one has in this world. So, once you understand, your own esteem goes up, and you see for yourself what you have to do!<br />
So then, everybody should, today, decide and take an oath, that, 'We'll do everything to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility.'<br />
So now we'll have the Pūjā and in this Pūjā you all should promise to yourself that you will create a dīpāwali [row of lights] in every household in every country in the whole world.<br />
May God bless you all."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="BlueViolet"><b>Chandraam Prabhaasaam Yashasaa Jvalantiim Shriyam Loke Deva-Jussttaam-Udaaraam 
Taam Padminiim-Iim Sharannam-Aham Prapadye-[A]lakssmiir-Me Nashyataam Tvaam Vrnne</b></font><br />
Who is the Embodiment of Sri and Whose Glory Shines like the Splendour of the Moon in all the Worlds; Who is Noble and Who is Worshipped by the Devas.<br />
I take Refuge at Her Feet, Who Abides in the Lotus;<br />
By Her Grace, let the Alakshmi (in the form of Evil, Distress, and Poverty) within and without be Destroyed.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(from Śhrī Sūktam)</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1998-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (6th day after Diwālī Day), Expression of Love, Pal Sports Complex, Novi Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/82917438"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi, Ayi, Āj Diwālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hum Āj Rāth</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the second day is where Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/30" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the second day is where Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed”" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_29_Diwali_Day_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/30"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are here, all of us, to celebrate the Diwālī, that is Dīpawali, meaning the rows of lights.</b><br />
In the darkness of Kali Yuga when you find from every place confusion of the worst type creating the darkness which cannot be penetrate into, and which looks like a solid mountain around us, and which can never be covered, as we feel, by the Grace of God. And even with the Grace of God it would never melt. In that darkness, in that hopeless state, when the creation is on the verge of its destruction, the light of Sahaja Yoga has arrived. And you are the lights, you are the dīpas, you are the little, little lights, which were waiting to be enlightened, to be enlightened to see for yourself what's wrong within your own lamp, what's missing in your own lamp."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1113 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), You Are the Dīpas, Tent, Marque, Back Garden, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0089.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>On the fourteenth day, he was killed by Ṣhaḍānana, Kārttikeya, was the Son of Pārvatī and Śhaṅkar who was a very powerful expression of Rudra Śhakti, is that He is the Killing Power of God.</b> And He was created specially for this purpose to kill Narakāsura [Tārakāsura].<br />
Then the ... this one was, this rākṣhasa was such a menace and he had ruined so many people slight. He has done such a havoc and people didn't know how to find protection.<br />
That time, when <b>Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed by the Śhakti in the form of Ṣhaḍānana, Kārttikeya, there was celebration all over. People celebrated the next night. And the next night was the darkest night of the whole year</b>, is tonight."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā, Āśhram, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The light which can enlighten can also burn. But this light will burn all those who try to burn the Kingdom of God. So on a Diwālī day let us know that we should have the lamps, burnt in such a way that it has purest of pure love in it. Not a lip service, lip service of love, but from your heart, it should pour, like the Nature pours all its blessings upon you."</b></font><br />
Then, wherever the flowers of your feet will touch, the nature will blossom with joy. There will be a dīpāwali.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1117 Diwālī Pūjā (6th Day after Diwālī Day), Bagni di Tivoli (24 kms E of Rome), Lazio, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pranatha sureswari, bharathi, bhargavi<br />
shoka vinasini, rathna maye,<br />
Mani maya bhooshitha karma vibhooshana,<br />
Santhi samavrutha hasyamukhe,<br />
Nava nidhi dhayini kalimala harini,<br />
Kamitha phalapradha hasthayuthe,<br />
Jaya Jaya he madhusoodhana kamini<br />
Vidhyalakshmi sada palaya mām</b><br />
<i>Victory to the Goddess!<br />
Who is the daughter of the Bhṛigu Mahaṛiśhi<br />
Who chases away all our sorrows.</i><br />
<b>Who radiates with all her ornaments containing precious gems<br />
Who blesses us with nine kinds of wealth</b><br />
<i>Who grants boons with Varada hastam (hand)<br />
Please protect us all the time</i></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>From Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī (praise of Śhrī Vidyā Lakṣhmī)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then there is, <b>the second day is where Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed</b>. Now Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was the one who was the devil from the Hell, let's say -- very cunning, very clever -- and he was killed by the Goddess. Actually he was killed by a, another Incarnation, Kārttikeya, but Goddess gave Him the power to kill. So when he was killed it was celebrated because the evil was killed. But we don't find that these days the evil people are getting peace awards. So what is the reason for this kind of a perverted brain? How is it they are using perversion? Just the opposite of it. What has worked out these things? So again we find the same so-called freedom to become also evil. So we have freedom to become evil. First of all we have freedom not to be benevolent, and secondly to become evil we have freedom.<br />
So the Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] within us must be killed, the one which teaches us evil, to do evil to others. If you are busy doing evil to others you can never enjoy. Because you enjoy doing evil to others. So that has to be faced within ourselves, not in other people. It's very easy to say that this Sahaja Yogi is caught up, that Sahaja Yogi is like that, but very difficult to say, 'Mother, I am caught up. I have got this problem within myself.' So when you start seeing yourself your heart opens out. Unless and until you learn how to open out your heart how can you enjoy? Open your heart.<br />
......<br />
<b>Open the heart. And opening the heart is only possible if Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] sitting on your heart is killed, finished, once for all.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Pāḍavā), Be Honest to Yourself, Auditorium, Gymnasium, Montecatini Terme, Tuscany, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So what do we do to remove the darkness of the night is to put lights. In the same way people should be enlightened. There should be light in the heart of people. Once they're enlightened, this darkness from which we are suffering because of our ignorance will be finished and we'll have the Absolute Knowledge. So this is a new age that they are talking about is here right now, here, that it is going to work out in such a manner that it will be all enlightened personalities together, and they'll know what is light is, what is Real Knowledge, Gyāna.<br />
So ours is a Path of Knowledge: Knowledge that is Love, Knowledge that is Compassion. This is what we have to understand, that we have come into another area, arena, where all the skirmishes and the troubles of Kali Yuga cannot enter.<br />
......<br />
<b>With the darkness in the heart, darkness in the mind that you don't know where are you, what are you doing and what you should be doing, just like going amok you go on hitting each other. This is what is Kali Yuga, and the one who recognizes it and gets out of it is the Sahaja Yogi.</b> Otherwise you are just like other people if you are still indulging into the same periphery, in the same circles of imbalance.
......<br />
So you are all enlightened souls. For Me that's the Diwālī. If the people are enlightened that's the Diwālī: that they remove all the darkness of Kali Yuga and you all enjoy the beauty and joy of Kali Yuga. It's very, very symbolic I should say, that Diwālī has already started. We have many lights, and we have to get more lights -- not because it is short of light; why are we taking more lights, why do you want? Because all must be saved."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1107 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), You Have to Be Very Meditative to Mature or Remove All the Darkness of Kali Yuga, Apollon Camping, Delphi, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0090.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Purple"><b>"A woman who has majesty and a firm character is Rājalakṣhmī. You might be feeling that Lakṣhmī Pūjā means giving a lecture on women, but it is not so.<br />
The third is Gajālakṣhmī [the Lakṣhmī riding on an elephant]. Gajālakṣhmī means, the principal form of Gaṇapati He has the head of an elephant] is that He is the sinless One. So, she should be sinless. Despite having a very sharp intellect, an elephant understands what is good and what is bad. The wisdom is of an extremely good quality.<br />
......<br />
All things should be done with grace and beauty."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + Marathi) (Diwālī Day), Puṣhpa Maṅgal Karyalaya, Mote Mangal Karyalay Road, Sheth Narayan Das Dugad Chowk, Bibwewadi, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Jaya jaya durgati-nashini kamini</b></font><br />
Victory to the ever-loving distorter of all our ills.<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Sarva-phala-prada shastra maye</b></font><br />
O Goddess of Divine Knowledge, You are the giver of all the fruits
(of our desires and actions),<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Ratha gaja turanga padati samavruta</b></font><br />
You are surrounded by chariots, elephants, horses and foot soldiers,<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Pari-jana mandit loka nute</b></font><br />
The whole world bows down to you in worship.<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Hari-Hara-Brahma supujita sevita</b></font><br />
The Lords Viṣhṇu, Śhiva and Brahmā serve You and offer auspicious Pūjā.<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Tapa nivarini pada yute</b></font><br />
You wash away the extreme sorrows of those who meditate upon your feet.
Jaya jaya he Madhu-sudan-kamini<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Jaya jaya he Madhu-sudan-kamini</b></font><br />
Victory to the beloved of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, the deserter of demon Madhu.<br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Rājalakṣhmī, Śhrī Nirmalā Devī, sada palaya mam</b></font><br />
O Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī, the giver of prosperity, Śhrī Nirmalā Devī, please protect me forever.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>From the 'Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī Stotram' by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then there is Rājalakṣhmī. She is the one who gives grace to the kings. If the kings behave like servants, then they are not called as kings. They have to behave in a dignified manner. <b>The dignity, the majesty of the king comes from the Rājalakṣhmī in him. But a Sahaja Yogi need not be trained. He walks very straight in a very stately manner. In his movements he's stately, he's very majestic in handling people. He's very gracious in doing anything</b> in such a manner that people think, 'Oh, here comes a king.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But this <b>ego can be easily managed if you worship the Rājalakṣhmī</b>.<br />
She is the giver of balance. Firstly, She rides on the elephant. Is not easy for a lady to climb on an elephant, I have done it, it's not easy. Without fear. And She sits straight with a complete balanced attitude.<br />
And Her blessings are tremendous.<br />
The first blessing one gets: the imbibement of dignity. Dignity of a king, dignity of a queen. You are a queen so you can't behave like street women. With Her blessing, first of all, you get that dignity. That dignity is full of love, love for others. That personality emits nothing but love and benevolence for others, nothing else. Wherever She looks, in every glance She blesses people. She doesn't expect anything. She is a queen, what can you give to the queen? She's the highest of all in every way, what can you give it to Her?<br />
These, all these politicians and all these so-called presidents of all these countries are beggars. All the time, 'Give me this,' 'Give me this,' like greedy people going around are beggars! They are not the people who can rule. Hankering after things.<br />
So first thing is the sign, is that such a person has a personality that just blesses people, thinks of their benevolence, cares for each and every person who comes along. This is a blessing of the Goddess. <b>Then the second blessing of the Goddess is that you develop a kind of a temperament, which is very dignified, but also very humorous and understanding what other people are like.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English + Hindi), The Royal Principal, Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0091.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You are Saints because inside you there is the fragrance of -- beautiful fragrance of your lotus. That's the Spirit. <b>This is a lotus you have made for Me here. Such a beautiful lotus, I am sitting in a beautiful lotus.</b><br /> 
In the same way is reflected in your heart as a beautiful lotus. Feel that lotus, how beautiful, how delicate. It's pink because pink is the lotus which invites everyone, sign of generosity, of invitation. Pink color attracts all kinds of insects, everybody.<br />
So lotus is pink and it invites everything, open to everything, not frightened of everything. But it comes out of the mire, comes out of absolutely horrible ponds. There are lots of worms going round it, all right, but it emits the fragrance and makes the whole pond so beautiful. That's what you are. Wherever you'll be, you can create that beauty. You can flow that beauty. You can make people see what a spiritual person is. You are the reflector of Sahaja Yoga, not Me. You have to reflect Sahaja Yoga. For such people are always in joy and wisdom."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ayi-kali kalmaṣha nāśhini kāmini, vaidika rūpiṇi veda-maye,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You come in this Kali Yuga to remove darkness, O loving Goddess in the form of sacred knowledge,</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Kṣhīra samud-bhava mañgala rūpiṇi, mantra nivāsini mantra-nute,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Auspicious Form who arose from the Ocean of Milk, You reside in the mantras that praise You,</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mañgala dāyini ambuja-vāsini, deva-gaṇ’āśhrita pāda-yute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Giving auspiciousness and abiding in a lotus, the Gods and Gaṇas take refuge at Your Feet,</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jaya jaya he Madhu-sūdana kāmini; Dhānya-lakṣhmi sadā pālaya-mām</b></font><br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>Victory to the loving consort of Shrī Viṣhṇu, O Giver of Sustenance, protect me always.</b></font><br /> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Once you come to Sahaja Yoga, and enlighten yourself, you see in that light, in that light, what's is good and what is bad, to begin with. And then you grow into it, beautifully, just like these flowers who are all the time happy, all the time giving you joy. In the same way, when you are enlightened, with that light you don't seek anything, you got everything within you. Keep the lights on.<br />
The another thing you can do is, with your light you can enlighten other people. Like we have done here, we had enlightened one candle, with that we have enlightened all of them. So you all can do it, because you have got that light within you. With that light you can enlighten others, and they can feel their joy of their Spirit. It's something to be seen now, like so many lights you have put, in the same way, you are the lights for the whole world. It's not sufficient that you have got the light, but also you have to give light to others, you have to enlighten others, just like these candles.<br />
<b>Once you start doing that, you'll realize what you have got, and then you'll respect yourself, and you'll behave in a matter ... manner that behoves [behooves] a Saint, could be a Sage, without proclaiming anything. Inside your being, you just develop that beautiful, extremely beautiful temperament that is joy-giving.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1103 Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), The Importance of Meditation, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0092.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Sahaja Yogi is a special character of a soldier who fights for the Truth. That kind of a personality, when you will have, there will be lights all over.<br />
In this Diwālī Day, I bless you all from My heart and I want you to respect yourself and understand what is the position of your being in this l... something ... organization we can call or a, in this Movement of Sahaja Yoga, and how are we working it out. The attention should move from all this nonsensical, mundane things to your Self. It should be a very dynamic force that should work out. And I am sure next year it will be very different. We'll have all the beautiful blessings of the Divine. We must do it collectively, understandingly.<br />
May God bless you!"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1118 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Soldiers of Divine Power and Sahaja Yogi Is a Special Character of a Soldier Who Fights for the Truth, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="BlueViolet"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāksho-bala Vimardana sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.<br />
(Victorious over the Asuric forces)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1118 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Soldiers of Divine Power and Sahaja Yogi Is a Special Character of a Soldier Who Fights for the Truth, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/78313893"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Andhar Phar Ahe (Śhrī Mātājī gives the meaning of the bhajan and sings along)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mateche Gondhari</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/6HVszNo1EBo">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Naraka Chaturdashi" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “The first day of Diwālī is called as Dhanatrayodaśhī”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/29" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “The first day of Diwālī is called as Dhanatrayodaśhī”" /><published>2024-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_29_Diwali_Day_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/29"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The significance of Diwālī is spread out in about five days.</b><br />
......<br />
And they are all together somehow, these five days are all put together. <b>So they have different aspects, but in every aspect there's one common point is that the Goddess plays the main role.</b> Now the first day is the worship of the housewife where you have to buy some sort of a utensil for the kitchen or for the use of the wife or could be a present for the wife, but is said that woman must be respected, but they should be respectable. If they are not respectable how can they be respected."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0085.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"The first day of Diwālī is called as Dhanatrayodaśhī: is the thirteenth day of the Moon. Because that day is the first day when Lakṣhmī, the first ... was born on the thirteenth day. That means She was born as a Gṛuhalakṣhmī, as a housewife."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Śhrī Lakṣhmī Welcome Song 1987</b></font><br />
<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Diwālī means the, the rows of lights. So, you are going to make this beautiful mansion of God full of Diwālī light. You have entered into the Kingdom of God and you have to enlighten it. So you are the decoration of God on one side, you are the glory of God and also, on the other side you are the guide, guidelines -- you are like the torches</b>, ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Dīpawali, dīp means these lights, āwali means the row of lights.</b><br /> 
'So I am going to be one of them. And we are going to enlighten the path of the people who want to have Self-realization.'<br />
All these great ideas come to us when we touch our depths. And we feel responsible for all the rest of the humanity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Since time immemorial, the festival of Diwālī has been celebrated in our country. However, the 'dīpāwali' [arrangement of lamps] of <b>Diwālī started with the beginning of Sahaja Yoga</b>. The lamps that were lit during Diwālī used to get extinguished in some time. The next year, Diwālī would be celebrated by putting oil and a wick in a new lamp. In this manner, every year, new lamps used to be bought. The speciality of the lamp was that at first, it would be put in water and made completely wet and then dried so that the lamp does not absorb the oil in it. It then used to burn for a long time. 

But we have been celebrating the Diwālī of the heart since Sahaja Yoga started. <b>The heart is the lamp which has the wick and we light it by putting in the oil of love.</b> But before putting in this oil, we have to cleanse the heart completely of all impurities and then decorate it beautifully. When this love is firmly established in our hearts, then the heart does not absorb it. When someone loves you, for example, at first your mother loves you, your father loves you and then some others also love you, you absorb that love within yourself. The love that you get from your husband or your wife, settles down in every pore of your body. However, that love is just restricted to you and others don't get its light.<br />
......<br />
However, <b>when the soft love of Sahaja Yoga is filled in the lamp of the heart, it is no longer restricted to oneself. When it starts burning with the light of the Spirit, it has the ability to light up the entire universe. Such a heart becomes empowered then, to light up the entire universe, to radiate its light throughout the universe, to destroy ignorance in the universe and to spread joy in the whole universe</b>. The same lamp that was broken every year [after Diwālī] now becomes an empowered and a special lamp that does not get extinguished at all. This lamp lights up many other lamps and even those lamps burn for all eternity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + Marathi) (Diwālī Day), Puṣhpa Maṅgal Karyalaya, Mote Mangal Karyalay Road, Sheth Narayan Das Dugad Chowk, Bibwewadi, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0086.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>A Gṛuhalakṣhmī should be a scintillating woman.</b> Her life should be such that the husband should feel that there is something tremendous in the house which will not allow me to take to wrong ways. In the old days, men used to call their wives as 'mālak' [master or owner] and 'sāhib.' There used to be great respect for the wife. How was it so? It was not because the wife used to shout but it was <b>because of her brilliance. It was because of her nobility, composure, generosity, devotion, service and love. A woman has a scintillating character because of these qualities.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + Marathi) (Diwālī Day), Puṣhpa Maṅgal Karyalaya, Mote Mangal Karyalay Road, Sheth Narayan Das Dugad Chowk, Bibwewadi, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī -- ah!"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0313 Public Program, The Meaning of Sahaja Yoga, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Gṛuhalakṣhmī is the Deity of the Family, the one who's the Deity of the Family.</b><br />
Now, any housewife need not be Gṛuhalakṣhmī. She can be a shrew, She can be a horrid thing. <b>The Deity of the Household, if She resides in you, then you are Gṛuhalakṣhmī, otherwise you are not.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The woman has to be a gṛuhalakṣhmī herself, and then she should be worshiped. <b>"Yatra narya[stu] pujyante tatra ramante Devatā." "Where the women are respected and worshiped, there reside all the Deities."</b> But they should be respectable also. If they are not respectable, then the Deities won't reside there. It's a big responsibility on a Gṛuhalakṣhmī to be the respectable, so that all the Deities are happy in the family. And once she is respected, she will try to be respectable also. So, the respect of the gṛuhalakṣhmī is very important."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0818 Śhrī Gṛuhalakṣhmī Pūjā, House, 48 Brompton Square, Knightsbridge, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0087.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The state of a Gṛuhalakṣhmī should be exactly like a lotus. The lotus is the abode of Gṛuhalakṣhmī. She should be like a lotus that blooms above the water, spreads its fragrance and is the complete support of Śhrī Lakṣhmī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + Marathi) (Diwālī Day), Puṣhpa Maṅgal Karyalaya, Mote Mangal Karyalay Road, Sheth Narayan Das Dugad Chowk, Bibwewadi, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Jaya kamal‛āsani sat-gati-dāyini, gñyāna vikāsini gāna-maye,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Victory to the lotus-seated Giver of happiness, You are abundant knowledge and sacred songs,</b></font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Anudinam-archita kumkuma dhūsara, bhūṣhita vāsita vādya-nute,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Worshipped daily, decorated with kum-kum and sandalwood and praised with music</b></font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Kanaka dharā stuti vaibhava vandita, śhañkara deśhika mānya-pade,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Wearing gold, praised with verses in Your glory, Lord Shiva is to be found at Your venerable Feet</b></font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Jaya jaya he Madhu-sūdana kāmini; Vijaya-lakṣhmi sadā pālaya-mām</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Victory to the loving consort of Shrī Viṣhṇu, O Giver of Victory, protect me always.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0088.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is a great day of Diwālī. That means today is the great day of [unclear putting up] lights of your heart together to make a greater light for the world to move in a proper direction. It’s a day of great joy, and those who join in this, are spreading also great joy.<br />
......<br />
Today is a day of spreading love, light of love so that everybody feels enlightened and happy and forgets these petty problems."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (16th day after Diwālī Day), The Need for Sincerity, Holiday Inn Express and Suites, 1080 Navigator Drive, Ventura, CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Gṛuhalakshmī sākshāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namaḥ</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Divine Mother, You are verily the ideal housewife. Salutations to You! </b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0814 Śhrī Fāṭimah Pūjā, Saint-George (40 kms W of Lausanne), Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/774438765"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Pavan Utsav ayya re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hasat Ali</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kanakadhara Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī Storam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Dhanatrayodashi" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 10: “now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 10: “now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God.”" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_12_Navaratri_Day_10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nine yugas, nine times, you all have been saved properly, and on the tenth month you are given your birth. Also this birth is always after seven days of nine months. So we had to wait for some time till it matures.<br />
<b>Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti. So today we are really going to worship the Ādi Śhakti.</b> On one side the Ādi Śhakti is Mahākālī, on the other side She is Mahāsaraswatī, in the center She is Mahālakṣhmī, and also She is the Ambā, the one who is the Kuṇḍalinī. But She’s also beyond that. She’s Parāśhakti, She’s beyond all the powers because She is the Generator of Power, so She has to be beyond all that.<br />
<b>So today when we are worshiping Her, we have to worship Her in all these forms.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0081.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"So She has created all these things just for you to be created, and ultimately to get your Self-realization; to have meaning for your life, to get connected to this All-pervading Power, to enter into the Kingdom of God. All is Her work.<br />
<b>So we can say nine times She came, and the tenth time She is supposed to give Realization to all of you. But at the tenth time, all these Three Powers are joined together – that’s why it’s called Triguṇātmika.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Navy"><b>Namo Devyai maha-devyai</b><br />
Salutations to the Devī, to the Mahadevī,<br />
<b>Shivaye satatam namah,</b><br />
To You who is ever Auspicious,<br />
<b>Namah prakrutyai bhadrayai</b><br />
To You who is the Primordial Cause,<br />
<b>Niyutah pranatah sma tam.</b><br />
And the sustaining Power, we bow to You.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>from 'Devī Suktam' in Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Bolo Ādi Śhakti</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you enter into the Kingdom of God. Then the Śhakti makes you sit on different beautiful positions, and some are sitting in the Heart of God, some are sitting in the Sahasrāra of God, in the Kingdom of God.</b><br />
Now you should assume your power. On Navarātri now, you should understand that it has now crossed the limit and now we are on the tenth position, where you must assume. I have told you many a times, now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God. You cannot judge God, you cannot say why She does that, why She does that, why He does that. You cannot say that -- that's different. But when you sit there, then it is not an assembly, it is not like a politician fighting, no; it is that you have entered into the Kingdom of God, blessed by God, looked after, protected, nourished, and made knowledgeable.<br />
......<br />
So Navarātri's -- <b>now, the tenth day of Navarātri, which is the most important for all of you, is where this Paramachaitanya has become active. And by its activity you should know it is become very powerful, and that now anybody who tries to be nasty with you, tries to trouble you -- "I don't have to worry at all." It will take care of it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0082.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Navy"><b>We should devote ourselves to that Devī<br />
Who resides at the center of our lotus hearts,<br />
Whose glory is like that of the rising sun,<br />
Whose face is pleasing,<br />
Who grants all boons and protection,<br />
Who is three-eyed, Who wears red clothes, and<br />
Who fulfills the desires of Her devotees.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha)</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"...... on this day of this Pūjā, <b>it's such a combination that it's the Dussehra, I am here and also you can call it the last day of the Devī Pūjā</b>. We have to see within ourselves, introspect, 'What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha</b><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma. Salutations to You! 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It’s very remarkable that, not only that you recognize Me as a Mother who loves you very much, but a Mother who is powerful to protect you. Is very powerful. If you realize that and if you feel that within your heart. Supposing I correct you some time, instead of feeling sad you should see that, ‘How fortunate I am that Ādi Śhakti Herself is correcting me. She’s taking interest in me. How fortunate I am to be born at this time, to be with Her in Her great work. What have I done [to deserve this]?’ <b>This recognition itself will fulfill all the Incarnations of Navarātri.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0083.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"On the ninth day, He worshiped the Goddess to get strength, Śhakti, for his weapons, and the tenth day He killed Rāvaṇa."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha </b></font><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma! Salutations to You!
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You desire something, you'll be surprised, immediately you'll find it works out. You ask for something, immediately it works out.<br />
<b>But there should be a complete dedication in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That's what it is.</b><br />
But if you are still moving with your egos, <b>and if you are still thinking on those lines that, `We are something and the we can start our own Sahaj Yog</b>. We can work out this way and that way,' or 'My wife is like that, my child is like that, my husband is like that,' <b>you have to give up all these problems on one side, otherwise you will not ascend</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0084.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You must pray to God and ask what you want.<br />
Ask for complete satisfaction in my heart, joy in my heart, bliss in my heart, so that the whole world becomes blissful.<br />
Give me love, love that I could love the whole world and that the whole world becomes one in love.<br />
Give salvation to this humanity which is suffering.<br />
Take me to Your feet. Cleanse me with Thy love."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0201 Public Program (Hindi+English), Dhyāna Kyoṃ Karanā Chāhiye (Why Should One Meditate), Prabhadevi, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other dates 0202 and 0209)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākshāt Śhrī Durgā Mātā Jagadambā sākshāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Durgā, the Mother of the universe. Salutations to You!<br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/76751298"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="OrangeRed"><b>Sarva Mangala Mangale</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Raghu Pati Raghav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 9: “This Navarātri should give you that power, those Nine Powers of Nine Chakras”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 9: “This Navarātri should give you that power, those Nine Powers of Nine Chakras”" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_11_Navaratri_Day_9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/11"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"She came on this Earth, many a times, to kill the people who were doing wrong things, who were trying to kill good people. She has done Her level [best] to do that, and today we are celebrating Her birthday.<br />
You all know so much about it, that I need not tell you, but what you have to know is that: <b>She came on this Earth to save you from all kinds of troubles. For Her you were important, very important, because you were doing Devī Pūj. And so we are celebrating today this Devī Pūjā, with all our heart, because whatever ill people did to you, She came to destroy them. So today is a very great day for you to thank Her: thank Her for Her protection and for Her understanding as to what you have been tortured for.</b><br />
I'm happy you are all here to celebrate Her birthday, and to be surrendered to Hers so that She can always, always, protect you, and give you Her blessings.<br />
So may God bless you all, your children, your families, and that you bring great joy er [and] protection.<br />
It's very kind of you to have come today, so far away. I'm very happy to see you. Moreover, you have got tomorrow also that you can celebrate.<br />
Today we are not going to have any questions and solutions. We are just going to worship the Goddess, that's all.<br />
<b>I request Her to protect us from all kinds of problems that are facing us.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1012 Navarātri Pūjā (8th day after Dussehra Day), Birthday of Śhrī Gaurī, Nevele Grande Hotel, 1 Country Club Road, Town of Wawarsing (outside Ellenville, 90 kms N of Manhattan), NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0078.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This Navarātri should give you that power, those Nine Powers of Nine Chakras.</b><br />
Seven chakras you already know. Above that you become the master yourself, and then you become the Power yourself.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Switzerland</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Navy">Manav. me ahankar. bhara hai<br />
<b>But mankind is full of ego,</b><br />
Ap.ni Shakti se dur. khada hai<br />
<b>Divorcing itself from its own powers. </b><br />
Peedith. narak. me bhayi, Par. kare Nirmala mayi<br />
<b>Mother Nirmalā grants Realization even to those suffering in Hell.</b><br />
Devī par.marth. ko ayi re, Meri Nirmalā Mā<br />
<b>She has arrived for the salvation of all mankind, my Mother Nirmalā.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Ayi Re</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>God is the witness and She is doing the play and She creates those chakras. In the chakras She places all these Deities to govern.</b><br /> 
Now, there is the existence, there is the creation, creative force, and there is the evolutionary force, all inside the Virāṭa State.<br />
Now, this is at the Vaikuṇṭha State, we say, because this state is on this first reflection. It is not in us, or we cannot feel it, the Vaikuṇṭha State, because it is in the first thing.<br />
Then another state was created, then third was created, but the fourth one is the Bhavasāgara: is the state at which all of us were born. First, in the fourth state. Now, can you think of a four strata personality which is facing a mirror? Now, which is the first one [that] shows? Is the topmost. And that's why the topmost shows is the Bhavasāgara. But if you can go deep down into your state, you can feel all the other three. But first of all, the one which you can see and feel it, is the Bhavasāgara. So, you are born in the Bhavasāgara. At this state you are at the Bhavasāgara State. At this Bhavasāgara State, now, you are created and you have to evolve. <b>At this time the Mahālakṣhmī Power acts to evolve you.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0220 Public Program, Creation and Evolution, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0079.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b><br />
Ayi śharaṇ’āgata vairi-vadhū-vara<br />
Vīra-var’ābhaya dāya-kare<br />
Tri-bhuvana-mastaka śhūla-virodhi<br />
Śhirō-’dhi kṛit’āmala śhūla-kare<br />
Dumi-dumi-tāmara dundubhi-nādam<br />
Aho-mukharī-kṛita diṅmakare, Jaya jaya he ......</b></font><br />
Giving courage, strength, boons and fearlessness to those who take refuge in You;<br />
Your spotless Trident captures the Heads of the Rulers of the Three Worlds;<br />
Making all directions resound with the ‘Dumi-duma’ sound of drums; Victory to You ......<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now you have had nine Pūjās here and out of these nine Pūjās have we improved more, have we got more? Did we fill ourselves more with greater love, with greater joy, with greater understanding and with greater satisfaction?<br />
This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation. Because we have done what? That is what. So today you should go and make a complete picture of yourself. What have I got in these nine days? What have I got? Let us see, have I got this? Have I got that? All these things, you should just within yourself see and then enjoy that you have got all these things. It is the victory. Tomorrow is the day of victory. That you have become victorious about yourself and about your ignorance. You have won yourself and you've won over the ignorance, the darkness of ignorance. This is what is tomorrow's message."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0080.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">" <b>"Ṛiddhi siddhi ki dātri hai”: means She is the giver of siddhis.<br />
Siddhis means by which you get powers, to give Realization to people, to cure people, to manifest all the Divinity, Siddhis.</b><br />
And ṛiddhi is by which contentment, peace, joy. Means that you grow into that, ṛiddhi."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1014 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font color="Navy"><font size="+0"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Siddhidatrī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">O Divine Mother, You are verily Siddhidatrī, the One who is the bestower of siddhis (Divine Powers)!
Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25791408"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Devī Sūktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/K7he8axOgfw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī playing harmonium as Sahaja Yogis sing Devī Bhajans</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Siddhidatri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 8: “If you want to really worship Me, that’s what you have to think, what are the devils within you, that’s all. So you don’t have to worry otherwise for outside devils, they cannot do anything to you.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 8: “If you want to really worship Me, that’s what you have to think, what are the devils within you, that’s all. So you don’t have to worry otherwise for outside devils, they cannot do anything to you.”" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_10_Navaratri_Day_8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/10"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we have gathered here to do the Devī Pūjā.<br />
<b>This Pūjā was performed many a times and the Devī was requested by the Devas to save them from the tyranny of devilish people.</b> Today I feel the same way, that we are now in the grip of a funny situation; that there are people who are themselves devils, I think, -- and also [who are] mesmerized by them -- who are trying to do something which they should never have done. But they don't know that there is a climax of everything. And that point has arrived where all the good people, especially the Sahaja Yogis should put all their mind to the destruction of these horrible personalities like Mahiṣhāsura.<br />
In those days, it was very simple because devils came as devils and you could see them, that they are devils, and all their behavior proved that they were devils. Why they did it? Why were they cruel? Because so-called 'human beings' as they are -- they are not -- they are by nature devilish and they want to do something by which they can destroy human beings, and good human beings. <b>It is evident that the time has come for them to be destroyed.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), You Should Become Really Soldiers of Love and Peace (Overcome Hatred with Love or To Hate is a Very Bad Quality), Sportcamp, Avras, Loutraki, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0074.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>Raudrāyai namo nityāyai</b></font><br />
Salutations to Her who is Terrible, Eternal,<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Gauryai dhātryai namo namaḥ,</b></font><br />
To Śhrī Gaurī, Supporter of the Universe,<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jyotsnāyai ch’endu-rūpinyai</b></font><br />
To Her who is the Moon and Moonlight,<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Sukhāyai satatam namaḥ</b></font><br />
And Happiness itself, we bow constantly.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Aneka-śhastra hasta sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(You are the One who wields many weapons in Her hands)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the eighth day of Navarātri, but it is great day for Sahaja Yogis because it is the most important period.</b> That is, the seventh center we have crossed and we are on the eighth center. We need not think of the Goddess what She did on the eighth day, we have to think today what we have to do within ourselves.<br />
After crossing the seventh day, after crossing the seventh chakra -- that is the real ascent in your spiritual ascent. What are we to do on the eighth one?<br />
It's so Sahaja that today should be Aṣhṭamī, because that is the day the Goddess killed so may evil doers, and demons and rākṣhasas. She did it on Her own, alone. Now these evil forces are manifesting in human beings. They have spread out. They are within us. So we all have to fight those forces within us. The war is within ourselves, is not without. First when you ascend the seventh chakra, when you are on the eighth step, you have to remember first you have to fight those forces within ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0930 Aṣhṭamī Pūjā (8th Day of Navarātri), Discipline Has to Be Sahaja (What We Have to Do within Ourselves), Complexe Sportif René Leduc, 12 Rue du Père Brottier, Meudon (12 kms SW of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0075.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"And on an Aṣhṭamī, that is today, is the eighth day of the Moon, of the Moon which is increasing, Śhuklapakṣhi, that first time all the weapons of the Goddess are to be worshiped. This was a great idea because these weapons who work all the time, not only to kill the evil but to protect the good, were never worshiped before.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Salutations to the Devī, to the Mahādevī.<br />
Salutations always to Her who is ever auspicious.<br />
Salutations to Her who is the primordial cause of the sustaining power. With attention, we have made obeisance to Her.<br />
Salutations to Her who is terrible, to Her who is eternal.<br />
Salutations to Gauri, the supporter of the universe.<br />
Salutations only to Her who is of the form of the moon and moonlight, and happiness itself.<br />
We bow to Her who is welfare.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the second thing is, [which] today we do, is a very great <b>Pūjā of Aṣhṭamī [eighth day]: is the day when the Goddess killed nine rākṣhasas together with Her eight hands. So today is a very special day for which a very special attention is needed.</b><br />
It's only at the behest of the bhaktas that the Goddess took Her form and killed all these rākṣhasas.<br />
Also with Her eight hands, She killed Mahiṣhāsura. That's why She's called as Mahiṣhāsuramardinī.<br />
She's called as Nava Chaṇḍī, one who has killed nine chaṇḍas, means nine rākṣhasas She has killed.<br />
So is a very important day and very vital and very deep."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0201 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), House of Madhukar Bhikobā Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today to see you on this Navarātri Day, so many people sitting to worship Me. So many people are here, so many Sahaja Yogis, it's so remarkable, it is not My achievement, I tell you. It's your seeking. Because I have been on this Earth many a times before -- that you know. But we never had like this, so many came and got crucified, died, this, that -- but I never had people of this caliber.<br />
So again we come to the same point, that we should be aware of ourselves -- complete śhraddhā in your Self. If you have some śhraddhā in your Self, you will have śhraddhā for Me also.<br />
......<br />
....... I will say that on this day, what we have to do is to kill the devils within ourselves, that's all. If you want to really worship Me, that's what you have to think, what are the devils within you, that's all. So you don't have to worry otherwise for outside devils, they cannot do anything to you.<br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0076.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You have to see that all the negativity goes away, around us, around the universe.<br />
<b>So first we sing the praise of the Goddess; when She destroyed every negative, satanic incarnation of Mahiṣhāsura.</b><br /> 
And when he was killed, all the Gods praised Her for saving them from the ... from the destruction, and that happened long, long time back -- it was ten thousand years back. So this is the praise of the Gods of that so that, whatever is the negativity, through those mantras will go away, because it surrounds us -- you see that, all of them have been there coming; from ten thousand years they have been coming. But this is the way you can throw them out of the present into their proper places."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1012 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (4th Day of Navarātri), Winterthurerstraße, Zürich, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini Nandit. Medini</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O beloved Daughter of the mountains, the One who brings about great joy to the earth</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Vishw. Vinodini Nandinute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">The One who brings joy to the whole universe, I I prostrate myselg before You Who are the form of complete bliss</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Girivar. Vindhya Shirodhini Vasini</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Your holy abode is in the king of the mountains, the Vindhyas</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Viṣhṇu Vilasini Viṣhṇu Nute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Viṣhṇu is filled with joy when He meditate on You, I seek refuge at Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay. Jay. Hai Mahiṣhāsuramardinī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Victory to You O Great Goddess
Who killed the terrible demon, Mahiṣhāsura</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Ramyak. Par.dini Shailasute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are the One with the beautiful luminous face, Daughter of the king of the Mountains,
Śhrī Pārvatī, the Wife of the One who has the matted locks, that is Lord Śhiva</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lAojYxfnKMs">Ayi Giri Nandini (Mahiṣhāsuramardinī)</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Navarātri is very good because these nine nights represent the main Nine Incarnations</b>. Where the Goddess took the form of Śhakti and killed the negative people.<br />
But those were easier days because negativity was understood by people and nobody sympathized.<br />
So this is what one has to understand that don't sympathize with negativity. You'll spoil them all. And always you'll find such sympathies bring forth your character also that you are also slightly negative.<br />
Because to fight negativity in modern times is a very difficult task. You cannot kill anyone: if you kill somebody, then may be that such a person is a brother or a sister or something of somebody. Or such a person would be himself or herself a seeker.<br />
So best thing is to separate like a contagious disease, keep that person out, no sympathies. And get the person cured and enjoy the life, otherwise that person is not going to be helped. It has become a very individual fight. And it's so troublesome and so disgusting.<br />
So to help Me out, you should not take any sides with negativity. That's how you can help Me the most. <b>This is what it is the Navarātri, the Pūjā that I give you powers to fight the negativity. That's how you cure people.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1009 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Like a Drama, On Arrival before the Public Program, Flat of Ruth and Kingsley Flint, Strasbourg, Grand Est, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0077.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, today's victory of the Power of the Divine Mother, is doing one very great work: is to expose. And this exposure will be condemning publicly those people who are doing wrong. If you see from that point of view, you will understand how we are victorious now."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Maiya Tere Charano ki</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>O Mother from Your Lotus Feet</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Yadi dhul. jo mil Jaye</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>Even if I could get a particle of dust</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Sach. kehta hu Nirmal Mā</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>Then verily, O Mother Nirmalā.</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Takdir badal Jaye,</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>My life will be transformed</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Maiya tere Charno ki</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>O Mother, from your Lotus Feet</b></font><br />  
<font size="-1"><font color="DarkGreen"><b>Maiyā tere Charno Ki</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0OlxRe8pbEs">Maiyā tere Charno kí -- Sahaja Yoga bhajan</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25653195"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Mahātmyam Eighth Night</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Mā Ādi Kuṇḍalinī by Sanjay Talwar</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe (Gondhala Mandila), by Ajit Kadkade</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b></b></font><br />
<a href="">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Mahagauri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 7: “I would request you the Sahaja Yogis, not to worry as to what is happening around, but to worry what is happening inside and build up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/09" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 7: “I would request you the Sahaja Yogis, not to worry as to what is happening around, but to worry what is happening inside and build up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle.”" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_09_Navaratri_Day_7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/09"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the ascent starts evolving. In that, the play of the Devī is the Navarātri -- in your ascent -- from ages.<br />
<b>Navarātri that's why is the most important Pūjā. In Sahaja Yoga, Navarātri is the most important Pūjā, I would say.</b> Though we can say in modern Sahaja Yoga Sahasrār Day is, because that's how you started getting your Realization.<br />
But if you go to the whole historical events of evolution you'll find [that] <b>Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra</b>. Without the help of the Devī at different stages of your ascent, you could not have been in a position to receive your Realization. <b>So all the steps that you took in the past are today worshiped and are used for thanking the Devī for what She did to bring you down here. So it's like a thanksgiving. Without Her work, nothing could have happened.</b><br />
So when we read about the Devī, about Her Incarnations, how She came on this Earth to save Her bhaktas, people who were trying to ascend, to cross this Bhavasāgara, how She worked hard, how She fought the devils, how She cough... <b>She killed the demons, single-handed, She took upon Herself the responsibility of making the people cross the Bhavasāgara.</b><br />
Guru gave you the strength to have dharma but She is the One who brought you out. Even those who were dhārmik could not do it because of the demonic pressure. <b>She's the One who fought, single-handed, with Her Powers of destruction. In Her Love for you She fought. She brought you to this level.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerlan</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0070.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... I must tell you that the Goddess took Her birth nine times on this Earth. And today [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] seventh, today is the seventh day of Her worship in Navarātri, Navarātri. And <b>the seventh day is ... uh ... for ... uh ... tremendous activity, tremendous ... uh ... creativity and also for prosperity".</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1004 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Wood Room, Hotel, Sasaima (78 kms NW of Bogotá), Cundinamarca, Colombia</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Bhavānī Aṣhṭakam</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/JQ3ibqZWgDI">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"On today's auspicious occasion we have gathered here. <b>Today is the seventh day of the Goddess. On the seventh day, the Devī Goddess destroyed the various rākṣhasas and sinners, because they were torturing the great Saints and Ṛiṣhis who were doing meditation and penance.</b><br />
We wonder, "Mother, why they did so much penance? What was the need?" The reason for doing it was because although human ascent was still low, yet their aspiration was very high. They aspired to achieve the Ātmā through the body. That is why they worked so hard and did penance in this place. It is due to their aspiration that today we are able to achieve this height. This does not mean that we should think that because of the blessing of Sahaja Yoga we are some great people or some specially chosen people by God. People who think like that will receive a great shock. You will see that those who are simple, innocent, and good-natured will ascend foremost and the rest will be left behind. Therefore just receiving your Realization is not the end.<br />
<b>On this auspicious occasion God Almighty has manifested all His śhaktis for your protection, benevolence and welfare. In everything God is blessing you. He wants to see you enter His Kingdom.</b> In a way it is His Desire that you should return to your Father's home and enjoy its comforts. But at least we should be worthy of it. If we are not worthy of it then how can we enter it? We should examine our worthiness and see what it is."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0071.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"About the Devī, it is said She is Ati Raudra, Ati Saumya.<br />
But Mahālakṣhmī Ati Raudra Rudra Swarūpi[n] and Rudra is very necessary. Otherwise, this negativity will not go away.<br />
This will only go away with the Rudra Form."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1211 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Mahāmāyā, Mahākālī, Śhāradā Devī, Mahālakṣhmī, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jaya Twam Devī Chāmuṇḍe jaya bhū-tāpa-hāriṇi,<br />
Jaya Sarva-gate Devī Kāḷarātri namostute</b></font><br />  
Victory be to You, O Devī Chāmuṇḍā<br />
Victory be to You Who destroys the suffering of all living beings.<br />
Victory be to You, O Devī Who is present everywhere.<br />
Salutations to You, O Kāḷarātri (the longest night)<br />
<font size="+0">(from Argala Strotram)</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"She has a double role all the time, She is at two extremes. On one side She is full of joy, Giver of Joy, feels very happy when She sees Her disciple[s] are joyous. Joy is Her own quality, is Her energy.<br />
......<br />
Sahaja Yoga, as you know, has a double action, as the Mahākālī has a double action: <b>She's extremely loving, full of joy, full of happiness and She's the one who's extremely cruel, wrathful. She's the one who is the slayer of all the demons and the evil, and those people who try to do evil.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0912 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Qualities of Mahākālī and You Have to be Collective (Purity Means Chastity and For the Saints the Main Thing Is Their Ascent), Centre Culturel Thierry Le Luron, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... Love is Power of the Goddess, is very subtle, silent, but it manifests. All these manifestations you call them as miracles. You may call them by any name.<br /> 
<b>It is this Goddess which is ruling this universe, which is in your center Heart, which looks after you and looks after the whole universe, is nothing but Pure Desire of Love.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0917 Śhrī Śhakti Devī Pūjā, Love and Joy of Collectivity, Moscow, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0072.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>I would request you the Sahaja Yogis, not to worry as to what is happening around, but to worry what is happening inside and build up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle.</b><br /> Once you have built up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle, you will have no problem at all. Then through you the Mahālakṣhmī Herself will work and fill your countries with great bounties and great joys.<br />
May God bless you all!</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0921 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Śhrī Jaldevatā, Oude Stadsfeestzaal, Mechelen (27 kms S of Antwerp), Belgium</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b></b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The Heart chakra is what the Christians call the Sacred Heart. Within it is the place of Bhavānī, Durgā, which is a very great place.<br />
It is not within you to understand Durgā. That all the rākṣhasas are also Her children. The whole world is Hers. A Mother's Śhakti destroyed them for the sake of Her love for Her children. To pull one's own hands is very difficult. To give an injection to oneself with one's own hands is very difficult. <b>So to kill one's own children to protect other children is even more difficult. But to kill is a very great act of the Śhakti</b> ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0120 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Kṣham Ki Śhakti Ka Mahatav (Power of Forgiveness) or Dharm va Adharm (Dharma and Adharma), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0073.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Her security is so great, She is so secure Herself, that She gives you all the security that you need. You can hold on to Her Feet. You can hold on to Her image or to anything.</b> You can even pray to Her. Many people are being cured only by praying to Her.<br />
......<br />
She is worshiped in the night, because then we can put on the light. She likes enlightened persons. Also She likes the light. She likes the Sun. She likes something that will be completely enlightened and brightened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), The Powers of Śhrī Mahākālī, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
Durgāyai Durga-parāyai<br />
Salutations always to Śhrī Durgā who takes one across in difficulties,<br />
Sārāyai Sarvakārinyai<br />
Who is the author of everything,<br />
Khyātyai tathaiva Kṛiṣhṇāyai<br />
Who is the knowledge of discrimination; and who is blue-black<br />
Dhumrāyai satatam namaḥ<br />
As also smoke-like complexion<br />
<font color="RoyalBlue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kāḷarātri sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī, the one who is the dark night of dissolution,<br />
Salutations to You!
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (7th Day), The Pure Knowledge or You All Should Depend on Paramachaitanya, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25645269"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parameśhwarī Bhagavatī Nirmalā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durgā Mātā Bhavānī (Rāg Durgā by Ajit Kadkade)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HgN42YkSHkY">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kalaratri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>