<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-07-17T14:50:55-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Mother’s Day</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Mother’s Day" /><published>2024-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/2024_05_10_Mother&apos;s_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"[Mother's is] a very special institution ... ... especially in this country [Italy], they have such respect for their mothers.<br />
<b>Mother is the Source of Love.</b><br /> 
In the Qur'ān they asked Muhammad Sāhab, Whom should we bow after Allah?" So He said, "To Mother" -- "To the Mother." Then again they asked Him, He said: "Only the Mother." Again they asked Him, He said: "Only the Mother."<br />
I'm sure He must have said about the Divine Mother, because worldly mothers may not be complete mothers, perhaps. They are a[n] embodied, or, we can say, examples of Mother's Love, of the Divine Mother's Love, but they are human.<br />
So they can be conditioned, influenced or could be egoistical, especially if they are living in a particular country for a long time and have no idea of Divine Love.<br />
In Divine Love there is no expectations, it just flows, it doesn't think how to judge a person or what to do for a person, it just flows."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0513 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother's Day), Living Room, Palazzo Doria, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0026.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Thank You</b> for descending from Your heavenly abode, Mātā Dvīpa, to bring light into the darkness of Kali Yuga.<br /> 
<b>Thank You</b>, Śhrī Mātājī, again and again.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for delivering Sahaja Yoga to a confused and self-destructive humanity.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing the meaning of creation and evolution to us.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing the actual existence of God to us.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for giving divine meaning to human existence.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing the reflection of the Viśhwarūpa within the human body to us.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b> The 108 Thank Yous offered to Śhrī Mātājī on 1996-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā in Cabella</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/wP_R9tpOVag">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is ... I like the day when it is the Mother's, I should say, Mother's Day also. Because I think only a Mother can work it out that way. One has to have a lot of patience with people.<br />
......<br />
But mother's position is different. She'll go on struggling and fighting for her child. She'll fight it out to the last to see that the child gets all the benefits and this patience and this love and this forgiveness is innately built in in a mother, because her attitude is very different. Not any achievement, not any big name or what you call a sort of an award or anything. It is just she does it because she is a mother. And that is what is the sign of any mother, if she is a real mother, at least for her own children, she will go all out, she will work out everything for day in day out and to save the child from disaster. But Sahaja Yoga is a much bigger family and for that you really had to be worked out through the Mother's Principle. You cannot take any other principle.<br />
......<br />
So, in your own way, when you are doing Sahaja Yoga, there also you have to be a mother. <b>More mother's quality than the father's quality, that there's no ambition, there's no competition, there's no jealousies, nothing.</b> Just you want your children to come up and to grow into their spirituality. If that is the only attitude we have then you'll be amazed how satisfied you'll feel, because this is a very, very joy-giving thing, to see people growing in spirituality. Not only talking about it, not only reading about it, but actually happening, actualizing within yourself. So this quality is very helpful and that really helps every Sahaja Yogi to be patient, to be kind, to be humble."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Blessing of the Divine Pours Only if the Sahasrāra is Open (Meditation Is the Only Way You Can Enrich Yourself with the Beauty of Reality), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0027.png" /></div>

<p style="color:MediumVioletRed; text-align:center;">
May I this day be what You'd have me be.<br />
May I this day say what You'd have me say.<br />
May I this day be part and parcel of the whole<br />
And may my thoughts be of a realized soul.<br />
May I this day have love for all mankind.<br />
Mother, be in my heart and in my mind.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, [the] Principle of Mother is in every, every Scripture, has to be there. Now the Mother's character is that She is the One Who is the Womb, She is the One Who is the Mother Earth and She is the One Who nourishes you. She's ... She nourishes us, you know that. And this feminine thing in a one ma... in every human being resides as this Kuṇḍalinī, as you have seen. And when She rises, She gives you this new awareness which becomes compassion, which is flowing, which becomes soothing, nourishing Energy of Love. And that's what today people are saying feminist go this thing and all that. That's again a pendulum -- a man becoming a woman, woman becoming man -- all these problem you have had because of this. But when you move spirally upward, then where do you move? You move, become a personality full of compassion, of love, of universal understanding, through Collective Consciousness. And then you rise up to a position where you become universally conscious. So that is what should happen to you. And, if that happens, then we should say that your motherly qualities within you have risen. And that's what we have so far neglected. You do not become a woman but you become motherly. First the Father, then the Son, and now the Mother! All right?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1001 Interview with Barbara Schuler for the Program `Discovery' of Kazu Radio Station in Monterey, Seminar, Day 1, Session 3, Part 1, Kennolyn Campgrounds, 8400 Glen Haven Road, Soquel (10 kms ENE of Santa Cruz), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0028.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">The Mother is everything — She is our consolation in sorrow, our hope in misery and our strength in weakness.<br />
She is the source of love, mercy, sympathy, and forgiveness. And this Earth is the Mother of the trees and flowers.<br />
It produces them, nurses them, and weans them.<br />
The trees and flowers become kind mothers of their great fruits and seeds.<br />
And the Mother, the prototype of all existence, is the Eternal<br />
Spirit, full of beauty and love. </font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>('Broken Wings' by Kahlil Gibran)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0510 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother's Day), On Creativity, Entertainment Program, Living Room, Nirmala House, Sant'Angelo Romano (7 kms N of Guidonia), Lazio, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/127372212"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>She's Got the Whole World in Her Hands</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mother I Adore You</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LsWaC7NktHA">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Matajila</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ybCnMcQi2ZQ">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Mother&apos;s Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day: “Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth, all talk about Divinity was a myth.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day: “Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth, all talk about Divinity was a myth.”" /><published>2024-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/2024_05_05_Sahasrara_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So this Sahasrāra Day or, we can say, on the day the Sahasrāra was opened out, is a very important one, it's very subtle.</b> We just know about the Kuṇḍalinī, that She's coiled up in three and a half, and She's lying in the triangular bone known as sacrum. But we don't know what She works, how She works, what happens to us. She rises in six centers and breaks the seventh ... I should say She breaks the sixth center, because Gaṇeśha's center doesn't play any role. <b>So when She breaks the sixth center, which is the Sahasrāra, then She connects you to the All-pervading Power of Divine Love.</b><br />
<b>But what is this Divine Love? What does this do? It is the Energy of the Mother. We can say it is the Energy of Ādi Śhakti, which is all over, works through vibrations.</b> But what are these vibrations? It's a very subtle energy that starts flowing through your Sahasrāra. All the thousand petals of the Sahasrāra get slowly enlightened and it starts flowing throughout your body, throughout your hands, feet, throughout your body. And the more you are ... I mean your attention is, on the Sahasrāra, the more it works faster."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0506 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0021.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating the Sahasrāra Day.</b><br />
Perhaps we have not realized what a day it must have been. <b>Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth, all talk about Divinity was a myth.</b> People believed in it but it was just a belief. And the science, as it was put forward, was about to obliterate all the value system, all the proof of God Almighty."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrar. Dwari<br />
Mukhi Nām. Gheta<br />
Nirmala Hi Tari <br />
Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrār. Dwari </b></font><br />
O Mother we are enjoying our meditation in Sahasrāra<br />
Whenever we take Your name, You are always there to help us<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Charani Tujhya Baisat. Mate, Man. Te Nivale</b><br />
Sushumnachya Marge,<br />
Swarupachya Tiri</font><br />
When we are at Your Lotus Feet our attention is settled,<br />
we are in the path of Sushumna and very close to Your Divine form.<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U0w8QSa7zNY&amp;ab_channel=SahajBhajans">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, <b>it's a great day for all of us, the seekers, that the last work of the Divine, of opening the last center in the Great Primordial Being, was done on the fifth of May nineteen seventy [1970].<br />
It is the greatest event of all the spiritual happenings of the Universe.</b> It was done with very great care and great adjustments.<br />
It is not in the limits of human understanding, how things are worked in the Heavens.<br />
It is your fortune and God's Love that has worked out this wondrous miracle.<br />
Without this happening, there could not have been a possibility to give [en] masse Realization to people. One could have done it for one or two persons here and there, but to give such a [en] masse awakening could not have been possible.<br />
As you know, in the Sahasrāra there are the Seats of the seven main chakras. There are one thousand nāḍīs or, as they call it, flames, and they all have each Sixteen Thousand Powers. Every nāḍī deals with a particular type of a person, and, with the permutations and combinations of all these nāḍīs, human beings are looked after.<br />
As soon as Sahasrāra was opened, the whole atmosphere was filled with tremendous Chaitanya."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Opening the Primordial Sahasrāra, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0022.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Of course, Sahasrāra is a day which is very important, which makes a big history in the spirituality, uh and also in the evolutionary process."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0730 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Divine Laws, after the Evening Program, the day before Guru Pūjā, Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tu Ādi Śhakti, Sahasrar viraji </b><br />
You are Śhrī Ādi Śhakti seated on the Cosmic Sahasrāra<br />
<b>Chaitanya lutati, Saty.yuga jagati</b><br />
Showering Divine Vibrations and heralding the beginning of Satya Yuga<br />
<b>Viśhwa kī Janani, Tu Mahādevī</b><br />
You are the Mother of the universe and the Great Goddess<br />
<b>Tere Putra banne ki Patrata de Mā</b><br />
Mother please grant us all the qualities by which we can be Your children in reality.<br />
<b>He Nirmalā Mā, He Nirmalā Mā<br />
Tera pyar. moksha ka Anand. hai Mā</b><br />
O Divine Mother, Your unbounded love is the bliss of liberation</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/v7T1xpKkYFU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>When we enter into the Realm of Sahasrāra, then only we have [a] right to do the Sahasrāra Pūjā.</b> Before this nobody talked about Sahasrāra, nobody did any Pūjā to Sahasrār. This is your privilege that you are in the Realm of Sahasrāra and that you can do this Pūjā, perform it, is your right, you are chosen for this. It's a very privileged place for you to enter into the Sahasrāra of the Virāṭ, to reside in the brain as cells of that Sahasrāra.<br />
<b>Let us see what is the quality of the cells of Sahasrāra. These are specially created cells through the working of the Swādhiṣhṭhāna. Passing through all the chakras, when they arrive at Sahasrāra they are equipped to handle the brain's activity without getting involved into other elements in the body.<br />
In the same way, the Sahaja Yogis are not to be involved in the other cells, human beings, of the body of this Universe.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, State of Absolute (Nirānanda Absolute Joy, Absolute Love, Absolute Compassion, Absolute Power), Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"To keep the Sahasrāra open is, in a way, very easy, as well as difficult. As you have known in Devī Māhātmyam that ``at Sahasrārare Mahāmāyā comes." She's a Mahāmāyā: not easy to recognize Her, not easy to know Her. She lives just like you. She moves just like you. And you can never make out Her real nature. She is in the form of Mahāmāyā.<br />
......<br />
<b>So, in Sahasrāra Pūjā, actually, you have to recognize your own divinity, that you are divine, by experiencing your divinity. How do you experience your divinity? That you give Realization to others.</b><br /> 
It's a great experience to give Realization to others. Not only that you give Realization but you can tell about their chakras, you know what's wrong with them. You are quite confident."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Recognize the Mahāmāyā and Your Own Divinity through Your Heart, Sports Stadium, Island of Ischia (1 hour from Naples), Campania, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So My own effort was to take you into that beautiful arena of Sahaja, where you will be absolutely one with your Self, one with the nature, one with the ... all the people who are around you, with your own country and countries. Everywhere, in the whole atmosphere, as they say, the whole Brahmāṇḍa [universe] becomes part and parcel of you, and you are not separated from that.</b> Then, they ... we can say the echoes -- they call nināda -- the echoes of your being, of your life can be easily seen, not in material advancement or in any other kind of a thing, but in the spiritual area which is the highest. Or everywhere, in every country, there have been people of that quality, and, till today, they are all remembered. In the same way, <b>you all will be representing a very great knowledge about reality: in your life, in your creation or in your working. In every way you can do it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0507 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Sahaja Avasthā (Sahaja State), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0023.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Now, the Will of God, you are feeling it on your fingertips. After Realization, now, you have discovered the Absolute Science, which is the Will of God, which is an Absolute Science."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tuzhya Krupe Nid.Rit. Shakti Urdhvamukhe Yei</b></font><br />
The energy which is awakened with your blessings start to rise<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sat. Chakre Tichya Sparshe Jagrut. Ti Hoi</b></font><br />
As it touches the seven chakras, they become enlightened<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Adnyasthani Yeta Mate</b></font><br />
When it reaches the Āgñyā chakra<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ka Ga Visawa<br />
Ughad. Sahastrār. Mate</b></font><br />
O Mother, please open the Sahasrara!<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> <font color="DarkRed"><b>Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks. Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
Nothing ever had a meaning nor a life, everyone so dry and so weak, then You came, O Mother, so caring, so sweet. You taught Your children even to walk and to speak. We thank You, O Mother, for bringing us up, opening the doors of Heaven for all of us.<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks. Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
We were the clay but You all the Supreme Creator.<br />
......<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations again and again to the Queen of the Seven Peaks. Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Mahāmāyā Swarūpa, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>O Queen of universe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Y2Z3tNAs0I">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahaja Yoga teaches how to love and adore the human body as the Temple of God Almighty.</b><br />
Sahaja Yoga is the working of the Unconscious and there are some very stupid people who think they can cheat God. In return they are cheated by Sahaja Yoga, and to their surprise, find themselves outwitted. The play of Sahaja Yoga can be very mischievous, and creates many miraculous happenings as well as a great deal of uproarious humor."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Adi Shakti, Chapter 8: Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahaja Yoga was known to Me all along.</b> It is a unique knowledge with which I was born. It was not so easy to reveal it and I wanted to find out how to reveal it.<br />
First of all I thought that the seventh chakra must be opened, which I did, on 05th May 1970. It is a secret in a way. Formerly, the Brahmachaitanya was avyakta. It was not manifested. It was not expressed by itself, and so the people who managed to reach Brahmachaitanya somehow, by attaining `realization', said -- ``it was nirākār kā guṇa" ``you are like a drop that gets dissolved in the ocean."<br />
No one could say, explain or tell people anything more about it. The Great Incarnations also who came out of this Great Ocean of Brahmachaitanya, tried their best to share it with the best available followers -- which were very few -- and introduce them to this Brahmachaitanya. But because the Brahmachaitanya was not in avyakta form, these Incarnations got dissolved in it.<br />
......<br />
<b>Now I have come as the Incarnation of the Brahmachaitanya as a whole.</b> The sea of the Nirākār has now become a big cloud [Sākār]. It has taken a form. Those who came before were all a part and parcel of it. Now the whole has come. This cloud has rain water. The rain water is nourishing the minds of the people. Gradually they are brought to a level were their Kuṇḍalinīs have risen. They have got their Realization and now gradually they are feeling everything on their senses, their fingertips. This is the reason why nobody has talked about vibrations so clearly. They managed to talk about Chaitanya Laharī. This was so because of its avyakta [unmanifest] form. It was only a state. A state to be enjoyed, only in that state with no manifestation in the gross."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0227 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi and Hindi), From Pieces of Conversation with Dr. Talwar and other Sahaja Yogis Leaders, after the Śhivarātri Pūjā, Juhu, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0024.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Amhi Matajinchya Char.nasi Alo</b></font><br />
As we have come to the Feet of Mother<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Chaitanya Sange Amrutat. Nhalo</b></font><br />
We have beenbathed in the Nectar of Chaitanya<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Janiv. Ti Jiva Kadhi Nahi Zhali</b></font><br />
Such recognition has never before happened to the Spirit<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shakti Kundalini Sharir. Vyapili</b></font><br />
And as we come to Your Feet the power of Kundalini drenches us completely<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Char.nasi Yeta Jagrutis. Alo</b></font><br />
By coming to Your Lotus Feet we got our realization.<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"When your Mother is the Deity of Sahasrāra, the only way to be able to keep the Sahasrāra open has to be complete surrendering."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0504 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirvikalpa, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Recognize the Mahāmāyā and Your Own Divinity through Your Heart, Sports Stadium, Island of Ischia (1 hour from Naples), Campania, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href=""> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Savera Aya Hai, Mātā Ne Jagaya Ha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lUNkxcIAEs4">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mā He Sahasrār Swāminī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/qWKprw2fe58">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mavena Nayani Ananda</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Matajila</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0025.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Ātā Viśhwātmakeṃ deveṃ yeṇe vāgyajñeṃ toṣhāveṃ. Toṣho..."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: Now it says that all of you, who are one in your Spirit -- this all description of Sahaja Yoga today, is the future, the present that you will get it, at this time what is going to happen. It is so beautifully shown, you'll be surprised, that you all will become one in the universe. The Spirit of the Universe will be satisfied with the Yagñyas they are going to do, with the fire ceremonies you are going to do. How it is appropriated! He said it three hundred years back.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Toṣhoniṃ maja jñāve pasāyadāna heṃ."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: And then you will, should give us the milk of your blessings by getting the complete satisfaction from us.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Jeṃ khaḷāṃchī vyaṃkaṭī sāṃḍo."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: That time all the horrible evil people will be ruined and their ... their plans will be spoiled.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Tayā satkarmī-ratī vāḍho."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: And people will take to righteousness. This is the description [unclear] Gupta</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Bhūtaṃ paraspare paḍo maitra jīvācheṃ."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: At that time there will be a tremendous friendship of the Spirit among people.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Duritāṃche timira jāvo."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: Those who are in ignorance will get light.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Viśhwa Swadharma Sūryeṃ pāho."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: The whole universe will see the light, the Sun of One Universal Religion.</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pasāyadān</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">'O' God, The entire Cosmos Divine , Be pleased with this pious word offering of mine,<br />
Grant me in goodwill benign | Your Benevolent Grace Divine<br />
(Gyāneśhwarī is considered to be a masterpiece in Marathi literature. At the end of which Gyāneśhwar asks for the blessings of the Almighty through this Pasāyadān)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Sahasrara Puja" /><category term="maroon @ Sahasrara Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Hanumān Jayanti: “We shall say that the right side is the source of power and the left of bhakti. Śhrī Hanumāna had in Him this harmony of bhakti and śhakti.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/22" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Hanumān Jayanti: “We shall say that the right side is the source of power and the left of bhakti. Śhrī Hanumāna had in Him this harmony of bhakti and śhakti.”" /><published>2024-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_22_Shri_Hanuman_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/22"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we have come here to do Hanumāna's Pūjā. 

Śhrī Hanumāna is a great character in our being and He runs all the way from Swādhiṣhṭhāna to your brain and He supplies all the necessary guidance we need in our futuristic planning or in our mental activities. He gives us guidance and protection.<br />
......<br />
It is very surprising how a Deity like Śhrī Hanumāna, who is an eternal child, because He was like a monkey. His head was that of a monkey, if not of an elephant.<br />
So He was an eternal child and He was the one who was used to run the right side of human beings. He was told that, ``You must control the Sun," to begin with He has to control the Sun, that the Sun in the people, if there is too much Sun then He must try to control it and make it cooler or smoother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā, Electromagnetic Force, Schloss Schwetzingen, Schloß Mittelbau, Schwetzingen, Baden-Württemberg, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0017.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"It is such a joy today, and the whole atmosphere seems to be bubbling with it, as if the angels are singing. And the speciality of Hanumāna was that He was an angel. Angels are born like angels. They are angels, and they are not human beings. They're born with the angelic qualities. But now, you all have become angels from the human beings. It's a very great achievement of Sahaja Yoga. The qualities that are born with the angels are seen from their very childhood."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Aarakta dekhile dola</b></font><br />
You saw with your eyes (the Sun) as red as blood,<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Grasile Surya-Mandala</b></font><br />
and You placed in your mouth the entire domain of the Sun<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Vadhata vadhata vadhe<br />
Bhedile shunya-mandala</b></font><br />
You who are forever increasing in size from the minutest dot;<br />
You can pierce even the domain of the absolute.<br />
<font size="-1"><b>Shri Māruti stotra<br />
(Verses in praise of Śhrī Hanumān by Rāmadāsa)</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating Hanumāna's Jayanti</b> [birthday].<br />
What to say about Hanumāna? The more powerful and wise, He was equally devoted and dedicated.<br />
Generally such a powerful person becomes right-sided and considers himself so high that he would not listen to anyone else.<br />
But <b>Hanumāna is a special Deity, a typical Deity full of qualities. There was a perfect balance between his devotion and power</b>. How could he achieve this balance is a thing to be understood. In Sahaja Yoga, when we are enlightened, we get many powers. Then we have to keep balance. We love others and with the power of the love, we keep on doing our duties.<br />
Śhrī Hanumāna was very powerful. He had many Divine Powers in Him Navadhā, that is Garima, Laghima, etc. He could be as big as he wanted to be and as small as an atom. He had achieved all these powers."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0018.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So in the left side we have gaṇas, on the right side we have angels. And translated in Sanskrit language or in any Indian language as Devadūt -- means they are the Ambassadors of Gods.<br /> 
So now you are the same, you are all angels now.</b> Only thing you are not aware that you are angels while they were aware from their childhood. If you know that you are angels, all your qualities will start shining through, and you'll be amazed that the quality of standing by the Truth at any cost is so easily managed for you, because you have been given the right, you have been given the special blessings, the special protection from the Divine that if you stand for the right, and if you stand for the righteous, and if you stand for the Truth, all kinds of help to protect you will be given."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Devadūta sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
(The messenger of God, You are the archangel, Gabriel)</font><br />  
<font size="+0">Jay Hanumān!</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Even His sevaka [most obedient worshiper] Śhrī Hanumāna was an ideal disciple to be emulated by all the Sahaja Yogis. He was of Great Powers. He is an innocent personality of a very high order, always keen to perform the task set out for Him by Śhrī Rāma. Later on also He appeared during the Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and used to ride on the top of the chariot of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
<b>He is known as Chirañjīv, an eternal being, one of the seven eternal personalities. He also comes and helps and performs all the tasks assigned to Him. He is always present in all My Pūjās</b> and on one occasion He had been visible in vibratory form, in one of the Photographs taken in Bombay [Mumbai]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0405 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0019.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"We say that Sahaja Yoga is the work of Divine Love. It's right, whether we know it or not, Its power is innate. It is Divine Power. <b>When a human being bows before someone and regards him higher, it is the expression of that Divine Power.</b> But when a person is respectful to his guru then he gets blessed with the grace and power of the guru.<br /> 
So <b>the devotion and the power (bhakti aur śhakti) are not different things. It is one. We shall say that the right side is the source of power and the left of bhakti. Śhrī Hanumāna had in Him this harmony of bhakti and śhakti</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Ham Hanumate Rudr'atmakaya Hum Phat</b></font><br />
<b>Śhrī Hanumān, whose soul is Śhrī Śhiva Himself</b>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha and Śhrī Hanumāna are the Incarnations of this Divine Wisdom.</b> Śhrī Hanumāna was very powerful and fast and Śhrī Gaṇeśha is cool-natured. But when required, both are very big hitters. They remain with you every moment. Whenever anyone troubles you, your protectors are there. Often you see that security moves with the ministers and VIPs. The security of Sahaja Yogis also moves with them; that is, the security of gaṇas. Gaṇas have many things to do. Gaṇapati -- <b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha keeps them informed about you as to where is the problem, from where you are getting attacked and troubled. You do not know that if anybody wants to attack you secretly, even then these God's gaṇas stand by you. When Śhrī Gaṇapati informs about it, Śhrī Hanumāna sets them right</b>. So Sahaja Yogis have no need to be frightened. No need at all to be frightened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So that is very important, especially <b>in the West where it's being really dangerously destroyed, the idea of auspiciousness and of holiness. So that is the power of any angel and that has to be fully established within us, and then on that power will work out, which gives you discretion, which gives you egolessness.</b><br />
I hope today both these things will work out within us in such a manner that we really become absolutely self-confident realized Souls whom I call as angels of modern times."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0020.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"I hope today you have understood the subtle side of your being which is there, which is exhibiting, which I can see clearly and that you will, all of you will, <b>in your meditation become aware of what you have within yourself. That's the greatest thing that will please the Divine, and Divine will look after you fully. With the same confidence as the angels like Hanumāna you have to go further and work it out.<br />
May God bless you all.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"> You are always at the Feet of Śhrī Mātājī.<br /> 
You worship the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī.<br />
You perform miracles to convince the Sahaja yogis that Śhrī Mātājī made them all angels.<br />
You are the most effective instrument for Śhrī Ādi Śhakti because You are nothing but obedience, humility and dynamism.<br />
You make all the Sahaja Yogis join Your company to do our Holy Mother's work and transform the whole world. </font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/65376957"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Hanumāna Chalisa</b> (1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Hanumāna Chalisa translation in English</b> (1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Hanumān Stuti (Anjanichya Suta)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Bhar de itni bhakti Ma</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Nām Gheta mukhi raghavache</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>He Mā de bhakti ka dān</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Hanumana Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Mahāvīr Jayanti: “In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/20" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Mahāvīr Jayanti: “In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George”" /><published>2024-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_20_Shri_Mahavira_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/20"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are going to celebrate the birthday of Mahāvīra.<br />
Mahāvīra is the Incarnation of Bhairavanāth, or you call Him as Saint Michael.</b> Now these two Saints as you know one as the Gabriel, Hanumāna, and another is Saint Michael. One is placed on the Piṅgalā nāḍī and another one, Saint Michael, on the Iḍā nāḍī.<br />
So, Mahāvīra had to go through lots of search. Of course He was a[n] angel, but came as human being and He had to find out the thing of the left side, and how the left side acts. It's a very complicated thing, left side, is much more complicated than right side. On the left side we have also seven nāḍīs, and these seven nāḍīs are placed one after another. They are described in books and given different names to them. Now these seven nāḍīs that are on the left side, as you know, they cater to our past. Say for example, every moment becomes a past. Every present becomes a past. Then we have past of this lifetime, and also we have past of our previous lives. Then all the past is built in within us since our creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0014.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">"Now, Mahāvīra also was one of Them, who ... who was born again and again, and He was Mārkaṇḍeya, and He was Kabīra.<br />
The way Kabīra lashes people, you can see that He is tremendous! <b>He is like Bhairava!</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The ascetic life of Mahāvīra was of a very, very extreme nature. He was the one who was born in a ... uh ... clan of warriors, Kṣhatriyas. And then He was also married, also He had a daughter. And then He decided, because He knew He had to do the work of the Divine, He decided to take a saṃnyāsa. So He took uh the permission of His brother because His parents were dead. He was a king, so He gave up all His uh material wealth, everything and He beg ... became a complete saṃnyāsī. And the He left His family, His left His ... house, everything behind and went alone with a little bowl for begging alms. And there people who joined Him were very few, and He asked them that, "You have to also become ascetics," Munis.<br />
He was a Reincarnation of Saint Michael and He resides on the left side, on the Iḍā nāḍī. And He looks after the whole of it, right from Mūlādhāra onwards up to the Sahasrāra. So Saint Michael was born as Mahāvīra, meaning The Greatest Warrior. But when He was born, the whole place got lot of uh prosperity, that's why <b>He was called as Vardhamān, to begin with.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>After they get their Realization, that He called as Kevalagyān: only the knowledge, only knowledge, means Pure Knowledge.</b> They will develop some Samyak Darśhan, means Integrated Personality and all the Collective Consciousness. He talked of all, all these things.<br /> 
But as He belonged to the left side, He has described Hell very clearly. Fundamentally, basically there are Fourteen Hells according to Him. And is horrible to read all that, what He has described about Hell. Because He wanted to tell people that, 'If you do all these wrong things, you'll go to Hell.'<br /> 
And He talked about, not about Form, Formly God, but Formless God, because He didn't want people to again start ritualism but get to right ... right to the position where they could get their Self-realization to cleanse themself.<br />
So you can imagine: how difficult, in those days at Mahāvīra, was even to be one of the candidates for Self-realization. It's frightening for you! <b>That's why I never had this uh Pūjā. Because to do all these things, first of all, and to become absolutely pure, then only He would give Realization.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0015.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Vardhamāna sākṣhāt<br />
Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namah!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the one who makes us progress and evolve.<br /> 
Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That's why, <b>I think, this Mahāvīra Jayanti is a very great thing for us to observe.</b><br />
Now, why was He called Mahāvīra? Because only a person like Him -- Vir means a person who is brave, who is chivalrous -- because only He could do this, so only He could enter into the being fully and could kill or, you can say, destroy those horrible rākṣhasas, devils, all these negative things that come to us.<br />
Now, as you know, we use left side very much for so many negativity that is torturing us, but if there is no help, say, from Mahāvīra, we cannot do it. You call the name of Mahāvīra -- you could call Him Saint Michael, you can call Him by any name, but Mahāvīra because He was a human being. All this works out because of Him and He's such a great identity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Even though Saraswatī has created all the Swaras, so what! <b>But the emotions it contains, the bhakti it contains it is due to the blessings of Mahāvīr.</b> Mahāvīr has really worked hard for this because he scared people that if you go to the wrong way, you go to hell, and on taking this correct way you will be overwhelmed and you all are actually witnessing it. Like this <b>we all should increase our bhakti and growing bhakti in the work of Mahāvīr. I am happy that on this day of Mahāvīr Jayanti you all are doing Mahāvīr's work</b> ......<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George [the Guardian angel of London]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0404 Śhrī Mahāvīra Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0016.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāvīra sākṣhāt<br />
Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namah!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Mahāvīra! Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76399695"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>21 names of Śhrī Bhairava recited during Mahāvīra Pūjā in Perth in 1991</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuz. Vina</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jarī Asel Anta</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Mahavira Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Rāma Navamī: “God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal. We don’t leave our dharma, Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, even if we have lot of difficulties.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Rāma Navamī: “God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal. We don’t leave our dharma, Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, even if we have lot of difficulties.”" /><published>2024-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_17_Day_9_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/17"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We have gathered here on the occasion of Rām Navamī.</b> Everybody has said, "Mother please tell us about Śhrī Rām."<br />
You know that Śhrī Rāma has a very important place on our chakra, He is situated on our right Heart. Śhrī Rāma has taken the place of father, hence if there is lack in the responsibility or love from father this chakra is caught.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we too understand that Śhrī Rāma and all other Deities have taken the form to fulfill Their divine work, in all Śhrī Rāma had a special task. As it was said by Socrates that the Benevolent King has to come the same way Śhrī Rāma had come on this Earth as benevolent king, He came in the form of human being, He even forgot that He was Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, forgot about Him but for all world He was Puruṣhottama Rāma.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we need to know when we pray any Deity, we have imbibed the specialties and qualities of the particular Deity within us, Śhrī Rāma had many qualities.<br />
You all know his childhood life and you have already heard about his qualities, he was Puruṣhottama he had another quality that in his ruling, he did not care for his wife or children's in front of his subjects view."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0010.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo">"Śhrī Rāma was born at midnight so let's have Pūjā late. Śhrī Rāma Pūjā is not a specially long one. As He is in a human form He is humanity within us by which we understand our intellect and our thoughts get changed. Śhrī Rāma is that through Him we can change our thoughts. Our nature can change because He is our ideal.<br />
After achieving His ideals, we reach another because He was human ideal.<br />
<b>It is great that God came to this world in a human form to became our ideal. He has gone through all the hardships to show us strength to keep dharma. That is Viśhwa Dharma and the State of Yoga.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Śhrī Rāma Himself was born on the right side. Great example for all of you is Śhrī Rām who was on the right side, who works the right side. When He was born and He was a child ... <b>He is a Sūryavaṃśhi, He is the son of Sūrya, I mean, Sūrya's everything comes from the Sun to Him.</b> When He was born and was a little child, He asked His mother that, ``I would like have uh like to have the Moon." The [He] started crying, and nobody knew how to satisfy. He said, ``I want to have the Moon." They gave Him any toys, He threw away. Said, ``What a child it is‽ Funny thing! He wants to have the Moon, now how to get Him the moon?" They did not know how to solve the problem. He said, ``Somehow you get Me the Moon. I don't want to eat or anything, I want to have the Moon." Here the Moon represents the Ātmā, the cooling [smiling:] capacity. He asked for the Moon.<br />
You are all on the right side, so ask for the Moon. Ask for the Spirit.<br />
And they didn't know how to satisfy this Śhrī Rāma, who was the [laughing:] Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, [laughing:] asking for the Moon of all the things, not for anything else. What's so important? So, the mother has always a[n] intuition. She brought a -- it's a, it's a māyā, it's a beautiful drama -- she brought a mirror and showed Him the Moon in the mirror. He [she] said, ``Now, you can get the Moon here." [Laughter, laughs.] So sweet! And He was satisfied! Even the reflection of that can satisfy.<br />
You are like the mirrors and I want to see the reflection of Moon [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] in you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0125 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Growth of the Being on the Subtler Plane (Count Your Blessings, Take Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga, Understand the Subtler Values of Everything, The Greatest Thing for a Sahaja Yogi Is the Living Energy, Be Sweet in Your Tongue, Just Open Your Heart, Great Power of Love, Take Up Love as Your Worshiping), Seminar, Day 3, Session 1 (morning), Lonavala (67 kms NNW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0011.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo">"Today I said that Śhrī Rāma was born at twelve o'clock hence the Pūjā should be at time as such it is not long Pūjā but we have to understand that the human form within us in form of humanity in which we understand and make changes in our mind, curiosity and thoughts.<br />
Through the medium of Śhrī Rāma can bring change in our thoughts, he can bring change in our behavior because he is ideal for us, reaching this ideal we can reach other ideals since he is ideal of human being.<br />
This is big thing that the God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal.<br />
<b>We don't leave our dharma, Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, even if we have lot of difficulties.</b><br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mātā Rāmo matpitā Rāma-chandrah Swāmī Rāmo matsakhā Rāma-chandrah</b><br />
Śhrī Rāma is my mother and my father; He is my lord and my friend,<br />
<b>sarvaswam me Rāma-chandro dayālur nānyam jāne n’aeva jāne na jāne</b><br />
 So also the ever-compassionate Śhrī Rāma is everything to me and I know nothing else at all</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>('Śhrī Rāma Kavach' in praise of Śhrī Rāma)</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Rāma was the Puruṣhottama, means-s-s: He was the best among all the human beings. That means: He incarnated as a human being, total human being, showing all the qualities of human beings is.</b><br />
Like He was, He married the Lakṣhmī Principle, that was Sītā, and then also He lived a normal married life, when He gave Her up, He lived like an ascetic, to show how a man should lead his life in a proper dharma, as a married man. And even when the Wife has gone away, how He was leading a life of complete chastity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0814 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Secondary School, Saffron Walden, Essex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0012.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo">"<b>On the night of Full Moon, you should meditate on Śhrī Rāma and surrender yourself to Him for protection. The meaning of the word rāmachandra is `creativity'. You should completely dedicate your creative powers to Him.</b> Thus you have to take special care of yourself on these two days.<br />
However, <b>on the seventh (Saptamī) and ninth (Navamī) days of Lunar fortnights you have My special blessings. Remember that you are specially blessed by Me on these two days.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0529 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Dhyān Kaise Karein (How to Meditate), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, Indi</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Rāma came on this Earth to establish the institution of benevolent king.</b> The political development and the political evolution started from this [right] side. <b>He is the one who gave leadership as a benevolent king, the one who represents God and who is a king. The idea of a king related to God came from Śhrī Rāma.</b><br /> 
But the modern kings are not like that, they have no relation with God. On the contrary, they are horrid people. Some of them are nothing but satanic people, absolutely Satan is there and you can see from the way they lead their lives, and they have led their life before. So the benevolence of Śhrī Rāma is here [shows the right Heart] to be followed by all the political leaders and all the people who are at the helm of affairs. He is the ideal that was created for human beings, to run their authority as the head, or the loving compassionate benevolent leader of the people, who has to govern them by making them respectful, by respect. And if human beings create such things who are not respectable, those who have no human values, those who have no moral courage, those who are selfish, those who are self-centered, then they have nothing to do to be there.<br />
<b>So this is the position of Rāma who is the Father. So the head of every state has to be the father of his subjects, that's what He has tried to show by His life. So much so that He had to sacrifice His beloved Wife, whom He loved so much.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Public Program (1st Day and 2nd Day of Navarātri), Self and Heart Chakra, Day 6, East West Center, 141 5th Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That is a very beautiful song was written by him. But still, the description of a child, how when he runs when he runs, when he jumps, when he walks it's a beautiful songs about Śhrī Rāma. Ṭhumko atta hai who -- Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra, atta hai kya?<br />
[In Hindi:] <b>Do you know the song `Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra' ...?</b><br />
[In English:] Now these words are such that we cannot explain in English, but when they walk, you know, with -- started walking, so their body, you know, moves in a way that's called `ṭhumakanā' [toddle, waddle] in Hindi language. <b>So described by Tulasīdāsa, as Śhrī Rāma is walking in that way. `Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra'. And His anklets are singing and then He's looking round and every pebble on which He's walking is reflecting Him, like the souls in which He's reflected.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0405 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Picnic, Lane Cove National Park, Lane Cone Valley Walk, West Pymble, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Thumak chalat raamachandra<br />
Thumak chalat raamachandra<br />
Baajat painjaniyaan</b><br />
(Baby) Śhrī Rām walks, swaying unsteadily<br />
(Baby) Śhrī Rām…. His anklets ring in tune with his steps<br />
<b>Kilaki kilaki uthat dhaay girat bhuumi latapataay<br />
Dhaay maat god let dasharath kī raniyaan</b><br />
Laughing joyously he stumbles around on the ground<br />
He is fondly picked into the laps of King Dasharath’s queens</font><br />
<b>Thumak Chalat</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0013.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau manasā smarāmi</b></font><br />
I worship the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra in my heart.<br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau vachasā gṛunāmi</b></font><br />
Through my songs and prayers, I praise the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra.<br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra</b></font><br />
I bow at the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra.<br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra</b></font><br />
I surrender at the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra. <br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāmachandra sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<br />

</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0402 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī Day), Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1982-0402-shri-ramas-birthday-puja"> audio</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vaishnav Jan To Tene Kahiye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kahe Samjhaye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī singing the bhajan with Sahaja Yogis</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kavach Part 1 by Pt.B.Subramanian</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/jU0lTR3Rdg8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kavach Part 2 by Pt.B.Subramanian</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/VIexvFle7iQ">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Gangaur Festival during Vasant Navarātri: “They have one festival called Gangaur that is a thing where they worship Gaurī.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Gangaur Festival during Vasant Navarātri: “They have one festival called Gangaur that is a thing where they worship Gaurī.”" /><published>2024-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_11_Day_3_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/11"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have decided to have a Pūjā of Śhakti that is the Power, that is the Devī.</b> You know within us there are many Powers of Mahākālī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahālakṣhmī, Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
All these Powers are there for us to ascent. If these Powers are properly used and understood, then your ascent can be permanent. Once you achieve your ascent and enter into the Kingdom of God, all these Powers get enlightened.<br />
And these Powers which are enlightened are absolutely filled with Love. Enlightenment, we have to understand that we get completely enlightened by Love. So after enlightenment, after Realization we use only one Power which is of Love."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Samara Oblast, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0006.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we'll worship the Śhakti</b> -- very much needed -- the Śhakti who destroyed all the devils, all the rākṣhasas. That is what you are going to worship today -- the Śhakti within you and without.<br />
<b>It's your desire which is going to work.</b><br />
So today we are going to worship the Śhakti Itself -- Mahākālī.<br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1209 Śhrī Śhakti Mahākālī Pūjā, Auditorium, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here to do the Pūjā of the Śhakti.</b><br />
  Till today many Saints have written and spoken a lot about the Śhakti. Those who could not explain the Śhakti in their texts they did it in their poems. Additionally they learnt different meanings of the Śhakti.<br />
  But one thing probably we may not know is that inside every human beings these powers are present in a dormant state and all these powers human being can awaken within himself. All these powers which are present in the dormant state are endless, nor anybody can guess their limit because as an example there are 35 crores [350 million] Deities seated within you. Apart from that there are several powers that are running them, but at least we can understand that the Self-realization that we received today, certainly <b>some Śhaktis must have worked this out. Without this work you cannot get your Self-realization. When we are receiving our Self-realization we think that we got it very easily</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1009 Śhrī Devī Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0007.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Kuṇḍalinī is Gaurī, today is Gaurī Pūjan, Gaurī Pūjan in the month of Chaitra is special. Means before installation of Gaṇapati we have installed Gaurī in the month of Chaitra. Gaurī who created Gaṇapati is the Gaurī from Chaitra and we all believe that."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0321 Birthday Pūjā (Marathi + English), Completely Surrender Our Lives to Sahaja Yoga and People Should See through You the Greatness of Sahaja Yoga (We Have Started Vishwa Nirmala Dharma and the Great Religion of Realized Souls), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti is the Power of Desire of Bhagavatī. She is easily awakened just by the Wish (Saṅkalpa) of Bhagavatī. A person of very high order has to put in great efforts for it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0000 Letter to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi) on Human Chitta from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 13 (January-February 1983), Pages 16 and 17</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti is your pure desire. It is the Desire of God Almighty.</b> When it is awakened in you, you get contented. You get satisfied and think that instead of material desire now I have entered into such a beautiful garden which is fragrant, full of joy, peace and love. When you achieve that state then you do not look back to material desires. To achieve this state in Sahaja Yoga is extremely beautiful. It happens very easily, you have to do nothing for it, give no money, do no rituals, no prayers, nothing. You should only have the pure desire to know the Spirit."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0326 Public Program (Hindi + English + Hindi) (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), Satya Ki Prāpti hī Sabase Baṛī Prāpti Hai (The Realization of Truth is the Greatest Achievement), Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium, Pragati Vihar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0008.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font size="+0">The Mahārāṇī adorned Śhrī Mātājī in a traditional Rajasthani ghagra (skirt) of vibrant colors. The Rajput women worshipped Her with flowers and Āratī.<br />
<b>From "The Tenth Incarnation", Volume 1 Chapter 40, Page 178, by Yogi Mahajan.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>They have one festival called Gangaur: that is a thing where they uh uh worship Gaurī.</b> That's the biggest festival where the Queen ... Mahārāṇī has to worship the Gangaurī: is a statue, which goes round the whole of Jaipur state and everybody celebrates it. Is regarded as the biggest festival. So she, in the morning she came and touched My Feet. And she said, "Mother, can I'p worship You?" I said, "Why?" "Because You are my Gangaur, really. That's just a statue." She made Me stand the same way, she did everything, she made Me eat betel. Uh I don't eat all that, but he, she said, "You have to, You are Gangaur, so You have to eat it." [Smiles, laughter.] And she worshiped Me and all her whole rituals she did for about f... forty-five minutes, and the ... then she said, "Now I'll go and worship that statue." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0421 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Vertical Ascent, the day before Easter Pūjā, Before Dinner, The Burlington Hotel, Grand Parade, Eastbourne BN21 3YN, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We are the worshipers of Śhakti.</b> Here we are Śhakti Dharmī [religiously devoted to Śhakti] and many kings have been worshiping Ādi Śhakti.<br />
Everyone has different Deities and the names of each Deity is different. <b>The name of the Deity of this place is also different, it is Gangaur.</b><br />
But Ādi Śhakti was once born in Rajasthan state whose name was Satī Devī. It is Her Grace that we find our culture the dharma of wife, dharma of husband, dharma of ruling, etc. which are nourished by Her Śhakti.<br />
You all know the story of Satī Devī, I don't have to tell you in new way but She was Gangaur. She was married and while She was returning after marriage with Her husband some of the bad elements surrounded them and killed Her husband. She came out of the bride's carriage, took the Rudra Form and destroyed all of them who attacked Her husband and then She finished Herself also. We should see in this that since childhood till marriage She did not disclose that She was Mahāmāyā in any condition."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1211 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Mahāmāyā, Mahākālī, Śhāradā Devī, Mahālakṣhmī, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0009.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Prabhavatı Prabha-rupa, Prasiddha Parameshvarı,<br /> 
Mula-prakritir-avyakta, Vyakt’avyakta-swarupinı. </b></font><br />
Full of light, as light is Your form, You are the Established, Supreme Ruler of the Universe;<br />
You are the Kundalini Shakti, imperceptible,<br />
both the manifest and the unmanifest are Your forms.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Lalitā Sahasrānama, verse 86)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<i>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon, Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font><br />
<i>Morning and evening I sing Your praise</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<i>Śhrī Mātājī I Have received Second Birth from You</i><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Samara Oblast, Russia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/26181854"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durge Jay Ambā Bhavānī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kuṇḍalinī Kuṇḍalinī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shri Gangaur Festival" /><category term="green @ Vasant Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Guḍhī Pāḍavā: “[Guḍhī Pāḍavā, New Year Day of Śhālivāhan Calendar]. And they have the Kalaśha and the Shawl of the Goddess as the emblem or you can call it as a flag of Śhālivāhanas.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/09" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Guḍhī Pāḍavā: “[Guḍhī Pāḍavā, New Year Day of Śhālivāhan Calendar]. And they have the Kalaśha and the Shawl of the Goddess as the emblem or you can call it as a flag of Śhālivāhanas.”" /><published>2024-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_09_Day_1_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/09"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Chaitra is the month.</b> And this is the time when -- [Marathi] -- <b>Gaurī is the Chaitra. So the establishment of the Gaurī is taken place during these nine days.</b> But Gaṇeśha has to be established before anything else. Though first Gaurī had to come, you can see that. Gaurī had to come first to establish Gaṇeśha. But Gaṇeśha is always put before even Gaurī. Before the Pūjana of the, worship of the Gaṇeśha, nothing starts; because He's the one who takes out all the obstacles, all the negativities, all the hurdles that are going to come up, all the attentions that are here and there. So that's why we first worship Gaṇeśha, just to ask Him to protect us. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0404 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Gaurī Pūjā, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0001.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>So this New Year's Day is the first day of Advent of Goddess -- the nine days there are.</b><br />
......<br />
So today is the day to mark absolutely the first day when She incarnated on this Earth. That's the day also of the Gaurī, because Virgin is the first form of the Goddess."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0404 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Gaurī Pūjā, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>In India, Navarātri falls twice in a year. Once it is in the month of Chaitra as it is today.<br />
On this day Devī is worshiped as Śhailaputrī, means the daughter of Himalaya.</b> Devī has many other names also but first of all She incarnated as Śhailaputrī in the cold of Himalayas. She incarnated and whatever She was to do, She started there.<br />
Further story is known to you. [King] Dakṣha did not invite Lord Śhiva in the Havana that he performed and Śhailaputrī was the consort of Lord Śhiva. She is called Satī because She entered the Holy fire of Havana and ablated Herself. But by then Lord Śhiva reached there. He lifted Her burnt up body from the fire. Burnt pieces of the body of Śhailaputrī fell at many places. All these places are considered to be Śhakti Pīṭhas, the places of worship, as there is in Vindhyāchala and many other places. Her power moves there and it is said that it Sanctifies everything.<br />
Her seventh power is considered to be the Power of Destruction. Śhakti manifested Itself on the right side as Sāvitrī and Gāyatrī but the destroying force was manifested in the center.<br />
In the form of Durgā and Her other forms manifested in Heart chakra. She is present there.<br />
If some one hurts you, confuses or disturbs you then this power will protect you and destroy your enemy.<br />
When Kuṇḍalinī rises and reaches the Heart chakra then it manifests and becomes more powerful and effective because Kuṇḍalinī is Jagadambā. In Sahaja Yoga when Kuṇḍalinī is awakened it settles in Heart chakra. It protects you and takes care of you nicely."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0405 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (Hindi), Noida Bhavan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0002.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"The first name of the Goddess is Śhailaputrī, as you know, that Śhailaputrī means the daughter of the mountains."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0502 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirānanda, Āśhram, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So this day is celebrated because it's a new year day and also because the New Moon appears on this day. It's ... is called Guḍhī Pāḍavā.</b> On this day they put up a small pitcher on a stick with a small flag. The pitcher represents the Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
Śhālivāhana Kings were worshipers of the Goddess and it is said that they used to present Shawl to the Goddess and they were also called as Sāt[a]vāhanas in the beginning because they recognized the seven chakras [Sāt[a]vāhana means seven chakras]. That's why they were earlier called as Sāt[a]vāhana but later it changed to Śhālivāhana. But the symbol of Śhālivāhana used to be guḍhī means a flag and above that a pitcher having a particular shape, which represented the Kuṇḍalinī. They were worshipers of Kuṇḍalinī and recognized it.<br />
That is the reason that they have made this thing like that and all those, who accept it, put up a 'guḍhī' in their houses. They [Śhālivāhans] wanted to welcome Kuṇḍalinī on this day and Kuṇḍalinī [in the form of pitcher] was exhibited specially on that day."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0413 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (Hindi), Terrace Garden, Palam Vihar, Gurgaon, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0003.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is the day, as you know, My forefathers called it the first day of the year [Guḍhī Pāḍavā, New Year Day of Śhālivāhan Calendar]. And they have the Kalaśha and the Shawl of the Goddess as the emblem or you can call it as a flag of Śhālivāhanas."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0321 Birthday Pūjā (Marathi + English), Completely Surrender Our Lives to Sahaja Yoga and People Should See through You the Greatness of Sahaja Yoga (We Have Started Vishwa Nirmala Dharma and the Great Religion of Realized Souls), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>I was telling them that after the introduction of this calendar the Śhālivāhan King founded his kingdom and lived there from the day of the Guḍhī Pāḍavā [Guḍhī is a symbol of auspiciousness].</b> Since you know all this I did not tell you and explained to them in English.<br />
With respect to the Guḍhī Pāḍavā the shawl has great significance. The Śhālivāhan Kings always carried the Goddess's shawl with them. You know the significance of Devī's shawl. You know it gives Her beauty. With the shawl She protects Herself from cold and wind. Also with it She protects Her chastity, as well as if any dirt is about to touch Her body it is prevented. So, a shawl which is offered to Goddess symbolizes Her protection, meaning, 'As You protect us we offer You this.' Further if the children are sleeping or are sick or have a problem, then She covers them with the shawl. So shawl is very important. You know, in the past it was a practice with all people in Maharashtra to take [put a] shawl over their bodies. Now that we have become modern we do not take it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0126 Śhrī Devī Pūjā (English + Marathi), 35th Republic Day Celebration, Maṅgal Karyalaya, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0004.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... Kuṇḍalinī is the Gaurī and we have got Gaṇeśha sitting in the Mūlādhāra chakra. <b>So we have Mūlādhāra as the abode of the Gaurī, of Kuṇḍalinī. And the protection of the Kuṇḍalinī is done by Śhrī Gaṇeśh.</b><br />
As you know, Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the Deity which is for our innocence."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0408 Śhrī Gaurī Pūjā, Residence near Āśhram, Parnell, Auckland, New Zealand]</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"So today I wish you happy New Year for a journey in the spiritual life of this world."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0330 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (the day before Guḍhī Pāḍavā), We Have to Be in Meditation Meditation (Be in Thoughtless Awareness and Meditation Is Where You Are No More), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0404 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Gaurī Pūjā, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/74915294"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Zulzul Vahe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/TbbNsFKL07c">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇapati Vandan Gan nayak</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay. Jay. Janani Śhrī Gaṇeśha Kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/osyZMyvmqfA">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jay Bolo Nirmal Gaṇeśha Kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gajānana Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0005.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is new year day and the beginning of the Moon. That is why this day is given so much significance. It is known as Guḍhī Pāḍavā.</b><br />
A flag is put on a stick and on it is put a small pitcher. This pitcher represents Kuṇḍalinī. It is taken as a symbol. The Śhālivāhanas were the devotees of the Devī [Goddess] and it is told that they used to offer shawl to the Goddess. In the beginning they were called Sāt[a]vāhans because they worshiped Seven Plexuses and this Sāt[a]vāhana was ultimately changed into Śhālivāhana. 
<b>But the symbol of Śhālivāhana is the same. They put up a 'guḍhī' means a flag and a small pitcher is put on it as a symbol. This pitcher has a particular shape which represents Kuṇḍalinī.</b><br />
So they were the worshipers of Kuṇḍalinī and followed it. That is the reason they made this symbol in this way. All those who follow Kuṇḍalinī put up a guḍhī in their houses and also put a flag on it and thus it is indicated that they welcome Kuṇḍalinī and exhibit it in a special way."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0413 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (Hindi), Terrace Garden, Palam Vihar, Gurgaon, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Wishing you all a happy Guḍhī Pāḍavā!</b></font><br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Gudhi Padawa" /><category term="green @ Vasant Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Holī: “Sahaja Yoga’s Holī should be the Holī of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Holī: “Sahaja Yoga’s Holī should be the Holī of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.”" /><published>2024-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/2024_03_25_Holika_Dahana</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As you know, <b>on the Day of Holī, Holikā was burnt</b>. Agni [God of Fire] had a very big blessing and task, because Agni Devatā had given Holikā a boon that in any circumstance, she will not burn, that death could come to her in any form, but not by fire. And after giving this boon, he regretted a lot because she took Prahlād in her lap and sat in the fire. And Agni Devatā had a big dilemma, that, "I have given this promise to her, that I will not burn her and how can I fulfill this promise? And Prahlād, is Himself innocence personified, He is Himself an Incarnation of Śhrī Gaṇeśha and how can I burn Him? Nobody can burn Him. And He is also beyond my powers. He is formed from my power." So he thought, "What is this ego? that in front of such a Great Power what can I talk about my power? I have no such power which can face Him. His Power is so great that I cannot burn Him whatsoever I may try. But at this time I have a very big dilemma in front of me."<br />
So in between duty and dharma the dilemma is in between these two. In this situation we must understand that dharma is higher than duty. <b>The duty of dharma is higher than a normal duty and even higher is the Dharma of the Ātmā.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Gifts Distribution and Offering, after the Holī Celebrations and before Departure, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1346.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, the great day of Holikā Dahana</b>, where the symbolism of this occasion is that the satanic forces were burnt by the innocence of Prahlāda. And that is what we have to remember, that when the Sahaja Yogis take to innocence and complete dependence on to their vibratory awareness, which is the indication of God's Manifestation through them, they are completely protected, and even a satanic person like Holikā could not burn him [them].<br />
And this is the day today, we have to recognize that, as Sahaja Yogis, we stand no dangers in life. We are fearless people, but we are humble people, loving people, and anxious to save as many as possible. To eman... to raise the whole humanity into another awareness, in the process of your evolution you have to achieve ghaṭ, for which you have to work hard."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0328 Public Program (Holikā Dahana) (English + Hindi), Concept and Reality, Birthday Celebration, Ajwan-E-Ghalib, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>"So, today, on the</b></font> <font color="red"><b>Holī</b></font> <font color="MediumPurple"><b>day if you only say the mantra of ‘Holika Dahan’ 
then with the mantra of ‘Holikamardinī’ "</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Gifts Distribution and Offering, after the Holī Celebrations and before Departure, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Holī was started during the time of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.</b> Before Him in the time of Śhrī Rāma ... He was very austere. Because of that the society became very peaceful but people were devoid of all joy. So He thought that there should be a way by which people should be able to laugh freely and be joyful. And like it happens to all such ventures it happened in the case of Holī also that it produced an opposite effect.<br />
......<br />
<b>The story of how it started is like this.</b> There was a demoness called Holikā. She was the sister of Prahlād and Prahlād's father used to trouble him a lot. Holikā had a boon that she would not be burnt by the fire. Prahlād's father wanted to kill him and told Holikā to take the child [Prahlād] and sit on the burning pyre thinking that she would not die. But it is surprising that she died and Prahlād was not hurt in the fire and came out of it unscathed.<br />
This is a very big happening which demonstrated that it is very wrong to be cruel and aggressive. She had the boon but still she got burnt. That's why we have this custom on Holī.<br />
In our country [India] all such things have a lot of truthfulness. We have to understand that if we do wrong things, trouble others ... then these are demonic qualities.<br />
......<br />
We should not have these demonic qualities because we are Sahaja Yogis. We are a special race of people who have taken birth to transform this world and we should pay our attention towards that. We are very highly placed, higher than all others and we have to save all others from such tendencies. These days it has spread a lot. That's why all such hateful, cruel behavior by which we dominate others, torture others is very, very bad and there is no need to do all that in Sahaja Yoga."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0329 Holī Pūjā (Hindi) (Holī Raṃgavalī), Palam Vihar, Gurgaon, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1347.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>"Always with Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's blessings you all should enjoy your Holī. But the greatest Holī is within yourself when you fill yourself with all kinds of colors. Your nature should be such that everybody should enjoy that color. That color that is within you, color of beauty -- not artificial, just showing of, just giving something without any love."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0317 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (English + Hindi + English), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebration, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So, <b>with Holī after dahan</b> [scorching], like I said yesterday, <b>let us decide today, that now Holī will be like Diwālī</b>. The joy of it should be overwhelming. Why the joy of Holī? Although we burn just one Holikā but afterwards, the joy flows in the Collective Consciousness, whether he is a sweeper or a garbage collector or even any other person working in the house. Like in My family, in Lucknow, from where My family belongs, these people are landlords. So the sweeper does not dare to enter inside the house. People don't like them coming even their threshold, to that extent. They reprimanded them.<br />
But <b>on the Day of Holī, any person, whether he is a master or a servant, anybody, they all play Holī together</b>. Even if you tear the clothes of the master then also no one will reprimand you on the Day of Holī. This is the way a social and collective celebration of happiness started in our country."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Gifts Distribution and Offering, after the Holī Celebrations and before Departure, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Abeer Gulaal Udhalitha Rang</b></font><br />
<font color="green"><b>Natha Ghari Naache Maajha Sakha Pandurang</b></font><br />
Amidst the fragrant colourful powder strewed in the air,<br />
Panduranga who is my master as well as my friend is dancing in his abode.<br />
<font size="+0">- Abeer Gulaal - Abhang by Sant Chokhamela</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0">Abir Gulal</font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/TjPTm04s6l8">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1348.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
[<font color="DarkRed">Inner awareness and a good attention is very important for burning your inner negativity.<br />
Only when it is burnt can you ascend on Nirmala Tattwa.<br />
Then you celebrate the real Holī, enjoy and play with color.</font><br />
<font color="DarGreen"><b>Sahaja Yoga’s</b></font> <font color="red"><b>Holī</b></font> <font color="DarGreen"><b>should be the Holī of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.</b></font>]<br />
[SYNOPSIS!]<br />  
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0318 Holī Pūjā (the day after the Raṃgavalī Holī), Holī Message, Sahaja Yoga Temple, C-17, Shaheed Jeet Singh Marg, Block C, Qutab Institutional Area (behind Qutub Hotel), New Delhi, India</b></font><br />  
<font color="DarkGreen">Tere ranga me aise range ham, dujā ranga nā lāge,</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>We are colored so deep and complete in Your color</b></font><br />  
<font color="red">Tum bin koi nazar nā āe, in naino ke āge</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>No other color will reflect through us, We are unable to see anything but You</b></font><br />
<font color="FireBrick">Jala ko sthala ko sāre jagata,Rangā ranga banāyā</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Through these eyes, You have made not only water and land But the whole universe very colorful</b></font><br />
<font color="blue">Ranga de jhini Hari, Mā ke ranga me kāyā, (kāyā)</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>God (Hari) please color my body (kaya) in the color of my Holy Mother</b></font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple">Ranga nā de ise, chanchala mana ko, Apne ranga me māyā</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Let my body not be adorned, By the hideous color of materialism</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo">Ranga de jhini Hari, Mā ke ranga me kāyā, (kāyā)</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>God (Hari) please color my body in the color of my Holy Mother </b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zcAvt3cDa0Y">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1349.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"The experience of God’s Love has been described in many books of ours but nobody believes in them.<br />
For example, when Prahlād, in whose presence Narasiṃha incarnated, was asked, “What do you want?” he replied,</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>“Tav Charaṇa arvinde prīti [The love of Your Lotus Feet]”<br />
that is “O God, give me the love of Your Lotus Feet.”</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0815 Havan, after Śhrī Yogeśhwara Pūjā, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/52724033"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Holi Khelat</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Śhrī Mā Hain Rang Raij Chunar Mori Rang</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mātājī Playing with Dandiya Sticks</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="Orange"><b>Āj Rang Hai Sahaj Ka</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Kṛiṣhṇa Govinda</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Wishing</b></font> <font color="Orange"><b>you</b></font> <font color="green"><b>all</b></font> <font color="red"><b>a</b></font> <font color="blue"><b>joyful</b></font> <font color="red"><b>H</b></font><font color="blue"><b>o</b></font><font color="blue"><b>l</b></font><font color="Orange"><b>ī</b></font><font color="red"><b>!!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Holika Dahana" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Birthday Pūjā: “The first gift you have to give is that you should express peacefulness through your own character.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/21" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Birthday Pūjā: “The first gift you have to give is that you should express peacefulness through your own character.”" /><published>2024-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/2024_03_21_Birthday_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/21"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Birthday of your Mother, and all such celebrations, have a very deep significance. Because on such occasions, special vibrations flow in the atmosphere.</b> When all the celestial bodies, the Eternal Personalities, Gods and Goddesses, s-s-sing the praise, and that's how the whole atmosphere is filled with mirth and happiness.<br />
Human beings also, express their gratitude. Expression of gratitude and love is done in different, different ways in different countries, but the substance remains the same and the forms change.<br />
The substance is like the ocean which flows continuously towards the shores, and the ripples which touch the shores are again repelled back, and a nice pattern is formed. It is such a spontaneous thing, and is so beautiful, creates such a beautiful pattern in the atmosphere. All these waves when they weave together the pattern of love, they soothe human beings, they enchant human beings, and the whole thing is very blissful.<br />
On such occasions a special type of feelings develop, which we cannot express in words so the expression could be in any form. But the main thing is the expression. <b>God has expressed Himself by Creation, by creating this Creation. While the Creation has to express its gratitude by glorifying Him, and this play must go on eternally. It's the most beautiful play.</b> Those who indulge into this play lead an eternal life. That life is unending, never breaks and binds the whole universe with its beautiful music. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0323 Birthday Pūjā, Guarding Against Slothfulness, Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan, 4A Castletown Road, London W14 9HE, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1342.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"This is what I have to tell you today, uh on this day where you are celebrating, that you celebrate your own birthday. Celebrate it! See for yourself what you have achieved and what you are going to achieve. Is time for you to celebrate than to celebrate My Birthday. I'll be very happy to celebrate your birthday than to celebrate My [Mine]."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0321 Birthday Pūjā (Hindi + English), New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shubh Mangalmay, Divas He Aya</b><br />
<font size="+0"><i>The Auspicious Benevolent Day has come</i></font><br />
<b>Ādi Śhakti, Swayam Hain Padhāri</b><br />
<font size="+0"><i>Ādi Śhakti has come Herself</i></font><br />
<b>Shubh Mangalmay, Divas He Aya</b><br />
<font size="+0"><i>The Auspicious Benevolent Day has come.</i></font><br />
Sur Nar Muni, Sab Jhoom Rahe Hain<br />
Aaj Prakriti Khil, Phul Rahi Hai<br />
Phool Khile, Bhanware Khag Mil Ke<br />
Rachaita Ke, Hi Gun Gaayen<br />
Shubhmangalmaye diwas hai āya</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You needed a Mother to look after you, to care for you and to be able to transform you with lot of wisdom. So every birthday I find that Sahaja Yogis are also expanding their hearts and realizing that they are no more drops but they are part and parcel of the Ocean.<br />
And that the Ocean itself is going to strengthen them and look after them. It's the Ocean that is going to nourish them. And the same Ocean is going to guide them. So the connection between a drop and an Ocean has to be fully established. So the limitations of a drop have to be absolutely dissolved into the greatness of the Ocean.<br />
<b>With care and with nice things to say we can improve the depth of the collectivity, and with sincere desire to be collective. The desire to be collective has to be very sincere.</b><br />
So, this expanse of your being will start.<br />
The first thing is needed: a sincerity to yourself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Ballroom, Curzon Hall, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1343.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>On My birthday today, I request you all to grow with Me. Grow in age. It means that you should become mature.</b> You have become one-pointed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0324 Birthday Pūjā (Hindi), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>O Param-pūjya Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī,<br />
Out of the Highest Realm of Divinity, You have come on this Earth only because of Your infinite love, compassion and benevolence.<br />
Your powers, which created all the universes, are insurmountable.<br />
Your completeness is such that everything that exists, that has existed and shall ever exist is contained within Your Indescribable Being.<br />
Despite that, O Supreme Mother, out of Your immeasurable love, You assumed a form similar to ours, to give us guidance, protection, and salvation </b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As you know, I have so many children all over the world, apart from the one[s] whom I actually physically gave birth. We have to think of all those, today, who are away from us, thousands of miles, praying to God Almighty for their spiritual ascent.<br />
One has to only pray for the spiritual ascent. Because as you ascend, you get all the rest of it.<br />
Because you do not ascend, you not ... you do not get what is needed. That's why there are problems. And even today I had to solve some problems before I could come to Pūjā.<br />
But if you decide that, 'We have to ascend spiritually within us,' then everything that you have to receive, all the blessings that God wants to shower upon you, to make you the citizen of His Great Kingdom, where you are no more judged, you are no more chastised, you are no more put to any test, but where you'll reside in Eternal Love of God and in His glory.<br />
......<br />
<b>First of all: you have to know you are Prophets and you must know that I am the Holy Ghost. I'm the Ādi Śhakti. I'm the one who has come on this Earth for the first time in this form to do this tremendous task. The more you will understand this, the better it will be. You will change tremendously.<br />
I knew I'll have to say that openly one day. And we have said it. But now it is you people who have to prove it, that I am that.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Sahaja Yogis Can't Afford to Have These Six Enemies, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1344.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mātājī Vandu Tav charna,</b></font><br />
Śhrī Mātājī, we bow to Your Lotus Feet<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nirmal he Vishwa apule</b></font><br />
You’ve created this faultless creation<br />
We have one request on this auspicious day Śhrī Mātājī<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Yoga tav.dila, Ashirvad. dya Amha</b></font><br />
And You have given us Sahaja Yoga to enjoy the life<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>*Apulya Janm. dina, Ashirvad. dya Amha</b></font><br />
On Your birthday, Let Your holy presence be in our hearts<br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tuts. Majha Janani, Vinati tav. Amuchi</b></font><br />
You are our Divine Mother<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>*Hya Shubhadini, Vinati tav. Amuchi</b></font><br />
On this auspicious day<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Amuchya Hridayat. Raho</b></font><br />
And we have a special request to You<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mangal. Murti hi Apuli </b></font><br />
May Your auspicious presence be felt<br />
In our hearts all the time.<br />
<font size="+0">Shri Mataji Vandu Tav. Charna</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font size="+0">Australian's presented this bhajan on occasion of 70th Birthday of Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
(* these lines to be sung on Shri Mataji's birthday)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Many people have always asked Me that why God created this Universe. Of course, we are not supposed to ask questions to God.</b> It's easy to ask questions to Mātājī when She is giving a lecture. But God is a person who is beyond questions. And why He created Universe is something like why I wore all these ornaments. As I am not habituated of wearing ornaments, but I have to do it. I have to do it just to please you people, or we can say that God created this Earth, just to please His own children, just to make them happy, just to make them enter into the Kingdom of God, to give all that what He has got.<br />
So He had to create this creation in such a way, that He could create His own image, reflect it, and make it enjoy itself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0330 Birthday Pūjā and Havan (English + Marathi), Birla Matushri Sabhagar, New Marine Lines, Churchgate, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b>RACHA PRABHU TUNEY YAHA BRAHMANDA SARA</b><br />
Oh God You have created the whole universe<br />
<b>PRANON SEY PYARA, BRAHMANDA SARA</b><br />
The whole universe is dearer than our lives<br />
<b>TUHI MAI BANDHU, TUHI JAGAT JANANI</b><br />
You are my Mother and brother, You are the Mother of the universe<br />
<b>SAKAL JAGAT MEIN YAH TERA PASARA</b><br />
The whole universe is but your formThe whole universe is but your form<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nice to see today so many Sahaja Yogis looking like beautiful lotus flowers, as the Blossom Time is filled with the fragrance of your beauty.<br />
<b>It is such a pleasure for Me to be your Mother, and to be able to communicate the Divine, the Powers of Divine, the Beauty of Divine, to you. It was never possible before, as you know. Everyone tried their level best, but nobody could achieve it, to communicate that beauty.</b><br />
As you know, Sahaja Yoga, or this Mahā Yoga, is a very unique system: it never existed before. It has come into existence, of course, I should say that because the Parabrahma decided to take a form, but you also all decided to come on this Earth to receive the blessings. It cannot be possible to do anything with one hand.<br />
The beauty of Sahaja Yoga is great, no doubt, which I'm sure, very soon people will realize. That this is the only way."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So today I am asking for two things from you. It is a funny thing that Mother has to ask for a gift.<br />
The first gift you have to give is that you should express peacefulness through your own character.</b> But it does not mean that you should be people who are timid, or people who are morbid or who tolerate nonsense. No, but the people who are peaceful resistance. You are not afraid of anything. You are not going to bow down to anything, compromise with anything, but you have that sort of a temperament you should develop and express -- is very important.<br />
<b>And the second one is that this peace and all this should express your love. Love to others.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0322 Birthday Pūjā (Marathi + English), Be Sweet, Loving and Peaceful, Sri Shanmukhananda Chandrasekarendra Saraswathi Auditorium, Vile Parle, Juhu, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1345.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"I bless you from My heart, bless you very much, that <b>you carry on your work of Sahaja Yoga, of spreading Sahaja Yoga, of giving Realization.</b> You have got powers. You know you have [got]. Only use that power and give Realization to people. <b>That is one promise you have to make on My birthday.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-0321 Birthday Pūjā (Hindi + English + Hindi), Nirmal Dham, Behind BSF Camp Chhawala, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>SAHAJACHI HA YOG. MALA TAV. KRUPE MIRALA</b><br />
By Your grace was I blessed with this Yoga so easily.<br />
<b>TAV. CHARANI LABHALA</b><br />
And at Your Lotus Feet, I received it.<br />
<b>ĀTM.RANGI MAN RANGE MEE BHAAV. MURI NA URE</b><br />
As my attention immerses in the depth of myself, I lose my I-ness.<br />
<b>NIJ. RUPACHA PRAKASH ANTARI PASARALA</b><br />
And the light of myself engulfs me from within.<br />
<b>UNMANI CHITTA HOT. DASHAM. DWARI STHAIRYA HOT.</b><br />
As the ecstatic attention now settles on the tenth door (brahmarandhra),<br />
<b>ANAHATACHA NAAD. SHRAVANASI ĀLA</b><br />
The unstruck sound (the original sound of the creation) becomes audible.<br />
<b>SARV. DEV. PRANIPATE LEEN. TAV. CHARANA TE </b><br />
All the Gods worship you, bowing themselves to Your Lotus Feet.<br />
<b>TAV CHARANACHA PRATYAY. AATM. RUPI ĀLA</b><br />
And it is these Lotus Feet that I now feel in Myself<br />
<b>SPANDAN TU KANAKANAT. CHAITANATA JANIVET</b><br />
You pulsate in every particle and are the living force of awareness.<br />
<b>TAV. RUPACHA PRABHAV. CHARACHARI PAHILA</b><br />
It is You who are expressing Yourself in the mobile and immobile forms.<br />
<b>TU ANADI TU APAAR AKSHAY. TU TU ANANT</b><br />
You are without beginning, You are infinite, You are without Ending, Eternal.<br />
<b>LABHO TAV. SAGUN. RUP. SATAT. MANAVALA</b><br />
Let the mankind be blessed by the presence of your Saguna Form forever</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Ballroom, Curzon Hall, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/577933944"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Janam. din. ayo, Ādiśhakti kā (1993-0320 Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī Birthday Felicitations)</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Adi Shakti's birthday has come!<br />
<b>Smaran. din. ayo, Nirmal. bhakti ka</b><br />
The day of recollection of Divine devotion has come!</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Matajila (1991-0406 Bhavasagara Puja, Brisbane)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Arpan Ye Tan Man Śhrī Mā Tere Charnan </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Powada</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vanadana Kare Vandana</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Chhindwara Mein</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: left"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1350.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="Red"><b>Happy</b></font> <font color="DarkGreen"><b>Birthday</b></font> <font color="FireBrick"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ayi ho Ma ham sab ke liye</b><br />
<font size="+0">You have come for our sake, O Mother</font><br />
<b>Bas ek bahane....aj ke din</b><br />
<font size="+0">Taking this very day as a pretext!</font><br />
<b>Aj ke din., Ma, aj.ke din</b><br />
<font size="+0">On this very day, O Mother, on this very day!</font><br />
<b>Bahe prem.hriday se jaha ke liye</b><br />
<font size="+0">Your heart is flowing with Love for the whole universe.</font><br />
<b>Barhe Yog Sahaj Ma</b><br />
<font size="+0">Let Sahaja Yoga prosper on this very day!</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Aj. Ke Din - Jab. Rat. Dhale</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/O3kudRDPf-E">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Birthday Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śivarātri Pūjā: “We pray to Lord Śhiva to look after our union.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/08" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śivarātri Pūjā: “We pray to Lord Śhiva to look after our union.”" /><published>2024-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-03-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/2024_03_08_Shivaratri_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/03/08"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"We have all assembled here to worship Lord Śhiva. <b>Śhiva Pūjā is a very great and special Pūjā.<br />
The ultimate aim of human beings is to attain that Śhiva Tattwa.</b><br />
Śhiva Tattwa is beyond the brain. It cannot be known through the brain. Till you have got your Self-realization you cannot know the Self, Ātmā or the Śhiva Tattwa.<br />
Too much falsehood, myth and blind faith has taken place in the name of Lord Śhiva.<br />
Till a person is self-realized he cannot know Lord Śhiva because his nature is such that to know Him, a person has first to attain that height where all the great virtues themselves enshrine within.<br />
......<br />
These Śhaktis reside within us through the Śhiva Tattwa.<br />
To attain the Śhiva Tattwa, Self-realization is essential. Kuṇḍalinī is the Śhakti and the chakras are the steps. One has to ascend all the steps to attain the Śhiva Tattwa.<br />
This is the revelation of all the Gods and Deities. This is Their job and They are completely absorbed in it. Unlike human beings, They do not think about themselves or their rank, etc. They are a part and parcel of Lord Śhiva. To facilitate human ascent to the Śhiva Tattwa is Their nature.<br />
They need not be lectured or told anything, They are completely submerged in Their task. They work in a karma. They do not think They are doing anything. They are thoughtless and unmindful for their powers, like sugar gives sweetness to food, but is unaware that it is sweet.<br />
Similarly, when Sahaja Yogis act, they are not aware of the Śhakti within which is behind their actions. If the consciousness comes that, 'I am the doer,' 'I am a leader,' etc. then you are not a Sahaja Yogi. Through Sahaja Yoga one becomes akarmi. He keeps performing without even remembering that he is doing anything. He does not even realize that he is loving though others find him very loving.
"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0219 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Kyukī Mānava kā Aṃtima Lakṣhya yahī hai kī Vo Śhiva Tattwa ko Prāpta Kare (The Ultimate Aim of Human Beings Is to Attain that Śhiva Tattwa), Tent, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1336.png" /></div>

<p style="color:Indigo; text-align:center;">
<b>Auṃ Śhivam Śhivakaram Śhantam Śhivakaram<br />
Śhivot-tamam Śhivamārga Pranetāram Pranatosmi Sadāśhivam</b><br />
Aum to the auspicious one, the bestower of auspiciousness, the one who is peace, who is the auspicious Spirit,<br />
The highest, most auspicious, and beautiful one, who is the path of auspiciousness, before whom everyone prostrates,<br />
I bow to the Lord God Almighty.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are going to do Pūjā to Śhiva, Śhrī Śhiva.</b><br />
As you know, Śhrī Śhiva is the reflection of Sadāśhiva within us. I've already told about the reflection. Sadāśhiva is the God Almighty, the One who sees the play of Ādi Śhakti. But He is the Father who is watching each one of His Creation, or Her Creation.<br />
His support to Ādi Śhakti is entirely, fully, strengthening. There's no doubt in His mind about the capability of the Ādi Śhakti. But when He finds that in the play of Ādi Śhakti, the people or the world as such, try to disturb Her or spoil Her work, then He gets into His wrathful mood, and He destroys all such people, and maybe, He destroys the whole world.<br />
On one side He's wrathful, no doubt, on the other side, He is the Ocean of Compassion and Joy. That's why, when He's reflected within us, we get our Self-realization, we get the light of our Spirit, and we get into the Ocean of Joy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0303 Śhivarātri Pūjā, Motivate Your Attention or God's Realization, Bundilla Scout Camp, 6 Baden Powell Pl, Winston Hills (35 kms E of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1337.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So it is important that you should join hands, work it out, the work of the Goddess so that Śhiva is happy and we create a new world of spirituality and beauty.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0209 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi + English), Pandal, opposite side from the Sahaja Yoga Temple, C-17, Shaheed Jeet Singh Marg, Block C, Qutab Institutional Area (behind Qutub Hotel), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we are ready to do Śhrī Śhiva's Pūjā.<br />
It is said about Śhrī Shivjī that He is very easy and very innocent. This is why it's very hard to know Him.<br />
<b>The work of Kuṇḍalinī is the work of Goddess. Goddess is the One who creates this universe and in the end She takes the form of Kuṇḍalinī and helps you to reach Śhrī Śhiva. When you worship Śhrī Śhiva you must remember that, `Did we have Śhrī Śhiva's qualities established within us or not?' That's why first of all we should understand the workings of Kuṇḍalinī.</b><br />
When Kuṇḍalinī is awakened, then foremost it heals your body to health because it is very important for the body to be healthy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0209 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi + English), Pandal, opposite side from the Sahaja Yoga Temple, C-17, Shaheed Jeet Singh Marg, Block C, Qutab Institutional Area (behind Qutub Hotel), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/image1338.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Tonight we have gathered here to do Śhrī Śhiva Pūjā. Those people who have a clean heart can only do Śhiva Pūjā. Those whose heart is not clean cannot do Śhiva Pūjā. It's a simple Principle of Śhrī Śhivarātri."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0317 Śhivarātri Pūjā, The Power of Love, Śhrī Śhiv Chhatrapati Sports Complex Stadium, Balewadi, Mahalunge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"When we worship Śhiva, we praise him. You are this you are that, you are that. When you worship Me also you praise Me, you are this. I am not aware of all that that you say. But you say all right, if you say so, it's all right. You are this you are that, the thousand names of Śhiva, thousand name of the Goddess, thousand name of Viṣhṇu. These are their names you are worshiping, what about you people, how many names you can have? Actually in the Pūjā when you take the names of these Śhaktis they also get awakened within, no doubt. After Pūjā you do feel that way but you don't utilize them. <b>So many people I've seen have come in the Pūjā and they have got that power within themselves, same powers. But by the time they are out, it's finished, it's gone.<br />
So, surrendering has another side: assumption. Assumption that I am a Sahaja Yogi and I can absorb all these powers within myself. So one side is surrendering. Why to surrender? To absorb. Automatically when you are surrendered you absorb. But once you have absorbed, then you should retain and assume within yourself, know that you have these powers.</b> There, where Sahaja Yogis fail more."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0314 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English + Hindi), Surrender, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>When Śhiva closes His eyes, He is called a destroyer</b> (saṃhārak). <b>He only is the state and He only is the laya [extinction], because He can be a state, He can also be laya</b> [extinction]. I had told you about Śhiva's place in Kuṇḍalinī Śhāstra. In a man's heart, He always enlightens like the light of a lamp. Because of which the knowledge of right-wrong, discretion remains awakened, which goes on forbidding us, `Don't do this, this is wrong, this is unrighteous. This is wrong, this is deceitfulness, this is is greed, this is pride, this is jealousy, this is adharm, this is below the dignity of a man, this is not worthwhile.' But the independence that a man has, is used by him very badly and he disregards Śhiva.<br />
Śhiva drinks the poison of the whole world. Whatever amount of poison is settled in our heart, aversion towards others, evil, etc., very impure thoughts, our heart becomes poisonous, when Śhiva awakens within us, He drinks that poison. Śhiva's food, His drink is poison, whatever intoxicating things are there, the intoxicants, etc., all that is injurious to consciousness is consumed (prāśhan) by Śhiva."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0216 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Śhivajī Ke Ūpara Sārā Saṃsāra Nirbhara Hai (The Whole World Is Dependent on Śhivajī), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1339.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We pray to Lord Śhiva to look after our Union. I surrender to You. Now Gaurī Kuṇḍalinī surrenders to the Spirit. We pray to Lord Śhiva to look after this. I forget everything else. I leave it in Your holy hands. You raise me up. I forget all that was in me before, just lift me up. You raise me up. Everything I have dropped out, no other desire but just lift me higher. Make me Your servant. The rest of it is not important. All the other manifestations of this desire are over. Now I am absolutely surrendered to You, my Spirit. Lift me higher and higher and higher. Away from all the thoughts and things that were not the Spirit. Make me complete Spirit.</b><br />
Forget all that was there. That elevation, that ascent becomes fast quick trip. A very fast thing. If you just try this every moment, anything that goes against the Spirit must be given up. And that Spirit is what? The pure desire.<br />
We have to be one with the Spirit, and all the rest is not important. You are in the beautiful Kingdom of God where all ugliness drops out like when the lotus opens out; all the mud drops out from it.<br />
<b>In the same beautiful way, let My children become fragrant beautiful offering to Lord Sadāśhiva.</b><br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Mātājī's prayer for the Spirit (left heart): prayer, praises and protocol, pg. 142</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0303 Śhivarātri Pūjā, Motivate Your Attention or God's Realization, Bundilla Scout Camp, 6 Baden Powell Pl, Winston Hills (35 kms E of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25606512"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gaiye Gaṇapati Jagvandan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tere hi Gun gate hai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hasat Ali</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhambho Śhaṅkara</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bolo Śhiv Śhiva Śhambhu Bam Bam Bam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bolo Śhiva Śhambhu Śhiva Śhaṅkara</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhiv Bhola Bhandari</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhiva Manasa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āya Mātā Ka Pujan Din Āya</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Śhiv Śhaṅkar</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkSlateBlue"><b>Śhiva Āratī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1340.png" /></div>

<p style="color:Indigo; text-align:center;">
<b>Auṃ Śhivam Śhivakaram Śhāntam Śhiv'ākaram</b><br />
Auṃ to the auspicious One, the bestower of auspiciousness, the One who is peace, who is the auspicious Spirit,<br />
<b>Śhivot-tamam Śhivamārga Pranetāram Pranatosmi Sadāśhivam</b><br />
The highest, most auspicious and beautiful One, who is the path of auspiciousness, before whom everyone prostrates,<br />
I bow to the Lord God Almighty.<br />
<br />
<b>We, the children, bow with complete devotion and adoration to the Sacred One who resides in the heart of Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī.<br />
From Him came the desire for our emancipation.</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shivaratri Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>