<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-11-02T08:51:28-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti.”" /><published>2023-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_24_Navaratri_Day_10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Don't worry about anything, just know that I am the Ādi Śhakti. That all the Powers of God and Goddesses and all that are within Me and they are within Me and they are all looking after you. But if that recognition is not there, they are not going to recognize you either.<br />
<b>So for today's Navarātri, I have to tell you that -- just try to keep in mind that today you are worshiping the Ādi Śhakti and not only Durgā.</b> And you are worshiping Durgā and all these Goddesses to thank them because, if they had not saved you that time, you had been so frightened, you would have become bad people and would not have been here. That is why we are thankful to them for saving us and giving us this protection at that time when we were very helpless.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1269.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Navy"><b>We should devote ourselves to that Devī<br />
Who resides at the center of our lotus hearts,<br />
Whose glory is like that of the rising sun,<br />
Whose face is pleasing,<br />
Who grants all boons and protection,<br />
Who is three-eyed, Who wears red clothes, and<br />
Who fulfills the desires of Her devotees.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti.</b> So today we are really going to worship the Ādi Śhakti. On one side the Ādi Śhakti is Mahākālī, on the other side She is Mahāsaraswatī, in the center She is Mahālakṣhmī, and also She is the Ambā, the one who is the Kuṇḍalinī. But She's also beyond that. She's Parāśhakti, She's beyond all the powers because She is the Generator of Power, so She has to be beyond all that. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you enter into the Kingdom of God. Then the Śhakti makes you sit on different beautiful positions, and some are sitting in the Heart of God, some are sitting in the Sahasrāra of God, in the Kingdom of God.</b><br />
Now you should assume your power. On Navarātri now, you should understand that it has now crossed the limit and now we are on the tenth position, where you must assume. I have told you many a times, now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God. You cannot judge God, you cannot say why She does that, why She does that, why He does that. You cannot say that -- that's different. But when you sit there, then it is not an assembly, it is not like a politician fighting, no; it is that you have entered into the Kingdom of God, blessed by God, looked after, protected, nourished, and made knowledgeable.<br />
......<br />
So Navarātri's -- <b>now, the tenth day of Navarātri, which is the most important for all of you, is where this Paramachaitanya has become active. And by its activity you should know it is become very powerful, and that now anybody who tries to be nasty with you, tries to trouble you -- "I don't have to worry at all." It will take care of it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1270.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... on this day of this Pūjā, <b>it's such a combination that it's the Dussehra, I am here and also you can call it the last day of the Devī Pūjā</b>. We have to see within ourselves, introspect, 'What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha</b><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma. Salutations to You! 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"><b>So today is Dussehra, is a very big day in India.</b> They say on this day Rāvaṇa was killed. He was the worst enemy of human beings, and he was killed. But whatever it is then, as a memory of that great man, Śhrī Rām, they celebrate today Dussehra. And on this day, they say, those who are duṣhṭas, means bad people or we can say negative, they are killed. Can you imagine? [Chuckles.]<br />
So this day is regarded as a very important day in India, and they make a big statue of Rāvaṇa. You all know who was Rāvaṇa, ...</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogis:</b> Yes, Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">... whom Śhrī Rāma killed. He was a horrible fellow and he took away the wife of Śhrī Rām, Sītā, by force. But she was such a chaste woman that he couldn't touch Her. He tried, he couldn't touch Her. He couldn't achieve any power over Her. On the contrary, She was very powerful.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1271.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"That's why I have to tell you that on this day of Dussehra, let us decide that we are going to have Rām Rāj in Sahaja Yoga, where there is benevolence, there is love, compassion, security, peace, joy, discipline among ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau manasā smarāmi</b></font><br />
I worship the feet of Shri Rama-chandra in my heart.<br />
Shrī Rāma-chandra charanau vachasā gṛunāmi<br />
Through my songs and prayers I praise the feet of Shri Rama-chandra.<br />
Shrī Rāma-chandra charanau shirasā namāmi<br />
I bow at the feet of Shri Rama-chandra.<br />
Shrī Rāma-chandra charanau sharanam prapadye<br />
I surrender at the feet of Shri Rama-chandra.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Shri Rama-raksha stotram)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76751298"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/dSIEMZflZa0">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Ayi Re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/BUcvc6e_9-E">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Mangala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kindle My Heart</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Raghu Pati Raghav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Man Ram Rangi Rangle By Bhimsen Joshi</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/o-_qx6VXMA4">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1272.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>When you offer Me flowers or anything else like water then the elements are happy, and the Deities are happy within their chakras so that they emit vibrations of their qualities and their blessings upon you.</b> They will give you their qualities and their blessings because this is how the Divine acts, and gradually after a Pūjā you will feel the whole thing is working out."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0524 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, The Importance of Pūjā, House of Juan Antonio Delgado, Madrid, Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>I've told you before also but again today I want to tell you the significance of Pūjā. The significance is this: that when you do the Pūjā you recognize Me. By your recognition, and your surrendering, the Deities get happy.</b> They're overjoyed that you have recognized it, you are fully identified yourself, that you are understanding Me in My full form, that you are coming closer to Them. Like elder brothers feel happy when the younger ones are coming to meet them. So, They start releasing My vibrations with a greater force, much greater force.<br />
You have seen that after Pūjā, sometimes when you do not absorb the vibrations, I get little tired because the vibrations start coming out of all the chakras and you do not absorb, so the give-and-take process is not balanced.<br />
The identification in the West is very slow because of mental activity. Your attachment to your mental activity and to your rationality is very great. With Pūjā, the vibrations try to detach you from your mental activity, from your rationality. And then you ... you are station into the Realm of Divine Existence."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0420 Pūjā, Significance of Pūjā, Flat of Marie Rouger, 175 Av. Ledru Rollin, 11th Arrondissement, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/23" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation.”" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_23_Navaratri_Day_9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/23"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is <b>the last day of Navarātri</b>. And this should be the culminating point for all of us. As you see, within us lie, as you know that there are seven chakras for you ascent and two above it. So all these Nine Chakras are to be crossed in this lifetime. That should be your destiny.<br />
But if you people go only on the Āgñyā move on Āgñyā, you cannot rise any higher. People have been lost on that chakra. So, that's a very important chakra for ......<br />
Sixth, Ṣhaṣhṭhī of the Goddess, is regarded as a very important thing and they say that, `Goddess comes on a nāv,' on a boat, Calcutta [Kolkata] people believe it because the sixth day is very big to cross it. That is what today is the problem with all of us that we have this sixth day still sitting on our heads and we cannot get out it. So to come to the ninth stage, though we may do Pūjā, we may do anything, but we are still on the sixth. So it is just outwardly that we are doing Pūjā. Seventh day is the day, where I am there. But 7th and 8th and 9th has to be achieved by crossing your sixth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nav Durgā Kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1265.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogi [reads]:</b> <font color="Maroon"><b>What is Your prowess to be compared to? Where can one find this beauty (of Yours) most charming, (yet) striking fear in enemies? Compassion in heart and relentlessness in battle are seen, O Devī, O Bestower of boons, only in You in all the three worlds!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Comments on the Reading from Devī Māhātmyam, before the Talk on the Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Siddhidātrī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Siddhidātrī, the One who is the bestower of Siddhis (Divine Powers), Salutations to You!
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you are worshiping today the Durgā, or all the nine forms of the Goddess.</b> She came nine times on this Earth, according to this, that She fought all the people who were destroying the seekers, who were trying to make a mess of their lives. And these tortured Saints, when they prayed to the Goddess -- because none of the Gods could do anything, and Sadāśhiva is never interfering with what the Goddess is doing -- so they worshiped the Bhagavatī, and then the Incarnation of Hers came nine times, according to the need of the time."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1266.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"The siddhis that people attempt to achieve are: Aṇima, Laghima, Mahima, Īśhatva, Vaśhitva, Prākāmya, Bhukti, Icchā, Prāpti, Mukti. Aṇima is to become like a small particle. Laghima is to become small, Mahima is to have a big form, Īśhatva is to create Gods out of human beings, Vaśhitva is the attraction, Prākāmya is the manifestation, Bhukti is the enjoyment, [Icchā] fulfillment of desire. Prāpti is the attainment, Mukti is the salvation.<br />
<b>These are all the siddhis that Sahaja Yogis can have."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0907 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Bīja Mantras, Śhrī Lalitā, Śhrī Chakra, 56 Ashley Gardens, Ambrosden Avenue (near Victoria Station), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"These are the things you must understand. Why are you doing that and try to get rid of it and try to improve yourself, be alert and to receive it. Receive it as much as you can. This is what is the Pūjā is made for.<br />
Now you have had nine Pūjās here and out of these nine Pūjās have we improved more, have we got more? Did we fill ourselves more with greater love, with greater joy, with greater understanding and with greater satisfaction?<br />
<b>This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation.</b> Because we have done what? That is what. So today you should go and make a complete picture of yourself. What have I got in these nine days? What have I got? Let us see, have I got this? Have I got that? All these things, you should just within yourself see and then enjoy that you have got all these things. It is the victory. Tomorrow is the day of victory. That you have become victorious about yourself and about your ignorance."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1267.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"This Pūjā is very special, many will go deep and receive tremendous blessings. But first make your attention steady. In your attention pray for peace, 'Mother, please bestow peace upon me.' <b>Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe. Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/251307065"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Devī Sūktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/K7he8axOgfw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Durgā Ādi Śhakti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/IZxG3j1wUyE">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī playing harmonium as Sahaja Yogis sing Devī Bhajans</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1268.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... 'God has given you so much, why should you try to show that you haven't got anything?' Just to show off that you have not got anything, God has given.<br />
<b>This is just a sort of a thanksgiving to God that, 'God, you have given me so much.' You have to wear the best, like in Pūjā if you see ladies here wear all their nose rings and all their ornaments and everything, in the temple</b>, everything they wear, and in the same way, men also wear their very clean dresses, very clean things, whatever they have, they wear simple clean dresses, whatever they have but no ostentatious, it is just a thing by which you express. <b>The God has given this, 'O God, I thank you.'</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0101 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Mahālakṣhmī Principle of Our Ascent (Try to Develop that Innocence which Is the Basis of Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa and Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa Is Strengthened through Guru Principle), Nirmalā Kuṭīr (Cottage), Lakṣmī Nārāyaṇa Mandir, Shahupuri, Kolhapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>We should devote ourselves to that Devī<br />
Who resides at the center of our lotus hearts,<br />
Whose glory is like that of the rising sun,<br />
Whose face is pleasing,<br />
Who grants all boons and protection,<br />
Who is three-eyed, Who wears red clothes, and<br />
Who fulfills the desires of Her devotees.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, you have to understand that you cannot rationalize the Pūjā. You should have the maximum advantage on your chakras.</b> For that, you must fully just concentrate on the Pūjā and how the Wind is blowing. And the Wind will see to it that they drive out all the clouds.<br />
So your only work is, or your only method is just to concentrate on the Pūjā and witness. You are a Seer. Seer has double meaning. The one who sees only, just sees, and is only knowledge is a Seer. Without any thought, without any reaction, just sees and absorb[s] automatically, spontaneously -- is the Seer. And so, that is the best way to perform a Pūjā.<br />
For Me sometimes it's burdensome, because there should be some parity between you and the Deities. Some balance must be there."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0618 Havan, Importance of Pūjā and Havan, before Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā, Garden, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Siddhidatri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “It’s only at the behest of the bhaktas that the Goddess took Her form and killed all these rākṣhasas.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/22" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “It’s only at the behest of the bhaktas that the Goddess took Her form and killed all these rākṣhasas.”" /><published>2023-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_22_Navaratri_Day_8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/22"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the eighth day of Navarātri, but it is great day for Sahaja Yogis because it is the most important period.</b> That is, the seventh center we have crossed and we are on the eighth center. We need not think of the Goddess what She did on the eighth day, we have to think today what we have to do within ourselves.<br />
After crossing the seventh day, after crossing the seventh chakra -- that is the real ascent in your spiritual ascent. What are we to do on the eighth one?<br />
It's so Sahaja that today should be Aṣhṭamī, because that is the day the Goddess killed so may evil doers, and demons and rākṣhasas. She did it on Her own, alone. Now these evil forces are manifesting in human beings. They have spread out. They are within us. So we all have to fight those forces within us. The war is within ourselves, is not without. First when you ascend the seventh chakra, when you are on the eighth step, you have to remember first you have to fight those forces within ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0930 Aṣhṭamī Pūjā (8th Day of Navarātri), Discipline Has to Be Sahaja (What We Have to Do within Ourselves), Complexe Sportif René Leduc, 12 Rue du Père Brottier, Meudon (12 kms SW of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1261.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Salutations to the Devī, to the Mahādevī.<br />
Salutations always to Her who is ever auspicious.<br />
Salutations to Her who is the primordial cause of the sustaining power. With attention, we have made obeisance to Her.<br /> 
Salutations to Her who is terrible, to Her who is eternal.<br />
Salutations to Gaurī, the supporter of the universe.<br />
Salutations only to Her who is of the form of the moon and moonlight, and happiness itself.<br />
We bow to Her who is welfare.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Tu Hi Durgā, Tu Hi Kālī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are Durga, You are Kālī</font><br />            
<font color="Indigo"><b>Tu Hi Chaṇḍī Bhavānī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are Chaṇḍī Bhavānī</font><br />             
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mā Nirmalā kī Jay Bolo, Jay Bolo!</b></font><br /> 
<font size="+0">Let us say Nirmalā Mā kī Jay!</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Dush.Man. Chal.Ko Chal.Ne Wali</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are destroying the plans of our foes</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Bhakto kī Kalnyani</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are taking care of the benevolence of Your devotees</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mā Nirmalā kī Jay Bolo, Jay Bolo!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Let us say Nirmalā Mā kī Jay!</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... today we do, is a very great Pūjā of Aṣhṭamī [eighth day]: is the day when the Goddess killed nine rākṣhasas together with Her eight hands. <b>So today is a very special day for which a very special attention is needed.<br />
It's only at the behest of the bhaktas that the Goddess took Her form and killed all these rākṣhasas.<br />
Also with Her eight hands, She killed Mahiṣhāsura.</b> That's why She's called as Mahiṣhāsuramardinī.<br /> 
She's called as Nava Chaṇḍī, one who has killed nine chaṇḍas, means nine rākṣhasas She has killed.<br /> 
So is a very important day and very vital and very deep."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0201 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1262.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b>O Goddess of the Universe,<br />
You are looking after the Universe.<br />
You support the Universe, as it is Your own form.<br />
O Devi, The Lord of the Universe bow before You.<br />
Those Who are humble before You with devotion provide shelter to the Universe.</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"And on an Aṣhṭamī, that is today, is the eighth day of the Moon, of the Moon which is increasing, Śhuklapakṣhi, that first time all the weapons of the Goddess are to be worshiped. This was a great idea because these weapons who work all the time, not only to kill the evil but to protect the good, were never worshiped before. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="Red"><b>"Today is the eighth day of the Devī Pūjā. And on this day the Power of Kālī acts and She is the One called as Saṃhāra Kālī, meaning the One who uh uh destroys all the evil forces.<br />
......<br />
On an Aṣhṭamī Day: 'Let us finish all this negativity and let us become that special type of people who are worshiped all over.' All right?<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1007 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (8th Day of Navarātri), Sahaja Yoga Style and We are Sahaj Yogis of the God's Kingdom (We Are the Makers of Styles and Let Us Finish All this Negativity and Let Us Become that Special Type of People Who Are Worshiped All Over), before the Evening Program, the day before Navarātri Pūjā, Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You have to see that all the negativity goes away, around us, around the universe.<br />
<b>So first we sing the praise of the Goddess; when She destroyed every negative, satanic incarnation of Mahiṣhāsura.</b><br /> 
And when he was killed, all the Gods praised Her for saving them from the ... from the destruction, and that happened long, long time back -- it was ten thousand years back. So this is the praise of the Gods of that so that, whatever is the negativity, through those mantras will go away, because it surrounds us -- you see that, all of them have been there coming; from ten thousand years they have been coming. But this is the way you can throw them out of the present into their proper places."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1012 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (4th Day of Navarātri), Winterthurerstraße, Zürich, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini Nandit. Medini</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O beloved Daughter of the mountains, the One who brings about great joy to the earth</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Vishw. Vinodini Nandinute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">The One who brings joy to the whole universe, I I prostrate myselg before You Who are the form of complete bliss</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Girivar. Vindhya Shirodhini Vasini</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Your holy abode is in the king of the mountains, the Vindhyas</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Viṣhṇu Vilasini Viṣhṇu Nute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Viṣhṇu is filled with joy when He meditate on You, I seek refuge at Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay. Jay. Hai Mahiṣhāsuramardinī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Victory to You O Great Goddess
Who killed the terrible demon, Mahiṣhāsura</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Ramyak. Par.dini Shailasute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are the One with the beautiful luminous face, Daughter of the king of the Mountains,
Śhrī Pārvatī, the Wife of the One who has the matted locks, that is Lord Śhiva</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lAojYxfnKMs">Ayi Giri Nandini (Mahiṣhāsuramardinī)</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"All of you, all of you, are in My Heart, and I love you very much, and I want you people to come as soldiers to fight with Me.<br />
I am also told that there are some people who are forming groups -- extremely negative attitude! At this time what we need is complete solidarity. So all such people whom you see, tell them to behave themselves! No use making them Sahaja Yogis.<br />
I am sure -- it's really heartfelt desire of Mine that you should become really soldiers of love and peace. Because that is why you are here, you are born here for that.<br />
So enjoy yourself. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), You Should Become Really Soldiers of Love and Peace (Overcome Hatred with Love or To Hate is a Very Bad Quality), Sportcamp, Avras, Loutraki, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1263.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>He Mahādevī, He Kalyāṇī,</b></font><br />
O Great Goddess, You are the benefactress<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Dushto Ka Samhar. Karo</b></font><br />
Please kill the the devils and bad people<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mangal.May Var.Dan Do Maiya,</b></font><br />
Mother give us the auspicious blessings<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Bhav. Se Beda Par. Karo, Mā</b></font><br />
Take us away from the illusions<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Bhav. Bhakti Me Sharanan. Ae</b></font><br />
We have come to Your Lotus Feet with our devotions<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Bin.ti Ma Swikar. Karo</b></font><br />
Please accept our prayers<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Teri Jayjaykar. Ho</b></font><br />
We pay our salutations to You!<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font color="IndianRed"><b>We pray to the Supreme Goddess today<br />
<i>O Devi, O Mahadevi, please protect us.</i></b><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāgaurī Mātā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font>
&lt;/p&gt;

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font> 
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), You Should Become Really Soldiers of Love and Peace (Overcome Hatred with Love or To Hate is a Very Bad Quality), Sportcamp, Avras, Loutraki, Greece</b></font>
<a href="https://vimeo.com/25792785"> video</a><br />

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Mahātmyam Eighth Night</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1264.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Now you want to give Me a sāṛī. <b>In Marathi it is called as 'pot zakaych', means they're covering the womb of the Goddess, the stomach of the Mother.</b> 'Because She's put us there, She has given us birth, so we must give Her something to cover it,' is a very humble way of saying it. Now you give Me a sāṛī -- I don't know when I'm going to wear all these, but whatever it is -- just give Me a sāṛī with a feeling, and maybe I may never wear it, I may wear it also. <b>But the progeny will see what you have given to your Mother. I'm not going to carry it with Me, nobody's going to carry the matter with them. But it had a purpose, it had a meaning, it had emotions behind it. It was given in a Pūjā when so many people gathered, you gave to your Mother.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0503 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before, during and after the Evening Program after Sahasrāra Pūjā, Thredbo Village, Kosciuszko National Park, New South Wales, Australia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mazhya Manichi Ga, Mazhya Manichi Manas. Puja,</b><br />
With all their devotion and love they worship You,<br />
<b>Preme Arpili Asht.bhuja</b><br />
Out of love, they make this offering to the eight-handed Goddess:<br />
<b>Khana Nar.lachi Ga, Khana Nar.lachi Oti Tula,</b><br />
They offer coconut and an embroidered silk cloth as 'Oti' (asking for blessings)<br />
<b>Bhakt. Yetil. Dar.shanas</b><br />
Devotees all come to receive Your Darshan</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Māhūra Gaḍāvarī</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/EWoUoau4BOw">video</a><br />
<font size="+0">(Saundaryalaharī by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"We have to today understand that, 'Why do we do Devī Pūjā? What is the reason for this Devī Pūjā? What do we get out of it? What are we supposed to achieve in our contents within ourselves?'<br />
The first thing is that Kuṇḍalinī is the Devī. She's the reflection of the Ādi Śhakti. So when you worship Devī, first you worship also your own Kuṇḍalinī by giving Her credit because She has given you this Realization. It's much deeper understanding than normally people have about the Devī Pūjā because they are not realized Souls. Their Kuṇḍalinī not is awakened. <b>So normally when they do Devī Pūjā it's for the purpose of getting Realization so that the Devī should be pleased -- prasanna -- and should give them Realization, or must get our chance to get to somebody who will give them Realization.</b> But you are at a different level now. So it's more of a thanksgiving to your own Kuṇḍalinī and to Ādi Śhakti, glorifying that whatever has happened so miraculously is because of the Kuṇḍalinī which was within you, which was reflected by the Ādi Śhakti.<br />
But one has to know that only we are realized Souls is not the point, only that we can feel the vibrations is not the point, that we can give Realizations to other is also not the point. Then what is it? Very important -- it's the content within us. What do we have within us is the point. These are all the expressions of what we have within."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1008 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 8th Day and 9th Day), The Content Within (How Deeply You Have Touched the Feet of the Divine), Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>
</font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Mahagauri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “…… seventh day to celebrate the Incarnations of these Seven Powers …… and to give them the vision of God.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/21" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “…… seventh day to celebrate the Incarnations of these Seven Powers …… and to give them the vision of God.”" /><published>2023-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_21_Navaratri_Day_7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/21"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the Seventh Day of the Goddess when She incarnated on this Earth in Her Seventh Incarnation.</b> On this day She incarnated again and again on this land, around this area, seven times. And She is being expressed through the exuberance of the Mother Land. That She has created all the temples which have come out of the Mother Earth spontaneously.<br />
The seven of these represent the seven chakras of the Sahasrāra, the Śhaktis of the chakra ... of Sahasrāra.<br />
<b>So we are so fortunate today to be here on the seventh day to celebrate the Incarnations of these Seven Powers: of these Seven Powers which came on this Earth to give protection to the whole world, to look after the Saints, and to give them the vision of God.</b><br />
They have killed so many devils and rākṣhasas, and established the blissful, innocent life here.<br />
God looks after the innocent. He loves only the innocent and not the ones who are cunning, who are troublesome. He goes a little way towards people who are not so good as these are, tries to save them, to help them, but up to a point. Then it gives up.<br />
This is what has happened in this area before also. They were many kings who ruled these areas where they were people who worshipped the Goddess and lived a righteous, innocent life. And those who tried to insult the Mother perished forever and ever."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India]</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1257.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b>Te devā abruvana - Namo Devyai Mahādevya shivāi satatam namah.<br />
Namah prakrutyai Bhadrāyai niyatāh prantāh sm-tām.</b><br />
The Gods spoke thus, Salutations to the Great Goddess, the bestower of auspiciousness.<br />
We all humbly surrender and obeise to the Prakruti (mother of the entire creation).<br />
One who bestows benedictions and rules over the entire world.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we have gathered here to do the Devī Pūjā.<br />
This Pūjā was performed many a times and the Devī was requested by the Devas to save them from the tyranny of devilish people. <b>Today I feel the same way, that we are now in the grip of a funny situation; that there are people who are themselves devils, I think, -- and also [who are] mesmerized by them -- who are trying to do something which they should never have done. But they don't know that there is a climax of everything. And that point has arrived where all the good people, especially the Sahaja Yogis should put all their mind to the destruction of these horrible personalities like Mahiṣhāsura.</b><br />
In those days, it was very simple because devils came as devils and you could see them, that they are devils, and all their behavior proved that they were devils. Why they did it? Why were they cruel? Because so-called 'human beings' as they are -- they are not -- they are by nature devilish and they want to do something by which they can destroy human beings, and good human beings. It is evident that the time has come for them to be destroyed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), You Should Become Really Soldiers of Love and Peace (Overcome Hatred with Love or To Hate is a Very Bad Quality), Sportcamp, Avras, Loutraki, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1258.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b>Tāmagnivarnā tapasā jwalanti. Vairochanim karma faleshu jushtām.<br />
Durgā Devim sharanam prapadyā mahe asurannash yitraye te namah.<br />
We all surrender to Dévi Durga.</b><br />
Who is having the complexion like the flames of burning fire,<br />
who is resplendent with the knowledge, who rewards the actions.<br />
Salutations to the destroyer of demons.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So for today's Navarātri, I have to tell you that ... <b>just try to keep in mind that today you are worshiping the Ādi Śhakti and not only Durgā</b>. And you are worshiping Durgā and all these Goddesses to thank them because, if they had not saved you that time, you had been so frightened, you would have become bad people and would not have been here. That is why we are thankful to them for saving us and giving us this protection at that time when we were very helpless.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... Mahākālī and Mahāsaraswatī, both are the Powers of Śhrī Sadāśhiva. Ādi Śhakti first formed Herself into Mahākālī, which is the Power of Desire. But all these powers are nothing but the Power of God's Love. So, in the series of this Great Love of God, Ādi Śhakti had to first become the Power of Desire.<br />
In the same way, <b>Sahaja Yogis who are bestowed with this Power of Love have to have full desire in their heart. Desire to love. That desire is very different from the other kinds of human love we have known.</b> In other kinds of human love, when we have relations with others, we have expectations, and that's why it is very disappointing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1259.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Kālarātri Braham stutām vaishnavi skanda mātaram.<br />
Saraswatim-aditim-daksha-duhitaram namāmah pāvnam śhivām.<br />
Salutations to the Goddess, who is the last night, who is praised by Brahmadeva,<br />
who is the power of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, the mother of Śhrī Kārttikeya, Śhrī Saraswatī, Śhrī Aditi (Mother of Gods), the daughter of Dākṣha and the consort of Śhrī Śhiva.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jaya Tvam Devī Chāmuṇḍe jaya bhū-tāpa-hāriṇi,<br />
Jaya Sarva-gate Devī Kālarātrī namostute</b>
Victory be to You, O Devi Chamunda,<br />
Victory be to You Who destroys the suffering of all living beings.<br />
Victory be to You, O Devī Who is present everywhere.<br />
Salutations to you O Kālarātrī (the longest night)&lt;/b&gt;</font><br />
(from Argala Strotram)<br />
<font color="Brown"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kālarātrī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<b>O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Kālarātrī, the One who is the dark night of dissolution, Salutations to You!</b>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1008 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 8th Day and 9th Day), The Content Within (How Deeply You Have Touched the Feet of the Divine), Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/72573127"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parameśhwarī Bhagavatī Nirmalā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ajit Kadkade Rāg Durgā Heart Anahata Chakra</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HgN42YkSHkY">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhavānī Aṣhṭakam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/JQ3ibqZWgDI">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mahāmāyā Mahākālī, Jay Śherawālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Durgā Chalisa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/h8LHLwZHCQM">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1260.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> <font size="+0"><font color="DarkGreen"><b>You are the Queen of the Universe. And we are Your devotees, we are Your disciples. So if we are allowed to crown You, it means that we have to have complete adherence, allegiance and surrender.</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Dussehra Day), before, during and after the Evening Program, after Śhrī Rāma Pūjā, Centre International, Les Avants, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>But this Pūjā is to be done with full understanding, and with full recognition that it's a great fortune.</b> Even the Devas are jealous of you, all the Ṛiṣhis are jealous of you, so many people are jealous of you. The greatest advantage for you, greatest fortune. Make full use of it. And they are very simple things that can please, very simple. You know your Mother can be pleased with very, very simple things. It's like that only. It's how much heart you have put into it, is the point. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kalaratri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Worship of the Śhakti means that there will be a Pūjā of all the Śhaktis of the Devatās.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/20" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Worship of the Śhakti means that there will be a Pūjā of all the Śhaktis of the Devatās.”" /><published>2023-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_20_Navaratri_Day_6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/20"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This is a <b>worship of the Śhakti</b>. Until now many Saints, Sages have known and revealed about this Śhakti. Whatever they could not describe in prose, they tried to convey by poetry. Whatever description was not possible to put in words -- they composed different names of the Devī and described. We know all this and many people also know the meaning of this. But one thing they perhaps do not know is that <b>every human being has all these śhaktis, powers dormant in them and they can awaken them. These dormant powers are eternal and limitless</b>.<br /> 
Besides the thirty-three crores of Devas, there are many Śhaktis. But we can say that this Self-realization that we have achieved today, has been achieved through working of some Śhakti or the other. Without this you could not have achieved the Self-realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1016 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (6th Day), Hamāre Jīvana kā Lakṣhya (The Aim of Our Lives), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1253.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Red">"<b>Navarātri is the day to give you the balance.</b> Those whose right hand is tired will get the power in the left hand. Those who have the left hand tired will get the power on the right hand to share the load."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today it's such a great day for Me to be with you all, again this year. It's so very joyous and full of fragrance. Today we have decided to have a Pūjā of Śhakti that is the Power, that is the Devī. You know within us there are many Powers of Mahākālī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahālakṣhmī, Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
All these Powers are there for us to ascent. If these Powers are properly used and understood, then your ascent can be permanent. Once you achieve your ascent and enter into the Kingdom of God, all these Powers get enlightened.<br />
And these Powers which are enlightened are absolutely filled with Love. Enlightenment, we have to understand that we get completely enlightened by Love. So after enlightenment, <b>after Realization we use only one Power which is of Love</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1254.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"><b>[Explains that Kattyayeni (Kātyāyanī) killed the demon Kolhāsur and this is why Kolhapur is called as such.]</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0300 Conversation with K.T. Tan with a Handwritten Line, during a Meal, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kātyāyanī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<b>O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Kātyāyanī, the One who is the foster-daughter of Sage Kātyāyana, Salutations to You!</b>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we are having this Pūjā of the Śhakti and I want you to understand that this Śhakti belongs to you. With this you are going to be sincere and true Sahaja Yogis.<br />
......<br />
I bless you today that all your dormant śhaktis will get awakened, gradually you will feel them and the flow of these śhaktis that are within you will bring the joy and many blessings to you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1016 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (6th Day), Hamāre Jīvana kā Lakṣhya (The Aim of Our Lives), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we have gathered to do Pūjā of the Śhakti.<br />
Śhakti means all the Śhaktis and not any one special śhakti. All these Śhaktis are situated on all our chakras and without these Śhaktis no work of the Devatās can be carried out. Like you know that the Śhakti of Kṛiṣhṇa is Rādhā and Rām's Śhakti is Sītā, Viṣhṇu's is Lakṣhmī. So in the same way the abode of the Śhaktis is with the Devatās. <b>The Devatās cannot do anything without the Śhakti. That sole Śhakti is situated in the center Heart as Jagadambā. This Jagadambā Śhakti is very powerful. You know that She lives as a mother or a wife with the Devatās. Worship of the Śhakti means that there will be a Pūjā of all the Śhaktis of the Devatās.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-1231 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi + English + Marathi), The Śhakti Within You Wants to Be Loving, Kind, and Generous, Kalwa, Thane, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>May this benevolent face of Yours, adorned with three eyes, protect us from all terror.<br />
O Kātyāyanī, we bow to You.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Etathe vadanam saumyam</b><br />
May this benign countenance of yours,<br />
<b>Lochana-traya bhushitam</b><br />
Adorned with three eyes,<br /><br />
<b>Patu nah sarva bhuti-bhyah</b><br />
Protect us from all the fears<br />
<b>Kātyāyanī namostute</b><br />
Salutations be to You, O Kātyāyanī</font><br />
<b>Sarva Mangala</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1255.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>To all devotees and followers of truth, who have assembled here for the Pūjā, I offer My protection.</b><br />
In this Kali Yug of today, when so much devotion and homage for the Mother, and so much love comes into the hearts of human beings, then we can know that Satya Yuga has begun.<br />
This is a most fortunate and divine coincidence for Me also, that on a Ṣhaṣhṭhī Day I came to Kolkata [arrival on 196-1009]. Because, in the Śhāstras it is written that the coming of the Mother is always on Ṣhaṣhṭhī Day. <b>Ṣhaṣhṭhī Day is of Śhākambharī Devī</b>, and on that day the whole nature should be green and lush. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1010 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (7th Day), Lions Club Safari Park, Southern Avenue, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>AMBE TU PĀRVATĪ PARAMEŚHWARĪ<br />
MAHALAKSHMI TU SAPTAŚHṚIṄGĪ TU JAY JAY ŚHĀKAMBHARĪ</b><br />
You are Mahālakṣhmī, You are Saptaśhṛiṅgī, Victory to Śhākambharī (The Bearer of the Greens)<br />
<b>JAY JOGEŚHWARĪ JAY MAHEHŚWARĪ JAY JAY PRAṆEŚHWARĪ</b><br />
Victory to Jogeśhwarī (Goddess of Yoga), Victory to Maheśhwarī (Goddess of Shri Shiva), Victory to Praṇeśhwarī (Goddess of vital breath)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1020 Havan, Blessed Are Those Who Are Sahaja Yogis, the day after Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Rūtli Kaltbad Mountain, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/117133344"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute Bhagavatī Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durge Durgati Pariharini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/F68hoY8ZhOI">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1256.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Belgium has a speciality that it creates glass bangles for the Mother. That is, <b>the bangles which are used as a beautiful musical accompaniment to the gait, to all the movements of the Goddess.</b> It brings a delicacy in a woman; and gives a consciousness to the man or the men that there are ladies around. And the ladies are around who are married ladies, are very auspicious. And this auspiciousness is the one that is going to bring in this country or in any country whatsoever all the blessings.<br />
<b>Also in Sanskrit language a bangle is called as valaya, and that is the last stage which one has to reach in one's ascent. That means the complete.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0921 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Śhrī Jaldevatā, Oude Stadsfeestzaal, Mechelen (27 kms S of Antwerp), Belgium</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now for Pūjā, one has to understand. But without Realization, Pūjā has no meaning. Because you are not ana-nya. Means: you have to become aware of your whole.</b><br />
Kṛiṣhṇa's description of bhakti is ananya. He says, ``I will give you Ananya Bhakti," He wants Ananya Bhakti, means when there is not the other, means when we are realized.<br />
Otherwise He says ``Puṣhpaṃ, phalaṃ, toyaṃ" [part of Bhagavad Gītā 9.26, line 1], <b>"A flower, a fruit and a water: whatever you give me I accept." But when it comes to giving, He says, ``You have to come to Me with Ananya Bhakti," means: when you have become one with Me, then you should have the devotion, not before that. Before that, you are not connected.</b><br />
Now Pūjā is the left-hand side projection. It's the neutralization of the right side, very much. Specially for people who are very right-handed, atmosphere which is very right-handed, <b>Pūjā is</b> ideal for them. <b>Is the bhakti, is the devotion ... that you project.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Katyayani" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “This is called as Sacred Heart in the Bible. She resides as Jagadambā.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “This is called as Sacred Heart in the Bible. She resides as Jagadambā.”" /><published>2023-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_19_Navaratri_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/19"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we are going to do Pūjā for Navarātri.<br />
Yesterday you saw, beautiful description of Navarātri and how the Mother Goddess has created all kinds of powers within you. It's not that only She has the powers, but you all have the powers, and you can all work it out, you can all find out whether these powers are there or not.<br />
<b>With us, the Realization is very important, but there the Kuṇḍalinī has given you this Realization. Of course Kuṇḍalinī is a part or, we can say, reflection of Ādi Śhakti, and also the Jagadambā is also part of Ādi Śhakti.</b><br />
She's placed in the center of two hearts, which is a very important point. Now all these powers are placed in that chakra. So you imagine how many of these powers must be there, and Her Powers are expressed through the center Heart in all the gaṇas you have around your body. Now these gaṇas are the ones who do give you the protection, give you the sleep, give you the energy, give you the blessings. All of them are at work all the time, and these bodies are extremely dedicated and connected all the time to the Mother Ambā, we can call Jagadambā. Now She is the Mother of the Universe, so you can imagine, how busy She has to be to look after the whole Universe! "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1009 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), Innocence (Fearlessness) and Enlightened Faith, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1245.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"She gives us the protection. She's the Protector.<br /> 
And She's the Mother of this world, Jagadambā."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Yashasã vardhate so-api keertimandita bhootale. Japet-saptaśhtim Chandim krutvã tu kavacham purã.</b><br />
That person receives more and more glory and prowess. On the earth he rises in prosperity and fame by reading the Kavacha and Saptaśhatī.<br /> 
<b>Jay twam Devī Chãmuṇḍe jaiy bhutãrtihãrini,<br />
Jay sarvagate Devī Kãlarãtri namostute.</b><br />
Victory be to you O Devī Chāmuṇḍā (the killer of Chaṇḍā and Muṇḍa) victory be to You O remover of miseries of all living beings.<br />
Victory be to You O Devī who is present everywhere.<br />
Salutations to you O Kãlarãtri (final destruction of the universe)</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The Devī has many forms, but is the Embodiment of the Śhakti. Ādi Śhakti gives Śhakti to all these Embodiments.&gt;<br />
And so, there are many Goddesses we have. At different times, They came on this Earth, and did all that was necessary for the ascent of people who were seekers.&gt;<br />
Specially, the One we know of Jagadambā, the Durgā, She was trying to protect all the Seekers of Truth and to destroy all evil forces.&gt;<br />
Because without the ascent of human beings, they do not know the Truth. And that's why, whatever they try to do is a mental projection.&gt;<br />
And this mental projection, if it is not sumsti ... substantiated by Truth, by dharma, it declines. In Sanskrit they call it glāni.&gt;<br />
When this glāni takes place, then Incarnations are born to solve the problem."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1246.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You are Sahaja Yogis.<br />
What is your destiny? Your destiny is to achieve the spiritual success [spiritual ascent].<br />
The Devī destroyed Chaṇḍā and Muṇḍa, that is why She is called Chāmuṇḍā. They are all back in this Kali Yuga, all of them.</font><br />
[Prayer to the Devī: 'O Devī, please give us the spiritual personality, the victory, the spiritual ascent and destroy our enemies'.]<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Saint Eknāth comes from Pratiṣhṭhān. Pratiṣhṭhān comes from Paiṭhaṇ.<br />
And he is the one, who has written this 'Jogawa', means the Yoga ......"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Your Destiny Is to Achieve the Spiritual Success and Have I Fulfilled My Destiny, Navarātri Celebrations (5th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Jagawa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Salutations to You O Goddess Chāmuṇḍā Nārāyanī,<br />
whose mouth was dreadful with its great teeth,<br />
Who wore a garland of human skulls as an ornament and killed the demon Muṇḍa.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Mahālakṣhmī Hymn, chapter 11 of the Devī Māhātmyam)</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You come up now to the Heart chakra. Heart chakra is divided into three parts. In the center of the Heart chakra resides Jagadambā Herself. But [in] the left side as I have told you resides Śhiva and His Power is Pārvatī. <b>When Pārvatī Herself separates Her identity with Her Lord and enters in the center to save Her children from the domination of the evil spirits, then She resides in the center and She is the Jagadambā. This is called as ``Sacred Heart" in the Bible. She resides as Jagadambā. She has taken many Incarnations to save.</b><br />
Today there was Lalitā Pañchamī, they sang the song of Lalitā. The way She took Her Incarnations to fight the evil forces, to save the bhaktas from the domination of satanic and depraving personalities. She is there within you also, if not awakened She can be awakened. She is all the time there to save you from those satanic forces."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1247.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Saraswatī is known as Skandamātā, She was not His mother and was virgin. But, but She took Skanda [Kārttikeya] as Her Son and held Him to Her heart."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1221 Śhrī Kārttikeya Pūjā (Marathi + English), Śhrī Gyāneśhwara, Park (200 m from ISYRH Center), C.B.D. Belapur, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">O Devī, we bow before You, who are yourself good fortune in the dwellings of the virtuous, and ill-fortune in those of the vicious, intelligence in the hearts of the learned, faith in the hearts of the good, and modesty in the hearts of the high-born.<br /> 
May You protect the universe!</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"><b>This is a prayer.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Comments on the Reading from Devī Māhātmyam, before the Talk on the Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Skandamātā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the Mother of Śhrī Kārttikeya!<br />
Salutations to You!</font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/44600555"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This song that you have heard has been composed in the year of 1600. And in this song the poet has sung for the rustic people, in their language. That, ``Oh Mother, give us our Realization!" Jogawa means the Yoga, the Union with the Divine and the Sahaja Yoga means spontaneous.<br />
It fills My heart to see how since long the seekers have been asking for this Union with the Divine. What a search! What a seeking!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0610 Public Program, University, Graz, Austria</b></font>
<font color="green"><b></b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Aye re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Argala Stotram</b> (recited on the 5th day of Navarātri)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lVgW5k89t44">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Argala Stotram</b> (English)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/rkHsdWAiL4Y">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jagadambetza Jogwa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Hey Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Bhavānī Dayānī</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1248.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... as you know <b>I am the Goddess, and the Goddess has to wear I don't know how many ornaments just to adorn Her chakras.</b> I mean, I have lots of ornaments Myself of My own. But only for Pūjā I wear, otherwise I don't wear: I am supposed to wear lots of things. Why? Because it may not be that -- all right, may be dignified, but may not be that all right to wear all those things all the time. But I am supposed to wear."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0504 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On Hygiene and Other Topics, After Sahasrāra Pūjā, Consorzio Alpe Motta, Via per Motta, 2, Madesimo (115 kms N of Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Tere Charana De Hainth</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... I would like to tell you about the meaning of Pūjā. There are two aspects. One is the aspect that you have got your own Deities within you inside. And these Deities are to be awakened within you. Deities are the different aspects of One God. So, on one side you have the Deities -- is the aspects of God, which are all the time awakened. On the other side you have your own Deities, which are sometimes awakened, sometimes half awakened, sometimes sleeping and sometimes sick. [Laughter.] So, you have to use two methods -- one to please the Deities of God and to ask them to bless your Deities or to ask them to awaken your Deities."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0822 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, House of Charles and Magda Mathys, Chemin des Moulins-de-Drize 5, Troinex (6 kms S of Geneva), Gèneve, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Skandamata" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “What the Devī can do, you should not do, that’s Her job, that She is supposed to do this, not you”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “What the Devī can do, you should not do, that’s Her job, that She is supposed to do this, not you”" /><published>2023-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_18_Navaratri_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/18"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Nine are the days, in the night, when the Goddess had to fight the demons and to save Her children from the effects of negativity.</b><br />
On one side She was Ocean of Love and Compassion, and on the other side She was protecting them like a tigress; because the times were such that nobody could meditate, nobody could take the name of God, nobody could think even of Self-realization. But those who are sitting here today, you have been there also in those days, and you were all saved for today, for this day, so that you can achieve your Self-realization.<br />
The form of the Goddess in those days was not Māyā Swarūpi[n]. She was in Her real form and that created a great awe, even among the disciples. So the question of giving them Self-realization was not there. First of all they were to be saved."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1249.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nṛisiṁha rūpeṇ‛ogreṇa</b></font><br />
<b>In the Fierce Form of a Man-Lion,</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Hantum daityān kṛit’odyame</b></font><br />
<b>You succeeded in Slaying the Demons,</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Trailokya trāṇa sahite</b></font><br />
<b>O Benevolent Saviour of the Three Worlds,</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nārāyaṇi namo-‛stu te</b></font><br />
<b>Salutations be to You, O Nārāyaṇi.</b><br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0"><b>Aiye Singha pe sawar</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"By the time Ādi Śhakti created the universe, after creating the entire universe, like how a king spread out his kingdom and comes to see the world thereafter in a disguise, in the same way Ādi Śhakti has also incarnated on this Earth many a times."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="Red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"><b> I say that before going out please take a bandhan.</b> It's a kavach, we call it a kavach. Means, kavach, in English there's a word for that?</font><br />
<b>Sahaaj Yogis [suggest]:</b> Protection.<br />
<font color="Red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">That's rather, protection is abstract, but this is a protection of the Mother is a concrete stuff, you see, kavach. So you take the kavach. Kavach is something you can say that people wear those armor, inside, you see that sort of a thing, is kavach. So you must take that before going out or talking to somebody. That you don't do.<br />
......<br />
It's just a simple thing, take your kavach when you are going out. It's so simple, I mean, in Sahaja Yoga we don't have to do horrible rituals that people do, nothing of the kind. Just take your bandhan in the morning when you are going out and if somebody is argumentative just give a bandhan. Anything, <b>little bandhan can work out so many things but we forget that we have entered into the Kingdom of God and all the Saints and all the angels and gaṇas are at your disposal</b>.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0704 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Viṣhṇumāyā's Powers, Āśhram, Everbeek, Belgium</b></font>
</p>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b>Padamékam na gachchhetu yadichchhéchchhu-bhamãtmanah.<br /> 
Kavachénã-vruto nityam yatra-yatraiva gachchhati.<br />
Tatra tatrartha labhashcha Vijayah sarvakamikah,<br />
Yam yam chintayété kãmam tam tam prãpnoti nishchitam.<br />
Parmaishvaryam-tulam prãpasyaté bhutalé pumãna.</b><br />
 One should invariably cover oneself with this Kavacha (by reading) wherever one goes, and should not walk even a step without it if one desires auspiciousness.<br /> 
Then one is successful everywhere, and all one’s desires are fulfilled and that person enjoys great prosperity on the earth.<br />
<b>Nirbhayo jāyate martyaḥ, saṅgrāmeṣhv’aparājitaḥ<br />
Trailokye tu bhavet-pūjyaḥ, kavachen'āvṛitaḥ pumān</b><br />
The person who covers himself with Kavach becomes fearless, and is never defeated<br />
In battle, And becomes worthy of being worshipped in the three worlds.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(In short now it is a bandhan, it is the same thing as Kavacha)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HZfJnqWq8Z0">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So as it is we are today praying to the Goddess that, `Help us to fight our negativity within us. <b>Give us Your tiger so that we fight, give us Your lion so we fight.</b>' Let us fight all these horrible animals that are within us, these horrible haunting things that are within us, these horrible conditionings we have. You have to get rid of it. Still, still if you watch yourself, lots of conditionings are there, lots of things, you see. If you see, there are covered with very thin curtains and you don't see it, but they are there. But let the tiger enter into all these dens and find out. And you enjoy that, riding over the horse, riding over the lion, and riding over the tiger -- like a Goddess. Why not? After all, children get all the heritage of the mother, don't they? So you have all the heritage available to you. <b>But you have to be worthy, in the sense that you have to know that you are worthy, that's all. You have to just know that you are worthy and that you can do it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1008 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 8th Day and 9th Day), The Content Within (How Deeply You Have Touched the Feet of the Divine), Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1250.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I would say, with this, today's special celebration of Navarātri. Like yesterday you saw Śhrī Durgā's Nine Forms, also. In that, <b>one is Kuṣhmāṇḍā, is one of the forms, that you absorb all the filth in yourself, in your stomach.<br />
But the Devī does that, not you. What the Devī can do, you should not do, that's Her job</b>, that She is supposed to do this, not you.<br />
What you have to do is to only be in silence so that you absorb whatever will increase that silence, will increase your depth. The Devī will look after all the rest of the things, She'll look after all the filth, all the anger, all the temper, all the everything that's going on in this world. She will absorb all that, but what you have to do is to just enjoy everything that is pure.<br />
Enjoyment is only possible when you are beyond your mind. With your mind you can never enjoy, it is like a big load. It will not act, it will not help. Enjoyment comes when you are in complete silence, in a rippleless lake, the reflection of all the joy that is created on the shores of that lake are completely reflected, they are not deflected, if they were repulsed it would have been a different image altogether, and would have been something nowhere near the image of reality."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1251.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>Visṛistau sṛisti-rūpā Tvam sthiti-rūpā cha pālane,<br />
Tathā saṁhṛiti-rūpānte jagato-'sya jagan-maye ǁ 5 ǁ</b></font><br />  
O You, whose Form is the Universe, at the time of creation You are the Creative Force,<br />
At the time of sustentation You are the Protective Power and at the time of the Dissolution of the World,<br />
You are the Destructive Power.<br />
<br />    
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>RACHA PRABHU TUNEY YAHA BRAHMANDA SARA<br />
Oh God You have created the whole universe<br />
PRANON SEY PYARA, BRAHMANDA SARA<br />
The whole universe is dearer than our lives<br />
TUHI MAI BANDHU, TUHI JAGAT JANANI<br />
You are my Mother and brother, You are the Mother of the universe<br />
SAKAL JAGAT MEIN YAH TERA PASARA<br />
The whole universe is but your form</b></font><br /> 
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />  
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kuṣhmāṇḍā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Kuṣhmāṇḍā, the one whose void contains the universe! Salutations to You!</font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/29890729"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Kavacha</b> (English)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/wJJXnDabTes">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ankhe band karu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī hamko</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1252.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Red"><b>"See the Swastika became cross at the time of Christ, Swastika is symbol of Gaṇesh ......"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1010 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (5th Day of Navarātri and Canadian Thanksgiving Day), Garden, 1386 Lincoln Avenue, Toronto, ON, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>These people have decided today to have a Pūjā, and you know what happens to Me when you do My Pūjā.</b> So with all those problems that will be facing later, I would like all of you to be attentive about the Pūjā and to take full advantage of that. <b>With this Pūjā you get the Mother's protection, to begin with.</b> And My chakras, when they start moving, they give you special powers of love and bless all your chakras and fill them up completely. So I would like you, though some two people are coming to do this, all of you to feel that you all are doing it, and you can feel it that way with oneness. And the blessings of My being will flow to you automatically."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0828 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Most Dynamic Power of Love, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kushmanda" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Kavach …… You have to take for your protection every morning when you go out, and before sleeping you should put your attention here and sleep off.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Kavach …… You have to take for your protection every morning when you go out, and before sleeping you should put your attention here and sleep off.”" /><published>2023-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_17_Navaratri_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/17"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, when we are <b>celebrating the greatest of greatest this Navarātri</b>, there must be something special about it, that we have to cleanse this heart completely, fully and make it so pure that it purifies all the blood that passes through the whole of the body. So the cells of this heart, which has made this great organ, has to be the best, because the cells of the heart within a human body are the best cells, the highest quality, the most sensitive. And it's the heart that expresses the Anāhata, the sound that is without percussion.<br />
......<br />
...... <b>this is the highest Pūjā, the greatest ritual, which you can attend</b>. So why do we do Navarātri? In the heart, to do Navarātri is to accept the Powers of the Śhakti, to realize the power that all these chakras have got in themselves, and that when they are enlightened how you can express all these powers of these Nine Chakras within ourselves; the seven chakras plus the heart and the Moon makes it nine."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), The Discipline, Hampstead Town Hall Centre, 213 Haverstock Hill, London NW3 4QP, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1241.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"...... the Goddess always uses lion as Her vehicle. Sh... that is the vāhana specially used when, at different levels, She has to be compassionate as well as very harsh to the people who are trying to destroy humanity."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1009 Public Program (6th Day of Navarātri), Lions Club International, G.D. Birla Sabahghar, 29, Ashutosh Choudhry Avenue, Ballygunge, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So many powers Mother has to have to protect Her children and to look after them.</b> These powers are all there, working relentlessly all the time, twenty-four hours. So anybody who surrenders to Mother, these powers express themselves and try to help you out of your problems. But <b>first thing is surrendering. If you are not surrendered, if you are not in the Kingdom of the God, then this is not the responsibility of the Mother</b>. Then it might be that some negative force might take over and may destroy you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1013 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (3rd Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But <b>all these powers are nothing but the Power of God's Love. So, in the series of this Great Love of God, Ādi Śhakti had to first become the Power of Desire.</b><br />
In the same way, Sahaja Yogis who are bestowed with this Power of Love have to have full desire in their heart. Desire to love. That desire is very different from the other kinds of human love we have known. In other kinds of human love, when we have relations with others, we have expectations, and that's why it is very disappointing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1242.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">Drushyanté rathmãrudhã devyah krodh-samãkulãh.<br />
Shankham chakram gadãm shaktim halam cha muslãyudham. Khétakam tomaram chaiv parshum-pãsha-méva cha.<br /> 
Kuntãyudham trishulam cha shãrangam-ãyudham-uttamam. Daityãnãm deha-nãshãya bhaktã-nama-bhayaya cha.<br />
Dhãryantãya-yudhaneet-tham devãnãm cha hitãya vai.<br />
<b>All these Goddesses are seen mounted in chariots and are on warpaths.<br />
They are wielding conch, discus, mace, plow, club, javelin, axe, noose, barbed dart, trident bows and arrows.<br /> 
These Goddesses are wielding their weapons, for destroying the bodies of demons, for the protection of their devotees, and for the benevolence of Gods.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Kavacha of the Devī)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Now the kavach. You have to take for your protection every morning when you go out, and before sleeping you should put your attention here and sleep off."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1207 Public Program, Day 2, Geetha Bhawan, 133 Lloyds Road, Ganapathy Colony, Gopalapuram, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This was a binding love. She could not escape it. <b>Mother's Love is binding. She cannot escape it. And She has to manifest it, work it out, and give that protection to all Her children.</b><br />
This protection in the modern times has taken another form.<br />
In those days, the evil was trying to harm, to destroy the people who were righteous, who were bhaktas, who were doing good things, who wanted to lead a very religious life. So <b>to save them, She incarnated. To protect them, She incarnated.</b> But they knew what was good, they knew what was wrong. And they wanted to preserve their good life, their precious life. They didn't care for money, they didn't care for power, but just they wanted their life, means they wanted to be alive to worship the Goddess. And when they were troubled or harmed or destroyed by these evil forces, She had to manifest.<br />
But in modern times, it's become very complicated, as the modern times are complicated. First of all, in the mind, in the lifestyle, in the society, of good human beings, righteous human beings, fear of the wrong has entered.<br />
Like, they are afraid, say, of their pries-sts [priests], of their churches, of their temples, of their mosques, which are all false! They are not afraid of God.<br />
They don't believe in God. They think that they have created God, and they can manage God. 'So who is God?' The way they behave, you can see clearly, that they do not recognize the existence of God, God Almighty who is a wrathful God. They are not at all worried as to what will happen to them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>But the greatest power that is belonging to the Mother is your protection.</b> Protection from all kinds of things – all the left hand side protections are there. They are described, as you must have learnt on the Devī Māhātmyam – what a protections She gives you. So tremendous in Her protecting power. And this protecting power gives you understanding – how kind She is and how, I should say, how very-very protective, extremely protective. She’ll guide you all the time that you should be protected – on the left side. And through Her Ganas She looks after you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1243.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"When there is worship always there's a bell rung. That is good for all the negativity to run away."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1009 Bestowing of Boons Pūjā, House of Maria Laventzi, Irchester (near Wellingborough), Northamptonshire, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Hinasti daitya tejamsi swanena pooryaya jagat,<br />
Saa ghanta patu no devi papebhyo nah sutaniva.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Devī, may Your bell which fills the world with its sound and destroys the power of asuras, protect us from sins, just as a mother protects her children</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Devī Māhātmyam, Chapter 11)</font><br />
<font color="Crimson"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<i>O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā, the One who is adorned with the Moon as Your bell, Salutations to You!</i><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25805578"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiyā tere Charano kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/2LmBT0q9f2M">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mahāmāyā Mahākālī, Jay Śherawālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1244.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, what we call as <b>the Charaṇāmṛut is, means the Ambrose</b> then a ... a Ambrose, Ambrose of My Feet, or you can say Ambrose of My Feet, is not meant for everyone. Neither the blessings of the Pūjā are not meant for everyone. So try to avoid people who are not e yet fully equipped. First thing they will start is doubting. <b>If they do not doubt, also, there will be a problem with the protocol. They won't be able to accept it with that protocol.</b>"/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Collective Spirit and Complete Integration (Active Sincerity and Patience and Sincerity Is the Key of Your Success), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
&lt;/p&gt;

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Pūjā is one of the things by which you can excite the forms into formless.</b> Now, your centers are the centers of energies. But they, too, have a guiding Deity sitting on all these chakras. They are also the formless made into forms. And when you do the Pūjā, the forms melt into Formless Energy, and this Formless Energy then starts flowing, and that then blows the wind. [Everyone laughs as the wind blows with a noise.] And that's how this misidentification, superimpositions on the Spirit are removed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0618 Havan, Importance of Pūjā and Havan, before Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā, Garden, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>
</font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Chandraghanta" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra …… thanking the Devī for what She did to bring you down here. So it’s like a thanksgiving.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra …… thanking the Devī for what She did to bring you down here. So it’s like a thanksgiving.”" /><published>2023-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_16_Navaratri_Day_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/16"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the ascent starts evolving. In that, the play of the Devī is the Navarātri -- in your ascent -- from ages. <b>Navarātri that's why is the most important Pūjā. In Sahaja Yoga, Navarātri is the most important Pūjā, I would say. Though we can say in modern Sahaja Yoga Sahasrār Day is, because that's how you started getting your Realization. But if you go to the whole historical events of evolution you'll find [that] Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra. Without the help of the Devī at different stages of your ascent, you could not have been in a position to receive your Realization. So all the steps that you took in the past are today worshiped and are used for thanking the Devī for what She did to bring you down here. So it's like a thanksgiving. Without Her work, nothing could have happened.</b><br />
So when we read about the Devī, about Her Incarnations -- how She came on this Earth to save Her bhaktas, people who were trying to ascend, to cross this Bhavasāgara, how She worked hard, how She fought the devils, how She cough... She killed the demons, single-handed -- She took upon Herself the responsibility of making the people cross the Bhavasāgara.<br />
<b>Guru gave you the strength to have dharma but She is the One who brought you out. Even those who were dhārmik could not do it because of the demonic pressure. She's the One who fought, single-handed, with Her Powers of destruction. In Her Love for you She fought. She brought you to this level.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1237.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b>Ā wahanam Janami</b><br />
I know not how to invoke You,<br />  
<b>Na Janami ta varchanam</b><br />
I know not how to welcome You,<br />
<b>Pūjam chaiwa na Janami</b><br />
I know not how to do Your Pūjā<br />
<b>Kshamyatam Parameśhwarā</b><br />
Forgive me, Ādi Śhakti,<br />
<b>Kshamyatam Parameśhwarā</b><br />
Forgive me, O Supreme One
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The Devī incarnated on this Earth to kill the demonic personalities who try to destroy all the good qualities of women. We also have those demonic personalities within us and they are to be destroyed -- not physically, but mentally.</b><br />
How you accept them and how you deal with whatever they try is very surprising.<br />
<b>You must understand that the goodness of a person is very important. If you are trying to be nasty or dominating then you'll be definitely destroyed. That's why this Devī has come on the Earth. That is the assurance of this Devī, the Goddess.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1004 Pūjā (9th Day of Navarātri), House, 268 Overpack Avenue, Ridgefield Park, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But Goddess Herself has done so many things for us already, within us, though we are not aware of it. Is said that, "Yā Devī sarvabhūteśhu": "All those whom You have created," means mostly the human beings, "What do You do? As what do You exist inside the human beings?"<br />
Now, just introspect if you have these qualities within you or not, because they are given to you by the Goddess, by the Śhakti within you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-1005 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), Your Beautiful Qualities Will Prove the Truth of Sahaja Yoga, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Yā Devī Sarvabhūteśhu</b> (2000-1008 Navarātri Pūjā, Cabella)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1238.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"You cannot make anyone brahmachārī or brahmachāriṇī. It is a state, avasthā, where a person has to rise, like Yogeśhwara, like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
......<br />
It is a state of mind where you are not involved. It is a different thing, that you just load somebody with an idea that You should become, absolutely a brahmachārī or a brahmachāriṇī or you should lead a celibate life, forcing them.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Celibacy must come from within, the purity must come from within.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0203 Public Program (English + Hindi + English), Day 5, The Āgñyā Chakra, N.D.M.C. Park, Hanumān Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"And that is why, <b>today is the day when the Virgin, Gaurī, sat down to worship Śhiva</b>. She made a Śhiva Lingua and was sitting and putting Her sindūr on that: "That you look after this, which is the mark of my Union with you. I leave it to you, to look after" -- to Śhiva. "You look after me. I surrender to you." With this, that's how Gaurī your Kuṇḍalinī surrenders to the Spirit: 'Now You look after this connection. I forget everything else. I leave it into Your hands. Lift Me up. You raise Me up. I forget all that was Me before. Everything I have dropped out. No other desire. But just lift Me higher and higher. Make Me Yourself. The rest of it is not important. All other manifestations of this, desires are over. Now, I am absolutely surrendered to You, My Spirit. Lift Me higher and higher. Higher and higher, away from all the things that were not the Spirit. Make Me complete Spirit, full Spirit.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="Indigo">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<font color="Indigo">MALA PAAHĪ PRABHUSANGE, DUI ATMA TAI PALE DURĪ</font><br />
When I am in the company of God, evil runs away<br />
<font color="Indigo">GALE SAMARTHYA MOHACHE NURE RUNT KUTHE VAIRĪ</font><br />
No temptation can dominate me and nobody can confront me<br />
<font color="Indigo">MALA BODHAAMRUT PAAJĪ, SADA ]AEI NAVI TRUPTĪ</font><br />
Every time I experience the Divine knowledge, I feel more satisfaction and Divine Joy<br />
<font color="Indigo">KUTHE CHINTA KUTHE DUKHHE KSHANE SAARI LAVA JAATĪ</font><br />
All moments of concerns and sorrows vanish<br />
<font color="Indigo">PRABHUSANGE MILE JĪVA, NASE KOTHE TASHI SHANTĪ</font><br />
Nowhere else can my soul find peace except in the company (in Union) with God Almighty<br />
<font color="Indigo">PRABHU MAZA SWAYE NĪTĪ, PRABHU MAZA SWAYE PRITĪ</font><br />
My God himself is Truth and Love<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1239.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<b>Now what are good My Feet for?<br />
......<br />
Very good for ego. And also superego. Is very good for people who suffer from ego or superego, My Feet. Because, such people are very gross. And the Feet solve the problem. So just use My Feet.</b>"&lt;/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0517 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Preparation for Becoming, Seminar, Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Old Alresford (13 kms ENE of Winchester), Hampshire, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Srutīnām mūrdhāno dadhati tava yau saekhara tayā<br />
mama apyaetou Matah sirasi dayayaa dhehi charanou,<br />
yayoh paadyam paathah Paśhupati jata jūta tatinī<br />
yayorlakshā Lakshmír aruna Hari Chūdamani ruchih.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Jagan Mātā! Thy two Feet are adored as the crowns on the peaks (Upaniṣhads) of the Vedas.<br />
The water that washes Your Feet is the celestial River Gaṅgā in the matted hairlocks of Lord Paśhupati.<br />
The luster of the lac dye used on Your Feet imparts a red color to the ruby that glorifies the diadem of Śhrī Hari.<br />
O Mother, please place them on my head too, taking mercy on me<br />
(Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76011764"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī Vandu Tav Charana</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1240.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now what happens actually when you project this Pūjā?</b><br />
It has been found out, and now as I am telling you, <b>that first you have to awaken within you the Deities that are still asleep, by worshiping them. But as these Deities, Primordial Deities, are with Me, you worship Me, and every Deity in Me is awakened, by which your Deities are awakened.<br />
So first, your vibrations must improve, to receive. If the reception is not good what's the use of any Pūjā or projection?</b> So first of all we, sort of, prepare our instrument, or prepare our projecting instrument. That preparation is done by praying to different Deities, as we call that: a Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā. By praying to My Kuṇḍalinī you improve your reflection. Because then the vibrations from Me start flowing into yours and they awaken it. This is the projection as far as you are concerned.<br />
Once the instrument is all right, then you project outside. <b>And now how do you project? By worshiping the Goddess as the Protector of the whole Universe, praising Her different attributes, even Her Face, Her Hands, everything has a meaning. Praising Her Powers. By saying that, by repeating that, you echo in your projection Her Powers, and then your projection becomes that powerful.</b> It's a very subtle happening that takes place, it's miraculous. <b>These things look so simple, like just like washing My Feet.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Salutations to You O Devī Nārāyanī, 
who took the form of Brahmanī (the Śhakti of Brahmadeva) 
and sprinkled water with kuśha grass while riding in the heavenly car (aeroplane Vimāna) of the swan</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0">(Mahālakṣhmī Hymn, Chapter 11 of Devī Māhātmyam)</font></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Brahmachāriṇī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Brahmachāriṇī, the One who observes the state of celibacy!
Salutations to You!</font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Brahmacharini" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Navarātri is very good because these nine nights represent the main Nine Incarnations”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Navarātri is very good because these nine nights represent the main Nine Incarnations”" /><published>2023-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_15_Navaratri_Day_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/15"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Navarātri is very good because these nine nights represent the main Nine Incarnations</b>. Where the Goddess took the form of Śhakti and killed the negative people.<br />
But those were easier days because negativity was understood by people and nobody sympathized.<br />
So this is what one has to understand that don't sympathize with negativity. You'll spoil them all. And always you'll find such sympathies bring forth your character also that you are also slightly negative.<br />
Because to fight negativity in modern times is a very difficult task. You cannot kill anyone: if you kill somebody, then may be that such a person is a brother or a sister or something of somebody. Or such a person would be himself or herself a seeker.<br />
So best thing is to separate like a contagious disease, keep that person out, no sympathies. And get the person cured and enjoy the life, otherwise that person is not going to be helped. It has become a very individual fight. And it's so troublesome and so disgusting.<br />
So to help Me out, you should not take any sides with negativity. That's how you can help Me the most. <b>This is what it is the Navarātri, the Pūjā that I give you powers to fight the negativity. That's how you cure people.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1009 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Like a Drama, On Arrival before the Public Program, Flat of Ruth and Kingsley Flint, Strasbourg, Grand Est, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1232.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Namo Devyai Māhādevyai</b><br />
The Gods said: Salutations to the Devī, to the Great Goddess.<br />
<b>Śhivayai satatam namah</b><br />
Salutations always to Her who is ever auspicious<br />
<b>Namah Prakrutyai Bhadrayi</b><br />
Salutations to Her who is primordial cause and the sustaining power.<br />
<b>Niyataha pranataha-smatam</b><br />
With complete reverence and full attention, we make obeisance to Her.</font><br />
<b>Devī Suktam</b><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Navarātri Song</b></font><br />
(9 descriptions of the 9 Avatārs of the Goddess and 10th is when She sits on the lion)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is the first day of Navarātri. Today your attention should be on Śhrī Gaṇeśha.</b> His devotion is infinite. He has never worshiped anybody else except Mother. Hence He is so great. All other Gods appear very strong. Everyone has some specialty. What is Mother's specialty? Her ego (aham) is nowhere felt by others. Hence Śhrī Gaṇeśha who has surrendered to such Mother, is so wise and venerable, Mother has nothing with Her. Her very name begins with Ni, e.g., Niṣhakāñchan[ā] having no wealth, Nirlepā unaffected; Nirvichārā thoughtless; Niṣhprayojanā having no motives, Nigarvitā egoless, Niricchā desireless, etc. Therefore, surrendering to such Mother, who has nothing with Her, needs some kind of subtle thought, in that, Mother has nothing with Her and therefore, nothing can be asked from Her. It shows how Śhrī Gaṇeśha by himself, is fully satisfied. Where does this contentment of Śhrī Gaṇeśha come from? It is own power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1002 Letter to All Sahaja Yogis (Marathi) (1st Day of Navarātri), London, UK from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 11 (September-October 1982), Pages 25 and 26</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1233.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Gaṇeśha, I am going to be worthy of Your attention.<br />
Please make me innocent, so that I am in Your attention.<br />
Śhrī Mother, You who are Śhrī Gaṇeśha please give me wisdom and discrimination."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Prayer to Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Āśhram, Rome, Italy from the 2012 edition of Sahaja Yoga Mantra Book, Page 29</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">In the first and the second phase of evolution matter was created. At this point, Śhrī Ādi Śhakti separated from Śhrī Sadāśhiva and She created Lord Gaṇeśha to bless Her creation with innocence and auspiciousness. Hence, <b>the first prayer to the Goddess is addressed to Lord Gaṇeśha in the first night of the nine phases of the moon in the period of worship called Navarātri or nine nights of worship. Lord Gaṇeśha's Power removes all obstacles and also purifies us for undertaking the prayers to the Goddess</b>. The Blessings of the moon which is also on the left side, also arise from the same source. This is the stage of Mūlādhāra chakra in us.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Excerpt from the book '9 Nights of worship to the Goddess'</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1234.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">Today we worship the Himalayas and the seven Goddesses whose blessings are here, and pray to them to bless us with Devī Śhakti. We have received the blessings of the Devī Śhakti from a Mother. That is why, in the form of Mother, let us come to the feet (śharaṇāgat) of the Himalayas.<br />
<b>Keep your attention on your Self.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Ai Girī Nandinī Nandita Medinī, Vishwa-vinodinī Nandanute,</b><br />
O joy-giving Daughter of the Mountain, Giver of joy to the whole universe<br />
<b>Girīvara Vindhya Shirodhī-nivāsinī,  Vishṇu-vilāsinī Jisḥu-nute,</b><br />
Living in the Vindhya mountains, Charming Lord Viṣhṇu, triumphant,<br />
<b>Bhagavatī he shitī-kantha Kutumbinī, Bhūrī Kutumbinī bhūrī kŗute,</b><br />
Abode of all Divine qualities, Whose home overflows with plenty.<br />
<b>Jaya, jaya, he Mahishāsura Mardini, Ramya kapardinī Shaila-sute.</b><br />
Victory to the Killer of Mahiṣhāsura, O Beautiful matted-haired Daughter of the Mountain.<br />
<b>(Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya's Praise of the Divine Mother)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/wx07p-jo-nA?list=PL391B5651D1805358">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>On this day Devī is worshiped as Śhailaputrī, means the daughter of Himalaya.</b> Devī has many other names also but first of all She incarnated as Śhailaputrī in the cold of Himalayas. She incarnated and whatever She was to do, She started there.<br />
Further story is known to you. [King] Dakṣha did not invite Lord Śhiva in the Havana that he performed and Śhailaputrī was the consort of Lord Śhiva. She is called Satī because She entered the Holy fire of Havana and ablated Herself. But by then Lord Śhiva reached there. He lifted Her burnt up body from the fire. Burnt pieces of the body of Śhailaputrī fell at many places. All these places are considered to be Śhakti Pīṭhas, the places of worship, as there is in Vindhyāchala and many other places. Her power moves there and it is said that it Sanctifies everything.<br />
Her seventh power is considered to be the Power of Destruction. Śhakti manifested Itself on the right side as Sāvitrī and Gāyatrī but the destroying force was manifested in the center.<br />
In the form of Durgā and Her other forms manifested in Heart chakra. She is present there.<br />
If some one hurts you, confuses or disturbs you then this power will protect you and destroy your enemy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0405 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (Hindi), Noida Bhavan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1235.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"When He desired to create this nature, He collected a desire, we may say a wave or vibration, and filled within a container or Ghaṭ. It is that Ghaṭ. And this Ghaṭ means the God Almighty.<br />
If we can separate God Almighty and His power of desire for our understanding, then it will be easy to understand.<br />
You, people, are similar but with a slight difference. You and your desire powers are different. First, the power of your desire is born. Until you have a desire for anything, nothing is executed.<br />
This means [that] this beautiful universe is created because of someone's desire. Everything is executed after a desire. To execute the desire of God Almighty it has to be separated from Him. We will call it Ādi Śhakti.<br />
When this first stage arrived this Ghaṭasthāpanā happened. This happened so many times in ancient times and even today when we have Ghaṭasthāpanā we memorize that aboriginal happening. So on the first day of Navarātri, we do Ghaṭasthāpanā, means, remember, what an important thing it is.</b><br />
Whatever God Almighty desired at that time collected and filled in a Ghaṭ before its execution. Today we are worshiping that desire, we worshiped it today. God Almighty had that desire and brought us up to human being-ness, up to this height stage he brought us, now it is your duty to bow in front of His desire."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0922 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī and Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Navarātri Celebrations (1st Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Gaṇeśha sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Śhailaputrī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), The Discipline, Hampstead Town Hall Centre, 213 Haverstock Hill, London NW3 4QP, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/185243549"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ghane Ghane Jangala mein</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jay Jagadambe </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇapati Vandan Gan nayak</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1236.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="Purple"><b>O Daughter of the King of the mountains!<br />
The sages say that the world has its dissolutions and Genesis<br />
With the closing and opening of Thine Eyes,<br />
Thine Eyes are bereft of winking,<br />
With a view to saving from dissolution this entire universe,<br />
Which has its origin in the opening of Thine Eyes.</b></font><br />
<font color="Purple"><font size="+0">(Saundaryalaharī by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)</font></font><br />
<br />  
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>But Pūjā is also an external offering. Even your heart has said so. But you should understand how you get the reward or blessings of the Pūjā and its prasād.</b><br />
A Pūjā or a prayer grows from your heart. Mantras are the words of your Kuṇḍalinī. But if Pūjā is not performed from heart or if Kuṇḍalinī is not associated with recitation of Mantras then that Pūjā becomes a ritual.<br />
If you become thoughtless in Pūjā, know that your heart is also involved in it. <b>Collect the Pūjā material and offer it sincerely. There should be no formality or bindings in the offerings.</b> It is correct to wash hands, but is your heart washed? When attention is on heart it does not go to others. Although you remain quiet from outside, you are speaking from within. Hence you should not, be silent for long time. If man's heart is not clean, then the silence becomes very harmful. At the same time loose talks can bring catastrophes.<br />
You should say the Mantras in Pūjā but with great faith (śhraddhā). There is no alternative to śhraddhā. You should perform the Pūjā when śhraddhā grows deep, so that heart itself gets all Pūjā performed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1012 Letter to Nirmalā (sister of Rājabhāī Modi) (Marathi), On Pūjā, London, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Shailaputri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>