<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-25T18:51:57-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri festival: “Navarātri is to accept the powers of the Śhakti.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri festival: “Navarātri is to accept the powers of the Śhakti.”" /><published>2022-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022_09_24_Navaratri_Preparations</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the ascent starts evolving. In that, the play of the Devī is the Navarātri – in your ascent – from ages. <b>Navarātri that’s why is the most important Pūjā. In Sahaja Yoga, Navarātri is the most important Pūjā, I would say.</b> Though we can say in modern Sahaja Yoga Sahasrār Day is, because that’s how you started getting your Realization. But if you go to the whole historical events of evolution you’ll find  Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra. Without the help of the Devī at different stages of your ascent, you could not have been in a position to receive your Realization. So all the steps that you took in the past are today worshiped and are used for thanking the Devī for what She did to bring you down here. So it’s like a thanksgiving. Without Her work, nothing could have happened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Nav Durgā kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1018.png" /></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Brahmadeva said:</b><br />
Brahmin, there is Devī Kavach which is most secret and useful to all beings.<br />
Please listen to that, O Great Sage.<br />
The following nine names have been told by the Great Soul Brahmadeva<br />
Himself. Durgā is known by these names:<br />
1st ŚHAILAPUTRĪ (Daughter of the King of Himalayas)<br />
2nd BRAHMACHĀRIṆĪ (One Who observes the state of Celibacy)<br />
3rd CHANDRAGHAṆṬĀ (One Who use the Moon as Her bell)<br />
4th KUṢHMĀṆDĀ (Mother's lap)<br />
5th SKANDAMATA (Mother of Śhrī Kārttikeya)<br />
6th KATYAYANI (Who incarnated to help the Devas)<br />
7th KALARATRI (Who is even the destroyer of Kali)<br />
8th MAHAGAURI (Ādi Kuṇḍalinī)<br />
9th SIDDHIDATRI (Giver of all Siddhis)<br />
10th ŚHRĪ ĀDI ŚHAKTI (Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī)"</font><br />
(from the Kavach of the Devī: Navarātri Nights, Pune 1988-10) 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Navarātri Song (9 description of 9 Avatār of the Goddess and 10th is when She sits on the lion)</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
The first day of Navarātri this year falls on the 17th of October. This day is signified as God’s desire to create the universe which is called Ghaṭasthāpanā (laying of the foundation) and Śhrī Gaṇeśha is worshipped as the first creation. Ghaṭasthāpanā also involves symbolically growing grains around the Kalash.<br />
For Ghaṭasthāpanā following guidelines have been suggested:
</p>

<p>
Dear Brothers and Sisters,<br />
Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
We are going to worship Śhrī Mātājī during this Navarātri, starting from September 26th to October 5th.<br />
These are very auspicious days in our spiritual ascent. Let's all surrender to the Holy Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī, prepare ourselves through meditation, and offer our bhakti to our beloved Mother of the Universe.<br />
The first day of Navarātri signifies God’s desire to create the universe which is called Ghaṭasthāpanā (laying of the foundation) and Śhrī Gaṇeśha is worshipped as the first creation. Ghaṭasthāpanā also involves symbolically growing grains around the Kailash.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>Things required for Ghaṭasthāpanā:</b><br />
* Ghaṭa (kalash) made of earth/Copper/brass<br />
* Coconut- decorated as we decorate for Pūjā Kalash<br />
* A big plate filled with 1/2 soil- Plate can be made of earth/copper/brass<br />
* 10 Mango or Betel (Pan) leaves<br />
* One handful Nine Grains (Nava-dhanya) or Whole Wheat Grains (soaked in normal water, night before the first day of Navarātri)<br />
* A big lamp (diya) which we can keep lit for 10 days uninterrupted in front of Mother</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>On the first day of Navarātri: Ghaṭasthāpanā</b><br />
All the members of the family or collective can sit and meditate. All the things mentioned above should be kept ready in front of Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
A small Pūjā can be offered at the Holy Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
Collectively recite Mahāmantras and then Śhrī Gaṇeśh Mantra.<br />
Collectively recite Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharvashirsha.<br />
We can wash Her Holy Lotus Feet, decorate it with kumkum, offer fragrance, flowers, etc., while singing Devī bhajans collectively.</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>Performing Ghaṭasthāpanā:</b><br />
Items listed above to be used in the following sequence:<br /> 
Keep the big plate on the left side of Śhrī Mātājī (our right side when we face towards Śhrī Mātājī) on the floor. A little amount of akshada (rice mixed with turmeric) is to be put on the floor below a big plate.<br />
* Fill in the big plate 1/2 full with the soil.<br /> 
* Decorate Kalash and coconut by drawing Swastika on it.<br />
* Fill in 3/4 full vibrated water in the Kalash, keep 10 leaves, and the coconut on the mouth of Kalash.<br />
* Keep the decorated Kalash in the center of the big plate already filled with soil.<br />
* Offer haldi and kumkum, akshada, flowers, and garland to the Kalash.<br />
* Spread sowing the Wheat grains/ Nine grains in the big plate around the Kalash in the soil (earth element).<br />
* Spread the soil in little quantity over the wheat grains and sprinkle some water over it.</font><br />
Offer prasad and perform Āratī to Śhrī Mātājī. Then sit in meditation collectively.
</p>

<p style="color:red; text-align:center;">
<b>Bolo Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Durgā Mātā Kī Jay!</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Anant Chaturdaśhī: “Gaṇesha is innocence …. the most powerful power, I should say, innocence”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Anant Chaturdaśhī: “Gaṇesha is innocence …. the most powerful power, I should say, innocence”" /><published>2022-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022_09_10_Anant_Chaturdashi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/10"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Mother, today is said it's Anant Chaturdaśhī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Huh?</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Anant Chaturdaśhī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Today? Aah-ha! That's great! Yes must be. I was wondering Anant Chaturdaśhī. Anant Chaturdaśhī is the day when we visarjan, dissolve Śhrī Gaṇeśha in the water. Gaṇeśhjī ko choṛate hai na pānī meṃ [it's that day we put Gaṇeśhjī in to the water]. Because He's established for ten days. And after ten days, He's born on the fourth, after ten days He's dissolved in the water so that everywhere His Power is spread through the water.</font><br />
T<font color="DarkRed">hat's why no wonder there was a Pūjā.</font> [Laughter.]<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Gaṇeśha settled down into the water. [Laughs.] That is Ananta Chaturdaśhī. Ananta is the, is Śhrī Gaṇeśha. Ananta means which cannot be destroyed. Innocence cannot be destroyed.</b> And that is why is the Gaṇeśh Chaturdaśhī, means the day when Gaṇeśha is dissolved in the water, in the ocean or He is created, worshiped for ten days and again given back. So it's a very great day today, I should say, like the Resurrection of Christ that you are, you had Christ here, He lived with you, and then went back to His Father. Father is the ocean and that's what in India they do, to establish Him on the fourth day and on the tenth day they put Him back to the ocean.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0920 Guru Pūjā (Anant Chaturdaśhī Day), This Finger Is Nothing but the Sahaja Yogis of America and They Have to Help by Their Dynamic Behavior and by Their Proper Understanding, Responsibility as the People Belonging to this Great Nation of Fatherhood, Houston, TX, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1014.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Gananayakaya Ganadaivataya Ganadhyakshaya Dhimahi<br />
Guna Shariraya Guna Manditaya Guneshanaya Dhimahi<br />
Gunatitaya Gunadhishaya Guna Pravishthaya Dhimahi<br />
Ekadantaya Vakratundaya Gauri Tanayaya Dhimahi<br />
Gajeshanaya Balachandraya Shri Ganeshaya Dhimahi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Leader of the [Bhūta]-Gaṇa, the Lord of the people, the representative of the people, I meditate on you.<br />
The embodiment of Guna (the three qualities of Sattva, Rāja, and Tamas), the one adorned with Guṇa, the lord of Guṇas, I meditate on you.<br />
The one beyond Guna, the controller of Guṇa, the one in whom Guṇa pervades, I meditate on you.<br />
The one with one tusk, the curved-trunked one, the son of Gaurī, I meditate on you.<br />
The lord of the elephants, the one with the moon on his forehead, Śhrī Gaṇeśha, I meditate on you.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So today first we have Gaṇesh Pūjā because <b>Gaṇesha is innocence and we have to establish Him in any place where we want to start a work or do anything about it because He is innocence and innocence was created before everything else was created. Is the most powerful power, I should say, innocence</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0920 Guru Pūjā (Anant Chaturdaśhī Day), This Finger Is Nothing but the Sahaja Yogis of America and They Have to Help by Their Dynamic Behavior and by Their Proper Understanding, Responsibility as the People Belonging to this Great Nation of Fatherhood, Houston, TX, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1015.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You are the One to be worshipped first. Obeisance to You again and again.<br />
You are the Word that was in the beginning. You are the Oṃkāra.<br />
You are the source of life. You are the source of security.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Only thing, it is for you to respect it, to behave in a manner that you respect your innocence. Not to feel shy about your innocence, never. Your innocence itself is a power and your innocence will definitely give you that wisdom by which you can solve all the problems without any difficulty."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0826 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Glow of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Lanersbach, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Establish Śhrī Gaṇeśha within you.</b> First of all, you must establish Him and then you can use it for others, for yourself, and for bettering and bettering the methods of Sahaja Yoga that you have learned.<br />
That’s how Śhrī Gaṇeśha is so important for all the Sahaja Yogis to be understood in all its aspects, but this principle is very enormous I should say. The principle is very spread out, it’s very subtle, so to understand in all its aspects is not an easy thing. The only thing you can do is to become One with it, like the Ocean. If you become One with the Ocean you become the Ocean. Just become One with it and that’s how it works out."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0301 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Perth, WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1016.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Śhrī Gaṇeśha, I am going to be worthy of Your attention.<br />
Please make me innocent, so that I am in Your attention.<br />
Śhrī Mother, You are Śhrī Gaṇeśha, please give me wisdom and discrimination."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Prayer to Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Āśhram, Rome, Italy from the 2012 edition of Sahaja Yoga Mantra Book, Page 29</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0922 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, You Have to Protect the Innocent, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25225428"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>Lavkar Yayi Śhrī Gaṇarāyā, Sakalanshi Bheti Dyaya</b> ((Bhajan in praise of Śhrī Mātājī before Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>Gaiye Gaṇapati Jagvandan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>Auṃ Bhūr Bhuvaḥ</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>Eka Gaṇapati</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Dg41OjGhrU8">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇarāyā, Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Anant Chaturdashi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Gaṇeśha Chaturthī: “Śhrī Gaṇeśha within Me is a powerful identity”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/31" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Gaṇeśha Chaturthī: “Śhrī Gaṇeśha within Me is a powerful identity”" /><published>2022-08-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/2022_08_31_Shri_Ganesha_Chaturthi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/31"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here on the right occasion and very auspicious day to worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha.</b><br />
Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the first Deity that was created so that the whole Universe is filled with auspiciousness, with peace, bliss, and spirituality. He is the Source. He’s the Source of Spirituality. As a result of that, all other things follow. Like when it rains and is windy you feel a coolness in the atmosphere. In the same way when Śhrī Gaṇeśha emits His Power we feel all these three things within and without."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0804 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Importance of Chastity, Brighton Friends Meeting House, Ship Street, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1008.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ namaste Gaṇapataye</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Amen. Obeisance to Gaṇapati (the Lord of the Gaṇas).</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Twameva pratyaksham Tattwam’asi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are the manifest Primordial Principle.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Twameva kevalam kart’āsi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You alone are the doer.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Twameva kevalam dhart’āsi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You alone are the supporter (of the universe).</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Twameva kevalam hart’āsi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You alone are the destroyer.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Twameva sarvam khalv’idam Brahm’āsi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are verily the all-pervading Brahman (Supreme Spirit).</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Twam sākshād-Ātm’āsi nityam</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are the manifest eternal Self (Ātman).</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0">Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Because Chaturthī is the day He is established, Gaṇeśha is established on this Chaturthī ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0822 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, House of Charles and Magda Mathys, Chemin des Moulins-de-Drize 5, Troinex (6 kms S of Geneva), Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today you have called Me here, to worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha, within Me. Śhrī Gaṇeśha within Me is a powerful identity.</b><br />
While worshiping Him you have to know that such a powerful thing you have to establish within yourself and by that establishment you have to manifest the Powers of Śhrī Gaṇeśha and the Power of Śhrī Gaṇeśha’s greatness is auspiciousness. It’s a coefficience; it’s a formula, we can say in scientific language, that emits auspiciousness. It’s a magnet in the Mother Earth. The same magnet is within you, which is Śhrī Gaṇeśha."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Holmes Lodge, YMCA Camp Marston, 4761 Pine Hills Road, Julian (near San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1009.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">We bow to You, Compassionate Gaṇeśha!</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Karat. Ho Bhakt. Naka Pratipal.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Verily You are the Protector and supporter of devotees</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">We bow to You, Compassionate Ganesha!</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nishidina Dhyan. Dhare Jo Prani</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">The one who meditates every day</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Hare Sakal. Bhav. Jal.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You free him from these wordly temptations</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Janam.-Maran. Se Hot. Nirala</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">He who watches the cycle of birth and death as a witness</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nahi Lag.Ti Kar. Mal.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Obtains ultimate liberation from his Karmas.</font><br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0">Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now why first Śhrī Gaṇeśha? Because Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the beginning of the desire, and the end of the desire. You start with Gaṇeśha and you end up with Gaṇeśha. That’s why Śhrī Gaṇeśha is worshiped.</b> Is the other way around now, is the source.<br />
When you direct your attention to the source, you worship it, and when you want to incite or open out your own being, then you chant it. This is the difference between worship and a mantra. If you just say mantra, you open yourself out. But when you worship and chant, then you tap the source. I don’t know if I’ve said this before or not. That’s how you understand the Pūjā part."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0801 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, The Privilege of this Worship, Seminar, Day 2, Cowley Manor, Cheltenham, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1010.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You are worshipped with red flowers.<br />
You are adored by Yogis and Yoginīs.<br />
You are the support of the root and the support of the fruit.<br />
You are auspiciousness and the bestower of auspiciousness.<br />
You are wisdom and the bestower of wisdom.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><font color="DarkGreen">Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pancha Ratnam</font></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Names of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Australian Songbook, Sanskrit 23)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/TxotrB3Gzo0">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So we have to first find out if the person is worthy of Pūjā or not. If the person is not worthy, it is better to leave the person alone till he becomes worthy of the Pūjā because doubts and all those things can obstruct the flow of vibrations to other people and such a person can create a problem for others. So it is not civil of that person also to be in the Pūjā if the person has not got an open heart and understanding of what Pūjā is. <b>Doing Pūjā to any Deity as such is not an easy thing, especially to Śhrī Gaṇeśha.</b> Those people who do Pūjā to Śhrī Gaṇeśha should know that of course it has to be a swayambhu means the one that is created by Mother Earth. No other than Gaṇeśha should be worshiped. And if they are not a realized Soul they can never worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha. They cannot even think of Him, they cannot even take His name, it is so difficult to reach Śhrī Gaṇeśha. <b>But after Realization, the first thing you have to do is to worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha because that’s the base on which you got your Realization.</b> He’s the One first who got His crucifixion then His Resurrection and it is the One who opened the path of Realization for you. So you have to worship Him before any other Deity with the greatest sacrifices."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0911 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Hotel `Lo Zodiaco', near Tivoli (35 kms ENE of Rome), Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>When you worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha keep your mind clean, keep your heart clean, keep your being clean</b> – no thoughts of lust and greed should come up. Actually, when the Kuṇḍalinī rises Gaṇeśha had to be awakened within us, the innocence has to come up – which obliterates all such degrading ideas within us. If ascent has to be achieved, we have to understand that we have to mature."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0804 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Importance of Chastity, Brighton Friends Meeting House, Ship Street, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1011.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You are the word that was in the beginning.<br />
You are the Aumkara.<br />
You are the source of life.<br />
You are the source of security.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><font color="DarkGreen">Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pancha Ratnam</font></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Omkar Pradhan)</font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yavVfThmkHk&amp;ab_channel=SahajiBhai">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now here I would like to say that it is Śhrī Gaṇeśha who is the Auṃkāra, who is the vibrations. So He is the Truth. What He says is the Truth. So what vibrations say is the truth. He’s Truth. So Auṃkāra is vibrations, that is Śhrī Gaṇeśh."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Holmes Lodge, YMCA Camp Marston, 4761 Pine Hills Road, Julian (near San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So today’s Pūjā is specially to be done with a prayer in your heart that: ‘Śhrī Gaṇeśha, please be kind and merciful and forgiving that You manifest within ourselves. Let all these hypocritical things, all these conditionings and all these wrong ideas we have or all the wrong life we have had, should just disappear like thin air, and let the beautiful moonlight of your soothing qualities of innocence be manifested through us.’<br />
Let us manifest these qualities. This is what is to be asked."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0826 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Glow of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Lanersbach, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1012.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>I am Gaṇeśha, and it is Me you are doing Pūjā to.</b></font><br />
[At the washing of the Lotus Feet:] <font color="DarkRed"><b>You see, you can’t feel any bones. There are no bones. My Feet are Śhrī Gaṇeśha. My hands are Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and My head is Śhrī Ādi Śhakti.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0301 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Perth, WA, Australia</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You are the master of a protocol of Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Nirmalā Devī. You are the foremost knower of Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Nirmalā Devī.<br />
You witness the awesome greatness of Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Nirmalā Devī.<br />
You allow the Divine Mother to feel Her motherhood.<br />
You allow the Divine Father to enjoy Her creation.</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0804 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Importance of Chastity, Brighton Friends Meeting House, Ship Street, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/740934626"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Lavkar Yayi Shri Ganaraya, Sakalanshi Bheti Dyaya</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Kinaryala Lau</b> (Australian Songbook, Marathi 62)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jay Jagadambe </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tujhyā Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sukhkarta dukhharta Śhrī Gaṇeśha Āratī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/hCjD-83qxLk?list=PL8E57180C36478F98">video</a> 
</p>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b>Vakra-tunda mahākāya, sūrya-koti-sama-prabha</b><br />
<font size="+0">O God with the curled-up trunk, whose body is mighty and who shines with the lustre of a million suns,</font><br />
<b>Nirvighnam kuru me deva, sarva kāryeshu sarvadā</b><br />
<font size="+0">May my endeavours be forever free from obstacles.</font><br />
<b>Sākshāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shri Ganesha Chaturthi" /><category term="orange @ Shri Ganesha Puja" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Ganesha" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Janmāṣhṭamī: Incarnations of Śhrī Viṣhṇu as a fish to begin with and went on till it came to the state of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, where they say that He has become complete.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Janmāṣhṭamī: Incarnations of Śhrī Viṣhṇu as a fish to begin with and went on till it came to the state of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, where they say that He has become complete.”" /><published>2022-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/2022_08_19_Shri_Krishna_Janmashtami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/19"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we are celebrating here in this holy land the birthday of Shrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
Shrī Kṛiṣhṇa is the ultimate of the fatherhood, that I described you before, who came on this Earth and illustrated the ultimate of that. So on this Earth, the highest fatherhood is Shrī Kṛiṣhṇa’s awareness.<br />
But in the Kingdom of God, we can say in Heavens, or even above everything else, resides Sadāshiva who does not take incarnations. He is one of the aspects, Shrī Kṛiṣhṇa is one of the aspects of Sadāshiva which is the Father. And the Ādi Shakti or the Holy Ghost is the other aspect of Sadāshiva which is His power. So when Shrī Kṛiṣhṇa incarnated on this Earth, an aspect of this Ādi Shakti came on this Earth as Rādhā."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0828 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, The Ultimate of the Fatherhood, Garden, Āśhram, 1 Chemin du Joran, Tannay (13 kms N of Geneva), Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1003.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">You are the Father, yet You are the friend.<br />
You are the revelation of Ultimate Fatherhood.<br />
You manifest Śhrī Sadāśhiva (Lord God Almighty).<br />
Ādi Śhakti's Creation is for Your play.<br />
You are the integrated brain of Divinity.</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But one has to realize that the message of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was to surrender.<br />
Now the surrendering that we think in the gross way is like an enemy surrenders to another enemy. So, when the word surrender is spoken, we build up our barriers by thinking that, 'Now, we have to surrender, leave something to the other party.'<br />
But when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa talked about surrender, He was saying that, 'Surrender your enemies to Me so that I will get rid of them.'<br />
Now, the worst enemy that we have is our ego. And with ego starts all kinds of other problems, because it is the biggest barrier for our growth. And the ego starts, as you know, from the Viśhuddhi chakra and can be sucked into Viśhuddhi chakra away. Now let us see how this Viśhuddhi chakra made is. All the vowels that we use come from Viśhuddhi chakra."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0904 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Viśhuddhi Chakra, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1004.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>Kṛiṣhṇa Govind. Govind Gaya Karo</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sing every day the praise of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Pyara Mohan Hṛiday me Bithaya Karo</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Establish Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, Who is the Charming One, within your heart!</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"With the understanding that today is the day -- in the night about twelve o'clock, now it must be about twelve o'clock in India also, about that, so it matches -- He was born at this time in the night, because it was real night symbolically, under horrible circumstances He came. At a time then, when His own birth was very dangerously placed, He was saved, and then in His very childhood He killed rākṣhasas. But all this He did because He was an Incarnation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0815 Śhrī Yogeśhwara (God of Yoga) Pūjā, To do Duty to Him First and Foremost Thing Is You Have to Develop that Purity of a Yogeśhwara (Complete Purity) and A Real Yogi Is a Person who Gets this Yogeśhwara Awakened within Him (Unless and Until You Follow the Path of Yogeśhwara, You Cannot Establish Yourself Fully), Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"What fruits you have, Śhasyaśhyāmalāṃ [part of line 4 of `Vande Mātaram']. Beautiful country you have, is Gokul itself, Vṛindāvan itself. I'm very happy I could come again. This is the first time that, Janmāṣhṭamī, I'm here first time. And today I'm wearing a sāṛī that Rādhā used to wear this kind, is all hand and dyed, is made with tying up every knot, thousands of knots like the thousand chakras. And what is our brain? Is nothing but Virāṭa itself. Brain is the place of Virāṭa, so the whole central nervous system is guided by this brain and the brains of the universe is America."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0818 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā (the day before Janmāṣhṭamī Day), Tent, Backyard, House of Judy Gaddy, 442 Liberty Road, Engelwood, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"They had to work together many a times, and with the Principle of Viṣhṇu, the Principle of Mahālakṣhmī has acted to help the ascent of the people. So the Principle of Viṣhṇu is for your ascent, for the evolutionary process of human beings. Through this Advent and through the Power of Mahālakṣhmī, we have become human beings from amoeba stage.<br />
This is a spontaneous working for us, but for the Principle of Viṣhṇu, He had to go through various Incarnations to evolve. As you know there have been <b>Incarnations of Śhrī Viṣhṇu as a fish to begin with and went on till it came to the state of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, where they say that He has become complete</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0806 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, The Witness State (Taṭasth), Lawn, Āśhram, Garlate (40 kms E of Como), Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1005.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... the best state which you call as Sākṣhi Swarūpatva, which you achieve when the Kuṇḍalinī comes up and the connection is established and the Divine Grace 
starts flowing through that and enriches your Viśhuddhi chakra."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0806 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, The Witness State (Taṭasth), Lawn, Āśhram, Garlate (40 kms E of Como), Italy</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Viśhwa Sākṣhi sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"To overcome all kinds of nonsense of religion, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa’s Advent was there. Is a very important Advent, but I don’t know how many people understand that. He came to show that it’s all Līlā, is all the Play of God. What is there to be serious? What is there to be ritualistic? You cannot bind God in any rituals. That’s why He came on this Earth, to tell you that you should not try to bind yourself by rituals which are nonsensical. This was His teaching soo many years back, He taught this six thousand year back, but still, if you-you see, in every religion there are so many rituals going on.<br />
So when the Incarnations died, people started rituals, funny stuff."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0806 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, The Witness State (Taṭasth), Lawn, Āśhram, Garlate (40 kms E of Como), Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1006.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Unless and until this America is put right, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is not going to leave My throat, I tell you.<br />
So, as America, I say, is the place of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa’s auspiciousness."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1002 Śhrī Yogeśhwara Pūjā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and the Enlightenment of the Brain, Camp Vacamas, 256 Macopin Road, West Milford, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātṛu-charan’āmṛuta-priya</b><br />
<b>sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
You are The one who enjoys the Amṛut of the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0806 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, The Witness State (Taṭasth), Lawn, Āśhram, Garlate (40 kms E of Como), Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/571534956"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Jay Rādhā Mādhav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Yoga Dayānī Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Rādhā Kanta Śhyām Manohar</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa Bhajele</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/P8g8UR1ZaU8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Āratī (1987-0816 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/DEzt1vmETlk">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Krishna Janmashtami" /><category term="orange @ Shri Krishna Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Rakshābandhan: “day you should ask for perfection, make big decisions and keep attention on high ideals.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Rakshābandhan: “day you should ask for perfection, make big decisions and keep attention on high ideals.”" /><published>2022-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/2022_08_11_Rakshabandhan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/08/11"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="blue">"<b>Is so important, that on this day if this is tied on your wrist, then you become brothers and sisters.</b><br />
Now, <b>in Sahaja Yoga brotherhood is the most important.</b> That is the friendliness among ourselves. When you are very good brothers and sisters, first of all, your left Viśhuddhi improves.<br />
This left Viśhuddhi. You get this left Viśhuddhi, because we don't have proper brother and sister relationship. Is not that we should have our own sister, but any woman who is a Sahaja Yoginī is your sister. Except for your own wife.<br />
And this is the feeling. Unless and until we develop that pure feeling within ourselves, we cannot work out Sahaja Yoga. Sahaja Yoga cannot be worked out. I know it's rather difficult to digest, but is a fact. You have to feel clean and pure within your heart."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0818 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (the day before Rakṣhābandhan Day), Room, Āśhram, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image999.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today in India, we celebrate a set ... special festival. It is called as Rakṣhā-bandhan.</b> Rakṣhā means protection and bandhan means the bondage: the bondage of protection. Is a very nice, good, social custom to have this beautiful festival today.<br />
Today is the Full Moon Day, and this day what we do is to tie a band of threads around the person whom you want to protect. But it is done between brothers and sisters."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0826 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Rakṣhābandhan Day), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue">"<b>So, this day is uh extremely important, in a way, for Sahaja Yogis to observe, and I’m happy that I am here, because it’s very important also for America.</b><br />
Uh as I told you that, I have already talked to you how the war between Alexander and Puru was finished because of a sister’s intervention.<br />
And, also, how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, whose sister was Draupadī, Viṣhṇumāyā was born as Draupadī, and how He came to save Her chastity, by rushing all the way from Dvārika.<br />
So, we can see that when we ascend in the Collective Consciousness and we have a collective living, collective meeting, at the Viśhuddhi chakra, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa establish this, or He manifested uh this pure relationship of a sister.<br />
In a collective life that we have, in the Āśhram where we live, where we move about as Sahaja Yogis, if we do not have this basic principle within us, there will be a chaos, complete chaos. Once this purity of relationship is established, that apart from my wife, all the rest are my sisters or mothers, it cannot be a proper society and the chaos of the social system of America is because they have no sense of pure relationships.<br />
<b>Once you call somebody a sister, she’s a sister. And once you call somebody a brother, he’s a brother. It’s not only that you should be born of the same parents, it’s not necessary, but this is a very important principle to have a very pure society where everybody can live peacefully.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0">1990-0807 Rakṣhābandhan Pūjā, Room, House of Dr. Vinod Worlikar, 17301 Maria Avenue, Cerritos (32 kms SE of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.<b></b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1000.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"But Rākhī Day, My brother [Bābā Māmā] is here. It's nice that we can have it in a way My physical brother is here. It's very good we are having a rākhī program today in his presence. And, all of you should also <b>understand that it's a very subtle, pure, beautiful relationship that exists between a brother and a sister.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0820 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā (1 week before Rakṣhābandhan Day), Cure that Left Viśhuddhi, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0">Nirmalā, Kiti Varnāvi Tujhiga Stuti:</font></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Bābā Māmā (March 1990): This is what the brother has written for the sister:
"O Nirmalā, my Sister, how much should I praise You? Because You have given the human being the experience of God."</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue">"So apart from ego and superego, the worst thing that has happened to these modern societies is that, that they have lost their innate understanding of purity.<br />
That innate understanding in Sahaja Yoga now you have got it. So try to develop it and flower it, so the fragrance of that innocence will make each other very happy and such a kind of a security. One feels so secure.<br />
And that’s why it is <b>a rakṣhābandhan, the protection of a brother and protection of a sister.<br />
All the time you know, my brother is there, after all, my sister is there. A kind of a very pure, beautiful feeling, that, ‘I have somebody to protect me.’</b><br />
And this beautiful feeling, if it’s nurtured, looked after, in a wider way in Sahaja Yoga, then you feel absolutely, absolutely secure."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0807 Rakṣhābandhan Pūjā, Room, House of Dr. Vinod Worlikar, 17301 Maria Avenue, Cerritos (32 kms SE of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1001.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Rākhī is Protecting Power.</b><br /> 
Its bond is very strong and extremely tender because it symbolizes the noble love of sister. Customarily, tying a rākhī to someone is establishing a place of Pure Protection. However, man's ability to understand love has become so feeble that tying of rākhī has become merely a mechanical process. All beautiful human traditions become lifeless and dry formalities if there is no warmth of faith in them.<br />
......<br />
<b>Rakhi Pūrnimā is a day of great significance.<br />
On that day you should ask for perfection, make big decisions and keep attention on high ideals.</b><br />
Sahaja Yogis should not destroy their attention on trifle issues.<br />
Lot of work has yet to be done.<br />
Those Sahaja Yogis who have progressed should get busy.<br />
New centers should be opened.<br />
<b>People should be cured of their diseases and their attention should be drawn towards God-realization.</b>"</font><br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0817 Letter (Marathi) on Rakṣhābandhan and Pūrṇimā Day (0818), London, UK from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 11 (September-October 1982), Page 25</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0807 Rakṣhābandhan Pūjā, Room, House of Dr. Vinod Worlikar, 17301 Maria Avenue, Cerritos (32 kms SE of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/545775094"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Rākhī Bhajan Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Rākhī offered to Śhrī Mātājī from America (1993-0815 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Dharma, Cabella)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>"I Am Your Rākhī Brother" (1985-0921 Seminar, Sheffield, UK)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>He Govinda He Gopāla</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1002.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You are my brothers and sisters<br />
Because you are human,<br />
And we all are sons and daughters<br />
Of one Holy Spirit;<br />
We are equal and made of the same Earth.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>('My Brethren' by Kahlil Gibran)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Rakshabandhan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Guru Pūrṇimā: “Because as God has created days of their advent, human beings have created days of their surrendering.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/07/13" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Guru Pūrṇimā: “Because as God has created days of their advent, human beings have created days of their surrendering.”" /><published>2022-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/07/2022_07_13_Guru_Purnima</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/07/13"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the day peoples, this is created by human beings and not by God, as Guru Pūrṇimā. Because as God has created days of</b></font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font> their advent], <font color="DarkRed"><b>human beings have created days of their surrendering. So this is the day when you have to give something to the Guru.</b> And Guru does not have to give anything to you. This is the time you have to say what you are going to give, what you are going to do for your Guru. Because so far the Guru has been giving. If you are in meditation supposing you say we’ll meditate because Guru Pūrṇimā is there. That’s not the way the Guru Pūrṇimā is to be celebrated, because if you meditate you are taking from Me. If you try to correct yourself you are taking from Me. If you are going to get cured you are taking from Me. So now what can you do for Me? Is the point you have to think about. What can you do? Now I have sent the same question to India, [unclear] I asked them to find out what can you do for Me. You will say: ‘Mother, what can we do? After all, what are we?’ That’s a way of evading the issue. <b>But if you really want to see, you can do a lot and that is what it is that you are My witness. You are My publicity.</b></font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0701 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day) (first more formal Pūjā in the West), Self-realization, Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image991.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>" "Guru is a person who makes you meet God": he raises the Kuṇḍalinī and makes you one with God."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0708 Guru Pūjā, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"It’s very interesting the way you found out: today is the real Guru Pūrṇimā. It’s a Pūrṇimā, is the day when the Moon is full."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0724 Guru Pūrṇimā Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Niṣhkala sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<b>The one without any phases (hence he is celebrated on a Pūrṇimā Day, a Full Moon)</b><br />
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is the day of Guru Pūrṇimā. It is a Full Moon Day, that’s why it’s called as Pūrṇimā. The guru has to be like a Full Moon, means completely grown, completely matured.<br />
......<br /> 
Now we have to understand the importance of guru. Why should we have a guru when we have God? We’ve got Śhakti, then why should we have a guru? What is the need to have a guru? Guru means ‘the weight’, the weight. We get our weight from the magnetic forces of the gravity of the Mother Earth. So guru means gravity, gravity in a person. Why do we need a guru? Because to know God is easy, specially in Sahaja Yoga, to be one with Him. <b>As soon as you get your Self-realization in Sahaja Yoga, the modern Sahaja Yoga, immediately you become entitled to give Realizations to other. It was said that guru is the person who makes you meet the Divine. That’s not true, because any self-realized person in the Sahaja Yoga can raise the Kuṇḍalinī and can give Self-realization to others, immediately after they have touched the Sahasrāra or opened the Sahasrāra. But normally a realized Soul cannot do it. Any born realized Soul cannot do it on its own, it has to have authority of Me as I am today.</b><br />
That’s why it was said that guru is a person who makes you meet God; he raises the Kuṇḍalinī and makes you one with God. Because in those days when the gurus were self-realized when the gurus were realized, they had the authority and power of raising the Kuṇḍalinī only after they had reached a very great state of evolution – complete purification, complete detachment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0708 Guru Pūjā, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image992.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Today is a Pūrṇimā Day. Pūrṇimā means a Complete Moon.<br />
The guru has to be a complete personality to talk about these Statutes and to elevate his disciples to this level of understanding, by which they imbibe those Statutes."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0727 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day), Statutes of the Lord (You Do Not Harm Anyone, The Testimony of the Truth, Develop Detachment, Lead a Moral Life) and Promise that You Will Be a Guru Worthy of Your Mother (Today I Authorize You to Be the Gurus and You Have a Very Supreme Guru), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Gurorrashtakam Yah pathet punya dehi</b></font><br />
That noble Soul who ponders these verses in the Guru's praise<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Yatir Bhoopatir Brahmachari Cha Gehi</b></font><br />
Of all ascetics and students, of all rulers and wordly men<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Labhhed Vanchhitartham padam Brahma Sangyam</b></font><br />
will attain the Brahman, the treasure coveted by all<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Gururukta Vakye Mano Yasya Lagnam</b></font><br />
By applying his mind with constant zeal to the Guru's teaching<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is a great day, for all of us, because we are celebrating the Guru Pūjā and remembering all the Great Gurus who came on Earth to teach the world about the Truth. So many of Them were here. And They tried Their level best to explain to humanity what is spirituality.<br />
But is such a disparity that people never understood that spirituality is the most important thing we need, that we have to be one with the Divine Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0721 Guru Pūjā, Spirituality Is the Most Important Thing We Need (Enlarge Your Heart and Spread Sahaja Yoga with Humility), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As today’s day is great, because we are thinking of all the great Saints who came on this Earth and who tried to lead us. What they did, all of them tried to spread the Truth all over the world. They suffered a lot, they had problems, so many problems, but they worked very hard in every way to spread Sahaja Yoga and talk about God and Divinity.<br />
All that is what today you have to give Me, a promise, that whenever you get any other human being, you can tell them about Sahaja Yoga. Not that it’s important but it’s absolutely immediate need of the world. If you understand this point, that at this time, why are you in this world and what is the need of the world, you will immediately start feeling the responsibility. Whether you are a man or a woman is not important.<br />
<b>Go all out to preach, think, make people understand about Sahaja Yoga in every way that is possible, and I think, then, you will become complete as gurus. If Sahaja Yoga is just with you, you cannot be a guru. ‘Guru’ also doesn’t mean that you go on preaching about Sahaja Yoga, talking about Sahaja Yoga, giving lectures about Sahaja Yoga, no! It means the one who gives Realizations to others.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0721 Guru Pūjā, Spirituality Is the Most Important Thing We Need (Enlarge Your Heart and Spread Sahaja Yoga with Humility), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image993.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"This is the day of Guru Pūrṇimā and I bless you that you all become gurus.
Whatever you have got now don’t waste it, don’t throw away but use it for the betterment of people."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0720 Guru Pūjā, You All Have to Become a Guru, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Guru Tutz. Vitthala Hari Tu Mahādev</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O Guru You are all prevading, You are my Viṭṭhal<br />
Your are my Hari and also my Mahādev,</font><br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Guru Charani Payi Vidya Satya Mev.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">At Your Lotus Feet O Guru, I have attained the true knowledge</font><br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Guru Totz. Manavi Khara Mazha</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">He only will be my True Guru</font><br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Guru Zhotz. Banavil. Mam. Mazha</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">The One who makes me my own Guru</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Sahaja Yoga is very different from all other gurus that we believe in the Power of Love. Power of Love teaches you how to be forgiving, it makes you noble, it makes you very balanced.<br />
<b>So, the gurus who were there for Bhavasāgara, to establish dharma in the human beings, first thing, they had to balance themselves against all practical things, as they call it.</b> They think is not practical!<br />
But they said, “No! For us, this is higher, nobler, and important.” <b>So they would balance people because they had this Power of Love within themselves. All these Ādi Gurus and Their Incarnations, if you see Them, They always had balance and always prayed ... praised the Love of God.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0704 Guru Pūjā, Understand Our Own Value, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Is a very important day, because as a Guru Pūjā, they say that a guru cannot give anything to you. But I can give you the advice, and the advice that you enlarge your heart, you become humble, and try to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility, not with aggressiveness. That is extremely important. If you can do that, then you’ll do full justice to this life, which is a spiritual life. Without that you cannot achieve, you cannot achieve, the strength of spirituality.<br />
For that you have to understand that it’s very, very important that you should give Sahaja Yoga a full chance, through your wisdom."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0724 Guru Pūrṇimā Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image994.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b> "On this Guru Pūrṇimā I bless all of you and all those who are realized, are very special people, and I would say to them that just as you have got, give to others.<br />
You too have to bring them around.<br />
Might be that they may get annoyed with you, hit you, beat you, they may not remain, but this is nothing. I have borne much more than this.<br />
That is why with joy and not arguments; they may not believe in you, doesn’t matter. Leave them. They may argue, just leave them.<br />
The ones who believe in you give them.<br />
This is what you have to give and this is all you can give that My love may reach each corner of the world and each house may be lit with it.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0715 Public Program (Hindi) (Guru Pūrṇimā), Sahaja Yoga a New Discovery, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other possible dates 1974-0704, 1975-0723, or 1976-0711)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>Guru Charnan. ki lagi lagan. hai</b><br />
Now we have got the Divine attachment to the Lotus Feet of our Guru<br />
<b>Tav. Charanan. me utara swarg. hai</b><br />
All the heavens have come down at Your Lotus Feet<br />
<b>Parmeśhwari. hai mangal. kari</b><br />
Goddess is giving the welfare to Her devotees<br />
<b>Khoye sadhak. par. Utari</b><br />
She gives realization to those who are lost</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/hMK6gaaQ1hU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font> 
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0704 Guru Pūjā, Understand Our Own Value, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<a href="https://vimeo.com/178753156"> video</a><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="Maroon"><b>Guru bin Kaun
</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="Maroon"><b>Guru kī Mahima</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="Maroon"><b>10 Names of Ādi Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/DJbZIRyUdpU?list=PLuAVZW42aaCmiw6ZTKHcdOcRBgEo8TZKu">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="Maroon"><b>Nirmal Sangīt Sarita - Namanat Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/KEdz1c-gM_4?list=PL407136734B2B056D">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="Maroon"><b>Guru Mauli</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image995.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">There are many people who do believe, but not yet got their Realization, so you have to work and you will be amazed you will find people who are very anxious to get their Realization.<br />
<b>It will work out on this Guru Pūrṇimā Day, it is a very auspicious day.</b><br />
<b>I bless you with a special power that you can give Realization to others.</b> Don’t get involved in your own problems, that’s not important, that will all be solved.<br />
......<br />
I am happy today is another day of Guru Pūrṇimā which is a very auspicious day and to be regarded as a very big blessing for you because this gives you, I mean this is a certificate, that you all are capable of being gurus. <b>You have to become that, becoming is important, in Sahaj Yoga becoming is important, all other things are really of no use.<br />
And I bless you all to do this work, which was left half done by the Saints, it’s your duty to complete it.</b><br />
<b>May God bless you.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0724 Guru Pūrṇimā Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Gurūr Brahmā Gurūr Viṣhṇu Gurūr devo Maheśhwara, Gurūr sākshāt Parabrahma tasmai Śhrī Guru Dev namaḥ."<br />"
The Guru is Brahmā [creator], Viṣhṇu [sustainer] and Maheśh [destroyer] and the Guru who is himself God, I offer My obeisance to him."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Guru Vandana</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Guru Purnima" /><category term="orange @ Guru Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Worship of Śhrī Ādi Śhakti: “I declare that I am the One who has to save the humanity. I declare I am the One who is Ādi Śhakti”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/06/19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Worship of Śhrī Ādi Śhakti: “I declare that I am the One who has to save the humanity. I declare I am the One who is Ādi Śhakti”" /><published>2022-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/06/2022_06_19_International_Shri_Adi_Shakti_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/06/19"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are worshiping Ādi Śhakti.</b><br />
I think this is the most important Pūjā, because it is the Power of Ādi Śhakti that has given you Self-realization, that has given you the Truth, that has given you the Power of Compassion and Love.<br />
That’s the power that separated from Sadāśhiva. And this Power wanted Herself to create this Complete Universe: universes after universes. She’s creating and loving. With Her love, She did this Great Creation, Creation of this world also.<br />
This is a specially selected planet, which was very beautifully brought in the center, between the Sun and the Moon, for the creation of, ultimately, the human beings."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0603 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, The Work of Ādi Śhakti and These Are the Most Important Times (Compassion Today Is to Transform Human Beings into Sahajīs and You Are the Ones Who Have to Build Up the Destiny of Human Beings), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image983.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>RACHA PRABHU TUNEY YAHA BRAHMANDA SARA</b></font><br />
<b>O God You have created the whole universe</b><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>PRANON SEY PYARA, BRAHMANDA SARA</b></font><br />
<b>The whole universe is dearer than our lives</b><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>TUHI MAI BANDHU, TUHI JAGAT JANANI</b></font><br />
<b>You are my Mother and brother, You are the Mother of the universe</b><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>SAKAL JAGAT MEIN YAH TERA PASARA</b></font><br />
<b>The whole universe is but Your Form</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are all going to worship Me, first time. It has been always the Pūjā of [an] aspect of Me or a part of Me.</b><br />
Now, one has to know very clearly what is Ādi Śhakti. As we say, is the Pure Desire of God Almighty, of Sadāśhiva. But what is the pure Desire of God Almighty?<br />
If you see your own desires, come out of what? Not out of the Divine Love but out of carnal love, out of material love, of out of power love. Behind all these desires there is love.<br /> 
If you do not love something you will not desire it. So, these mundane types of love that you have, for which we spend so much of our time uselessly, actually they do not give you satisfaction, because that is not true love that you have. Just infatuation for the time being, and then you just get fed up with it, and from there you jump to another thing, to another thing, to another thing. So Ādi Śhakti is the Embodiment of God's Divine Love, is God's Pure Love, and in His Love what did He desire? He desired that He should create human beings, who would be very obedient, would be sublime, would be like angels. And that was His idea: to create Adam and Eve. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0606 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, Incarnation of Divine Love, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image984.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Dene Zeri Amuchya Shiri,</b></font><br />
<i>You have given us so much</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pari Agnya Jana Tu Par Kari,</b></font><br />
<i>even to those who don't have any knowledge,</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Deshi Jag. Tu Sahaj. Yoga,</b></font><br />
<i>You give Sahaja Yoga to the whole universe</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jan Kotama,</b></font><br />
<i>Verily You are the highest Father of Mankind</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<i>O Primordial Mother, O Eternal Mother</i><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Love is the Message of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
Now you think about it. One Ādi Śhakti created the whole world.</b> How she must have done it. What she must have planned. How she must have organized. It is not a[n] easy thing. Only because she loved.<br />
Love is the expression that you are all there. That is why to be one with Her one should learn to love.<br /> 
Of course in that you have to know that you should forgive. If you don’t know how to forgive and find mistakes of other people you won’t help. What is your now job is, is to see that you are loving, no hatred for anyone, you don’t think of hating anyone and hitting somebody.<br />
This has to work out."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-0624 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, You Have to Become Fragrant, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Somebody asked Me “Is it necessary to have this Pūjā.” I think if there is any Pūjā you should do, it is this one – is Ādi Shakti.<br />
It is very important that this Pūjā must be performed</b> because that is how you grow, this reflection improves and you grow more and more within yourself, through the power of Ādi Shakti or through the power of Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
As you know that Ādi Shakti has her own Kuṇḍalinī, which is the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī, and the reflection of that within you – is the Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
So you have to worship and it’s the best way to please your own Kuṇḍalinī, your own Mother, who has given you this birth"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0609 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, Kuṇḍalinī -- the Binding Principle or You Dissolve into the Divine Power, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image985.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Vin.ti Suniye Ādi Śhakti Meri</b></font><br />
<b>O Ādi Śhakti, please listen to my request</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pujan. ka adhikar. dijiye</b></font><br />
<b>Please give me the authority to do Your Pūjā</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sharanagat. hai hṛiday. pujari</b></font><br />
<b>Your worshipper is surrendered to You from the heart.</b><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/hMK6gaaQ1hU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed&gt;">"And at this place meet the three chakras, and that is why Śhrī Mahākālī, Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī and Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī, all these Three Powers meet.<br /> 
<b>As these Three Powers meet, they form One Power, that is Śhrī Ādi Śhakti.<br />  
That is why in Sahasrāra Śhrī Ādi Śhakti resides, but it is said so, that in Sahasrāra Ādi Śhakti exists in a form of Mahāmāyā -- Śhrī Ādi Śhakti exists, but She is in the form of Mahāmāyā.</b><br />
That is why the result of all these Three Powers was like this, that Śhrī Ādi Śhakti comes into this world in the form of Mahāmāyā (Mahāmāyā Swarūp), and She can penetrate the Sahasrāra of everyone.<br />
As you know, She is in front of you and you know all about it, so I need not tell anything more."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0106 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Marathi+English), Ascent Is the Main Attention, Sangli, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b>Bolo Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī, Śhrī Nirmalā Devī kī Jay<br />
Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī kī Jay<br />
Mā Bhakti Priya, Mā Nishka Mā<br />
Hay Nirguna Mā, Nishpapa Mā<br />
Sara Brahmand. Hai Jisme Racha Nirmal kī Jay<br />
Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī kī Jay</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Bolo Ādi Śhakti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image986.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"But today is the day, I declare that I am the One who has to save the humanity. 
I declare I am the One who is Ādi Śhakti, who is the Mother of all the Mothers, who is the Primordial Mother, the Śhakti, the Desire of God, who has incarnated on this Earth to give Its meaning to Itself, 
to this creation, to human beings, and I’m sure through My Love and Patience and My Powers, I am going to achieve it.<br />
I was the One who was born again and again, but now in My Complete Form and Complete Powers, 
I have come on this Earth, not only for salvation of human beings, not only for their emancipation, 
but for granting them, the Kingdom of Heaven, the Joy, the Bliss, that your Father wants to bestow upon you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1202 Guru Pūjā, The Declaration, Living Room, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<i>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</i><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=L1wSDCxZKS0&amp;list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0&amp;index=16&amp;ab_channel=VIOLONISTUL">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0603 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, The Work of Ādi Śhakti and These Are the Most Important Times (Compassion Today Is to Transform Human Beings into Sahajīs and You Are the Ones Who Have to Build Up the Destiny of Human Beings), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/24300259"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Ganapati Vandan Gan nayak</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Nirmalā Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/v7T1xpKkYFU">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sare Jag Mein tere Dhūm</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mavena Nayani Ananda</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sabako Dua Dena Ma Sabako Dua Dena and Three Mahāmantras:</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lGC_kUMmabQ?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vinati suniye Ādi Śhakti meri</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/J3Qhod0xxPs">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image987.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Thank You, O Śhrī Ādi Śhakti, for the seeking which brought us to Sahaja Yoga.<br />
You now lift up humanity into the omega of the Last Judgment.<br />
We pray that Śhrī Ādi Śhakti's love continues to protect all the saints and seekers around the world.<br /> 
Śhrī Ādi Śhakti, Your work is greater than any.<br />
You created the Pīṭhas, the chakras, nature and humanity, and its subtle workings.<br />
May the complexity of Your work humble us down completely.<br />
Your love gives power to the bandhan, which directs the vibrations.<br />
Your power of Kuṇḍalinī brings freedom that is divine. It is the only true freedom.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><b>Bolo Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī kī Jay!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Shri Adi Shakti Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Buddha Jayanti: “Because you are all connected with the same Divine Force there can be no difference of opinion”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Buddha Jayanti: “Because you are all connected with the same Divine Force there can be no difference of opinion”" /><published>2022-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/2022_05_16_Shri_Buddha_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/16"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, today we have gathered here to worship Buddha.</b><br />
Lord Buddha, as you know, was Gautama: the One who was born in a royal family.<br />
And then, He became an ascetic. Because He was very much hurt to see three types of problems from which human beings suffer. And He came to [the] conclusion: ‘All these three types of problems are because we have desires.’ So He said that, “If you become desireless, then there will be no problem for you.”<br />
So He studied Vedas, He studied Upaniṣhadas, He studies [studied] all kinds of things, He went to many Saints and many people, [but] He could not get His Realization.<br />
Actually, He was an Incarnation.
The Incarnation also has to reach a point of Realization in a different way. Like the whole potential has to open out. But the Incarnation has tremendous potential. And that expresses itself once the door is opened outward."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0520 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Gautama, The Lord of the Ego, Open Air near El Farell Hotel, Barcelona, Spain</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image976.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Buddha realized the greatest problem of human beings is his ego.<br />
In his ego, he goes to the extremes: from one end to another.<br />
And so He worked throughout on the Piṅgalā nāḍī for us, and stationed Himself on our ego, to control it."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0520 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Gautama, The Lord of the Ego, Open Air near El Farell Hotel, Barcelona, Spain</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mātājī, salutations to Thee again and again.<br />
Thou art the Primordial Splendor of God, the Ādi Śhakti and Mother of the Devatas.<br />
Thou art the roots of all action, the success in any action, and the sole and only Doer in the countless universes of Thy creation.<br />
Thou art Śhrī Mahāmāyā, the Mother of the Ādi Ahaṅkāra, the Primordial Ego of God, the Prince of Kapilavastu who became, by Thy grace, the Buddha.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Prayer to Śhrī Buddha from 1988-0723 Pūjā, CA, U.S.A.)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have decided to celebrate the Buddha Jayanti, it's the day of Buddha's birthday.</b> In the whole map of time, Buddha came to this Earth at a time when it was so important for Him to come. That time, especially in India, we had two types of people: one, who were very ritualistic, trying to be extremely strict and disciplined; and the another were the people who were too much conditioned and were full of so-called devotion to God. So these two types of people were occupying the area of seekers. So it was necessary to neutralize these two styles of seekings. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0723 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Tent, YMCA Camp Surf, 560 Silver Strand Blvd, Imperial Beach (21 kms S of San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now Buddha was one of the very Great Incarnations in the sense that He was the son, one of the sons of Rāma who incarnated on this earth, Buddha, to occupy the highest life on this earth.</b> So He had to take saṃnyāsa because without that He could not show that. But there was no need for anybody else to take saṃnyāsa. But in His case mistakes, I mean, why there were some mistakes about things, because when He tried all these tricks of saṃnyāsa, going here and there He never realized that this is all not needed. He was so tired and fagged out, that suddenly, spontaneous, the Primordial Mother Herself gave Him the Realization because He was so tired."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0611 Public Program, How Aspects of God Are Expressed within Us, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image977.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The Pūjā to Shrī Buddha is being performed today to open this chakra.<br />
At the level of the Āgñyā chakra, there are thoughts. Because you are all connected with the same Divine Force there can be no difference of opinion."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0514 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Saint Petersburg, Russia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Siddhārtha Gautama Buddha sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Buddha. Salutations to You!
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So the people who today are worshiping Buddha should know that His Message of Truth, which we know through our right side, through our attention, must be applied to ourselves, first of all.</b><br />
...... The problem with Sahaja Yogis sometimes is that they don’t know the importance of what they are, they are not aware. If their ego was correct, in that ahaṅkāra, ego, the essence of it is aham-bhāva, is that, ‘I am a Sahaja Yogi.’ I am a Sahaja Yogi.’ Now keep the point of honesty with it. ‘Honestly, I’m a Sahaja Yogi and I’m a follower of a religion, which is a Universal Religion, which is innately built myself. There’s no hanky panky about it. Is my experience, and I believe in it fully, and is innately within myself.’ This is the aham-bhāva. I don’t know what is it in the English language, is could be ‘I’-ness, ‘I’-ness.<br />
Then, “I am on this Earth now, this life is for the work of God. And for that, I have to be a pure person because I belong to Vishwa Nirmal Dharm. I have to be pure. I have to achieve my purity: through meditation through every way watching myself, ‘I have to be a pure person.’ And if I am a Sahaja Yogi, if I am united with that All-pervading Power of Love, I should be the medium to give that love to others and compassion. I have no time for other things. Other things are of no value. My attention has to be pure. My life has to be pure."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0520 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Gautama, The Lord of the Ego, Open Air near El Farell Hotel, Barcelona, Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, this special thing is that we are worshiping a Deity on the right Āgñyā which makes you think too much, first of all, and also it makes you aggressive, and also it makes you a very right-sided.</b> By this worship, you will become very mild, very gentle, very beautiful people and you’ll be able to see things much more clearly.<br />
Now, this right side gives you a kind of a ego which troubles everyone, but you could never feel the trouble till you get into a very serious state. It gives you the overactivity of the brain and conscious mind works too hard. For that you are, you are not very hard-working people, but you can see, first of all, that your mind is more active than your body. So, this Āgñyā chakra has to be controlled by Buddha, and that’s why we do Pūjā today."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0514 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Saint Petersburg, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image978.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Śhrī Mātājī, salutations to Thee again and again.<br />
Śhrī Mātājī, may all aspects of the Bodhi Chitta, the enlightened consciousness, be awakened at Thy command.<br />
May all Bodhisattvas perform Thy Āratī.<br />
May Thy grace prevail! Amen.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Buddham śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi</b></font><br />
I surrender myself to my Self-realization and to all those who are realized Souls (Buddhas)<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Dhammam śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi</b></font><br />
I surrender myself to dharma, to the Innate Religion that is Vishwa Nirmala Dharma <br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Saṅghaṃ śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi</b></font><br />
I surrender myself to collectivity and to the collective community of realized Souls<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Ādi Śhaktyai Nirmalā Mātaram śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi</b></font><br />
I surrender myself to Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Nirmalā Matajī<br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0520 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Gautama, The Lord of the Ego, Open Air near El Farell Hotel, Barcelona, Spain</b></font>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/vM-qYgVY5Hg"> video</a></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<font color="green"><b>Tum Asha Vishwas Hamare</b></font>
<p><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a></p>

<font color="green"><b>Sandhanya ya Janmi Nirvan</b></font>
<p><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a></p>

<font color="green"><b>Buddha Deva Tujhi Dnyan Ganga</b></font>
<p><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a></p>

<font color="green"><b>Mā Hai Ek. Rup Anek</b> (1991-0804 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Belgium)</font>
<p><br />
<a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-yoga-music/maa-hai-ek-rup-anek-1991-0804">video</a></p>

<font color="green"><b>Nirgunache Bheti</b></font>
<p><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a></p>

<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Buddha Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Sahasrāra Pūjā: “To be one with the Divine is the greatest blessing for human beings.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/08" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Sahasrāra Pūjā: “To be one with the Divine is the greatest blessing for human beings.”" /><published>2022-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/2022_05_08_Sahasrara_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/08"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a very great day, I must say, to celebrate Sahasrāra, the Pūjā of Sahasrāra.</b><br />
It’s a very unique thing that has happened, that your Sahasrāras were opened out.<br />
......<br /> 
So it’s a very great day because collectively this Sahasrāra has been opened. Every one of you have got it. Also all over the world, you have many people who have got their Sahasrāras open. Of course, we need many more for them to understand what is this great event of such a collective opening of Sahasrāra.<br />
Some have grown very much, after getting their Realization, very much. They have understood Sahaja Yoga very well, and they have developed their depth, and their consciousness is really a great awareness of Oneness with the Divine.<br />
<b>To be one with the Divine is the greatest blessing for human beings.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Watch Yourself, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image970.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Sahasrāra is the day which is very important, which makes a big history in the spirituality 
and also in the evolutionary process."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0730 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Divine Laws, after the Evening Program, the day before Guru Pūjā, Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Tū Ādi Śhakti, Sahasrār viraji</b><br />
You are Śhrī Ādi Śhakti seated on the cosmic Sahasrāra</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Chaitanya lutati, Satya Yuga jagati</b><br />
Showering Divine Vibrations and heralding the beginning of Satya Yuga</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Viśhwa ki Janani, Tū Mahādevī</b><br />
You are the Mother of the universe and the Great Goddess</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Tere Putra banne ki Patrata de Mā</b><br />
Mother please grant us all the qualities by which we can be Your children in reality.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>He Nirmalā Mā, He Nirmalā Mā<br />
Tera pyar. Mokṣha ka Anand. hai Mā</b><br />
O Divine Mother, Your unbounded love is the bliss of Liberation</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/v7T1xpKkYFU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So this Sahasrāra Day or, we can say, on the day the Sahasrāra was opened out, is a very important one, it’s very subtle.</b> We just know about the Kuṇḍalinī, that She’s coiled up in three and a half, and She’s lying in the triangular bone known as sacrum. But we don’t know what She works, how She works, what happens to us. She rises in six centers and breaks the seventh ... I should say She breaks the sixth center because Gaṇeśha’s center doesn’t play any role. So when She breaks the sixth center, which is the
Sahasrāra, then She connects you to the All-pervading Power of Divine Love.<br />
But what is this Divine Love? What does this do? It is the Energy of the Mother. We can say it is the Energy of Ādi Śhakti, which is all over, works through vibrations. But what are these vibrations? It’s a very subtle energy that starts flowing through your Sahasrāra. All the thousand petals of the Sahasrāra get slowly enlightened and it starts flowing throughout your body, throughout your hands, feet, throughout your body. And the more you are ... I mean your attention is, on the Sahasrāra, the more it works faster."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0506 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image971.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Viśhveśhwarī twam paripasi viśhwam</b><br />
O Queen of the universe You are its guardian.<br />
<b>Viśhwātmā dharayas'iti vishwam</b><br />
In the form of the Universe You are its receptacle.<br />
<b>Viśhweśha vandhya bhavati bhavanti</b><br />
You are worshipped by the lords of the universe.<br />
<b>Viśhwaśhraya ye twayi bhakti namraha</b><br />
Those who are devoted to You themselves become supporters of the universe</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Prayer to Śhrī Rājarājeśhwarī.<br />
(79 names of Śhrī Rājarājeśhwarī created by Śhrī Mātājī Herself and read out during the 2000 Sahasrāra Pūjā in Albera Ligure)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/7jLDenmw7So">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, it’s a great day because Sahasrāra Day and Mother’s Day have come together. It’s a very Sahaj happening, I think, and that is what we have to understand, how Sahasrāra and motherhood go together.</b><br />
Sahasrāra was definitely opened and Mother had to do it, because formerly those people who came on this Earth tried to teach people about dharma, to bring them to the central path, to the straightforward path of ascent. They tried everything, whatever way They thought was good for a particular community, particular area, particular country. They talked about it and lots of books came out of it, but instead of all these books creating people of religious, spiritual and a united nature, created people who were all against each other."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Blessing of the Divine Pours Only if the Sahasrāra is Open (Meditation Is the Only Way You Can Enrich Yourself with the Beauty of Reality), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, opening Sahasrāra was the most important part of the evolutionary process.</b> All the evolution process brought human beings to what level? We had wars, we had all kinds of silly programs by which we really ruined the so many countries, so many people.<br />
Now, when you are one with that All-pervading Power – it’s a pure power, it’s a nirmal power, absolutely pure power – that gives you complete sense and complete understanding as to how you should move, how you should live and what you should have. This is what is Self-realization, they say."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0509 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Awareness Has to Become Paramachaitanya or Paramachaitanya Is with You, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image972.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>The Mother is everything</b> — She is our consolation in sorrow, our hope in misery, and our strength in weakness.<br />
She is the source of love, mercy, sympathy, and forgiveness. And this Earth is the Mother of the trees and flowers.<br />
It produces them, nurses them, and weans them.<br />
The trees and flowers become kind mothers of their great fruits and seeds.<br />
And the Mother, the prototype of all existence, is the Eternal Spirit, full of beauty and love.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Kahlil Gibran: 'Broken Wings')</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mother, I Adore You</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LsWaC7NktHA">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It’s very gratifying to see so many Sahaja Yogis have come to celebrate the Sahasrāra Day.<br />
Without breaking the Sahasrāra, we could not have achieved the ascent en masse. But the Sahasrāra which is the brain has gone into too much complications in the West. And the thoughts are very much twisted, one upon the other. To keep Sahasrāra open should be very easy if the Western brains could understand and be aware about your Mother.<br />
<b>When your Mother is the Deity of Sahasrāra, the only way to be able to keep the Sahasrāra open has to be complete surrendering.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0504 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirvikalpa, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a unique combination of Mother’s Day in many countries and Sahasrār Day for Sahaj Yogis. I think this is the most important day in the history of human evolution</b> because all other events, Incarnations and ventures in the spiritual atmosphere have been of no avail. On the contrary, they have gone into a kind of a cocoon which has no door, banging themselves against the walls, creating problems out of something very auspicious and extremely, beautifully spiritual.<br />
Is not possible to find faults with the Incarnations in whose names all the religions came in. But this cocoon is the Mahāmāyā, I think, cocoon is the one which is ignorance. We can say that Māyā ... Mahāmāyā does not create it. This cocoon is created by the basic ignorance of human beings and their misidentifications."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Mahāmāyā Swarūpa, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image973.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> <font color="DarkRed"><b>Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks.
Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
Nothing ever had a meaning nor a life, everyone so dry and so weak, then You came,<br />
O Mother, so caring, so sweet.<br />
You taught Your children even to walk and to speak.<br />
We thank You, O Mother, for bringing us up, opening the doors of Heaven for all of us.<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks.<br />
Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
We were the clay but You all the Supreme Creator. ......<br />
......<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations again and again to the Queen of the Seven Peaks.<br />
Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Mahāmāyā Swarūpa, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Y2Z3tNAs0I">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Blessing of the Divine Pours Only if the Sahasrāra is Open (Meditation Is the Only Way You Can Enrich Yourself with the Beauty of Reality), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/23072228"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mā He Sahasrār Swāminī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/qWKprw2fe58">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrar. Dwari</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/U0w8QSa7zNY">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ughad. Sahastrār. Māte</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Mātājīla</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ybCnMcQi2ZQ">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image974.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So now you understand from there that, on this Sahasrāra Day, you have to also demand.</b><br />
I want you to demand and ask, because I have no desire. And you just go ahead!<br />
You have all the rights to demand from Me.<br />
And ask for the biggest and the highest and the most fantastic and the most dynamic that you want to do.<br />
<b>Put up your minds and heads together, and ask for something big.<br />
This is a very great day today; go home, think about it. Collectively also you decide.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Essence of Sahasrāra Is Integration, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Ātā Viśhwātmakeṃ deveṃ yeṇe vāgyajñeṃ toṣhāveṃ. Toṣho..."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> Now it says that all of you, who are one in your Spirit -- this all description of Sahaja Yoga today, is the future, the present that you will get it, at this time what is going to happen. It is so beautifully shown, you'll be surprised, that you all will become one in the universe. The Spirit of the Universe will be satisfied with the Yagñyas they are going to do, with the fire ceremonies you are going to do. How it is appropriated! He said it three hundred years back.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Toṣhoniṃ maja jñāve pasāyadāna heṃ."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> And then you will, should give us the milk of your blessings by getting the complete satisfaction from us</font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Jeṃ khaḷāṃchī vyaṃkaṭī sāṃḍo."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> That time all the horrible evil people will be ruined and their ... their plans will be spoiled.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Tayā satkarmī-ratī vāḍho."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> And people will take to righteousness. This is the description [unclear] Gupta.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Bhūtaṃ paraspare paḍo maitra jīvācheṃ."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> At that time there will be a tremendous friendship of the Spirit among people.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Duritāṃche timira jāvo."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> Those who are in ignorance will get light.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Raman D. Kulkarni: "Viśhwa Swadharma Sūryeṃ pāho."</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> The whole universe will see the light, the Sun of One Universal Religion.</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pasāyadān</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">'O God, the entire Cosmos Divine, Be pleased with this pious word offering of mine,<br />
Grant me in goodwill benign | Your Benevolent Grace Divine<br />
(Gyāneśhwarī is considered to be a masterpiece in Marathi literature.<br />
At the end of which Gyāneśhwar asks for the blessings of the Almighty through this Pasāyadān)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Sahasrara Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day: “In the breaking of the Sahasrāra, I have never left anything undone. It’s a perfect job.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day: “In the breaking of the Sahasrāra, I have never left anything undone. It’s a perfect job.”" /><published>2022-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/2022_05_05_Sahasrara_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/05/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We can say, in 1970, fifth May, [for the] first time, the Collective Spirit of God opened out.</b><br />
So far, the blessings of God came to human beings individually as Grace and they received their Self-realization individually, one by one. And the method for individual Realization was just the opposite of the collective. First, they had to establish their dharma, cleanse themselves fully, desiring all the time for their salvation, putting their attention to their salvation, as you call it Īśhwarapraṇidhān [desire for God], thinking of God, asking for His Grace and acting in a scrupulous, dhārmik ways to keep themselves pure. They had to control their mind, control their desires, control their action in such a manner that they absolutely kept to the center path. And when they could get through all that testing and immunity, I mean they deserved, then only the Grace of Mother gave them Realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Sincerity is the Key of Your Success, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image965.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>When we enter into the Realm of Sahasrāra, then only we have right to do the Sahasrāra Pūjā.</b><br />
Before this nobody talked about Sahasrāra, nobody did any Pūjā to Sahasrār.<br />
This is your privilege that you are in the Realm of Sahasrāra and that you can do this Pūjā, perform it, is your right, you are chosen for this.<br />
It’s a very privileged place for you to enter into the Sahasrāra of the Virāṭ, to reside in the brain as cells of that Sahasrāra."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, State of Absolute (Nirānanda Absolute Joy, Absolute Love, Absolute Compassion, Absolute Power), Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">"<b>It's a great day for all of us, the seekers, that the last work of the Divine, of opening the last center in the Great Primordial Being, was done on the fifth of May 1970. It is the greatest event of all the spiritual happenings of the Universe.</b> It was done with very great care and great adjustments.<br />
It is not in the limits of human understanding, how things are worked in the heavens. It is your fortune and God's Love that has worked out this wondrous miracle. Without this happening, there could not have been a possibility to give [en] masse Realization to people. One could have done it for one or two persons here and there, but to give such a masse awakening could not have been possible.<br />
As you know, in the Sahasrāra there are the seats of the seven main chakras. There are 1,000 nāḍīs or, as they call it, flames, and they all have each Sixteen Thousand Powers. Every nāḍī deals with a particular type of a person and, with the permutations and combinations of all these nāḍīs, human beings are looked after.<br />
As soon as Sahasrāra was opened, the whole atmosphere was filled with tremendous Chaitanya [vibrations]. And there was tremendous light in the sky. And the whole thing came on this Earth as if a torrential rain, or a waterfall, with such a tremendous force, as if I was unaware and got stupefied. The happening was so unexpected and so tremendous that I was stunned and I became completely silent at its grandeur. I saw the Primordial Kuṇḍalinī rising like a big furnace. And the furnace was very silent but burning uh appearance it had. As if you heat up some metal and it has many colors, in the same way, the Kuṇḍalinī showed up like a huge furnace, say of a, you can say, of a furnace which is like a tunnel, where you see these plants you have for uh coal burning to create electricity. And it stretched like a telescope one after another, it came out, tchue, tchue, tchue, like that. And the Deities came and sat on their Seats, on their Golden Seats, and then They lifted the whole of the head, like a big dome, and opened it. And then this torrential rain completely drenched Me, and I started seeing all that and got lost into the joy. It was like an artist seeing its own creation fulfilled, I felt the joy of great fulfillment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Opening the Primordial Sahasrāra, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image966.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"When the seventh chakra was opened, all the chakras came to your Sahasrāra, and so I could manage all your chakras and all your Deities.<br />
Any Deity you ask and you get the vibrations.<br />
<b>So that proves that I am the Brahmachaitanya.<br />
The Brahmachaitanya is the Ādi Śhakti and Sadāśhiva is also in My heart.</b><br />
But since I am so much humanized, it is not so easy to find it out. If you tell this to modern human beings, they will not understand.<br />
It can only be told to Sahaja Yogis because they will understand. To bear this Truth is so difficult."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0227 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi and Hindi), From Pieces of Conversation with Dr. Talwar and other Sahaja Yogis Leaders, after the Śhivarātri Pūjā, Juhu, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">"<b>So first I had to open out My Sahasrāra itself. Then your Sahasrāras could be opened out</b>, that’s why. And then I felt that: a tremendous flow of My Grace started flowing. So much Grace even upon Me, My own face, like torrential rain, you see, on Me. Absolutely I was so drenched in that joy, really I was lost, absolutely lost. Sort of I felt that the whole creation is now resounded with that Universal Consciousness, just like that. Everything was finished, only the joy was permeating. It was such a beautiful time.
And then I started My work."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Essence of Sahasrāra Is Integration, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>In the breaking of the Sahasrāra, I have never left anything undone. It’s a perfect job.</b> Your nerves are not hurt. Your brain is not hurt. Such a powerful Kuṇḍalinī comes up. How sweetly, beautifully, delicately She pierces through. Only a thread comes out. And how then the connection is established and the relaxation starts coming in on the sympathetic. How all the beautifully chakras open and more of the, these threads coming up.<br />
<b>Now you are also told how to work it out. You know all the technical know-how. But what you don’t know: that you are not yet a perfect machine. You have to perfect yourself.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, How it Was Decided (Nothing Is More Important Than Your Ascent or Our Ascent Is the Only Concern, Fregene (40 kms E of Rome), Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image967.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Now, the Will of God, you are feeling it on your fingertips.<br />
After Realization, now, you have discovered the Absolute Science, which is the Will of God, which is an Absolute Science."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tuzhya Krupe Nid.Rit. Shakti Urdhvamukhe Yei</b></font><br />
The energy which is awakened with your blessings start to rise<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sat. Chakre Tichya Sparshe Jagrut. Ti Hoi</b></font><br />
As it touches the seven chakras, they become enlightened<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Adnyasthani Yeta Mate</b></font><br />
When it reaches the agnya chakra <br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ka Ga Visawa </b><br />
<b>Ughad. Sahastrār. Mate</b></font><br />
O Mother, please open the Sahasrāra!<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As a result of Sahasrāra being opened out, one thing: the illusions have vanished. What you call in Sanskrit is bhrānti. Illusions have vanished. You should have no illusion as to the existence of God Almighty, the Power of His Will and the Truth about Sahaja Yoga. You should have no doubts at all! Minimum of minimum should be like that.<br />
But while using this Power, you should be aware that this Power is given to you because you are capable of handling it. This is the Highest Power that you could think of.<br />
Take any governor, take any minister, anyone, they can be removed tomorrow. They can become corrupt. They can become absolutely devoid of any knowledge of their own powers. There are many people who just get elected without knowing what they have to do.<br />
<b>So this is not just a conversion of people, is not only even transformation, but it is a new fashioning of a new human being which has come forward and which is capable of carrying the Will of God further.</b><br />
So, as a result of your Realization, what you have got?<br />
The first thing that has happened is that your illusions have gone. You should have no illusions about God Almighty, His Will, and that He is omnipotent, omnipresent and omniscient. All His omnipotence has done this work.<br />
And, as Collective Consciousness, you should also know that you are also omnipotent, omnipresent and omniscient. Omniscient is the thing, that He sees everything, knows everything. Part of it, that Power, is also within you. So, to prove His omnipresence, you have to be all the time aware that you are Sahaja Yogis.<br />
So the Omnipotent God who is everywhere, who has done all this, the Will of God that has worked it out, has to work through you people. And you have to be very strong, very sensible, very wise, also very effective people. The more effective you become the more energy you'll get.<br />
But still I feel that the Sahaja Yogis are more, not taking the responsibility of understanding that they have to represent this God Almighty who is omnipresent, omniscient, who knows everything, who sees everything and who is potent, means Almighty.<br />
If you understand that this is what has happened after opening the Sahasrāra, that you have now got the Power which has these three qualities in it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahasrāra is your awareness. When it is enlightened you get into the technique of the Divine.</b><br />
Now there are two techniques: the technique of the Divine, and the technique that you follow. You cannot act as Divine, but you can use the Divine Power and maneuver it.<br />
For example, Divine looks after all the universal happenings. Every minutest particle is controlled by Divine.<br />
When your Sahasrāra opens out and your Kuṇḍalinī touches the fontanel bone, sort of a igniting force is ready in your Sahasrāra, and as soon as the fontanel bone area opens up through the Brahmarandhra, the Grace of your Spirit ignites that igniting force and your nāḍīs get enlightened. Not all of them, quite a lot of them; not all the length, but quite the peripheries. That's how you get your enlightenment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Opening the Primordial Sahasrāra, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image968.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrar. Dwari<br />
Mukhi Nām. Gheta<br />
Nirmalā Hi Tari<br />
Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrār. Dwari</b></font><br />
O Mother we are enjoying our meditation in Sahasrāra<br />
Whenever we take Your name, You are always there to help us<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Charani Tujhya Baisat. Mate, Man. Te Nivale<br />
Sushumnachya Marge,<br />
Swarupachya Tiri</b></font><br />
When we are at Your Lotus Feet our attention is settled,<br />
we are in the path of Sushumna and very close to Your Divine Form.<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/U0w8QSa7zNY">video</a>
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī: Now say the Sahasrāra's mantras, three. Sahasrāra Swāminī Mokṣha Pradāyinī Sahaja Yoga Dāyinī. </b></font><br />
<b>All Sahaja Yogis:</b> Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sahasrāra Swāminī Mokṣha Pradāyinī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī: Sahaja Yoga Dāyinī.</b></font><br />
<b>All Sahaja Yogis:</b> Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sahaja Yoga Dāyinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī: Now, after saying all these mantras you have reached up to Sahasrāra and you have also pierced through the Sahasrāra. The most effective mantra you know is Nirmalā and that works the best for Sahasrāra.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0614 Small Pūjā, Farewell, Āśhram, Route de Courte Raye, Founex (19 kms N of Geneva), Switzerland<br />
Śhrī Mātājī giving individual Sahasrāra Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mPBwtVUOHKg">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sahasrāra Swāminī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mokṣha Pradāyinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, How it Was Decided (Nothing Is More Important Than Your Ascent or Our Ascent Is the Only Concern, Fregene (40 kms E of Rome), Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/568853318"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Savera Aya Hai, Mātā Ne Jagaya Ha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lUNkxcIAEs4">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjanī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Mātājīla</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Anyatha Śharanam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sahasrāra Swāminī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image969.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red">"Meditation, where you are connected to the All-pervading Divinity, is the starting point in Sahaja Yoga."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Nineteen Quotes from the e-mail booklet Come the Mother Calls</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Prabhu Mazha Mal Jevha base gheun. Ekanti</b></font><br />
When I am alone with my God (in meditation)<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Kiti Varnu Mala Tevha Ghade ji ho Sukhaprapti</b></font><br />
The Joy which I feel is beyond any description<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Sahasrara Puja" /><category term="maroon @ Sahasrara Say" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>