<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-05T19:18:08-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That’s what it is.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That’s what it is.”" /><published>2022-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_05_Navaratri_Day_10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nine yugas, nine times, you all have been saved properly, and on the tenth month you are given your birth. Also this birth is always after seven days of nine months. So we had to wait for some time till it matures.<br />
<b>Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti. So today we are really going to worship the Ādi Śhakti.</b> On one side the Ādi Śhakti is Mahākālī, on the other side She is Mahāsaraswatī, in the center She is Mahālakṣhmī, and also She is the Ambā, the one who is the Kuṇḍalinī. But She’s also beyond that. She’s Parāśhakti, She’s beyond all the powers because She is the Generator of Power, so She has to be beyond all that.<br />
<b>So today when we are worshiping Her, we have to worship Her in all these forms.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1051.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today to see you on this Navarātri Day, so many people sitting to worship Me. So many people are here, so many Sahaja Yogis, it’s so remarkable, it is not My achievement, I tell you. It’s your seeking.</b><br />
Because I have been on this Earth many a times before – that you know. But we never had like this, so many came and got crucified, died, this, that – but I never had people of this caliber"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you enter into the Kingdom of God. Then the Śhakti makes you sit on different beautiful positions, and some are sitting in the Heart of God, some are sitting in the Sahasrāra of God, in the Kingdom of God.</b><br />
Now you should assume your power. On Navarātri now, you should understand that it has now crossed the limit and now we are on the tenth position, where you must assume. I have told you many a times, now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God. You cannot judge God, you cannot say why She does that, why She does that, why He does that. You cannot say that – that’s different. But when you sit there, then it is not an assembly, it is not like a politician fighting, no; it is that you have entered into the Kingdom of God, blessed by God, looked after, protected, nourished, and made knowledgeable.<br />
...... So Navarātri’s – <b>now, the tenth day of Navarātri, which is the most important for all of you, is where this Paramachaitanya has become active. And by its activity you should know it is become very powerful, and that now anybody who tries to be nasty with you, tries to trouble you – “I don’t have to worry at all.” It will take care of it</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1052.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>On this day of this Pūjā, <b>it’s such a combination that it’s the Dussehra, I am here and also you can call it the last day of the Devī Pūjā.</b><br /> 
We have to see within ourselves, introspect ‘What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha </b></font><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma! Salutations to You!
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So today is Dussehra, is a very big day in India.</b> They say on this day Rāvaṇa was killed. He was the worst enemy of human beings, and he was killed. But whatever it is then, as a memory of that great man, Śhrī Rām, they celebrate today Dussehra. And on this day, they say, those who are duṣhṭas, means bad people or we can say negative, they are killed. Can you imagine? [Chuckles.]
So this day is regarded as a very important day in India, and they make a big statue of Rāvaṇa. You all know who was Rāvaṇa, ...... whom Śhrī Rāma killed. He was a horrible fellow and he took away the wife of Śhrī Rām, Sītā, by force. But she was such a chaste woman that he couldn’t touch her. He tried; he couldn’t touch her. He couldn’t achieve any power over her. On the contrary she was very powerful."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That’s why I have to tell you that on this day of Dussehra, let us decide that we are going to have Rām Rāj in Sahaja Yoga, where there is benevolence, there is love, compassion, security, peace, joy, discipline among ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1053.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">" You desire something, you'll be surprised, immediately you'll find it works out. You ask for something, immediately it works out.<br />
<b>But there should be a complete dedication in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That's what it is.</b><br />
But if you are still moving with your egos, <b>and if you are still thinking on those lines that, `We are something and the we can start our own Sahaj Yog</b>. We can work out this way and that way,' or 'My wife is like that, my child is like that, my husband is like that,' <b>you have to give up all these problems on one side, otherwise you will not ascend</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href=""> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini:</b></font><br />
<a href="">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Ayi Re</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/BUcvc6e_9-E">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Anyatha Śharanam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Mangala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kindle My Heart</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Raghu Pati Raghav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ramrangi Rangale: Bhimsen Joshi</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/uDjaxDiFRNU">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe. Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/04" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe. Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.”" /><published>2022-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_04_Navaratri_Day_9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/04"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you are worshiping today the Durgā, or all the nine forms of the Goddess.</b> She came nine times on this Earth, according to this, that She fought all the people who were destroying the seekers, who were trying to make a mess of their lives. And these tortured Saints, when they prayed to the Goddess -- because none of the Gods could do anything, and Sadāśhiva is never interfering with what the Goddess is doing -- so they worshiped the Bhagavatī, and then the Incarnation of Hers came nine times, according to the need of the time. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1048.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red">"The siddhis that people attempt to achieve are: Aṇima, Laghima, Mahima, Īśhatva, Vaśhitva, Prākāmya, Bhukti, Icchā, Prāpti, Mukti. Aṇima is to become like a small particle.<br />
Laghima is to become small, Mahima is to have a big form, Īśhatva is to create Gods out of human beings, Vaśhitva is the attraction, Prākāmya is the manifestation, Bhukti is the enjoyment, [Icchā] fulfillment of desire. Prāpti is the attainment, Mukti is the salvation.<br /> 
These are all the siddhis that Sahaja Yogis can have."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0907 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Bīja Mantras, Śhrī Lalitā, Śhrī Chakra, 56 Ashley Gardens, Ambrosden Avenue (near Victoria Station), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we have gathered here to do the Pūjā of the Devī. The Devī has many forms, but is the embodiment of the Śhakti. Ādi Śhakti gives Śhakti to all these embodiments and so there are many Goddesses we have.<br />
At different times they came on this Earth and did all that was necessary for the ascent of people who were seekers. Especially the one we know of, Jagadambā, the Durgā. She was trying to protect all the Seekers of Truth and to destroy all evil forces, because without the ascent of human beings they do not know the Truth, and that’s why whatever they try to do is a mental projection, and this mental projection, if it is not substantiated by Truth, by dharma, it declines. In Sanskrit they call it glāni. When this glāni takes place, then incarnations are born – to solve the problem.<br />
In all incarnation of the Goddess there have been very much incarnated the satanic forces, they had incarnated, and She had to fight with them and destroy them. But this destruction was not for the destruction’s sake that the evil forces are to be destroyed, but evil forces always try to put down the seekers, put down the Saints, try to harm them, sometimes even destroy [them]. All these destructive forces do not come at the same time, normally. At different times, is easy to handle."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1049.jpg" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="purple"><b><br />
Ayi śharaṇ’āgata vairi-vadhū-vara<br />
Vīra-var’ābhaya dāya-kare<br />
Tri-bhuvana-mastaka śhūla-virodhi<br />
Śhirō-’dhi kṛit’āmala śhūla-kare<br />
Dumi-dumi-tāmara dundubhi-nādam<br />
Aho-mukharī-kṛita diṅmakare, Jaya jaya he ......</b></font><br />
Giving courage, strength, boons and fearlessness to those who take refuge in You;<br />
Your spotless Trident captures the Heads of the Rulers of the Three Worlds;<br />
Making all directions resound with the ‘Dumi-duma’ sound of drums; Victory to You ......<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now you have had nine Pūjās here and out of these nine Pūjās have we improved more, have we got more? Did we fill ourselves more with greater love, with greater joy, with greater understanding and with greater satisfaction?<br />
This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation. Because we have done what? That is what. So today you should go and make a complete picture of yourself. What have I got in these nine days? What have I got? Let us see, have I got this? Have I got that? All these things, you should just within yourself see and then enjoy that you have got all these things. It is the victory. <b>Tomorrow is the day of victory. That you have become victorious about yourself and about your ignorance. You have won yourself and you've won over the ignorance, the darkness of ignorance. This is what is tomorrow's message.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1050.jpg" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"This Pūjā is very special, many will go deep and receive tremendous blessings.<br />
But first make your attention steady.<br />
In your attention pray for peace, ‘Mother, please bestow peace upon me.’ <b>Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe.<br />
Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English+Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25805578"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Devī Suktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/K7he8axOgfw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Anyatha Śharanam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/IZxG3j1wUyE">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī playing harmonium as Sahaja Yogis sing Devī Bhajans</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nav Durgā kī Jyot </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Siddhidatri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “on an Aṣhṭamī Day let us finish all this negativity and let us become that special type of people who are worshiped all over all right.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/03" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “on an Aṣhṭamī Day let us finish all this negativity and let us become that special type of people who are worshiped all over all right.”" /><published>2022-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_03_Navaratri_Day_8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/03"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>And on an Aṣhṭamī, that is today, is the eighth day of the moon, of the moon which is increasing, Śhukla Pakṣhi; that first time all the weapons of the Goddess are to be worshiped.</b> This was a great idea because these weapons who work all the time, not only to kill the evil but to protect the good, were never worshiped before; and that today, if human beings realize their importance and significance, then lots of problems of atomic bombs and all these things that have been created could be solved by diverting them to the right direction, using them for the destructions of the evil forces and not the good; also for protecting human life, nourishing human life. The same weapons can be used in a wrong direction; but, rightly used, they can be dedicated for the use of God’s work."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1044.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red"><b>"Today is the eighth day of the Devī Pūjā and on this day the Power of Kālī acts and She is the one called as Saṃhāra Kālī, meaning the one who destroys all the evil forces.<br />
...... on an Aṣhṭamī Day let us finish all this negativity and let us become that special type of people who are worshiped all over all right.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1007 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (8th Day of Navarātri), Sahaja Yoga Style and We are Sahaj Yogis of the God's Kingdom (We Are the Makers of Styles and Let Us Finish All this Negativity and Let Us Become that Special Type of People Who Are Worshiped All Over), before the Evening Program, the day before Navarātri Pūjā, Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1045.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>Tu Hi Durgā, Tu Hi Kālī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are Durgā, You are Kālī</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Tu Hi Chaṇḍī Bhavānī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are Chaṇḍī Bhavānī</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Mā Nirmalā Kī Jay Bolo, Jay Bolo!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Let us say Nirmalā Mā kī Jay!</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Dush.Man. Chal.Ko Chal.Ne Wali</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are destroying the plans of our foes</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Bhak.To Ki Kalyani</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are taking care of the benevolence of Your devotees</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Mā Nirmalā Kī Jay Bolo, Jay Bolo!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Let us say Nirmalā Mā kī Jay!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the second thing is, [which] today we do, is a very great <b>Pūjā of Aṣhṭamī [eighth day]: is the day when the Goddess killed nine rākṣhasas together with Her eight hands. So today is a very special day for which a very special attention is needed</b>.<br />
It’s only at the behest of the bhaktas that the Goddess took Her form and killed all these rākṣhasas.<br />
Also with Her eight hands, She killed Mahiṣhāsura. That’s why She’s called as Mahiṣhāsura Mardini. She’s called as Nava Chaṇḍī, one who has killed nine Chandas, means nine rākṣhasas She has killed. So is a very important day and very vital and very deep."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0201 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā (English+Marathi+English), House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1046.png" /></div>

<p style="color:red; text-align:center;">
Salutations to You O Devī,
Killer of Mahiṣhāsura and giver of happiness to Your Devotees!
Please give us the spiritual personality, victory and glory and destroy our enemies.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In the 'Mahālakṣhmī Strotum', why should we have all these. Because it is the Kuṇḍalinī. The Mahālakṣhmī is the channel of the Kuṇḍalinī, so there are Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmīs. Then Mahālakṣhmī and lastly the Dakṣha Lakṣhmī. We have got one after another these powers within us which are expressed on the Mahālakṣhmī channel. Now, in the Mahālakṣhmī channel we have to talk about Gaurī. Because Gaurī is the one which is the Kuṇḍalinī. So they have to talk that's why they say, "Uday, uday hey Ambe." They say in the Mahālakṣhmī temple. Why because, in the Mahālakṣhmī temple only they have to say that now you rise, we are ready, we are prepared, we have got the <b>Mahālakṣhmī Principle within us and now you can rise,' the Kuṇḍalinī and that's why the āvāhana</b>.<br />
'Pālan[a]' means mothering or looking after the child. She is the one who looks after the whole world like a mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1018 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (8th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"Uday, Uday Hey Ambe"</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāgaurī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b>&lt;/font&gt;<br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī (the purest form)<br /> 
Salutations to You!<br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1047.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>He Mahādevī, He Kalyāṇī,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Oh Great Goddess, You are the benefactress</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Dushto Ka Samhar. Karo</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Please kill the the devils and bad people</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Mangal.May Var.Dan Do Maiya,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Mother give us the auspicious blessings</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Bhav. Se Beda Par. Karo, Ma</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Take us away from the illusions</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Bhav. Bhakti Me Sharanan. Ae</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>We have come to Your Lotus Feet with our devotions</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Bin.ti Ma Swikar. Karo</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Please accept our prayers</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Teri Jayjaykar. Ho</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>We pay our salutations to You!</b></font><br />
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>We pray to the Supreme Goddess today<br />
O Devi, O Mahadevi, please protect us.</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), The Powers of Śhrī Mahākālī, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25643943"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini:</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Mā Ādi Kuṇḍalinī by Sanjay Talwar</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe (Gondhala Mandila), by Ajit Kadkade</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mamtamai Mā Durgā Si Lage</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Mahagauri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Today is the seventh day of Her worship in Navarātri …… seventh day is for tremendous activity, tremendous creativity, and also for prosperity.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/02" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Today is the seventh day of Her worship in Navarātri …… seventh day is for tremendous activity, tremendous creativity, and also for prosperity.”" /><published>2022-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_02_Navaratri_Day_7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/02"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"We have to today understand that, ‘Why do we do Devī Pūjā? What is the reason for this Devī Pūjā? What do we get out of it? What are we supposed to achieve in our contents within ourselves?’<br />
The first thing is that Kuṇḍalinī is the Devī. She’s the reflection of the Ādi Śhakti. So when you worship Devī, first you worship also your own Kuṇḍalinī by giving Her credit because She has given you this Realization. It’s much deeper understanding than normally people have about the Devī Pūjā because they are not realized Souls. Their Kuṇḍalinī not is awakened. So normally when they do Devī Pūjā it’s for the purpose of getting Realization so that the Devī should be pleased – prasanna – and should give them Realization, or must get our chance to get to somebody who will give them Realization. But you are at a different level now. So it’s more of a thanksgiving to your own Kuṇḍalinī and to Ādi Śhakti, glorifying that whatever has happened so miraculously is because of the Kuṇḍalinī which was within you, which was reflected by the Ādi Śhakti."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1008 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 8th Day and 9th Day), The Content Within (How Deeply You Have Touched the Feet of the Divine), Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1041.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>prakṛtistvaṃca sarvasya guṇatraya vibhāvinī<br />
kāḷarātrirmahārātrirmoharātriśca dāruṇā</b><br />
You are the primordial cause of everything<br />
Bringing into force the three qualities (sattva, rajas and tamas)<br />
You are the dark might of periodic dissolution<br />
You are the great night of final dissolution and the terrible night of delusion</font><br />
<font size="+0">Chapter 1 of the Durgā Saptaśhatī, verse 75, references the destructive concept personified by Goddess Kālrātrī in all Purāṇas</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">"I must tell you that the Goddess took Her birth nine times on this Earth.<br />
And today [unclear] seventh, today is the seventh day of Her worship in Navarātri, Navarātri.<br />
And <b>the seventh day is for tremendous activity, tremendous ... uh ... creativity, and also for prosperity</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1004 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Wood Room, Hotel, Sasaima (78 kms NW of Bogotá), Colombia</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Bhavānī Aṣhṭakaṃ</b></font>
<a href="https://youtu.be/JQ3ibqZWgDI">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nala was told that when this time comes, thousands of people will get their Realization, they will be emancipated, they will transform. Kali said, <b>"Those who are seeking God now in the hills and valleys, will ultimately find Him in Kali Yuga." This is the blessing.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1005 Śhrī Gaurī Pūjā (Hindi+Marathi) (2nd Day of Navarātri), Garware College Hall, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1042.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"So, today's victory of the Power of the Divine Mother, is doing one very great work: is to expose. And this exposure will be condemning publicly those people who are doing wrong. If you see from that point of view, you will understand how we are victorious now."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"On today's auspicious occasion we have gathered here. Today is the seventh day of the Goddess. On the seventh day, the Devī Goddess destroyed the various rākṣhasas and sinners, because they were torturing the great Saints and Ṛiṣhis who were doing meditation and penance.<br />
{We wonder, "Mother, why they did so much penance? What was the need?" The reason for doing it was because although human ascent was still low, yet their aspiration was very high. They aspired to achieve the Ātmā through the body. That is why they worked so hard and did penance in this place. It is due to their aspiration that today we are able to achieve this height. This does not mean that we should think that because of the blessing of Sahaja Yoga we are some great people or some specially chosen people by God. People who think like that will receive a great shock. You will see that those who are simple, innocent, and good-natured will ascend foremost and the rest will be left behind. Therefore just receiving your Realization is not the end.<br />
<b>On this auspicious occasion God Almighty has manifested all His śhaktis for your protection, benevolence and welfare. In everything God is blessing you. He wants to see you enter His Kingdom.</b> In a way it is His Desire that you should return to your Father's home and enjoy its comforts. But at least we should be worthy of it. If we are not worthy of it then how can we enter it? We should examine our worthiness and see what it is."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English+Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1043.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>Victory be to You, O Devī Chāmuṇḍā,<br />
Victory be to You Who destroys the suffering of all living beings.<br />
Victory be to You, O Devī, who is present everywhere.<br />
Salutations to You O Kālarātrī (the longest night)</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(from Argala Strotram)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1008 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 8th Day and 9th Day), The Content Within (How Deeply You Have Touched the Feet of the Divine), Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/72573127"> video</a><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/tbsK8cJtU5Q">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parameśhwarī Bhagavatī Nirmalā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durgā Mātā Bhavānī (Rāg Durgā by Ajit Kadkade)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HgN42YkSHkY">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mahāmāyā Mahākālī, Jay Śherawālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kalaratri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Goddess used to give enlightenment and Goddess used to be alert for you”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/01" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Goddess used to give enlightenment and Goddess used to be alert for you”" /><published>2022-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_01_Navaratri_Day_6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/01"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we have gathered here to do the Navarātri Pūjā.</b><br />
There were nine times when the Major Incarnations of the Mother of this Universe were manifested. They were manifested with a purpose. That purpose is to protect Her bhaktas, Her disciples, Her children.<br />
This was a binding love. She could not escape it. Mother’s Love is binding. She cannot escape it. And She has to manifest it, work it out, and give that protection to all Her children.
This protection in the modern times has taken another form.<br />
In those days, the evil was trying to harm, to destroy the people who were righteous, who were bhaktas, who were doing good things, who wanted to lead a very religious life. So to save them, She incarnated.<br />
To protect them, She incarnated. But they knew what was good, they knew what was wrong. And they wanted to preserve their good life, their precious life. They didn’t care for money, they didn’t care for power, but just they wanted their life, means they wanted to be alive to worship the Goddess. And when they were troubled or harmed or destroyed by these evil forces, She had to manifest."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1038.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Etathe vadanam saumyam</b></font><br />
May this benign countenance of Your,<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Lochana-traya bhushitam</b></font><br />
Adorned with three eyes,<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Patu nah sarva bhuti-bhyah</b></font><br />
Protect us from all the fears<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Kātyāyanī namostute</b></font><br />
Salutations be to You, O Kātyāyanī<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the Sages, Saints have made this arrangement that you worship the Devī. But the person who is not realized is not authorized to worship the Devī.<br />
......<br />
So, you have a special authority with you that you can do the Pūjā of the Devī and Sākṣhāt Devī. This is not so with everyone. If everyone tries to do it, it has the reverse effect; the wrong effect.<br />
Most important thing is, this Śhakti is so comforting, so nurturing, so generous, so loving, it is so complete. There is nothing in between. Either it is very generous or very angry. Nothing in between."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1016 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (6th Day), Hamāre Jīvana kā Lakṣhya (The Aim of Our Lives), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1039.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Actually, nobody has right even to do a Havana unless and until he is not a realized Soul.<br />
All this Bhūr Bhuvaḥ Swāhā whatever is said is all the seven chakras.<br />
Nobody has the right to touch that fire because you cannot enlighten the fire.<br />
When you get Realization you will be surprised fire gets enlightened and you put your hands towards the fire you might get a black soot coming out of you. It’s all artificial."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0314 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Evening Program, House of Yogi Mahajan, A 47 Friends Colony East, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0">As we perform the Havan we could recite the <b>108 names of Śhrī Durgā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/42XQqX3g96U">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Goddess used to give enlightenment and Goddess used to be alert for you.</b> She would sit like a tigress for Her children. They are praying, they are doing Pūjā, they are doing some sort of a Homa, Havana, so the Goddess would sit down, protect them from all negativity coming, all rākṣhasas coming, kill them, this, do that. But that stage is gone now. Now She's entered into you. So you have to kill your negativity, you've become as powerful as your Mother. No negativity can touch you. So you can give Realization, you've got that power very well; and you can watch your defects more than that of others. And you try to put them out because they're not good, they're not for your benevolence, they're not for your ascent."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1008 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 8th Day and 9th Day), The Content Within (How Deeply You Have Touched the Feet of the Divine), Butlins Grand Hotel, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK (other day 1007)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1040.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>[Śhrī Mātājī explains that Kattyayeni (Kātyāyanī) killed the demon Kolhāsur and this is why Kolhapur is called as such].</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-03xx Conversation with K.T. Tan with a Handwritten Line, during a Meal, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>She is the destroyer of sins,<br />
giver of both enjoyment and Moksha, without end,<br />
giving victory [over distractions of Samsar], pure, worth taking refuge,<br />
giver of peace, peace personified, we pray to Her.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kātyāyanī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Kātyāyanī, the one who is the foster daughter of Sage Katyayana!<br />
Salutations to You!<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Namostute (Mantra of Śhrī Kātyāyanī is taken): </b></font><br />
<a href="">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1020 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, after Havan on 8th Day of Navarātri and before Departure, Rütli Kaltbad Mountain, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/142435846"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Maṅgala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute Bhagavatī Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jai Durge Duargati Pariharini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/F68hoY8ZhOI">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Katyayani" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “She’s the Mother of this world, Jagadambā.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/30" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “She’s the Mother of this world, Jagadambā.”" /><published>2022-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022-09_30_Navaratri_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/30"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>...... Navarātri is very good because these nine nights represent the main Nine Incarnations.</b> Where the Goddess took the form of Śhakti and killed the negative people. But those were easier days because negativity was understood by people and nobody sympathized. So this is what one has to understand that don't sympathize with negativity. You'll spoil them all. And always you'll find such sympathies bring forth your character also that you are also slightly negative. Because to fight negativity in modern times is a very difficult task. You cannot kill anyone: if you kill somebody, then may be that such a person is a brother or a sister or something of somebody. Or such a person would be himself or herself a seeker. So best thing is to separate like a contagious disease, keep that person out, no sympathies. And get the person cured and enjoy the life, otherwise that person is not going to be helped. It has become a very individual fight. And it's so troublesome and so disgusting. So to help Me out, you should not take any sides with negativity. That's how you can help Me the most. This is what it is the Navarātri, the Pūjā that I give you powers to fight the negativity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1009 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Public Program, Flat of Ruth and Kingsley Flint, Strasbourg, France]</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1035.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"She gives us the protection.<br />
She’s the Protector.<br />
And She’s the Mother of this world, Jagadambā."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<b>Today the love of Śhrī Jagadambā is expressed</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We decided to have this Pūjā of Durgā today that all negativity should be destroyed.</b> So many Deities build up the body of Kālī. Every part of Her body was created by a Deity, looked after by a Deity, and is also, later on, is reflected in you all. So they say that God has made human beings in His own image, I would say, I’ve made you in My own image, all the Deities at your disposal. They’re all with you, and they have created you – if you see it minutely – it is the Deities who have brought forth all the beauty that you had. They have made all this beautiful congregation, beautiful transformation, and they have created such angelic people out of you. They are always working it out, but one thing you have to do is to have the drive. You had pure desire to ascend, but for what? You want to have the light, but for what? You want to become gurus, for what? To save people, for their salvation. Only through your channels, I can work out Sahaja Yoga. If I could work out Myself, I would have. It’s not a question of killing one rākṣhasa. God knows how many there are, rākṣhasas and rākṣhasas. And they are everywhere, even within you they were. Now they’ve gone out.<br />
So you have to do full justice to Sahaja Yoga, that’s very important."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0725 Śhrī Durgā Mahākālī Pūjā, France on the Verge of Destruction, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1036.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>Salutations to You O Goddess Chāmuṇḍā Nārāyanī,<br />
whose mouth was dreadful with its great teeth,<br />
Who wore a garland of human skulls as an ornament and killed the demon Muṇḍa.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Mahālakṣhmī Hymn, Chapter 11 of the Devī Mahātmyam)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You come up now to the Heart chakra. Heart chakra is divided into three parts. In the center of the Heart chakra resides Jagadambā Herself. But [in] the left side as I have told you resides Śhiva and His Power is Pārvatī. <b>When Pārvatī Herself separates Her identity with Her Lord and enters in the center to save Her children from the domination of the evil spirits, then She resides in the center and She is the Jagadambā. This is called as “Sacred Heart” in the Bible. She resides as Jagadambā. She has taken many Incarnations to save.</b><br />
Today there was Lalitā Pañchamī, they sang the song of Lalitā. The way She took Her Incarnations to fight the evil forces, to save the bhaktas from the domination of satanic and depraving personalities. She is there within you also, if not awakened She can be awakened. She is all the time there to save you from those satanic forces."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now the Durgā's qualities are that She is protective of Her children, She's very gentle, very soft with Her children, and She's extremely horrifying to the satanic people, to the negative people.</b> So in this rāga I think because there are, the notes are spaced out. So either you could play it slow or you could play it fast. Nothing in between. That's why it is on a Durgā's style. You see, either She is extremely gentle or She is extremely horrifying. So because She has a double function: is one to look after Her children, and another is protect Her children from the devils. So She has to be very quick about it, to fight them, and to, in every way to frighten them and to be alert about it.<br />
So in the second part you all became very alerted I saw. In the first part you were having a lullaby because it was the Mother's Love that was playing. The second part you became alert, because She has to fight. Now, this is such a nice rāga because it gives you a better sense of security within yourself, builds up sense of security, and also as you know medically that it's important to build up this chakra because that gives you antibodies created. So to fight all the diseases, to fight all the foreign things which try to attack us.<br />
So this rāga is so apt, absolutely apt for today's atmosphere and for today's need. That we have to have the security of the Mother and the protection of the Mother and that all the evil forces must be finished from this world, and that's how this rāga has a very great significance ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0819 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1037.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Saraswatī is known as Skandamātā, She was not His mother and was virgin.<br />
But, but She took Skanda [Kārttikeya] as Her Son and held Him to Her heart."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1221 Śhrī Kārttikeya Pūjā (Marathi+English), Śhrī Gyāneśhwara, Park (200 m from ISYRH Center), C.B.D. Belapur, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Kāla-rātrīm Brahma-stutām Vaishnavīm Skanda-mātaram<br />
Saraswatīm Aditim Daksha-duhitaram namāmah pāvanām shivām</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Salutations to the Goddess, Who is the darkest night, 
Who is praised even by Brahmadeva himself, 
Who is the Power of Śhrī Vishnu, The Mother of Śhrī Kartikeya, 
Who is Saraswati, Śhrī Aditi (Mother of the Gods), 
the Daughter of Daksha, and the Consort of Śhrī Śhiva.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo">Aum twameva sākshāt Shrī Skanda-mātā sākshāt<br />
Shrī Ādi Shakti Mātājī Shrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namah<br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily The mother of Shri Kartikeya<br />
Salutations to You!</font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/44600555"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This song that you have heard has been composed in the year of 1600. And in this song the poet has sung for the rustic people, in their language. That, “Oh Mother, give us our Realization!” ‘Jogawa’ means the Yoga, the Union with the Divine and the Sahaja Yoga means spontaneous.<br />
It fills My heart to see how since long the seekers have been asking for this Union with the Divine. What a search! What a seeking!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0610 Public Program, University, Graz, Austria</b></font><br />
<font color="green"><b>Jogwa 1, (Marathi 6), Śhrī Mātājī explaining the meaning of the bhajan.</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Argala Strotam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lVgW5k89t44">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jagadambetza Jogawa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Aye re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Hey Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You understand the meaning: is the ... is the praise of the Dayānī uh ... the Bhavānī, the Goddess.<br />
Is She so compassionate and She's the One who is uh described by all the human beings, and all the great Saints, and all the Gods.<br />
And the second [thing] is that She Herself, She when She gets angry, She can become a volcano.<br />
And when She's a Chaṇḍī, She's ... She's a volcano, and that is how She killed Mahiṣhāsura.<br />
That is the song, is uh quite a powerful song. But My voice ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0518 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Evening Bhajans, the day before Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Nirmala House, Sant'Angelo Romano (7 kms N of Guidonia), Italy</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/vqd4mzk44Qk">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Skandamata" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Kuṣhmāṇḍa, is one of the forms, that you absorb all the filth in yourself”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/29" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Kuṣhmāṇḍa, is one of the forms, that you absorb all the filth in yourself”" /><published>2022-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022-09_29_Navaratri_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/29"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, God has created only One World,  He’s not created many worlds. He’s created only One World, this one, where alone here only human beings are created. So this is the most important planet, you can say, which has been in the Attention of the Divine. So the whole cosmos works out for the benefit of this planet. And the working of that cosmos has created this Earth, and then human beings, and then the Sahaja Yogis. So, <b>Sahaja Yogis are the epitome of the creative powers, they are the epitome of God’s Desire. That’s what He desired, that’s why He created this cosmos, this universe, and this Earth</b>.<br />
So now His Desire is fulfilled when He says ... sees He being reflected through the Sahaja Yogis. But there is still a few things we have to clear out within ourselves.<br />
His Desire represents the Mahākālī Power within us. Now, we have to see how His Desire has worked in creating ourselves. First is the desire which is absolutely passionate. There’s nothing desired, nothing else is desired, but the creation of Sahaja Yogis.<br />
So, the first desire of any Sahaja Yogi is to create more Sahaja Yogis. No other desire should be dominant or exist, in a way. But to fulfill that desire, we have to fulfill some conditions."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0518 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, French Seminar, Dourdan (47 kms SW of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1031.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>Visṛistau sṛisti-rūpā Tvam sthiti-rūpā cha pālane,<br />
Tathā saṁhṛiti-rūpānte jagato-'sya jagan-maye ǁ 5 ǁ</b></font><br />
O You, whose Form is the Universe, at the time of creation You are the Creative Force,<br />
At the time of sustentation You are the Protective Power and at the time of the Dissolution of the World,<br />
You are the Destructive Power.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>You see God’s creation.</b> He has created you and He’s not the one who is going to destroy His own creation. You don’t do anything. You just don’t do anything.<br />
You see, this is the wrong impression human beings have got. What they do is a dead work. Now see, the flowers are dead so you have arranged them. The tree is dead so you have made the furniture, that is all.<br />
Dead to the dead. Any living work can you do? Any living work? Nothing. Only after Realization, you can do it, by awakening the Kuṇḍalinī. Then you can do it. Then you are entitled to become the master.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0306 Interview with a Lady for a Radio Station, Hong Kong, China</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1032.png" /></div>

<p style="color:indigo; text-align:center;">
<b>RACHA PRABHU TUNEY YAHA BRAHMANDA SARA<br />
Oh God You have created the whole universe<br />
PRANON SEY PYARA, BRAHMANDA SARA<br />
The whole universe is dearer than our lives<br />
TUHI MAI BANDHU, TUHI JAGAT JANANI<br />
You are my Mother and brother, You are the Mother of the universe<br />
SAKAL JAGAT MEIN YAH TERA PASARA<br />
The whole universe is but your form</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Yesterday you have seen how Durgā used to protect all the seekers, sādhakas, and how She killed the people who have been troubling, torturing, killing the Seekers of Truth. Her whole Advent was to protect them from all these evil forces. In those days that was the most important work.<br />
So that’s how the sādhakas came up to these modern times and now they are Seekers of Truth or they have found the Truth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I would say, with this, today's special celebration of Navarātri. Like yesterday you saw Śhrī Durgā's Nine Forms, also. In that, one is <b>Kuṣhmāṇḍā, is one of the forms, that you absorb all the filth in yourself, in your stomach. But the Devī does that, not you. What the Devī can do, you should not do, that's Her job</b>, that She is supposed to do this, not you. What you have to do is to only be in silence so that you absorb whatever will increase that silence, will increase your depth. The Devī will look after all the rest of the things, she'll look after all the filth, all the anger, all the temper, all the everything that's going on in this world. She will absorb all that, but what you have to do is to just enjoy everything that is pure. Enjoyment is only possible when you are beyond your mind. With your mind you can never enjoy, it is like a big load. It will not act, it will not help. Enjoyment comes when you are in complete silence, in a rippleless lake, the reflection of all the joy that is created on the shores of that lake are completely reflected, they are not deflected, if they were repulsed it would have been a different image altogether, and would have been something nowhere near the image of reality."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1033.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātāj</b></font>: Kavach – kavach is the cover, kavach is the cover.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Shield.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātāj</b></font>: Shield, shield, kavach. <b>Kavach is shield</b>, sorry kavach is shield!<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1009 Bestowing of Boons Pūjā, House of Maria Laventzi, Irchester (near Wellingborough), UK</b></font><br />
Devī Kavach: <a href="https://youtu.be/AgWCcYR9gHU?list=PL439F7AE9D4C1E99A">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now, when we are celebrating the greatest of greatest this Navarātri, there must be something special about it, that we have to cleanse this heart completely</b>, fully, and make it so pure that it purifies all the blood that passes through the whole of the body. So the cells of this heart, which have made this great organ, has to be the best because the cells of the heart within a human body are the best cells, the highest quality, the most sensitive. And it’s the heart that expresses the Anāhata, the sound that is without percussion. While we find that there are some people of caliber, there are, but others talk more, show off more, and do not have the caliber."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), The Discipline, Hampstead Town Hall Centre, 213 Haverstock Hill, London NW3 4QP, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Kindle My heart</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1034.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogi [reads]:</b> "O Devī, we bow before You, who are Yourself good fortune in the dwellings of the virtuous, and ill-fortune in those of the vicious, intelligence in the hearts of the learned, faith in the hearts of the good, and modesty in the hearts of the high-born. May You protect the universe!"<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"><b>This is a prayer.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Comments on the Reading from Devī Māhātmyam, before the Talk on the Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kuṣhmāṇḍa sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Shri Kush-manda, the one whose void contains the universe!<br />
Salutations to You!</font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/29890729"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Kavach and Devī Suktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/AgWCcYR9gHU?list=PL439F7AE9D4C1E99A">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ankhe band karu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kushmanda" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Before going out please take a bandhan. It’s a kavach, we call it a kavach.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/28" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Before going out please take a bandhan. It’s a kavach, we call it a kavach.”" /><published>2022-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022-09_28_Navaratri_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/28"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But the Greatest Power that is belonging to the Mother is your protection. Protection from all kinds of things – all the left-hand side protections are there. They are described, as you must have learnt on the Devī Māhātmyam – what a protections She gives you. So tremendous in Her protecting power. And this protecting power gives you understanding – how kind She is and how, I should say, how very-very protective, extremely protective. She’ll guide you all the time that you should be protected – on the left side. And through Her gaṇas She looks after you.<br />
But on the right side also. Those who are on the right side, the Goddess puts Her Powers to put you right, to bring you back to normal conditions, to humble you down and make you understand that you are a child of the Mother and you have to behave like a child."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1027.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">In the Name of Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī,<br />
The Merciful, the Compassionate.<br />
The Protection of Śhrī Chaṇḍī.<br />
Salutation to Shri Gaṇeśha. Salutation to Śhrī Saraswatī.<br />
Salutation to Śhrī Guru. Salutation to the Deity worshipped in the family,<br />
Who is Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī.<br />
May there be no obstacles.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"Now the Kavach. You have to take for your protection every morning when you go out, and before sleeping you should put your attention here and sleep off."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1207 Public Program, Day 2, Geetha Bhawan, 133 Lloyds Road, Ganapathy Colony, Gopalapuram, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So many powers Mother has to have to protect her children and to look after them, These powers are all there, working relentlessly all the time-24 hours.  So anybody who surrenders to Mother, these powers express themselves and try to help you out of your problems.  But first thing is surrendering.  If you are not surrendered, If you are not in the kingdom of God, then this is not the responsibility of the Mother. Then it might be that some negative force might take over and may destroy you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1013 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (3rd Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1028.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Kamala-dal’āmala komala kāntī<br />
Kalā kalit’āmala bhāla-late,<br />
Sakala vilāsa kalā nilaya-krama<br />
Keli chalat-kala haṁsa kule,<br />
Ali-kula sañkula kuvalaya mandala<br />
Mauli milad bakulāli kule, Jaya, jaya, he</b></font><br />
Like a tender, lovely spotless Lotus-petal the crescent Moon adorns Your forehead;<br />
Your movements are like a graceful and playful group of Swans;<br />
Like a swarm of bees to fragrant flowers, the stars adorn Your forehead. Victory to You<br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/dSIEMZflZa0">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The emblem of the Ādi Śhakti, of course you know, is a thing like this, you see, is ... we call it a ... a[n] elliptical isn't it. This is elliptical, elliptical. You all know that. But the mark of the Ādi Śhakti is the Half-moon and a star. You can put a Half-moon and a Bindu -- is a what you call a bindu? -- is a point.<br /> 
......<br />
But that point is a star. So, you see, the Islam follows the star, the inside, and below that is this, what you call, they call it the Moon. But that's the half mudrā, or we can call it the half ......
......<br />
... half of the coil. But half, according to the Western mind, half means is bad. But half is the one that takes everything within itself. You see, the one like the bottom of the sea. Bottom of the sea is always bigger than ...
......<br />
... the sea itself.<br />
......<br /> 
So this ... the Half Śhakti takes all the śhaktis into Itself. And the Bindu represents the Heart or we can say the Ātmā. So is the complete thing, is the Ādi Śhakti and the Bindu. That's the Islam seal. And in the same way this is the seal, this is the seal of the Ādi Śhakti, is a half circle. Is not even half -- we shouldn't say now first night's Moon and a star. And why this is used, because this is the thing coming from the creation, from the nature.<br />
So that also what we call Islam is nothing but is the creation of Ādi Śhakti."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1217 Pūjā (English+Marathi+English), Right Type of Conduct and The Establishment of Our Dharma Is Very Important, House of Dr. Ramesh Adinath Saṃghavī, B.N-1, Sapt Shrung, Krishnanagar Housing Society, Saharanpur Road, Nasik, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1029.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Hinasti Daitya Tejamsi Swanena Pooryaya  Jagat,<br />
Saa ghanta patu no devi papebhyo nah sutaniva.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>O Devī, may your bell which fills the world with it's sound and destroys the power of asuras, protect us from sins, just as a mother protects her children</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Devī Māhātmyam, Chapter 11)</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"When there is worship always there’s a bell rung. That is good for all the negativity to run away."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1009 Bestowing of Boons Pūjā, House of Maria Laventzi, Irchester (near Wellingborough), UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font></font> <font color="DarkRed">I say that before going out please take a bandhan. It’s a kavach, we call it a kavach. Means, kavach, in English there’s a word for that?</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogis [suggest]:</b> Protection.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font></font> <font color="DarkRed">That’s rather, protection is abstract, but this is a protection of the Mother is a concrete stuff, you see, kavach. So you take the kavach. Kavach is something you can say that people wear those armor, inside, you see that sort of a thing, is kavach. So you must take that before going out or talking to somebody. That you don’t do.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0704 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Viṣhṇumāyā's Powers, Āśhram, Everbeek, Belgium</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1030.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Padam'ekam na gacchet tu, yadīcchet-śhubham'ātmanaḥ<br />
Kavachen'āvṛito nityam, yatra-yatr'aiva gacchati</b></font><br />
One should invariably cover oneself with this Kavach wherever one goes<br />
And should not walk even a step without it, if one desires auspiciousness.<br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Nirbhayo jāyate martyaḥ, saṅgrāmeṣhv’aparājitaḥ<br />
Trailokye tu bhavet-pūjyaḥ, kavachen'āvṛitaḥ pumān</b></font><br />
The person who covers himself with Kavach becomes fearless, is never defeated<br />
In battle, And becomes worthy of being worshipped in the three worlds.<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Devī Kavach and Devī Suktam</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/AgWCcYR9gHU?list=PL439F7AE9D4C1E99A">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā, the One who is adorned with the Moon as Your bell!<br />
Salutations to You!<br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25791408"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiyā Tere Charano Kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/0OlxRe8pbEs">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Aṃbābāī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Chandraghanta" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “introspect if you have these qualities within you or not, because they are given to you by the Goddess”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/27" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “introspect if you have these qualities within you or not, because they are given to you by the Goddess”" /><published>2022-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022-09_27_Navaratri_Day_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/27"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The Devī incarnated on this Earth to kill the demonic personalities who try to destroy all the good qualities of women. We also have those demonic personalities within us and they are to be destroyed – not physically, but mentally.</b><br />
How you accept them and how you deal with whatever they try is very surprising.<br />
<b>You must understand that the goodness of a person is very important. If you are trying to be nasty or dominating then you’ll be definitely destroyed. That’s why this Devī has come on the Earth. That is the assurance of this Devī, the Goddess.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1004 Pūjā (9th Day of Navarātri), House, 268 Overpack Avenue, Ridgefield Park, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1024.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red"><b>Namo Devyai maha-devyai</b></font><br />
Salutations to the Devī, to the Mahādevī,<br />
<font color="red"><b>Shivaye satatam namah,</b></font><br />
To You who is ever Auspicious,<br />
<font color="red"><b>Namah prakrutyai bhadrayai</b></font><br />
To You who is the Primordial Cause,<br />
<font color="red"><b>Niyutah pranatah sma tam.</b></font><br />
And the sustaining Power, we bow to You.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>from 'Devī Suktam' in Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But Goddess Herself has done so many things for us already, within us, though we are not aware of it. Is said that, <b>"Yā Devī sarvabhūteśhu"</b>: "All those whom You have created," means mostly the human beings, "What do You do? As what do You exist inside the human beings?"<br />
Now, <b>just introspect if you have these qualities within you or not, because they are given to you by the Goddess, by the Śhakti within you.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-1005 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), Your Beautiful Qualities Will Prove the Truth of Sahaja Yoga, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><font color="green"><b>Yā Devī sarvabhūteśhu (2000-1008 Navarātri Pūjā, Cabella)</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1025.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You cannot make anyone brahmachārī or brahmachāriṇī. It is a state, avasthā, where a person has to rise, like Yogeśhwara, like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
......<br />
It is a state of mind where you are not involved. It is a different thing, that you just load somebody with an idea that You should become, absolutely a brahmachārī or a brahmachāriṇī or you should lead a celibate life, forcing them.<br />
......<br />
<b>Celibacy must come from within, the purity must come from within.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0203 Public Program (English+Hindi+English), Day 5, The Āgñyā Chakra, N.D.M.C. Park, Hanumān Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>It’s a great thing today that we are celebrating the Virgin’s worship</b> in England.<br />
As you know, according to Sahaja Yoga, England is the heart where resides the Spirit of Śhiva. And that Virgin should be respected and revered, uh worshiped in England is a great honor, I think, for all the Sahaja Yogis.<br />
Now one has to think, ‘Why such an importance is paid to a Virgin? Why a Virgin is respected ... to that extent? What are the Powers of a Virgin?’ That She can bear a child of that magnitude that was Christ, that She could create Śhrī Gaṇeśha out of Her own body, that She could protect innocent, dynamic force of Her children who are egoless, who have not known what is ego.<br />
So this Great Power and Force resides in a person who has lots of puru [many, abundant] puṇyas, who has done lots of good things in previous lives, who has always understood that Virginity is a power higher than any other power and would save the Virginity and Chastity with all Her effort and care.<br />
As you know that, within our body, She is placed as Kuṇḍalinī. [It] means She is the Virgin. She is untouched. The desire to become Spirit is without any blemish: nirmala. There is no blemish. I[t]s waiting is pure. There’s no other desire, but to be one with the Divine. All other desires are finished."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">"When we lose our Innocence and our Virginity, first thing happens to us is that we become ego-oriented, and we start thinking “what’s wrong?”<br />
<b>Your śhakti is your Kuṇḍalinī and She is Virginity. She is your power. She is your strength.</b> Your Innocence is your strength, the day you lost it that is the day we have committed the original sin."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1026.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>You must pray to God and ask what you want.<br />
Ask for, 'Complete satisfaction in my heart, joy in my heart, bliss in my heart, so that the whole world becomes blissful. Give me love, love that I could love the whole world and that the whole world becomes one in love. Give salvation to the entire humanity which is suffering. Take me to Your Feet. Cleanse me with Thy Love.'</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0201 Public Program (Hindi+English), Dhyāna Kyoṃ Karanā Chāhiye (Why Should One Meditate), Gurudev Cooperative Housing Society, Prabhadevi Sea Face, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other dates 0202 and 0209)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
When I am alone with my God (in meditation)<br />
<font color="indigo">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<font color="indigo">MALA PĀHĪ PRABHUSANGE, DUI ATMA TAI PALE DURĪ</font><br />
<b>When I am in the company of God, evil runs away</b><br />
<font color="indigo">GALE SAMARTHYA MOHACHE NURE RUNT KUTHE VAIRĪ</font><br />
No temptation can dominate me and nobody can confront me<br />
<font color="indigo">MALA BODHĀMRUT PĀJĪ, SADA JAEI NAVI TRUPTĪ</font><br />
Every time I experience the Divine knowledge, I feel more satisfaction and Divine Joy<br />
<font color="indigo">KUTHE CHINTA KUTHE DUKHHE KSHANE SĀRI LAVA JĀTĪ</font><br />
All moments of concerns and sorrows vanish<br />
<font color="indigo">PRABHUSANGE MILE JĪVA, NASE KOTHE TASHI SHANTĪ</font><br />
Nowhere else can my soul find peace except in the company (in union) with God Almighty<br />
<font color="indigo">PRABHU MAZA SWAYE NĪTĪ, PRABHU MAZA SWAYE PRITĪ</font><br />
My God himself is Truth and Love<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76011764"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Kinaryala Lau</b> (Australian Songbook, Marathi 62)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī Vandu Tav Charaṇa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Māhūragaḍ. Wari</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/EWoUoau4BOw">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/4__6MBE5AZc">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Lalitā Sahasranām</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/PKNAgirTBr4">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Brahmacharini" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “On this day Devī is worshiped as Śhailaputrī, means the daughter of Himalaya”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/26" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “On this day Devī is worshiped as Śhailaputrī, means the daughter of Himalaya”" /><published>2022-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/2022-09_26_Navaratri_Day_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/09/26"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the first day of Navarātri. Today your attention should be on Śhrī Gaṇeśha.</b> His devotion is infinite.<br />
He has never worshiped anybody else except Mother. Hence He is so great. All other Gods appear very strong. Everyone has some specialty. What is Mother’s specialty? Her ego (aham) is nowhere felt by others. Hence Śhrī Gaṇeśha who has surrendered to such Mother is so wise and venerable, Mother has nothing with Her. Her very name begins with Ni, e.g., Niṣhakāñchan[ā] having no wealth, Nirlepā unaffected; Nirvichārā thoughtless; Niṣhprayojanā having no motives, Nigarvitā egoless, Niricchā desireless, etc. Therefore, surrendering to such Mother, who has nothing with Her, needs some kind of subtle thought, in that, Mother has nothing with Her, and therefore, nothing can be asked from Her. It shows how Śhrī Gaṇeśha by himself is fully satisfied. Where does this contentment of Śhrī Gaṇeśha come from? It is own power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1002 Letter to All Sahaja Yogis (Marathi) (1st Day of Navarātri), London, UK from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 11 (September-October 1982), Pages 25 and 26</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1019.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red">"Today we worship the Himalayas and the seven Goddesses whose blessings are here and pray to them to bless us with Devī Śhakti.<br />
We have received the blessings of the Devī Śhakti from a Mother.<br />
That is why, in the form of Mother, let us come to the feet (śharaṇāgat) of the Himalayas.<br />
<b>Keep your attention on yourself.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English+Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"And even that there was Military, and there were jeeps passing when I was coming, they saw Me, they had to salute. And the gentleman in charge of the command, he came down, three times, just to see Me. He saw Me off at the station, I mean, all ... as if all of them knew. And they were singing the song, <b>'You, the person that belongs to our hills.' 'Paharoṃwālī Śheroṃwālī', the one who is of the tigress, the one who is the daughter of the mountains.<br />
The first name of the Goddess is Śhailaputrī, as you know, that Śhailaputrī means the daughter of the mountains. So to them, I was just their own.</b> They were waiting for Me, they knew, I was to come, I came -- they got it. So that's the good conditioning. You are conditioned the other way, never recognize anyone."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0502 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirānanda, Āśhram, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1020.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Mahākālī Power, first of all, gave birth only to Śhrī Gaṇeśha. Then Śhrī Gaṇeśha was established.</b><br />
Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the Deity established first of all.<br />
So is the case of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, like Mahākālī it is the Seed and the whole universe emerged out of it and again get merged into it, similarly, everything emerges out of Gaṇeśha Principle and gets merged into it.<br />
Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the seed of whatever is there, you see through your eyes, in creation, in desire.<br />
<b>That is why Śhrī Gaṇeśha is considered first among Deities.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0922 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī and Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Navarātri Celebrations (1st Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>On this auspicious occasion God Almighty has manifested all His śhaktis for your protection, benevolence and welfare. In everything God is blessing you.</b> He wants to see you enter His Kingdom. In a way it is His Desire that you should return to your Father's home and enjoy its comforts. But at least we should be worthy of it. If we are not worthy of it then how can we enter it? We should examine our worthiness and see what it is.<br />
The first thing is that you should come to your Father's house. Today I have also come to My Father's house. I feel like that because Himalaya is My Father. On coming here, I cannot express in words the feelings that are rising within Me, but I think that today I have found a great occasion to celebrate the glory of My Father. A great opportunity has come before Me to praise the glories of My Father and narrate the great achievements of those who meditated here. With the inspiration derived [received] from the Himalayas they rose from nowhere to such heights that they achieved the highest state.<br />
The Himalayas are the Sahasrāra that Mother Earth has created for you. This Sahasrāra is to be worshiped. This Sahasrāra is very great. I don't know if you can see vibrations emitting from it. I am completely engulfed by their vibrations that I cannot see anything else. There are only vibrations and vibrations. Nothing else."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English+Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1021.png" /></div>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1022.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;"><font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Mātājī wrote the poem 'Mountain' in Cabella)</b></font></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>On this day Devī is worshiped as Śhailaputrī, means the daughter of Himalaya.</b> Devī has many other names also but first of all She incarnated as Śhailaputrī in the cold of Himalayas. She incarnated and whatever She was to do. She started there. Further story is known to you. [King] Dakṣha did not invite Lord Śhiva in the Havana that he performed and Śhailaputrī was the consort of Lord Śhiva. She is called Satī because She entered the Holy fire of Havana and ablated Herself. But by then Lord Śhiva reached there. He lifted her burnt up body from the fire. Burnt pieces of the body of Śhailaputrī fell at many places. All these places are considered to be Śhakti Pīṭhas, the places of worship, as there is in Vindhyāchala and many other places. Her power moves there and it is said that it Sanctifies everything. Her seventh power is considered to be the Power of Destruction. Śhakti manifested Itself on the right side as Sāvitrī and Gāyatrī but the destroying force was manifested in the center. In the form of Durgā and Her other forms manifested in Heart chakra. She is present there. If someone hurts you, confuses or disturbs you then this power will protect you and destroy your enemy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0405 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (Hindi), Noida Bhavan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1023.png" /></div>

<p style="color:indigo; text-align:center;">
<b>Auṃ Śhrī Mahāgaṇapati Devatā bhyo namaḥ padyaṃ samarpayāmi!</b><br />
O Supreme Chief of the Gaṇas<br />
We pay Homage to You,<br />
We offer You this bath of Your Holy Feet, please accept it!<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red; text-align:center;">O Daughter of the King of the mountains!<br />
The sages say that the world has its dissolutions and Genesis<br />
With the closing and opening of Thine Eyes,<br />
Thine Eyes are bereft of winking,<br />
With a view to saving from dissolution this entire universe,<br />
Which has its origin in the opening of Thine Eyes.<br />
<font size="+0">(Saundarya Lahiri by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)</font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25803726"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gajānana Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī teaching the bhajan Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ghane Ghane Jangala mein</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Shailaputri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>