<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-01-17T19:19:27-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Makar Saṅkrānti: “Today we have come together on the occasion of Saṅkrānti to perform Pūjā to Sūrya.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Makar Saṅkrānti: “Today we have come together on the occasion of Saṅkrānti to perform Pūjā to Sūrya.”" /><published>2023-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/2023-01_14_Makar_Sankranti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/14"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating here a special day called Makar Saṅkrānt.</b> For the information of the foreign Sahaja Yogis, I will explain to you what it means.<br />
......<br />
It means the day, today is the day the Sun crosses over from the Tropic of Capricorn to the Tropic of Cancer. It is a very big day for us because, now during the summertime we have the harvest, and we look forward to the rain and so many things that happen in every country. The Sun falls at right angles in this country during the summer season and so we welcome the Sun. We eat something -- that you must have eaten already -- what we call as tīḷ and jaggery. It is to prepare your body and your mind to give it sufficiency to receive the Sun. Because if you are living in the cool season, then all your body, mind becomes lethargic and you become also sometimes very lazy about things in the sense, that the day is so small, that you cannot achieve many results. So the body has become cold as we call it. We take these things, which give us heat so body is prepared to receive the heat of the Sun to welcome."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), We Are Going to Make Peace with Ourselves and with Others (We Will Take to Peaceful Methods), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1092.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Today we have come together on the occasion of Saṅkrānti to perform Pūjā to Sūrya."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Hindi+English+Marathi), Importance of Saṅkrānti and Śhrī Sūrya Devatā, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="orange">"Now the Sun is so much respected in this country,<br />
that in early morning time all the people get up and say namas-kārs to Sūrya with all His names<br />
and do a particular type of exercise to show that they are completely surrendered to the will of the Sūrya."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), We Are Going to Make Peace with Ourselves and with Others (We Will Take to Peaceful Methods), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>12 Names of Śhrī Sūrya</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/jqmPOEnU9tg">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The meaning of Makar Saṅkrānti is saṅkramaṇ, that is, the day that brings about some change. <b>On this day the Sun starts its movement toward the Northern Hemisphere. In India, all the festivals are according to the position of the Moon. That’s why their dates are different in different years. Makar Saṅkrānti is based on the position of the Sun and that is the reason this festival is celebrated every year on fourteenth January.</b><br />
Makar Saṅkrānti indicates the day when the Sun becomes warmer. The heat of the Sun is benevolent for the human race. It is because of this heat that we can walk, we can talk. The heat of the Sun makes a human being angry. This is the reason why we take jaggery on this day so that we talk sweetly. The heat of the Sun is responsible for all the vegetation and wealth of the Earth. On this day we offer fruits and vegetables to the Devī and receive Her blessings. With the blessings of Ādi Śhakti the earth element cools down and the human race progresses."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi), Gain Self-confidence from the Light of the Sun and Become Radiant, House of Mrs. Kalpana Srivastava, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1093.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>This special day today is a day of Saṅkrān-ta. Saṅkri you know, saṅ means good, holy, and krānt means ......<br />
Revolution! Holy revolution. Holy.</b> And that’s what I’m telling them.<br />
What is the Holy Revolution is? <b>That your own dharma is established now through Sahaja Yoga. You know what is your dharma.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi+English), Ahitagni Rajwade Maṅgal Karyalaya, 840 Sadashiv Peth, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is Saṅkrānti. <b>Saṅkrānti means that today there is something new going to happen. Kuṇḍalinī has awakened within you and you have become a new person compared to what you were before. But on the day of Saṅkrānti, you should know that you have to please the Goddess who is sitting within you.</b><br />
What should you do to make Her happy? You distributed sesame seeds and jaggery. That is for love. To increase the love between each other, we give sesame seeds and jaggery.<br />
Today the Sun left its place and, in its northward movement, came towards us. At this moment we should be very thankful to the Sun. It is by the grace of the Sun that so many things take place in our country. <b>We have to do namaskār to the Sun today and His Power and His knowledge should come to us.</b><br />
I would say that all of you have become realized and vibrations are flowing through you. Now you should make use of these vibrations, establish the śhakti within you, establish the peace within you and show the world that this power is within us and we have to acquire it. We have to nurture this, improve this with your good qualities and truthful speech."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0117 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Hindi), Hall, Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1094.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="orange"><b>"Saṅkrānti means Power of the Sun.<br />
Sun power means self-confidence. Sun gives us heat and light.<br />
Now it depends on us whether to get scorched from the heat of the Sun<br /> 
or gain self-confidence from the light of the Sun and become radiant.<br />
Eternal blessings to all of you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi), Gain Self-confidence from the Light of the Sun and Become Radiant, House of Mrs. Kalpana Srivastava, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Your Face Shines like a thousand suns,<br />
You have given us more than we have asked for,<br />
Bliss and peace and Harmony</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the day they give you a sweet thing to say that: ‘You must speak sweetly,’ which is very important for Western people.</b> That when you are doing and organizing, you become heated up, there’s tension and you develop the temperament which is dry, emotionless, you know the heart goes into a tantrum. At that time, they say that, ‘You take the sweet.’<br />
This sweet is a heated thing because now the Sun is moving towards the other side. That time, also they, to give it a balance, they say: ‘Speak very sweetly. Use sweet words, use sweetness. Bring sweetness in your language.’ Which is very important, you understand that.<br />
And this is one of the religions we have to accept: that we will not use harsh words to each other, and then later on to others."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi+English), Ahitagni Rajwade Maṅgal Karyalaya, 840 Sadashiv Peth, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1095.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is the day to make joy and to enjoy everything and to feel the blessings of God all around us. 
The Sun has come back in His own glory and we have to wish Him all success in the coming year, ......</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), Carry the Sun with You, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā, The Revolution Within Ourselves and Feel Your Subtler Sensitivities (It's Only the Spirit that Can Save the World), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/71464483"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātājī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/6ByVzklhnWU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute Namostute</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Brahma Shodile</b> (1988-0110 Music after Śhrī Sūrya Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Mangala Mangale</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1096.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The most important thing in Sahaja Yoga is that you have to change<br />
and that’s what you should do to the Goddess with changed heart, full of love, affection, and kindness.<br />
Therefore, hope you will spread Sahaja Yoga.<br />
It is very important because you know My vision is too big and you have to really work hard to fulfill My vision.<br />
And to give Realization to people as many as possible.<br />
You have to think what is your mind doing. There are many people who are waiting to come in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
You should have the light of spirituality: you have to feel that you are spiritual, you have to grow it, and also make others grow."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), You Have to Change, Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="orange"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sūrya sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<b> Wish You All A Happy Makar Saṅkrānti!<br />
<br />
"Tīḷ-guḷ ghyā āṇi goḍ goḍ bola.”</b>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Makar Sankranti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya’s Jayanti</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/12/07" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya’s Jayanti" /><published>2022-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/12/2022-12_07_Shri_Adi_Guru_Dattatreya_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/12/07"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is Śhrī Dattā Jayanti [birthday]. Today is a very great day. I think this day has come only because of His blessings that Sahaja Yoga has been blossomed in you people. The Guru of all the Gurus -- Ādi Guru Śhrī Dattā Mahārāja. I bow to Him, He is My Guru also. He has taught Me quite enough on Sahaja Yoga all through My many births. And because of that only I have been able to do some work in this birth also, continuing to do.<br />
<b>"Gurūr Brahmā Gurūr Viṣhṇu Gurūr devo Maheśhwara, Gurūr sākṣhāt Parabrahma tasmai Śhrī Guru dev namaḥ." The Guru is Brahmā [creator], Viṣhṇu [sustainer] and Maheśh [destroyer] and the Guru who is Himself God, I offer My obeisance to Him.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1086.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"That's My own. I have no guru, neither I ever had, <b>but I have the Guru, I call him as Dattātreya, if that is so, but that is also within Me. In My stomach is the Guru.</b> You ask this question, 'Mother, have You any Guru?' Just ask this question in your hand, and you will know it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="Peru">Aei maan Guru Sharan. me rahio, rahio,<br />
He man Ma ki Sharan. Me rahio rahio<br />
<font size="+0"><b>O my heart, please stay under the Guru’s Protection,<br />
O my heart, please stay under the Mother’s Protection</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/qRDLZNVcF6M">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"All your ancient Scriptures are singing praise of the Incarnations as Gurus. Dattātreya, the three fold innocence that guides the Path of Dharma. There are Ten basic Dharmas of human beings. They must be guarded, respected and are to be identified with Tādātmya.<br />
<b>There is no compromise but human intelligence gives ideas by which human societies have gone into horrible conditions.</b> They play of mind takes us to sin and we become insensitive to sin.<br />
<b>Today I want you to resolve that you all will become absolutely dhārmik. It is hard to be a dhārmik. The society and the environment forces you to be adhārmik. You are born in innocence and later you go on compromising and accepting adhārmik patterns as normal.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0600 Letter to Children Sahaja Yogis on Guru Pūrṇimā (Marathi), London, UK from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 1 and 3</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1087.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"And this G... Dattātreya is the One who is comprising all these forces: say, the existence force and the evolutionary force and the creative force, all of them, in Its innocence.<br />
I don't know if you understand it, but there is a story about Them is, that there are Three Deities, which belong to these Three Forces: the left one is Śhiva's Force, then the right one is Brahmadeva's Force, and the center one is Viṣhṇu's Force."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><font color="Peru">Guru Vandana</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"All these people can feel it within themselves: is the religion in their stomachs, they can feel it. <b>They can find out where is the religion. Because, I say, there, religion in the stomach is looked after by the Deities of Primordial Master whom we call as Dattātreya, in the Sanskrit language.<br />
But does't mean Hinduism. It doesn't mean Hinduism at all. But it is called as Dattātreya in the Sanskrit language, in English is Primordial Master.</b><br />
He is the same who incarnated on this earth: as Moses, as Abraham, and, say, incarnated as Muhammad Sāhab, as Rāja Janaka, as Nāṇaka, and also as Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. Can you believe that Muhammad Sāhab is the same as our Nāṇak?<br />
......<br />
...... the living religion is within us ...... So your religion automatically awakens and you just don't have to bother. Nobody has to tell you ......<br />
So this is a religion that is within you which is enlightened through Kuṇḍalinī and then it works out. But it is an Absolute Religion in the sense that you all feel the same thing. If you feel one finger the other is also going to feel the same thing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0507 Public Program, Sahaja Yoga and Christianity, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1088.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Today is the day of Guru Pūrṇimā. It is a Full Moon Day. That's why ... it is called as Pūrṇimā. The guru has to be like a Full Moon. Means completely grown, completely matured.<br />
There are sixteen kalās or the phases of the Moon, and when the complete Pūrṇimā comes in, the Full Moon Day, all the sixteen kalās are completed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0708 Guru Pūjā, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Dattātreya is the innocence of all these Three Powers.<br />
And this Guru uh was the One whose ... who then had a big tradition of Gurus.</b><br />
In the same tradition we had many Gurus in our country and specially in the area near Bombay [Mumbai], which is called as Maharashtra.<br />
They came as Nāth. <b>They were called as Nāth.</b> So the first one was Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], then Dattātreya, then Macchindranāth, then Gorakhnāth, like that a tradition of these Gurus came.<br />
But all their knowledge was kept as a guarded secret. It was a Gupta Vidyā, is absolutely guarded secret, a secret knowledge about Kuṇḍalinī. They never talked about it; they never told about it. Because they thought that, 'Just now let us experiment with it fully and then we will give some idea about it to people.'<br />
But as you see everywhere it happens, even it happens with us here sometimes that we get people who do not get Realization or are half-baked and they cannot rise much higher. Then they get, sort of you see, very angry or sometimes they take this half-baked knowledge and start working on it and they go absolutely wrong on this side or that side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1089.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Though you pursue no pleasures,<br />
Derive no joy from wealth or wife,<br />
Reject the powers of Yoga,<br />
and scorn the fruits of sacrifice,<br />
Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet,<br />
What will it all avail you?<br />
What, indeed, will it all avail?</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(In praise of the Guru, from Self-knowledge, by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)</b></font><br />
Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0727 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day), Statutes of the Lord (You Do Not Harm Anyone, The Testimony of the Truth, Develop Detachment, Lead a Moral Life) and Promise that You Will Be a Guru Worthy of Your Mother (Today I Authorize You to Be the Gurus and You Have a Very Supreme Guru), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/zm8FLJxSaas"> audio</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Paramātma Pareśhu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Oṃkār Swarūpa (1991-0406 Bhavasāgara Pūjā, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru kī Mahima</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namanat Karo (I bow to Lotus Feet of my Guru)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavi Kara Mazha (1999-0801 Guru Pūjā)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1090.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Maheśha (Śhiva), Viṣhṇu and Brahmadeva form the Trinity which incarnated as one teacher God, the Primordial Master, Dattātreya.</b> He came onto this Earth to teach people the secrets of the Divine, to reveal God, and to help them cross the Ocean of Illusion themselves within their own identity. Evolution could not go further in the hands of human beings who were in the bondage of ignorance, so they were given guidance through this Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) again and again in different lives. He was created as the three-headed child, Dattātreya, by Ādi Śhakti who appeared on Earth during the Tretā Yuga as Satī Anasūyā, wife of the Sage Atreya.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations<br />
– Ambassadors of God</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Brahmā Viṣhṇu Maheśh kī Abodhita hai Ādi Guru<br />
Dattātrey hai Maitreya hai<br />
Dattātreyhai Maitreya hai Trigunatmika Nirmalā mayi<br />
Ādi Guru Janak Laotze<br />
Socrates Sāī Nirmalā mayi</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Adi Guru Dattatreya Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇak Jayanti: “we are worshiping today Guru Nāṇaka, that’s Me, that may you become Great Guru Nāṇakas”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/11/16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇak Jayanti: “we are worshiping today Guru Nāṇaka, that’s Me, that may you become Great Guru Nāṇakas”" /><published>2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/11/2022-11_16_Shri_Guru_Nanak_Birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/11/16"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Is a great thing we are worshiping today Guru Nāṇaka, that's Me, that may you become Great Guru Nāṇakas.</b><br />
All of Them were created by Ādi Śhakti. All these Gurus were created by Her. And today I say that you all become as great as Guru Nāṇaka, as great as Moses, as great as Sāī Nāth, as great as Nāṇaka, Janaka, Muhammad. All [of you] have to become as great as all these Great Incarnations. Just desire, have earnestness in you and alertness to achieve it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1078.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Know that in every heart that beats<br />
The Lord of Life has His mansion.<br />
It is through the Guru’s teaching<br />
We merge in the Formless One.<br />
By the gentle path of Sahaja<br />
Attain God, Purest of the Pure.<br />
A disciple who serves his Guru and no other<br />
Will succeed, says Nāṇak, that is sure.</b><br />
<br />
<b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTEE</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTEE</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a special day of Guru Nāṇaka's birthday.</b><br />
Uh we have celebrated one Guru Pūjā uh-uh-uh ... and the, as you know that Guru Nāṇak was also the Incarnation of the Primordial Master, the same Spirit came on this Earth. And the He's the One who tried to re-establish the work of Muhammad.<br />
Muhammad was the Incarnation of the same Spirit, the Primordial Master. He came on this Earth to establish the religion.<br />
Islam is the name of that religion, is the religion of every Sahaja Yogi, of every Christian, of every Hindu. We all belong to One Religion which believes in expanding our ourne ... awareness to the new perception of collectivity: from human level to the higher level, where you can perceive and manifest the Divine Power. This is the religion we are following.<br />
<b>All the religions were established on this Earth to create the seekers. You are the seekers: you are the Men of God. Now, all of you have to become Prophets. And to become Prophets, today's Sahaja Yoga has taken the form of Mahā Yoga. All of you have to become Prophets.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1079.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b>"See the brotherhood of all mankind as the highest order of yogis, conquer your own mind, and conquer the world."<br />
"In the calm of Sahaj’s cave You can discover the True One, Sayeth Nanak, the True One loves the truthful."<br />
Śhrī Guru Nāṇak</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is the birthday of Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka.</b> It is being celebrated throughout the world with so much of zeal that I have not seen in India. For the first time it has been advertised in so many papers and by different means.<br />
Guru Nāṇaka always talked of Sahaja Yoga. ``Everything else," He said, ``is just showing off." About religion He said that, "Observing fasts, going on pilgrimage, etc., are just meant to show off. Now you have to discover the power that is within you and establish it." Guru Nāṇaka kept on repeating the same thing again and again.<br />
......<br />
But Guru Nāṇaka always talked of the Spirit. He explained it very clearly, but no one heeded what he wrote. They will just put a finger on the couplet and read it out. Could we understand him this way? If we go through his writings properly and absorb it, then the whole śhabda jālam [web of words], in which most of the people are caught, will come to an end. See the condition of Sikhs!<br />
Without looking within and experiencing the innate energy, how could one follow Sikh religion? Only this is the teaching of Guru Nāṇaka, this is what is called `Sikh' [learning]. All the Saints of that age had the discretion to know who is a Saint and who is not. All the gurus incorporated their poems and experiences in Guru Grantha and that is why Guru Grantha is revered so much. Only the renowned gurus contributed to it. They were so spiritual that they did churning of all the religious Scriptures and put the substance in Guru Grantha.<br />
That is what we do in Sahaja Yoga. <b>We do not follow any particular Saint or Incarnation; we respect all of them and strike a balance.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti (Hindi), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1080.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b><b>Ikoaŉkār saṯ nām karṯā purakẖ nirbẖao nirvair akāl mūraṯ ajūnī saibẖaŉ gur parsāḏ.</b><br />
There is One and only One God who is transcendent as well as immanent.<br />
True and Eternal Name. Creator and Person. Without Fear and without Enmity.<br />
Timeless Form, Unborn, Self-existent.<br />
Realized by Divine Grace.<br />
Śhrī Guru Nāṇak's Mool mantra</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Muhammad Sāhib Himself was born [again] as our Great Guru, Guru Nāṇaka.</b> Guru Nāṇak was not a human being, He was not only a Paigambar [Prophet] but He was the Reincarnation of Ādi Guru, the Primordial Master, He was a Divine Personality. Of course, the people who were there at His time were so useless and gross people that they actually tortured His life and nobody followed Him. After His death is a different point. He also has said that it is the Primordial Mother who has created the Universe."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0222 Public Program (English+Hindi) (Śhivarātri Day), Day 5, Lord Śhiva, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then came, you know Nāṇaka who preached that there should be no enmity between Hindus and Muslims, he preached that, because he saw the Muslims behaving in such a manner, they were such fanatics and they had become so funny that he could not understand how is it? These are the people whom I have made Muslims and what are they doing here? Actually Mussulman means the person who is realized and Pīr is a person whose Realization is established so much so that he said that those who have become Mussulman should be buried and not burnt, because he thought they are all realized Souls, but Realization finished off with his son-in-law and his daughter, after that he had two sons who were great Souls who are really the Reincarnation[s] of Lav and Kuśh."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1081.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery, which you all should become the Great Prophets who are going to change all the men of God into Prophets.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/WxZmETTX3_M"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ (1993 Guru Pūjā Cabella) </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nāṇak Muhammad</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiya Tere Charano Ki – Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti (2008 Noida)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/iOXcrlduLNM">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavil</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/I1nxKFe8QOU?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guruon kī Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhaya kāya tayā</b> (when we belong to God what is to fear) (song by Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/47fMsue7fs8">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1082.png" /></div>

<p>
Āratī - Gagan Main Thāl | Śhrī Guru Nāṇak Āratī (recited by Guru Nāṇak)<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jNeQY2lnjko">video</a><br />
Guru Nāṇak Dev has imagined the entire universe decorated as a prayer platter on the altar of the almighty. The starting verses of the Āratī are as follows:<br />
"Gagan mein thaal, rav chand deepak bane, taarka mandal janak moti dhoop malay aan lao, pawan chavro kare sagal ban raai phulant jyoti kaisi Āratī hoye, bhavkhandana teri Āratī.<br />
anhat sabad bajant bheri kaisi Āratī hoye, bhavkhandana teri Āratī."<br />
Means: "The sky is the prayer platter, the sun and the moon are the lamps, and the stars and the constellations are the pearls and jewels. The air coming from the sandal-laden Malay mountain is the incense, the air is the fan, and the entire flora of the earth are the flowers ..... oh ... what an Āratī is it! O Destroyer of Fear!"<br />
(Wikipedia)
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Guru Nanaka Birthday" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Now the last day is very important, is a very universal day I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/26" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Now the last day is very important, is a very universal day I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj”" /><published>2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_26_Diwali_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/26"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Diwālī is supposed to be Enlightenment Day.</b><br />
But enlightenment within is: how much you are in thoughtless awareness.<br />
And everything works out because you are the Ocean of it. You have it within yourself.<br />
Only, you have to tap it. If you don’t tap it, then it doesn’t work out.<br />
You have to just tap it, and you’ll be amazed that you are a source of such joy, source of such happiness, I should say source of real enlightenment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1103 Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), The Importance of Meditation, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1074.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Then the second day is also very important: is the second day is the Moon. That is the Moon came out of the ...... Sea. According to this mythology, the Lakṣhmī came out of the Sea and with Her this Moon came out, which was only a two-day-old Moon, the New Moon but the two-day-old Moon. And this was regarded as the brother of Lakṣhmī, because they were born at the same time from the sea. So He is the brother of Lakṣhmī. It's all symbolic! This is very, very symbolic."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So this is the fifth day is Dvija [Bhāī Dūja]. So from thirteenth to the fifth day they celebrate Diwālī.<br />
For us Diwālī has a very great significance. That is: from one light many lights are awakened and they are put in a line. So they are called as diwālī, means the 'lights put in a line'. So when you hold My hands together, all of us, through that the energy passes and the enlightened Rāsa is established. And the whole world has to become that beautiful dream of your Mother where nothing but the bliss of your Father and His enjoyment when He sees His own Creation dancing in that Ocean of Bliss.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1075.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Pūrna chandr’ābhā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the radiance of the Full Moon! Salutations to You!<br />
</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Is such a great day today to meet you all. Today is a day we celebrate in India where relationship between brothers and sisters have to be established. They're very pure. Brothers and relationsh... sisters relationship is without any lust or greed. Is pure relationship, where the sister prays for the protection of the brother and brother play ... pray ... prays for the self-sufficiency of the kṣhema, well-being, of the sister.<br />
So this time you have to think of your other Sahaja Yoginīs and Sahaja Yogis who are like your brothers and sisters. You have to think like that. Purify your hearts. Is something funny in these countries, you know that, there's no such relationship may exist. Purify your mind today on that point that, `Everybody else is my brother or sister.' If you are married, is all right. But look at everyone, try to look at everyone as a brother, and a sister. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1076.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now the last day is very important, is a very universal day I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj</b>, this day, or they call it also in Marathi Bhāūbīj, different names.<br />
The brothers and sisters day. Now the brothers’ and sisters’ relationship has to be very, very strong.<br />
And the purity of that relationship is to be maintained.<br />
It is not necessary that you should be born as brothers and sisters, not necessary.<br />
But you are born because if you are realized Souls you are born as brothers and sisters.<br />
So that purity must be maintained in the society of Sahaja Yoga. Very important, that we should try to develop this situation that brothers and sisters are something very pure. Their relationships are very pure. And they should not be at all challenged.<br />
It is so much so that even if you call somebody your brother, he is your brother and the more you develop this relationship, the better your left Viśhuddhi will be.<br /> 
Because left Viśhuddhi is the relationship with God as a brother or with a Goddess as a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But for a gṛuhalakṣhmī, the brother is very important.<br />
<b>And the brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity.</b> If you understand that brotherhood and sisterhood is love which is very pure, there is no expectation, is just love: is giving love and taking love. And Absolute Purity within us should exist between our relationships when we call them as Sahaj Yogi brothers and sisters. And as there is understanding, complete understanding between the brother and sister, in a family, one has to know we are all part and parcel of a family, born out [of] the same Mother.<br />
Nobody has to shoot off, you know, nobody has to become something great, nobody has to correct others, nobody has to uh say that, ‘I’m something unique.’ All of you have to work it out together and find out the solution working out together, in complete friendship and unison. Anyone who cuts off himself and goes out or becomes anything else goes out of circulation and useless for Sahaj Yoga. Such a person is completely useless: the one who tries to get out of the family. All of you have to be supporting as each other, helping to each other, not shouting at each other, [not] getting angry with each other, trusting each other, not finding faults, treating each other with respect [unclear and love].<br />
This is the most important thing, which Sahaj Yogis don’t understand, that you are Saints and you have to respect each other."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1077.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>"So, for today’s New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1231 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Year's Eve, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon,  Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Morning and evening I sing Your Prais</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Mātājī I Have received Second Birth from You</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1113 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), You Are the Dīpas, Tent, Marque, Back Garden, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/573513651"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā - Rang De Jhini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zcAvt3cDa0Y">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuzhe Rupa Pāhuniyā Mi danga zhalo ai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Awaz Uthayenge</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Ttp3KyI2rew">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Bhai Duja Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/25" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity.”" /><published>2022-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_25_Diwali_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/25"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>It’s the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā night, not only of Lakṣhmī Pūjā</b>; there’s a difference between the two. Mahālakṣhmī is one of the powers of the Three Powers, Main Powers of Ādi Śhakti. As you know: Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī. Now, these powers have powers at a material level also, at a subtler level also. So Mahālakṣhmī Power is achieved after Lakṣhmī Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1071.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"...... the first day of the Moon. That is the forefathers of your Mother, Śhālivāhanas, they started the calendar, from that date.<br />
And so, on the first, that means the first day of the Moon, the New Year is celebrated.<br />
Now, see symbolically, Christ is born and the New Year is celebrated next day.<br /> 
As soon as He is born, New Year starts with. So next year it starts, the New Year."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"So, first of all, <b>I wish you all a very Happy Diwālī and a prosperous whole year, after this New Year Day.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1106 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Apollon Camping, Delphi, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So the whole idea of celebrating today the Lakṣhmī’s day is to understand that in us She has become the Mahālakṣhmī.</b> By that we have so many powers of which we are not aware, I mean we do not know that we are realized Souls. Some of us, we do not know and that we have those powers within us that we can permeate into others. We can project our personalities to others. We can find out what’s wrong with them. We can find out about ourselves.<br />
We can go into ourselves, we can go into – our permeation is like water is moving, is flowing all the time.<br />
And this is a very important thing that we should be aware of: our powers that we have achieved.<br />
Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity. We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It’s against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody’s life miserable. It’s against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1072.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"...... this new awakening within you that you have to achieve God now, is the power of Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
By the power of Mahālakṣhmī only, you achieve your saintliness, your Realization." </b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Jagan-mātā Mahālakṣhmī sākṣhāt Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī, You are the Mother of this Universe and the Power of Evolution.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity.</b> We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It’s against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody’s life miserable. It’s against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time.<br />
You leave the person to be; the human dignity is the most important thing.<br />
But respect everybody. And that’s possible because now you have the Mahālakṣhmī principle. Those who do not have the dignity also will get it from you because you are dignified now."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So what is the Principle of Mahālakṣhmī? Is that first is of sacrifice.</b> Sacrifice their own children on the Altar of Truth. Of course that is not needed in Sahaja Yoga. You are all blessed people, you don't have to sacrifice anything whatsoever. But if you do not develop your children into proper ways, they will hold you responsible and they will say, "Why did you not give us a full scope to develop?"<br />
......<br />
So this Mahālakṣhmī Principle has to grow among men, as well as in women. We have families now and this has to work out, that, do the whole family people sit down and meditate? Do we teach our children the proper protocol of Śhrī Mātājī? Like a lady bringing a perambulator in the hall -- is absurd! I mean, can you bring a perambulator in the church? This is more than a church. Do you realize whom are you facing? <b>And this is what you have to tell your children because this is the greatest time. This is the greatest time when you are here, the greatest time of spirituality, of the complete manifestation of the Powers of the Goddess, where your children have to be the real flowers of beauty.</b> Please don't try to cover them up with their souls dying out there under the cover of so-called love for them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia/Sottomarina, Venice, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1073.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkRed">So now for the whole world you can ask that, `Remove the curse of the negativity and bless them with the Principle of Mahālakṣhmī.'</font><br /> 
<b>Sahaja Yogi</b>: All of us?<br /> 
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkRed">All of you.</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi</b>: [Repeat.]<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkRed">May God bless you.<br />
So we have to do a lot, all of us have to do it. You are My hands, you are My eyes, you are My ears. You have to do. Whatever you are asking for, you have to do yourself. I can just give you power, but you have to move your hands, you have to move your tongue, you have to do everything.<br />
If you don't move your tongue and if you do not talk to people about it, how can I help it? So this is what you have to do, is to know that whatever you ask for, not only to pray, but also to use your instrument.<br /> 
May God bless you all.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Padm‛āsana sthite Devi, Para-brahma swa-rūpiṇī,</b></font><br />
O Devī, seated on the Lotus, who is the Supreme Consciousness,<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Parameśhi jagan-mātar, aah; Mahālakṣhmī namō‛stu-te.</b></font><br />
Supreme Ruler and Mother of the Universe, O Great Mother, Obeisance to Thee.<br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), What State You Have to Reach, Quinta do Mar, Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25922658"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhjya Pujani archani lina vhave </b></font><br />
(We are totally lost in prayer at Your Lotus Feet while performing Your Pūjā)<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parabrahma Rūpiṇī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Ch-wz0NR08">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="BlueViolet"><b>Wishing you all a very Happy Diwālī and a Happy New Year!!</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Padava" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “I’m celebrating My Diwālī enlightening light in your hearts that you enjoy your own joy and your own beauty; that you are now the Spirit.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “I’m celebrating My Diwālī enlightening light in your hearts that you enjoy your own joy and your own beauty; that you are now the Spirit.”" /><published>2022-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_24_Diwali_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a great day of Diwālī.</b> That means today is the great day of [unclear putting up] lights of your heart together to make a greater light for the world to move in a proper direction. It’s a day of great joy, and those who join in this, are spreading also great joy. But the problems are there, as they say, but for us, there is no problem because there is no darkness, we don’t see any darkness anywhere, we see lights, and lights, and lights.
Then what is the thing missing, missing is our sincerity. We have to be very sincere with ourselves because it is not just a borrowed love or a borrowed joy, but it is from within the source, it’s flowing, flowing, and flowing. So that is to be awakened, and that love should flow, and our small petty things like jealousies and competitions and all those things which spoil us must be washed away. And it can be washed if your heart is full of love.<br />
Today is a day of spreading love, light of love so that everybody feels enlightened and happy and forgets these petty problems."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (16th day after Diwālī Day), The Need for Sincerity, Holiday Inn Express and Suites, 1080 Navigator Drive, Ventura, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1064.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Then the fifteenth day is the day when the Moon is absolutely missing from everything.</b> Is absolute darkness, where you put these lights to suggest that: `There are lights, now let Lakṣhmī come within us.' So, there is no spot that should be left which is dark, <b>so everywhere the Lakṣhmī resign ... resides, and give us the glory of Her blessings.</b>' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1114 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Deeper Wealth, Divine Temperament, Fondness of Generosity, Keep your Suṣhumṇā Open and Real Days of Diwālī Celebration (The Greatest Generosity a Human Being Can Do Is to Forgive, All of Us Have to Go Together, Discretion to Improve Your Value System and Universal Theme for People), Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Lakṣhmī is the Goddess of well-being and wealth. She is the wife of Śhrī Viṣhṇu and the mother of Kāma, the God of Love.<br />
She is also called Myriam, because She was born from the ocean, which is the very source of wealth.</b><br />
Even if human beings impoverish more and more the Mother Earth, taking from Her all Her raw materials, She still gives infinitely more resources.<br />
Śhrī Lakṣhmī is standing on a lotus. <b>Her right hand protects and Her left hand gives blessings.</b><br />
She incarnates the wealth but also the glory of wealth. It is the first opening to our spiritual search. We first look for material wealth, but soon we understand that we need something else to reach the complete bliss. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Śhrī Lakṣhmī from the book The Light of the Koran (1998) by Flore Descieux, Pages 254 and 255</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1065.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Then the fifteenth is that darkest night. That's the darkest night when there is no Moon. Absolutely that's the day when they celebrate this Diwālī.</b> But symbolically, in India also, Śhrī Rāma returned to Dvārika ... to this place on that day, and was crowned on that day. So the significance of Diwālī is expressed in this manner: that this is the day when Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was on doubt the martyric, they have all gone to Narak, they have gone to the Hell, and the people now are safe from them and they are celebrating the joy, this thing.<br />
And that is the time when Christ was born. That's why lights are being put in the night, 'cause He was born at twelve o'clock in the night."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">Śhrī Rāma's crowning or any other aspect of Śhrī Lakṣhmī here now becomes your own crowning, that is now you have entered into the Kingdom of God and once you are there then automatically as the citizens of God's Kingdom you are blessed and as you become the lotuses then you start spreading your fragrance all around. Now you do not keep this joy to yourself but you become generous about it and you go all out to give it to others. Generosity at another level, at a lower level is transformed into this Universal Love. Whatever you gain, whatever joy, satisfaction, vibrations, knowledge, all that you want to give it to others. You want to spread it because now you got the reality and you don't want to keep it to yourself, you think it is very important that everyone in the world should know about reality.<br />
This is significant in putting these lights, that now you are the lights. It is the darkest night today, tonight is the darkest night, in the same way these are the darkest days, this is the Kali Yuga and it is the core Kali Yuga, the worst time where the worst things are happening, human beings are going to the worst level and at this time we have to put Sahaja Yoga before them. You know what is the ordeal one has to go through to break the hard nuts of the brains of people, but it is working, it has clicked already. ......<br />
Now you have to enlighten many lights, we call it Dīpawali, Diwālī is dīpāwali, means the rows of lights, and by celebrating this Diwālī with so many of you I'm sure we'll have such a torch of light which will go around the whole world. Just remember you are not a small drop, now you have become the Ocean and you have to spread. Now you are sitting on your thrones and assume your powers. You have all the powers within you, you have to just manifest it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1066.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Such a beautiful lotus, I am sitting in a beautiful lotus.
 In the same way, is reflected in your heart as a beautiful lotus.</b> Feel that lotus, how beautiful, how delicate. 
It’s pink because pink is the lotus which invites everyone, a sign of generosity, of invitation. Pink color attracts all kinds of insects, everybody.<br />
So lotus is pink and it invites everything, open to everything, not frightened of everything.  
You can make people see what a spiritual person is. <b>You are the reflector of Sahaja Yoga, not Me. You have to reflect Sahaj Yoga.<br />
For such people are always in joy and wisdom.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Joy and Happiness, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Lakṣhmī is the Goddess, is the power within us, by which we balance, lead a very balanced life, by which we are satisfied.</b><br />
Now they have made a beautiful picture of this Lakṣhmī also one should understand this power -- is a Lady, is a Mother and She stands on a lotus. Now these are all symbols which suggest that these symbols are carved out with such deep significance. She stands on a lotus. Means imagine, who can stand on a lotus? And She's a very healthy woman, very healthy woman and She stands on a lotus. It means that, that She is never putting pressure on anyone.<br />
......<br />
Then, it has got two red, pink flowers in the hand, that are lotus flowers again. Now the lotus is regarded as a very holy flower in India, because it is so receptive to everything that is crude and funny. First of all it is born in the mud. Just think of it, in the mud, in the filth, where the horrible smell is coming out, the lotus is born. And the one lotus gives the fragrance, the beautiful fragrance to the whole atmosphere, and kills all that's filth and everything, and covers the whole pond with its big, big leaves so that it looks a beautiful pond. That's what is the lotus for. But this lotus is a pink lotus, means pink, you know, is the sign of love. <b>Pink is the sign of love. So such a person has to have tremendous love and that softness of the lotus.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0327 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 3, Nābhī Chakra (Must Have a Balanced Attitude Towards Life), Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1067.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"And, today’s day is a very great day for us because the Saints are celebrating Diwālī. 
I’m celebrating My Diwālī enlightening light in your hearts that you enjoy your own joy and your own beauty; 
that you are now the Spirit. Enjoy it. That you are there. Now, you are in the Kingdom of God. No doubt."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>You know that today is the Pūjā of Śhrī Lakṣhmī.</b> Here nobody performs Lakṣhmī Pūjā. So, it must be understood that today is a very important day. <b>Lakṣhmī gives you everything. She is Mother. She gives everything, all blessings, all comfort, and most important is that She enlightens your inner being.</b><br />
So somehow you recognize Lakṣhmī. Lakṣhmī doesn’t mean money. You have to understand that She is a Goddess, and you have to respect money like a Goddess. In our country, people do a lot for the sake of money; wrong things that are very bad. But you have got a responsibility to recognize Lakṣhmī as Devī, and worship Her and understand that you cannot make fun of Lakṣhmī. Lakṣhmī blesses you and will go on blessing you. Such evil people are a few only, and you should be contented that Lakṣhmī resides in your being and has accumulated many moments of joy and comfort for you. You are going to get all that and have already got it.<br />
...... I am sure that everyone will worship Lakṣhmī, and in the Lakṣhmī Pūjā, one should understand all forms of Lakṣhmī and what Her nature is. We cannot understand Her, and if we cannot understand Her, we will follow the wrong path. So it should be understood that She is Devī and that She is your Mother, and that She can do anything for you because She is very powerful and very affectionate, She doesn’t give you any problem.<br />
If you get trapped somewhere, She will save you. Such is the blessing of Lakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-1026 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi) (Dhanatheras Day), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1068.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"This is the promise of Diwālī to you all, that you will reach highest and the noblest way of life. Every word I say will be there to prove what I say is there. Whatever petty problems you have, they'll all be washed off. All these are the messages from the Divine, you don't have to worry about petty things, about money, about jobs, that's not your job. Your destiny will work it out. You have a promise that you'll be looked after. I hope you believe in that promise and are joyous in the highest way.<br />
I bless you all from My heart, all of you, for a very happy and prosperous Diwālī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (16th day after Diwālī Day), The Need for Sincerity, Holiday Inn Express and Suites, 1080 Navigator Drive, Ventura, CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Chandrām Prabhāsām Yashasā Jvalantiim Shriyam Loke Deva-Jussttām-Udaarām 
Taam Padminiim-Iim Sharannam-Aham Prapadye-[A]lakssmiir-Me Nashyataam Tvām Vrnne</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Who is the Embodiment of Sri and Whose Glory Shines like the Splendour of the Moon in all the Worlds;<br />
Who is Noble and Who is Worshipped by the Devas.<br />
I take Refuge at Her Feet, Who Abides in the Lotus;<br />
By Her Grace, let the Alakshmi (in the form of Evil, Distress, and Poverty) within and without be destroyed.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(from Śhrī Suktam)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Lakṣhmī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<b>O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Lakṣhmī. Salutations to You!</b><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1997-1102 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Śhrī Lakṣhmī (Symbols, Lakṣhmī Principle, Difference between Money and Lakṣhmī, The Hidden Weapon of Lakṣhmī Devī, and Her Mahāmāyā Character), Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25899158"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi, Ayi, Āj Diwālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hum Āj Rāth</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhjya Pujani archani lina vhave</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1069.png" /></div>

<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1070.png" /></div>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
Wishing you a very Happy and prosperous Diwālī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “yourself such beautiful instruments of Rājalakṣhmī that people when they will see you they will vote for you and tomorrow you will rule the world.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/23" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “yourself such beautiful instruments of Rājalakṣhmī that people when they will see you they will vote for you and tomorrow you will rule the world.”" /><published>2022-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_23_Diwali_Day_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/23"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So it is today we are here to enjoy our joy, our Ātmānanda, Nirānanda and Paramānanda.</b><br /> 
All these we are here to enjoy, which are of eternal value.<br />
You have to understand that now believe that you are in the Kingdom of God and all the subtle beauties of your being are going to be opened out to you.<br />
You are going to see yourself all the beauty.<br />
But here, if your eyes are already closed, if your heart is already closed and you don’t want to see something that’s so beautiful, how can I say what a beautiful thing they have made?<br />
Is a very important thing in life, is to have a very positive attitude.<br /> 
For Sahaja Yoga also. In Sahaja Yoga, we have to develop ourselves within."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Joy and Happiness, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1059.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Then the fourteenth day is very important, because that is the day the Goddess as a power, 
as a power, because it was Kārttikeya who killed Narakāsura, the devil.</b><br />
And he was one of the worst of all, could not be killed.<br />
So Śhiva and Pārvatī were married for this special purpose to produce this powerful Śhakti Putra, means the Son of the Śhakti, known as Kārttikeya.<br />
And He was just born to kill this horrible devil, called as Narakāsura. And He killed.<br />
<b>That is the day, fourteenth day. It is something like Halloween, that day.<br />
Because that is the day they opened the gates of hell and put all the devils into hell.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa has got four sides. ...... we have got the Rājalakṣhmī.</b><br />
Rājalakṣhmī Principle is that you are like a king “I am the realized Soul, so what! I’m like a king!” The kings don’t beg, do they? I mean if they beg then they are beggars, they are not kings. Of course these days I don’t know what the kings are doing.<br />
But, we are kings, we are royal. We walk like royal people. I mean I see people sometimes walking in a manner that doesn’t behoove a Sahaja Yogi, living in a manner that doesn’t behoove a Sahaja Yogi. <b>We have to walk with the dignity of a king. And the king is the one who gives, who doesn’t take anything. Is the Rājalakṣhmī Principle in you, has to come, in all the ladies.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia/Sottomarina, Venice, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1060.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Purple"><b>"Another blessing of Rājalakṣhmī is that She grants a particular type of a body, which has a coefficience, which gives vibrations."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Hindi), The Royal Principal, Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"When this thing happens that you get some position, any power, even in Sahaja Yoga I was surprised. If somebody becomes leader, I don’t know what happens to him. It is a myth. There’s nothing like leadership in Sahaja Yoga, nothing like that. It’s just a myth. But suddenly people jump up. It is ego that gets pampered.<br />
But this ego can be easily managed if you worship the Rājalakṣhmī. She is the giver of balance. Firstly, She rides on the elephant. Is not easy for a lady to climb on an elephant, I have done it, it’s not easy. Without fear. And She sits straight with a complete balanced attitude. And Her blessings are tremendous.<br />
The first blessing one gets the imbibement of dignity. Dignity of a king, dignity of a queen. You are a queen so you can’t behave like street woman. With Her blessing, first of all, you get that dignity. That dignity is full of love, love for others. That personality emits nothing but love and benevolence for others, nothing else. Wherever She looks, in every glance She blesses people. She doesn’t expect anything. She is a queen, what can you give to the queen? She’s the highest of all in every way, what can you give it to Her?<br />
So <b>first thing is the sign, is that such a person has a personality that just blesses people, thinks of their benevolence, cares for each and every person who comes along. This is a blessing of the Goddess. Then the second blessing of the Goddess is that you develop a kind of a temperament, which is very dignified, but also very humorous and understanding what other people are like.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Hindi), The Royal Principal, Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1061.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Purple">"So the person who is innately a king has the blessings of the Rājalakṣhmī.<br />
Then what does She do? What does She do to such a man?<br />
What She does is first his name is written on the hearts of the people whom he rules.<br />
She writes it with her own hand. They adore him, they admire him and they try to imbibe his qualities within himself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Hindi), The Royal Principal, Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Rājalakṣhmīs are the Goddesses who are looking after the country.</b><br />
Like England has a Rājalakṣhmī, too. Now, the, say, we can say the princess now is ... is a Rājalakṣhmī, he’s a ... she’s a woman with dignity, she carries herself with that bashful sweetness and all that, she’s a Rājalakṣhmī.<br />
Our Queen is very good, too.<br />
...... <b>A Rājalakṣhmī is a dignified woman: she is the one who is the glory of the country.</b> She has to be a glorious woman. She has to be a woman with all the attributes of a queen. And that is the Rājalakṣhmī: is the, is the queen, or the Goddess, that is the queen. And She resides in every country. Every country has a Gṛuhalakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1114 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Deeper Wealth, Divine Temperament, Fondness of Generosity, Keep your Suṣhumṇā Open and Real Days of Diwālī Celebration (The Greatest Generosity a Human Being Can Do Is to Forgive, All of Us Have to Go Together, Discretion to Improve Your Value System and Universal Theme for People), Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1062.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Purple">"So now you have entered into the Kingdom of God, you are now sitting in the court of God Almighty.<br />
Here, of course, as courtiers you have to dress up well, sit properly, should take up your seats.<br />
You have to be systematic and above board because you are Sahaja Yogis.<br />
You are not ordinary people. You are special people. How many people in this world are going to be Sahaja Yogi?<br />
<b>You are special people, so try to make yourself such beautiful instruments of Rājalakṣhmī 
that people when they will see you they will vote for you and tomorrow you will rule the world.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Hindi), The Royal Principal, Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Hindi), The Royal Principal, Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/29067918"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Andhar Phar Ahe (Śhrī Mātājī gives the meaning of the bhajan and sings along)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/BM9TIVx2h3M">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1063.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Purple"><b>"The vāhana is the elephant. The elephant is vāhana, is Her conveyance, is the elephant. Because it is the sign of dignity, of Her majesty. And also is the wisest animal, very wise animal, and very forgiving, extremely generous. That signifies Gajālakṣhmī day. Rājalakṣhmī is a belonging, you can say, of the Goddess. Gaja is this."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Jaya jaya durgati-nashini kamini</b></font><br />
Victory to the ever-loving distorter of all our ills.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Sarva-phala-prada shastra maye</b></font><br />
O Goddess of Divine Knowledge, You are the giver of all the fruits
(of our desires and actions),<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Ratha gaja turanga padati samavruta</b></font><br />
You are surrounded by chariots, elephants, horses and foot soldiers,<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Pari-jana mandit loka nute</b></font><br />
The whole world bows down to you in worship.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Hari-Hara-Brahma supujita sevita</b></font><br />
The Lords Viṣhṇu, Śhiva and Brahmā serve You and offer auspicious Pūjā.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Tapa nivarini pada yute</b></font><br />
You wash away the extreme sorrows of those who meditate upon your feet.
Jaya jaya he Madhu-sudan-kamini<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Jaya jaya he Madhu-sudan-kamini</b></font><br />
Victory to the beloved of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, the deserter of demon Madhu.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Rājalakṣhmī, Śhrī Nirmalā Devī, sada palaya mam</b></font><br />
O Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī, the giver of prosperity, Śhrī Nirmalā Devī, please protect me forever.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>From the 'Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī Stotram' by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Naraka Chaturdashi" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “yourself such beautiful instruments of Rājalakṣhmī that people when they will see you they will vote for you and tomorrow you will rule the world.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/22" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “yourself such beautiful instruments of Rājalakṣhmī that people when they will see you they will vote for you and tomorrow you will rule the world.”" /><published>2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_22_Diwali_Day_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/22"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nothing is rigid. Rigidity comes from ignorance.<br />
It's all for you, for your joy and happiness. The whole festival system is for your happiness and not for the happiness of the time or date. It's for you, so it should be adjustable according to your needs and understanding. And also according to your national way you live. They should be no addiction to any particular type of culture, a particular type of ideas. It's all for you. <b>All these festivals are for you, not for Gods. They don't have these festivals. It's only for you people these festivals are there. And when you celebrate them, that's only for your joy and your happiness. And that's how you should celebrate in a way that gives you the greatest amount of happiness. And the festivals, all the festivals of the world must be celebrated. The more you are festive, the happier it is.</b> Why miss the chance, you see."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1055.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Now today is the Pūjā – as you know there are five days they celebrate Diwālī.<br />
<b>The first day is the thirteenth day where it is the gṛuhalakṣhmī’s day, that is the day when the gṛuhalakṣhmī is worshiped.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkGreen">Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī -- ah!</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0313 Public Program, The Meaning of Sahaja Yoga, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The first day of Diwālī is called as Dhanatrayodaśhī: is the thirteenth day of the Moon. Because that day is the first day when Lakṣhmī, the first ... was born on the thirteenth day. That means She was born as a Gṛuhalakṣhmī, as a housewife.<br />
Now there are eight Lakṣhmīs, which she will read it out. And I will tell you later on what is the meaning of all [them]. So one of them is Gṛuhalakṣhmī.<br />
<b>So the first is the form of a Gṛuhalakṣhmī. She is born as a Gṛuhalakṣhmī, to begin with. That means the awareness, of human beings also, started really getting into evolutionary process when they started their family life.</b> When they were vagabonds, moving about, then the awareness was just like animals. Though they had become human beings, but they were like animals. Then when they established their families, then the Gṛuhalakṣhmī started working and that's how the first Advent of Gṛuhalakṣhmī was felt.<br />
So She is the first Lakṣhmī who was born, and that's why on that thirteenth day is the day of the Gṛuhalakṣhmī, of the housewife. And so, one has to go in the market and buy some utensils or something that she uses for cooking in the house. In India on the thirteenth day everyone goes and buys a pot or, say, we can say, what you call, a cooking utensil or something. Or they may buy a sāṛī or something or gold or something for the gṛuhalakṣhmī. That is the day of the housewife.<br />
So, to reach the Lakṣhmī one has to understand that motherhood is very important. The <b>motherhood as a gṛuhalakṣhmī is important</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1056.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Gṛuhalakṣhmī is the Deity of the Family</b>, the One who’s the Deity of the Family. ......  
The Deity of the Household, if She resides in you, then you are Gṛuhalakṣhmī, otherwise, you are not."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Fāṭimah ...... was the Embodiment of Gṛuhalakṣhmī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today women have gone weaker so the men have also become weak and powerless. Till the purity and loving mother-like qualities develop in a woman the Gṛuhalakṣhmī Śhakti does not get awakened in her. But she should be wise. <b>Gṛuhalakṣhmī has to be wise and intelligent. So we can say that when this Mahākālī Śhakti gets cool and peaceful it becomes Gṛuhalakṣhmī.</b><br />
<b>We believe in the Power of Fāṭimah as perfect Gṛuhalakṣhmī and she should sit on the Throne of Gṛuhalakṣhmī. By this Power of Mahākālī, a woman can correct her children.</b> She keeps her character pure and we are witness that the pativrata, women’s devotion towards her husband cannot be destroyed by anything because it is her śhakti. People and negativities are afraid of pativratā women. Also, the husbands should understand that the power within them is from the śhakti, their wife."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1211 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Mahāmāyā, Mahākālī, Śhāradā Devī, Mahālakṣhmī, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Fāṭimah Bi, who was the symbol of Gṛuhalakṣhmī.</b> And so we are going to have the Pūjā of the Gṛuhalakṣhmī Principle within us.<br />
...... Now, the Principle of Gṛuhalakṣhmī has been evolved and developed by the Divine, it’s not a human beings’ creation. And as you know, it resides in the left Nābhī. The Gṛuhalakṣhmī is the one that is represented in the life of Fāṭimah who was the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab. Now She is always born in a relationship to a Guru which is of virginity, of purity. So She comes as a sister or She comes as a daughter.<br />
...... <b>It’s a very beautiful thing how the Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa of Sītā took a form of Viṣhṇumāyā just to establish the beautiful Principle of a Housewife.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0814 Śhrī Fāṭimah Pūjā, Saint-George (40 kms W of Lausanne), Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1057.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Gṛuhalakṣhmī is the woman who should know that she has the great responsibility of creating a very great society of Sahaja Yoga."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0428 Śhrī Haṃsa Chakra Pūjā, The Source of Discretion, Queens, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="BlueViolet"><b>Bolo Śhrī Gṛuhalakṣhmī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī kī jay!</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The significance of Diwālī is spread out in about five days.</b><br />
And they are all together somehow, these five days are all put together. 
<b>So they have different aspects, but in every aspect, there’s one common point is that the Goddess plays the main role.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Romania</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Lakṣhmī Welcome Song 1987 </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Pavan Utsav ayya re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hasat Ali</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kanakadhara Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī Storam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Lakṣhmī Ali</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1058.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Today is a very interesting day when you are worshiping the Gṛuhalakṣhmī here, with the Gṛuhalakṣhmī of this house.
In the same way, in your families, also in your houses, homes, you must do gṛuhalakṣhmī’s pūjā. 
The woman has to be a gṛuhalakṣhmī herself, and then she should be worshiped.
<b>“Yatra narya[stu] pujyante tatra ramante Devatā."</b> 
“Where the women are respected and worshiped, there reside all the Deities.” 
But they should be respectable also. If they are not respectable, then the Deities won’t reside there. 
It’s a big responsibility on a Gṛuhalakṣhmī to be the respectable so that all the Deities are happy in the family. 
And once she is respected, she will try to be respectable also. So, the respect of the gṛuhalakṣhmī is very important."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0818 Śhrī Gṛuhalakṣhmī Pūjā, House, 48 Brompton Square, Knightsbridge, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
Wishing you all a very joyous Diwālī Festival and a Happy Dhanateras!<br /> 
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Dhanatrayodashi" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That’s what it is.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That’s what it is.”" /><published>2022-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_05_Navaratri_Day_10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nine yugas, nine times, you all have been saved properly, and on the tenth month you are given your birth. Also this birth is always after seven days of nine months. So we had to wait for some time till it matures.<br />
<b>Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti. So today we are really going to worship the Ādi Śhakti.</b> On one side the Ādi Śhakti is Mahākālī, on the other side She is Mahāsaraswatī, in the center She is Mahālakṣhmī, and also She is the Ambā, the one who is the Kuṇḍalinī. But She’s also beyond that. She’s Parāśhakti, She’s beyond all the powers because She is the Generator of Power, so She has to be beyond all that.<br />
<b>So today when we are worshiping Her, we have to worship Her in all these forms.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1051.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today to see you on this Navarātri Day, so many people sitting to worship Me. So many people are here, so many Sahaja Yogis, it’s so remarkable, it is not My achievement, I tell you. It’s your seeking.</b><br />
Because I have been on this Earth many a times before – that you know. But we never had like this, so many came and got crucified, died, this, that – but I never had people of this caliber"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you enter into the Kingdom of God. Then the Śhakti makes you sit on different beautiful positions, and some are sitting in the Heart of God, some are sitting in the Sahasrāra of God, in the Kingdom of God.</b><br />
Now you should assume your power. On Navarātri now, you should understand that it has now crossed the limit and now we are on the tenth position, where you must assume. I have told you many a times, now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God. You cannot judge God, you cannot say why She does that, why She does that, why He does that. You cannot say that – that’s different. But when you sit there, then it is not an assembly, it is not like a politician fighting, no; it is that you have entered into the Kingdom of God, blessed by God, looked after, protected, nourished, and made knowledgeable.<br />
...... So Navarātri’s – <b>now, the tenth day of Navarātri, which is the most important for all of you, is where this Paramachaitanya has become active. And by its activity you should know it is become very powerful, and that now anybody who tries to be nasty with you, tries to trouble you – “I don’t have to worry at all.” It will take care of it</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1052.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"On this day of this Pūjā, <b>it’s such a combination that it’s the Dussehra, I am here and also you can call it the last day of the Devī Pūjā.</b><br /> 
We have to see within ourselves, introspect ‘What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?"&lt;/b&gt;</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha </b></font><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma! Salutations to You!
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So today is Dussehra, is a very big day in India.</b> They say on this day Rāvaṇa was killed. He was the worst enemy of human beings, and he was killed. But whatever it is then, as a memory of that great man, Śhrī Rām, they celebrate today Dussehra. And on this day, they say, those who are duṣhṭas, means bad people or we can say negative, they are killed. Can you imagine? [Chuckles.]
So this day is regarded as a very important day in India, and they make a big statue of Rāvaṇa. You all know who was Rāvaṇa, ...... whom Śhrī Rāma killed. He was a horrible fellow and he took away the wife of Śhrī Rām, Sītā, by force. But she was such a chaste woman that he couldn’t touch her. He tried; he couldn’t touch her. He couldn’t achieve any power over her. On the contrary she was very powerful."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That’s why I have to tell you that on this day of Dussehra, let us decide that we are going to have Rām Rāj in Sahaja Yoga, where there is benevolence, there is love, compassion, security, peace, joy, discipline among ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1053.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You desire something, you'll be surprised, immediately you'll find it works out. You ask for something, immediately it works out.<br />
<b>But there should be a complete dedication in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That's what it is.</b><br />
But if you are still moving with your egos, <b>and if you are still thinking on those lines that, `We are something and the we can start our own Sahaj Yog</b>. We can work out this way and that way,' or 'My wife is like that, my child is like that, my husband is like that,' <b>you have to give up all these problems on one side, otherwise you will not ascend</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76751298"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dSIEMZflZa0&amp;ab_channel=SahajiBhai">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Ayi Re</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/BUcvc6e_9-E">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Anyatha Śharanam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Mangala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kindle My Heart</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Raghu Pati Raghav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ramrangi Rangale: Bhimsen Joshi</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/uDjaxDiFRNU">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe. Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/04" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Worshipping the Devī during Navarātri Festival: “Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe. Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.”" /><published>2022-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_04_Navaratri_Day_9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/04"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you are worshiping today the Durgā, or all the nine forms of the Goddess.</b> She came nine times on this Earth, according to this, that She fought all the people who were destroying the seekers, who were trying to make a mess of their lives. And these tortured Saints, when they prayed to the Goddess -- because none of the Gods could do anything, and Sadāśhiva is never interfering with what the Goddess is doing -- so they worshiped the Bhagavatī, and then the Incarnation of Hers came nine times, according to the need of the time. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1048.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red">"The siddhis that people attempt to achieve are: Aṇima, Laghima, Mahima, Īśhatva, Vaśhitva, Prākāmya, Bhukti, Icchā, Prāpti, Mukti. Aṇima is to become like a small particle.<br />
Laghima is to become small, Mahima is to have a big form, Īśhatva is to create Gods out of human beings, Vaśhitva is the attraction, Prākāmya is the manifestation, Bhukti is the enjoyment, [Icchā] fulfillment of desire. Prāpti is the attainment, Mukti is the salvation.<br /> 
These are all the siddhis that Sahaja Yogis can have."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0907 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Bīja Mantras, Śhrī Lalitā, Śhrī Chakra, 56 Ashley Gardens, Ambrosden Avenue (near Victoria Station), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we have gathered here to do the Pūjā of the Devī. The Devī has many forms, but is the embodiment of the Śhakti. Ādi Śhakti gives Śhakti to all these embodiments and so there are many Goddesses we have.<br />
At different times they came on this Earth and did all that was necessary for the ascent of people who were seekers. Especially the one we know of, Jagadambā, the Durgā. She was trying to protect all the Seekers of Truth and to destroy all evil forces, because without the ascent of human beings they do not know the Truth, and that’s why whatever they try to do is a mental projection, and this mental projection, if it is not substantiated by Truth, by dharma, it declines. In Sanskrit they call it glāni. When this glāni takes place, then incarnations are born – to solve the problem.<br />
In all incarnation of the Goddess there have been very much incarnated the satanic forces, they had incarnated, and She had to fight with them and destroy them. But this destruction was not for the destruction’s sake that the evil forces are to be destroyed, but evil forces always try to put down the seekers, put down the Saints, try to harm them, sometimes even destroy [them]. All these destructive forces do not come at the same time, normally. At different times, is easy to handle."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1049.jpg" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="purple"><b><br />
Ayi śharaṇ’āgata vairi-vadhū-vara<br />
Vīra-var’ābhaya dāya-kare<br />
Tri-bhuvana-mastaka śhūla-virodhi<br />
Śhirō-’dhi kṛit’āmala śhūla-kare<br />
Dumi-dumi-tāmara dundubhi-nādam<br />
Aho-mukharī-kṛita diṅmakare, Jaya jaya he ......</b></font><br />
Giving courage, strength, boons and fearlessness to those who take refuge in You;<br />
Your spotless Trident captures the Heads of the Rulers of the Three Worlds;<br />
Making all directions resound with the ‘Dumi-duma’ sound of drums; Victory to You ......<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now you have had nine Pūjās here and out of these nine Pūjās have we improved more, have we got more? Did we fill ourselves more with greater love, with greater joy, with greater understanding and with greater satisfaction?<br />
This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation. Because we have done what? That is what. So today you should go and make a complete picture of yourself. What have I got in these nine days? What have I got? Let us see, have I got this? Have I got that? All these things, you should just within yourself see and then enjoy that you have got all these things. It is the victory. <b>Tomorrow is the day of victory. That you have become victorious about yourself and about your ignorance. You have won yourself and you've won over the ignorance, the darkness of ignorance. This is what is tomorrow's message.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1050.jpg" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"This Pūjā is very special, many will go deep and receive tremendous blessings.<br />
But first make your attention steady.<br />
In your attention pray for peace, ‘Mother, please bestow peace upon me.’ <b>Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe.<br />
Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English+Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25805578"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Devī Suktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/K7he8axOgfw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Anyatha Śharanam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/IZxG3j1wUyE">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī playing harmonium as Sahaja Yogis sing Devī Bhajans</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nav Durgā kī Jyot </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Siddhidatri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>