<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-18T19:01:46-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 10: “now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 10: “now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God.”" /><published>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_12_Navaratri_Day_10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Nine yugas, nine times, you all have been saved properly, and on the tenth month you are given your birth. Also this birth is always after seven days of nine months. So we had to wait for some time till it matures.<br />
<b>Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti. So today we are really going to worship the Ādi Śhakti.</b> On one side the Ādi Śhakti is Mahākālī, on the other side She is Mahāsaraswatī, in the center She is Mahālakṣhmī, and also She is the Ambā, the one who is the Kuṇḍalinī. But She’s also beyond that. She’s Parāśhakti, She’s beyond all the powers because She is the Generator of Power, so She has to be beyond all that.<br />
<b>So today when we are worshiping Her, we have to worship Her in all these forms.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0081.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"So She has created all these things just for you to be created, and ultimately to get your Self-realization; to have meaning for your life, to get connected to this All-pervading Power, to enter into the Kingdom of God. All is Her work.<br />
<b>So we can say nine times She came, and the tenth time She is supposed to give Realization to all of you. But at the tenth time, all these Three Powers are joined together – that’s why it’s called Triguṇātmika.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Navy"><b>Namo Devyai maha-devyai</b><br />
Salutations to the Devī, to the Mahadevī,<br />
<b>Shivaye satatam namah,</b><br />
To You who is ever Auspicious,<br />
<b>Namah prakrutyai bhadrayai</b><br />
To You who is the Primordial Cause,<br />
<b>Niyutah pranatah sma tam.</b><br />
And the sustaining Power, we bow to You.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>from 'Devī Suktam' in Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Bolo Ādi Śhakti</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you enter into the Kingdom of God. Then the Śhakti makes you sit on different beautiful positions, and some are sitting in the Heart of God, some are sitting in the Sahasrāra of God, in the Kingdom of God.</b><br />
Now you should assume your power. On Navarātri now, you should understand that it has now crossed the limit and now we are on the tenth position, where you must assume. I have told you many a times, now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God. You cannot judge God, you cannot say why She does that, why She does that, why He does that. You cannot say that -- that's different. But when you sit there, then it is not an assembly, it is not like a politician fighting, no; it is that you have entered into the Kingdom of God, blessed by God, looked after, protected, nourished, and made knowledgeable.<br />
......<br />
So Navarātri's -- <b>now, the tenth day of Navarātri, which is the most important for all of you, is where this Paramachaitanya has become active. And by its activity you should know it is become very powerful, and that now anybody who tries to be nasty with you, tries to trouble you -- "I don't have to worry at all." It will take care of it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0082.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Navy"><b>We should devote ourselves to that Devī<br />
Who resides at the center of our lotus hearts,<br />
Whose glory is like that of the rising sun,<br />
Whose face is pleasing,<br />
Who grants all boons and protection,<br />
Who is three-eyed, Who wears red clothes, and<br />
Who fulfills the desires of Her devotees.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha)</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"...... on this day of this Pūjā, <b>it's such a combination that it's the Dussehra, I am here and also you can call it the last day of the Devī Pūjā</b>. We have to see within ourselves, introspect, 'What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha</b><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma. Salutations to You! 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It’s very remarkable that, not only that you recognize Me as a Mother who loves you very much, but a Mother who is powerful to protect you. Is very powerful. If you realize that and if you feel that within your heart. Supposing I correct you some time, instead of feeling sad you should see that, ‘How fortunate I am that Ādi Śhakti Herself is correcting me. She’s taking interest in me. How fortunate I am to be born at this time, to be with Her in Her great work. What have I done [to deserve this]?’ <b>This recognition itself will fulfill all the Incarnations of Navarātri.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0083.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"On the ninth day, He worshiped the Goddess to get strength, Śhakti, for his weapons, and the tenth day He killed Rāvaṇa."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha </b></font><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma! Salutations to You!
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You desire something, you'll be surprised, immediately you'll find it works out. You ask for something, immediately it works out.<br />
<b>But there should be a complete dedication in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
When I say Sahaj Yog, you know that is the Yoga of your attention with My Feet. That's what it is.</b><br />
But if you are still moving with your egos, <b>and if you are still thinking on those lines that, `We are something and the we can start our own Sahaj Yog</b>. We can work out this way and that way,' or 'My wife is like that, my child is like that, my husband is like that,' <b>you have to give up all these problems on one side, otherwise you will not ascend</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0084.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You must pray to God and ask what you want.<br />
Ask for complete satisfaction in my heart, joy in my heart, bliss in my heart, so that the whole world becomes blissful.<br />
Give me love, love that I could love the whole world and that the whole world becomes one in love.<br />
Give salvation to this humanity which is suffering.<br />
Take me to Your feet. Cleanse me with Thy love."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0201 Public Program (Hindi+English), Dhyāna Kyoṃ Karanā Chāhiye (Why Should One Meditate), Prabhadevi, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other dates 0202 and 0209)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākshāt Śhrī Durgā Mātā Jagadambā sākshāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Durgā, the Mother of the universe. Salutations to You!<br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/76751298"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="OrangeRed"><b>Sarva Mangala Mangale</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Raghu Pati Raghav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 9: “This Navarātri should give you that power, those Nine Powers of Nine Chakras”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 9: “This Navarātri should give you that power, those Nine Powers of Nine Chakras”" /><published>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_11_Navaratri_Day_9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/11"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"She came on this Earth, many a times, to kill the people who were doing wrong things, who were trying to kill good people. She has done Her level [best] to do that, and today we are celebrating Her birthday.<br />
You all know so much about it, that I need not tell you, but what you have to know is that: <b>She came on this Earth to save you from all kinds of troubles. For Her you were important, very important, because you were doing Devī Pūj. And so we are celebrating today this Devī Pūjā, with all our heart, because whatever ill people did to you, She came to destroy them. So today is a very great day for you to thank Her: thank Her for Her protection and for Her understanding as to what you have been tortured for.</b><br />
I'm happy you are all here to celebrate Her birthday, and to be surrendered to Hers so that She can always, always, protect you, and give you Her blessings.<br />
So may God bless you all, your children, your families, and that you bring great joy er [and] protection.<br />
It's very kind of you to have come today, so far away. I'm very happy to see you. Moreover, you have got tomorrow also that you can celebrate.<br />
Today we are not going to have any questions and solutions. We are just going to worship the Goddess, that's all.<br />
<b>I request Her to protect us from all kinds of problems that are facing us.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1012 Navarātri Pūjā (8th day after Dussehra Day), Birthday of Śhrī Gaurī, Nevele Grande Hotel, 1 Country Club Road, Town of Wawarsing (outside Ellenville, 90 kms N of Manhattan), NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0078.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This Navarātri should give you that power, those Nine Powers of Nine Chakras.</b><br />
Seven chakras you already know. Above that you become the master yourself, and then you become the Power yourself.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Switzerland</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Navy">Manav. me ahankar. bhara hai<br />
<b>But mankind is full of ego,</b><br />
Ap.ni Shakti se dur. khada hai<br />
<b>Divorcing itself from its own powers. </b><br />
Peedith. narak. me bhayi, Par. kare Nirmala mayi<br />
<b>Mother Nirmalā grants Realization even to those suffering in Hell.</b><br />
Devī par.marth. ko ayi re, Meri Nirmalā Mā<br />
<b>She has arrived for the salvation of all mankind, my Mother Nirmalā.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Ayi Re</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>God is the witness and She is doing the play and She creates those chakras. In the chakras She places all these Deities to govern.</b><br /> 
Now, there is the existence, there is the creation, creative force, and there is the evolutionary force, all inside the Virāṭa State.<br />
Now, this is at the Vaikuṇṭha State, we say, because this state is on this first reflection. It is not in us, or we cannot feel it, the Vaikuṇṭha State, because it is in the first thing.<br />
Then another state was created, then third was created, but the fourth one is the Bhavasāgara: is the state at which all of us were born. First, in the fourth state. Now, can you think of a four strata personality which is facing a mirror? Now, which is the first one [that] shows? Is the topmost. And that's why the topmost shows is the Bhavasāgara. But if you can go deep down into your state, you can feel all the other three. But first of all, the one which you can see and feel it, is the Bhavasāgara. So, you are born in the Bhavasāgara. At this state you are at the Bhavasāgara State. At this Bhavasāgara State, now, you are created and you have to evolve. <b>At this time the Mahālakṣhmī Power acts to evolve you.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0220 Public Program, Creation and Evolution, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0079.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b><br />
Ayi śharaṇ’āgata vairi-vadhū-vara<br />
Vīra-var’ābhaya dāya-kare<br />
Tri-bhuvana-mastaka śhūla-virodhi<br />
Śhirō-’dhi kṛit’āmala śhūla-kare<br />
Dumi-dumi-tāmara dundubhi-nādam<br />
Aho-mukharī-kṛita diṅmakare, Jaya jaya he ......</b></font><br />
Giving courage, strength, boons and fearlessness to those who take refuge in You;<br />
Your spotless Trident captures the Heads of the Rulers of the Three Worlds;<br />
Making all directions resound with the ‘Dumi-duma’ sound of drums; Victory to You ......<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now you have had nine Pūjās here and out of these nine Pūjās have we improved more, have we got more? Did we fill ourselves more with greater love, with greater joy, with greater understanding and with greater satisfaction?<br />
This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation. Because we have done what? That is what. So today you should go and make a complete picture of yourself. What have I got in these nine days? What have I got? Let us see, have I got this? Have I got that? All these things, you should just within yourself see and then enjoy that you have got all these things. It is the victory. Tomorrow is the day of victory. That you have become victorious about yourself and about your ignorance. You have won yourself and you've won over the ignorance, the darkness of ignorance. This is what is tomorrow's message."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0080.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">" <b>"Ṛiddhi siddhi ki dātri hai”: means She is the giver of siddhis.<br />
Siddhis means by which you get powers, to give Realization to people, to cure people, to manifest all the Divinity, Siddhis.</b><br />
And ṛiddhi is by which contentment, peace, joy. Means that you grow into that, ṛiddhi."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1014 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font color="Navy"><font size="+0"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Siddhidatrī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">O Divine Mother, You are verily Siddhidatrī, the One who is the bestower of siddhis (Divine Powers)!
Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25791408"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Devī Sūktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/K7he8axOgfw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī playing harmonium as Sahaja Yogis sing Devī Bhajans</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Siddhidatri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 8: “If you want to really worship Me, that’s what you have to think, what are the devils within you, that’s all. So you don’t have to worry otherwise for outside devils, they cannot do anything to you.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 8: “If you want to really worship Me, that’s what you have to think, what are the devils within you, that’s all. So you don’t have to worry otherwise for outside devils, they cannot do anything to you.”" /><published>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_10_Navaratri_Day_8</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/10"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we have gathered here to do the Devī Pūjā.<br />
<b>This Pūjā was performed many a times and the Devī was requested by the Devas to save them from the tyranny of devilish people.</b> Today I feel the same way, that we are now in the grip of a funny situation; that there are people who are themselves devils, I think, -- and also [who are] mesmerized by them -- who are trying to do something which they should never have done. But they don't know that there is a climax of everything. And that point has arrived where all the good people, especially the Sahaja Yogis should put all their mind to the destruction of these horrible personalities like Mahiṣhāsura.<br />
In those days, it was very simple because devils came as devils and you could see them, that they are devils, and all their behavior proved that they were devils. Why they did it? Why were they cruel? Because so-called 'human beings' as they are -- they are not -- they are by nature devilish and they want to do something by which they can destroy human beings, and good human beings. <b>It is evident that the time has come for them to be destroyed.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), You Should Become Really Soldiers of Love and Peace (Overcome Hatred with Love or To Hate is a Very Bad Quality), Sportcamp, Avras, Loutraki, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0074.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>Raudrāyai namo nityāyai</b></font><br />
Salutations to Her who is Terrible, Eternal,<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Gauryai dhātryai namo namaḥ,</b></font><br />
To Śhrī Gaurī, Supporter of the Universe,<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jyotsnāyai ch’endu-rūpinyai</b></font><br />
To Her who is the Moon and Moonlight,<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Sukhāyai satatam namaḥ</b></font><br />
And Happiness itself, we bow constantly.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Aneka-śhastra hasta sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(You are the One who wields many weapons in Her hands)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the eighth day of Navarātri, but it is great day for Sahaja Yogis because it is the most important period.</b> That is, the seventh center we have crossed and we are on the eighth center. We need not think of the Goddess what She did on the eighth day, we have to think today what we have to do within ourselves.<br />
After crossing the seventh day, after crossing the seventh chakra -- that is the real ascent in your spiritual ascent. What are we to do on the eighth one?<br />
It's so Sahaja that today should be Aṣhṭamī, because that is the day the Goddess killed so may evil doers, and demons and rākṣhasas. She did it on Her own, alone. Now these evil forces are manifesting in human beings. They have spread out. They are within us. So we all have to fight those forces within us. The war is within ourselves, is not without. First when you ascend the seventh chakra, when you are on the eighth step, you have to remember first you have to fight those forces within ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0930 Aṣhṭamī Pūjā (8th Day of Navarātri), Discipline Has to Be Sahaja (What We Have to Do within Ourselves), Complexe Sportif René Leduc, 12 Rue du Père Brottier, Meudon (12 kms SW of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0075.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"And on an Aṣhṭamī, that is today, is the eighth day of the Moon, of the Moon which is increasing, Śhuklapakṣhi, that first time all the weapons of the Goddess are to be worshiped. This was a great idea because these weapons who work all the time, not only to kill the evil but to protect the good, were never worshiped before.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Salutations to the Devī, to the Mahādevī.<br />
Salutations always to Her who is ever auspicious.<br />
Salutations to Her who is the primordial cause of the sustaining power. With attention, we have made obeisance to Her.<br />
Salutations to Her who is terrible, to Her who is eternal.<br />
Salutations to Gauri, the supporter of the universe.<br />
Salutations only to Her who is of the form of the moon and moonlight, and happiness itself.<br />
We bow to Her who is welfare.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the second thing is, [which] today we do, is a very great <b>Pūjā of Aṣhṭamī [eighth day]: is the day when the Goddess killed nine rākṣhasas together with Her eight hands. So today is a very special day for which a very special attention is needed.</b><br />
It's only at the behest of the bhaktas that the Goddess took Her form and killed all these rākṣhasas.<br />
Also with Her eight hands, She killed Mahiṣhāsura. That's why She's called as Mahiṣhāsuramardinī.<br />
She's called as Nava Chaṇḍī, one who has killed nine chaṇḍas, means nine rākṣhasas She has killed.<br />
So is a very important day and very vital and very deep."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0201 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), House of Madhukar Bhikobā Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today to see you on this Navarātri Day, so many people sitting to worship Me. So many people are here, so many Sahaja Yogis, it's so remarkable, it is not My achievement, I tell you. It's your seeking. Because I have been on this Earth many a times before -- that you know. But we never had like this, so many came and got crucified, died, this, that -- but I never had people of this caliber.<br />
So again we come to the same point, that we should be aware of ourselves -- complete śhraddhā in your Self. If you have some śhraddhā in your Self, you will have śhraddhā for Me also.<br />
......<br />
....... I will say that on this day, what we have to do is to kill the devils within ourselves, that's all. If you want to really worship Me, that's what you have to think, what are the devils within you, that's all. So you don't have to worry otherwise for outside devils, they cannot do anything to you.<br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0076.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You have to see that all the negativity goes away, around us, around the universe.<br />
<b>So first we sing the praise of the Goddess; when She destroyed every negative, satanic incarnation of Mahiṣhāsura.</b><br /> 
And when he was killed, all the Gods praised Her for saving them from the ... from the destruction, and that happened long, long time back -- it was ten thousand years back. So this is the praise of the Gods of that so that, whatever is the negativity, through those mantras will go away, because it surrounds us -- you see that, all of them have been there coming; from ten thousand years they have been coming. But this is the way you can throw them out of the present into their proper places."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1012 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (4th Day of Navarātri), Winterthurerstraße, Zürich, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini Nandit. Medini</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O beloved Daughter of the mountains, the One who brings about great joy to the earth</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Vishw. Vinodini Nandinute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">The One who brings joy to the whole universe, I I prostrate myselg before You Who are the form of complete bliss</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Girivar. Vindhya Shirodhini Vasini</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Your holy abode is in the king of the mountains, the Vindhyas</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Viṣhṇu Vilasini Viṣhṇu Nute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Viṣhṇu is filled with joy when He meditate on You, I seek refuge at Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay. Jay. Hai Mahiṣhāsuramardinī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Victory to You O Great Goddess
Who killed the terrible demon, Mahiṣhāsura</font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Ramyak. Par.dini Shailasute</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are the One with the beautiful luminous face, Daughter of the king of the Mountains,
Śhrī Pārvatī, the Wife of the One who has the matted locks, that is Lord Śhiva</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lAojYxfnKMs">Ayi Giri Nandini (Mahiṣhāsuramardinī)</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Navarātri is very good because these nine nights represent the main Nine Incarnations</b>. Where the Goddess took the form of Śhakti and killed the negative people.<br />
But those were easier days because negativity was understood by people and nobody sympathized.<br />
So this is what one has to understand that don't sympathize with negativity. You'll spoil them all. And always you'll find such sympathies bring forth your character also that you are also slightly negative.<br />
Because to fight negativity in modern times is a very difficult task. You cannot kill anyone: if you kill somebody, then may be that such a person is a brother or a sister or something of somebody. Or such a person would be himself or herself a seeker.<br />
So best thing is to separate like a contagious disease, keep that person out, no sympathies. And get the person cured and enjoy the life, otherwise that person is not going to be helped. It has become a very individual fight. And it's so troublesome and so disgusting.<br />
So to help Me out, you should not take any sides with negativity. That's how you can help Me the most. <b>This is what it is the Navarātri, the Pūjā that I give you powers to fight the negativity. That's how you cure people.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1009 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Like a Drama, On Arrival before the Public Program, Flat of Ruth and Kingsley Flint, Strasbourg, Grand Est, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0077.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, today's victory of the Power of the Divine Mother, is doing one very great work: is to expose. And this exposure will be condemning publicly those people who are doing wrong. If you see from that point of view, you will understand how we are victorious now."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Maiya Tere Charano ki</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>O Mother from Your Lotus Feet</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Yadi dhul. jo mil Jaye</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>Even if I could get a particle of dust</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Sach. kehta hu Nirmal Mā</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>Then verily, O Mother Nirmalā.</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Takdir badal Jaye,</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>My life will be transformed</b></font><br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Maiya tere Charno ki</b></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>O Mother, from your Lotus Feet</b></font><br />  
<font size="-1"><font color="DarkGreen"><b>Maiyā tere Charno Ki</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0OlxRe8pbEs">Maiyā tere Charno kí -- Sahaja Yoga bhajan</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1020 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Faith is the State of Being One with the Reality or Be Aware of Your Own State, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25653195"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Devī Mahātmyam Eighth Night</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Mā Ādi Kuṇḍalinī by Sanjay Talwar</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe (Gondhala Mandila), by Ajit Kadkade</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b></b></font><br />
<a href="">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Mahagauri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 7: “I would request you the Sahaja Yogis, not to worry as to what is happening around, but to worry what is happening inside and build up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/09" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 7: “I would request you the Sahaja Yogis, not to worry as to what is happening around, but to worry what is happening inside and build up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle.”" /><published>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_09_Navaratri_Day_7</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/09"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the ascent starts evolving. In that, the play of the Devī is the Navarātri -- in your ascent -- from ages.<br />
<b>Navarātri that's why is the most important Pūjā. In Sahaja Yoga, Navarātri is the most important Pūjā, I would say.</b> Though we can say in modern Sahaja Yoga Sahasrār Day is, because that's how you started getting your Realization.<br />
But if you go to the whole historical events of evolution you'll find [that] <b>Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra</b>. Without the help of the Devī at different stages of your ascent, you could not have been in a position to receive your Realization. <b>So all the steps that you took in the past are today worshiped and are used for thanking the Devī for what She did to bring you down here. So it's like a thanksgiving. Without Her work, nothing could have happened.</b><br />
So when we read about the Devī, about Her Incarnations, how She came on this Earth to save Her bhaktas, people who were trying to ascend, to cross this Bhavasāgara, how She worked hard, how She fought the devils, how She cough... <b>She killed the demons, single-handed, She took upon Herself the responsibility of making the people cross the Bhavasāgara.</b><br />
Guru gave you the strength to have dharma but She is the One who brought you out. Even those who were dhārmik could not do it because of the demonic pressure. <b>She's the One who fought, single-handed, with Her Powers of destruction. In Her Love for you She fought. She brought you to this level.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerlan</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0070.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... I must tell you that the Goddess took Her birth nine times on this Earth. And today [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] seventh, today is the seventh day of Her worship in Navarātri, Navarātri. And <b>the seventh day is ... uh ... for ... uh ... tremendous activity, tremendous ... uh ... creativity and also for prosperity".</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1004 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Wood Room, Hotel, Sasaima (78 kms NW of Bogotá), Cundinamarca, Colombia</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Bhavānī Aṣhṭakam</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/JQ3ibqZWgDI">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"On today's auspicious occasion we have gathered here. <b>Today is the seventh day of the Goddess. On the seventh day, the Devī Goddess destroyed the various rākṣhasas and sinners, because they were torturing the great Saints and Ṛiṣhis who were doing meditation and penance.</b><br />
We wonder, "Mother, why they did so much penance? What was the need?" The reason for doing it was because although human ascent was still low, yet their aspiration was very high. They aspired to achieve the Ātmā through the body. That is why they worked so hard and did penance in this place. It is due to their aspiration that today we are able to achieve this height. This does not mean that we should think that because of the blessing of Sahaja Yoga we are some great people or some specially chosen people by God. People who think like that will receive a great shock. You will see that those who are simple, innocent, and good-natured will ascend foremost and the rest will be left behind. Therefore just receiving your Realization is not the end.<br />
<b>On this auspicious occasion God Almighty has manifested all His śhaktis for your protection, benevolence and welfare. In everything God is blessing you. He wants to see you enter His Kingdom.</b> In a way it is His Desire that you should return to your Father's home and enjoy its comforts. But at least we should be worthy of it. If we are not worthy of it then how can we enter it? We should examine our worthiness and see what it is."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0071.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"About the Devī, it is said She is Ati Raudra, Ati Saumya.<br />
But Mahālakṣhmī Ati Raudra Rudra Swarūpi[n] and Rudra is very necessary. Otherwise, this negativity will not go away.<br />
This will only go away with the Rudra Form."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1211 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Mahāmāyā, Mahākālī, Śhāradā Devī, Mahālakṣhmī, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jaya Twam Devī Chāmuṇḍe jaya bhū-tāpa-hāriṇi,<br />
Jaya Sarva-gate Devī Kāḷarātri namostute</b></font><br />  
Victory be to You, O Devī Chāmuṇḍā<br />
Victory be to You Who destroys the suffering of all living beings.<br />
Victory be to You, O Devī Who is present everywhere.<br />
Salutations to You, O Kāḷarātri (the longest night)<br />
<font size="+0">(from Argala Strotram)</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"She has a double role all the time, She is at two extremes. On one side She is full of joy, Giver of Joy, feels very happy when She sees Her disciple[s] are joyous. Joy is Her own quality, is Her energy.<br />
......<br />
Sahaja Yoga, as you know, has a double action, as the Mahākālī has a double action: <b>She's extremely loving, full of joy, full of happiness and She's the one who's extremely cruel, wrathful. She's the one who is the slayer of all the demons and the evil, and those people who try to do evil.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0912 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Qualities of Mahākālī and You Have to be Collective (Purity Means Chastity and For the Saints the Main Thing Is Their Ascent), Centre Culturel Thierry Le Luron, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... Love is Power of the Goddess, is very subtle, silent, but it manifests. All these manifestations you call them as miracles. You may call them by any name.<br /> 
<b>It is this Goddess which is ruling this universe, which is in your center Heart, which looks after you and looks after the whole universe, is nothing but Pure Desire of Love.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0917 Śhrī Śhakti Devī Pūjā, Love and Joy of Collectivity, Moscow, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0072.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>I would request you the Sahaja Yogis, not to worry as to what is happening around, but to worry what is happening inside and build up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle.</b><br /> Once you have built up your Mahālakṣhmī Principle, you will have no problem at all. Then through you the Mahālakṣhmī Herself will work and fill your countries with great bounties and great joys.<br />
May God bless you all!</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0921 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Śhrī Jaldevatā, Oude Stadsfeestzaal, Mechelen (27 kms S of Antwerp), Belgium</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b></b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The Heart chakra is what the Christians call the Sacred Heart. Within it is the place of Bhavānī, Durgā, which is a very great place.<br />
It is not within you to understand Durgā. That all the rākṣhasas are also Her children. The whole world is Hers. A Mother's Śhakti destroyed them for the sake of Her love for Her children. To pull one's own hands is very difficult. To give an injection to oneself with one's own hands is very difficult. <b>So to kill one's own children to protect other children is even more difficult. But to kill is a very great act of the Śhakti</b> ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0120 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Kṣham Ki Śhakti Ka Mahatav (Power of Forgiveness) or Dharm va Adharm (Dharma and Adharma), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0073.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Her security is so great, She is so secure Herself, that She gives you all the security that you need. You can hold on to Her Feet. You can hold on to Her image or to anything.</b> You can even pray to Her. Many people are being cured only by praying to Her.<br />
......<br />
She is worshiped in the night, because then we can put on the light. She likes enlightened persons. Also She likes the light. She likes the Sun. She likes something that will be completely enlightened and brightened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), The Powers of Śhrī Mahākālī, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
Durgāyai Durga-parāyai<br />
Salutations always to Śhrī Durgā who takes one across in difficulties,<br />
Sārāyai Sarvakārinyai<br />
Who is the author of everything,<br />
Khyātyai tathaiva Kṛiṣhṇāyai<br />
Who is the knowledge of discrimination; and who is blue-black<br />
Dhumrāyai satatam namaḥ<br />
As also smoke-like complexion<br />
<font color="RoyalBlue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kāḷarātri sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī, the one who is the dark night of dissolution,<br />
Salutations to You!
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (7th Day), The Pure Knowledge or You All Should Depend on Paramachaitanya, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25645269"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parameśhwarī Bhagavatī Nirmalā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durgā Mātā Bhavānī (Rāg Durgā by Ajit Kadkade)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HgN42YkSHkY">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kalaratri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 6 “Sixth and the seventh is the day when Mahāsaraswatī finished Her work and the Incarnation of the Śhakti Itself started.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/08" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 6 “Sixth and the seventh is the day when Mahāsaraswatī finished Her work and the Incarnation of the Śhakti Itself started.”" /><published>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_08_Navaratri_Day_6</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/08"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is a great day, of Navarātri, we are sitting on the cusp of the sixth and the seventh. <b>Sixth and the seventh is the day when Mahāsaraswatī finished Her work and the Incarnation of the Śhakti Itself started.</b> So at twelve o'clock today the Devī takes the Śhakti upon Herself.<br />
Of course, as you know, that Mahākālī and Mahāsaraswatī, both are the Powers of Śhrī Sadāśhiva. Ādi Śhakti first formed Herself into Mahākālī, which is the Power of Desire. But <b>all these powers are nothing but the Power of God's Love. So, in the series of this Great Love of God, Ādi Śhakti had to first become the Power of Desire.</b><br />
In the same way, Sahaja Yogis who are bestowed with this Power of Love have to have full desire in their heart. Desire to love. That desire is very different from the other kinds of human love we have known. In other kinds of human love, when we have relations with others, we have expectations, and that's why it is very disappointing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0066.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Navarātri is the day to give you the balance.</b> Those whose right hand is tired will get the power in the left hand. Those who have the left hand tired will get the power on the right hand to share the load.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Namostute Bhagavatī Śhrī Mātājī</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>That's how the Power of Saraswatī works. People go into action for achieving the results of getting into power.<br />
But it should act to discover the Truth. Saraswatī should give you the leap to find out the Truth.</b> That, when you act in those funny places and streets, you discover, 'This is not the path, we have missed it. The path is somewhere else. We've lost it. Let us find out the real path because this doesn't give joy.'<br />
This, one can learn from others, from history, from so many other things and from your own parents, from your society and from yourself and from your children also.<br />
If you want to learn, that is the quality of Saraswatī pujārīs, that they take to gyāna, they take to reality.<br />
Vedas, in the beginning of the Vedas, it's said that: 'If by reading these four Vedas, if you do not get the Vida,' Vida is the knowledge on your nerves, means Realization, 'there is no use reading these Vedas.'<br />
<b>So the Saraswatī's first thing is that through the reading, through the process of Saraswatī's manifestation, you must reach a point to understand that this is a rat race and we have to get out of it. We have to step out.</b> When that happens, then the Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa starts working in you, that is the third tattwa, which starts working.<br />
<b>Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa then starts expressing its love in its full extent through evolutionary process in human beings.</b> He starts evolving simultaneously. He sees on both the sides what's happening, like a witness and he uses his Mahālakṣhmī Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This is a worship of the Śhakti. Until now many Saints, Sages have known and revealed about this Śhakti. Whatever they could not describe in prose, they tried to convey by poetry. Whatever description was not possible to put in words -- they composed different names of the Devī and described.</b> We know all this and many people also know the meaning of this. But one thing they perhaps do not know is that every human being has all these śhaktis, powers dormant in them and they can awaken them. These dormant powers are eternal and limitless.<br />
Besides the thirty-three crores of Devas, there are many Śhaktis. But we can say that this Self-realization that we have achieved today, has been achieved through working of some Śhakti or the other. Without this you could not have achieved the Self-realization.<br />
You have received your Self-realization in Sahaj way. Now there are two meanings of Sahaj. One meaning is you have got it easily. The other meaning is, -- like any living process this has happened on its own. You have received it on your own."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1016 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (6th Day), Hamāre Jīvana kā Lakṣhya (The Aim of Our Lives), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0067.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>May this benevolent face of Yours, adorned with three eyes, protect us from all terror.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>O Kātyāyanī, we bow to You.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Etathe vadanam saumyam</b><br />
May this benign countenance of yours,<br />
<b>Lochana-traya bhushitam</b><br />
Adorned with three eyes,<br /><br />
<b>Patu nah sarva bhuti-bhyah</b><br />
Protect us from all the fears<br />
<b>Kātyāyanī namostute</b><br />
Salutations be to You, O Kātyāyanī</font><br />
<b>Sarva Mangala</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today it's such a great day for Me to be with you all, again this year. It's so very joyous and full of fragrance. <b>Today we have decided to have a Pūjā of Śhakti that is the Power, that is the Devī. You know within us there are many Powers of Mahākālī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahālakṣhmī, Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
All these Powers are there for us to ascent.</b> If these Powers are properly used and understood, then your ascent can be permanent. Once you achieve your ascent and enter into the Kingdom of God, all these Powers get enlightened.<br />
<b>And these Powers which are enlightened are absolutely filled with Love. Enlightenment, we have to understand that we get completely enlightened by Love. So after enlightenment, after Realization we use only one Power which is of Love.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Samara Oblast, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So all your powers that are there are enlightened by the All-pervading Power.</b> It transforms you and It has such a beautiful, delicate way of handling everything.<br />
The only thing that is needed is faith in this Power and to have love for others, and this enlightened love is going to give you whatever you want.<br />
And there is such a Power, All-pervading Power! There is no doubt about it! And we have to just accept it with our open heart that It fills it and makes us a great personality.<br />
So <b>there's no competition, there's no ambition, there's no jealousy, nothing of the kind.<br />
The only desire then left is that, 'I am enjoying Myself, let others also enjoy.'</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Samara Oblast, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0068.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>To all devotees and followers of truth, who have assembled here for the Pūjā, I offer My protection.</b><br />
In this Kali Yug of today, when so much devotion and homage for the Mother, and so much love comes into the hearts of human beings, then we can know that Satya Yuga has begun.<br />
This is a most fortunate and divine coincidence for Me also, that on a Ṣhaṣhṭhī Day I came to Kolkata [arrival on 196-1009]. Because, in the Śhāstras it is written that the coming of the Mother is always on Ṣhaṣhṭhī Day. <b>Ṣhaṣhṭhī Day is of Śhākambharī Devī</b>, and on that day the whole nature should be green and lush."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1010 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (7th Day), Lions Club Safari Park, Southern Avenue, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>AMBE TU PĀRVATĪ PARAMEŚHWARĪ</b><br />
<b>MAHALAKSHMI TU SAPTAŚHṚIṄGĪ TU JAY JAY ŚHĀKAMBHARĪ</b><br />
You are Mahālakṣhmī, You are Saptaśhṛiṅgī, Victory to Śhākambharī (The Bearer of the Greens)<br />
<b>JAY JOGEŚHWARĪ JAY MAHEHŚWARĪ JAY JAY PRAṆEŚHWARĪ</b><br />
Victory to Jogeśhwarī (Goddess of Yoga), Victory to Maheśhwarī (Goddess of Shri Shiva), Victory to Praṇeśhwarī (Goddess of vital breath)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"This work -- this Chaitanya -- that is flowing in the Universe -- is this Mahāmāyā's Śhakti -- and with this Mahāmāyā Śhakti only all the work is being done. This Śhakti -- thinks, knows, understands everything properly and organizes everything. And most important thing is that it loves you and this love is without interest (nirvāj). This love does not want anything from you, it only desires to give you, it desires your progress, it desires your well-being. But along with this, those things who want to be thorns, put obstacles in your way, put up fights or in any way trouble you, all those people should essentially be destroyed. But for this you don't put in your energy. <b>You should only invite this power, āvāhan [call] the Devī, and then you tell them to destroy these demonic people. This is a big thing and you have a relief that anyone who is trying to trouble you, abuse you, dominate you, you have a special state in you which is Nirvichār. Everything you should see in a Witness State.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1016 Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi) (6th Day), Hamāre Jīvana kā Lakṣhya (The Aim of Our Lives), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0069.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>[Śhrī Mātājī explains that Kattyayeni (Kātyāyanī) killed the demon Kolhāsur and this is why Kolhapur is called as such].</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0300 Conversation with K.T. Tan with a Handwritten Line, during a Meal, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Kātyāyanī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<b>O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Kātyāyanī, the one who is the foster daughter of Sage Katyayana!</b><br />
Salutations to You!<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Namostute (Mantra of Śhrī Kātyāyanī is taken): </b></font><br />
<a href="">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1020 Havan, Blessed Are Those Who Are Sahaja Yogis, the day after Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), Rūtli Kaltbad Mountain, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Lucerne, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/117133344"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgā Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durge Durgati Pariharini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/F68hoY8ZhOI">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Katyayani" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 5: “What is your destiny? Your destiny is to achieve the spiritual success”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/07" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 5: “What is your destiny? Your destiny is to achieve the spiritual success”" /><published>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_07_Navaratri_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/07"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Yesterday you saw, beautiful description of Navarātri and how the Mother Goddess has created all kinds of powers within you. It's not that only She has the powers, but you all have the powers, and you can all work it out, you can all find out whether these powers are there or not.<br />
With us, the Realization is very important, but there the Kuṇḍalinī has given you this Realization. Of course Kuṇḍalinī is a part or, we can say, reflection of Ādi Śhakti, and also <b>the Jagadambā is also part of Ādi Śhakti</b>.<br />
She's placed in the center of two hearts, which is a very important point. Now all these powers are placed in that chakra. So you imagine how many of these powers must be there, and Her Powers are expressed through the center Heart in all the gaṇas you have around your body. Now these gaṇas are the ones who do give you the protection, give you the sleep, give you the energy, give you the blessings. All of them are at work all the time, and these bodies are extremely dedicated and connected all the time to the <b>Mother Ambā, we can call Jagadambā. Now She is the Mother of the Universe, so you can imagine, how busy She has to be to look after the whole Universe!</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1009 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), Innocence (Fearlessness) and Enlightened Faith, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0062.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"She gives us the protection. She's the Protector.<br /> 
And She's the Mother of this world, Jagadambā."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now, when we are celebrating the greatest of greatest this Navarātri, there must be something special about it, that we have to cleanse this heart completely,</b> fully and make it so pure that it purifies all the blood that passes through the whole of the body. So the cells of this heart, which has made this great organ, has to be the best, because the cells of the heart within a human body are the best cells, the highest quality, the most sensitive. And it's the heart that expresses the Anāhata, the sound that is without percussion. While we find that there are some people of caliber, there are, but others talk more, show off more, and do not have the caliber."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), The Discipline, Hampstead Town Hall Centre, 213 Haverstock Hill, London NW3 4QP, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="green"><b>Kindle My Heart</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0063.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"If there is the Father and the Son there has to be a Mother. Because of that, the whole time the motherhood has not been respected. <b>But Mother is the power behind every creation.</b><br />
Now, this Kuṇḍalinī is the reflection of Athena, of Ādi Śhakti, of the Holy Ghost. She is your individual, your own mother and She is the one who is anxious to give you your Second Birth. She has been with you for so many years, for so many past years and She knows everything about you and also She loves you, loves very much and She cares for your benevolence.<br />
So like this instrument has to be connected to the mains, you are also to be connected to the mains. As ... as this instrument has no meaning without this connection, we have no meaning without our connection to the Divine Power. <b>So it is a myth if you go on taking the name of God and calling Him and nothing works out because you are not connected.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0428 Public Program advertised as 'The Goddess Athena Proved to Be Reality', Theatro Akropol, Ippokratous 9, Athens, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Mahāsaraswatī created the entire universe</b>. The earth element is special in this. The earth element has been placed in such a way between the Sun and the Moon that any living work can easily happen on it. From this living work, slowly and gradually human beings have been generated.<br />
But we should know our own great power. <b>That power is what we call creation power, it's also called creativity.</b><br />
This creation power is the blessing of Saraswatī by which many arts have been generated. The evolution of art is due to the blessings of Saraswatī. [{\bf Variant:} This power is the blessing of Śhrī Saraswatī due to which all the various art forms originated. The outback of art is due to the blessings of Śhrī Saraswatī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0403 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Emerlin College, Yamunānagar, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;"> 
<font color="Indigo"><b>RACHA PRABHU TUNEY YAHA BRAHMANDA SARA<br />
Oh God You have created the whole universe<br />
PRANON SEY PYARA, BRAHMANDA SARA<br />
The whole universe is dearer than our lives<br />
TUHI MAI BANDHU, TUHI JAGAT JANANI<br />
You are my Mother and brother, You are the Mother of the universe<br />
SAKAL JAGAT MEIN YAH TERA PASARA<br />
The whole universe is but your form</b></font><br /> 
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now the Durgā's qualities are that She is protective of Her children, She's very gentle, very soft with Her children, and She's extremely horrifying to the satanic people, to the negative people. So in this rāga I think because there are, the notes are spaced out. So either you could play it slow or you could play it fast. Nothing in between. That's why it is on a Durgā's style. You see, either <b>She is extremely gentle or She is extremely horrifying. So because She has a double function: is one to look after Her children, and another is protect Her children from the devils</b>. So She has to be very quick about it, to fight them, and to, in every <b>way to frighten</b> them and to be alert about it.
So in the second part you all became very <b>alerted I saw</b>. In the first part you were having a lullaby because it was the Mother's Love that was playing. The second part you became alert, because She has to fight. Now, this is such a nice rāga because it gives you a better sense of security within yourself, <b>builds up sense of security</b>, and also as you know medically that it's important to build up this chakra because that gives you <b>antibodies created</b>. So to fight all the diseases, to fight all the foreign things which try to attack us.
So this rāga is so apt, absolutely apt for today's atmosphere and for today's <b>need</b>. That we have to have the security of the Mother and the protection of the Mother and that all the evil forces must be finished from this world, and that's how this rāga has a very great significance ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0819 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, Essex, UK]</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0064.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Saraswatī is known as Skandamātā, She was not His mother and was virgin. But, but She took Skanda [Kārttikeya] as Her Son and held Him to Her heart."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1221 Śhrī Kārttikeya Pūjā (Marathi + English), Śhrī Gyāneśhwara, Park (200 m from ISYRH Center), C.B.D. Belapur, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Kāla-rātrīm Brahma-stutām Vaishnavīm Skanda-mātaram<br />
Saraswatīm Aditim Daksha-duhitaram namāmah pāvanām shivām</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Salutations to the Goddess, Who is the darkest night, 
Who is praised even by Brahmadeva himself, 
Who is the Power of Śhrī Vishnu, The Mother of Śhrī Kartikeya, 
Who is Saraswati, Śhrī Aditi (Mother of the Gods), 
the Daughter of Daksha, and the Consort of Śhrī Śhiva.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo">Aum twameva sākshāt Shrī Skanda-mātā sākshāt<br />
Shrī Ādi Shakti Mātājī Shrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namah<br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily The mother of Shri Kartikeya<br />
Salutations to You!</font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mazhya Manichi Ga, Mazhya Manichi Manas. Puja,</b><br />
With all their devotion and love they worship You,<br />
<b>Preme Arpili Asht.bhuja</b><br />
Out of love, they make this offering to the eight-handed Goddess:<br />
<b>Khana Nar.lachi Ga, Khana Nar.lachi Oti Tula,</b><br />
They offer coconut and an embroidered silk cloth as 'Oti' (asking for blessings)<br />
<b>Bhakt. Yetil. Dar.shanas</b><br />
Devotees all come to receive Your Darshan</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Māhūra Gaḍāvarī</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/EWoUoau4BOw">video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You are Sahaja Yogis.<br />
What is your destiny? Your destiny is to achieve the spiritual success [spiritual ascent].<br />
The Devī destroyed Chaṇḍā and Muṇḍa, that is why She is called Chāmuṇḍā. They are all back in this Kali Yuga, all of them.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>[Prayer to the Devī: 'O Devī, please give us the spiritual personality, the victory, the spiritual ascent and destroy our enemies'.]</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Your Destiny Is to Achieve the Spiritual Success and Have I Fulfilled My Destiny, Navarātri Celebrations (5th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0065.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>Anadi nirguni pragatali Bhavani</b><br />
The Goddess without beginning or form has incarnated,<br />
<b>Moha Mahishasura mardan laguni,<br />
Trividh tapanzi karavaya zhadani<br />
Bhakta laguni pavsi nirvani</b><br />
She is the One who has killed the evil Mahishasura, created by sins, so to finish them all<br />
And for sake of Her devotees, and to give salvation to this world, She has incarnated</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>On this day, the fifth night of Navarātri, we also sing Jogawa.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Jogawa</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1009 Navarātri Pūjā (5th Day), Innocence (Fearlessness) and Enlightened Faith, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25800440"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Aye re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Argala Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/rkHsdWAiL4Y">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jagadambetza Jogwa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Hey Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Skandamata" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 4 “the aim of the Incarnation is to save, to protect the people who are seekers, because they are the most important people in the realm of spirituality”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/06" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 4 “the aim of the Incarnation is to save, to protect the people who are seekers, because they are the most important people in the realm of spirituality”" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_06_Navaratri_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/06"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we have gathered here to do the Navarātri Pūjā.</b><br />
There were nine times when the Major Incarnations of the Mother of this Universe were manisfested [manifested]. They were manifested with a purpose. That purpose is to protect Her bhaktas, Her disciples, Her children.<br />
This was a binding love. She could not escape it. Mother's Love is binding. She cannot escape it. And She has to manifest it, work it out, and give that protection to all Her children."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0058.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>In Sahaja Yoga, Navarātri is the most important Pūjā, I would say.</b> Though we can say in modern Sahaja Yoga Sahasrār Day is, because that's how you started getting your Realization.<br />
But if you go to the whole historical events of evolution you'll find [that] Navarātri is the one which has brought you to Sahasrāra. Without the help of the Devī at different stages of your ascent, you could not have been in a position to receive your Realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Tu Hi Durgā, Tu Hi Kālī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are Durga, You are Kālī</b></font><br />            
<font color="Indigo"><b>Tu Hi Chaṇḍī Bhavānī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are Chaṇḍī Bhavānī</b></font><br />             
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mā Nirmalā kī Jay Bolo, Jay Bolo!</b></font><br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>Let us say Nirmalā Mā kī Jay!</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Dush.Man. Chal.Ko Chal.Ne Wali</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are destroying the plans of our foes</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Bhakto kī Kalnyani</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are taking care of the benevolence of Your devotees</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Mā Nirmalā kī Jay Bolo, Jay Bolo!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Let us say Nirmalā Mā kī Jay!</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>You see God’s creation.</b> He has created you and He’s not the one who is going to destroy His own creation. You don’t do anything. You just don’t do anything.<br />
You see, this is the wrong impression human beings have got. What they do is a dead work. Now see, the flowers are dead so you have arranged them. The tree is dead so you have made the furniture, that is all.<br />
Dead to the dead. Any living work can you do? Any living work? Nothing. Only after Realization, you can do it, by awakening the Kuṇḍalinī. Then you can do it. Then you are entitled to become the master."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0306 Interview with a Lady for a Radio Station, Hong Kong, China</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So we have made it short now, just take a bandhan, it is he same thing as kavacha you see. Realized Souls, if they take bandhan is the same thing. Whatever you have said here is done, yesterdays and todays, everything that has been said, all these rakṣhākari [act of protection] is done in one stroke.<br />
But now we should know how many of us take bandhan before going from the house, before sleeping or before doing something important. How many people take bandhan. Very seldom you forget it. Very important, going on a journey, going on a road, better take a bandhan, not that we are all right, Mother is looking after us, is not the point. You must take bandhan before doing all these things.<br />
If you get an accident, then know that you have done some mistakes, or something otherwise, normally there should be not an accident, means there is something still lacking in you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1014 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (4th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Mātājī explaining bandhan</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DkW7L9veu6M&amp;ab_channel=alibaba"> video</a><br />
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0059.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"She gives us the protection. She's the Protector.<br /> 
And She's the Mother of this world, Jagadambā."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The Devī has many forms, but is the Embodiment of the Śhakti. Ādi Śhakti gives Śhakti to all these Embodiments.<br />
And so, there are many Goddesses we have. At different times, They came on this Earth, and did all that was necessary for the ascent of people who were seekers.<br />
Specially, the One we know of <b>Jagadambā, the Durgā, She was trying to protect all the Seekers of Truth and to destroy all evil forces</b>.<br />
Because without the ascent of human beings, they do not know the Truth. And that's why, whatever they try to do is a mental projection.<br />
And this mental projection, if it is not sumsti ... substantiated by Truth, by dharma, it declines. In Sanskrit they call it glāni.<br />
<b>When this glāni takes place, then Incarnations are born to solve the problem.</b><br />
In all Incarnation of the Goddess, there have been very much incarnated, the satanic forces, they had incarnated, and She had to fight them ... with them, and destroy them. But this destruction was not for the destruction's sake that, `The evil forces are to be destroyed,' but evil forces always try to put down the seekers, put down the Saints, try to hard ... harm them, sometimes even destroy [them].<br />
All these destructive forces do not come at the same time, normally. At different times: is easy to handle.<br />
But <b>the aim of the Incarnation is to save, to protect the people who are seekers, because they are the most important people in the realm of spirituality.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0060.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>Visṛistau sṛisti-rūpā Tvam sthiti-rūpā cha pālane,<br />
Tathā saṁhṛiti-rūpānte jagato-'sya jagan-maye ǁ 5 ǁ</b></font><br />  
O You, whose Form is the Universe, at the time of creation You are the Creative Force,<br />
At the time of sustentation You are the Protective Power and at the time of the Dissolution of the World,<br />
You are the Destructive Power.
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I would say, with this, today's special celebration of Navarātri. Like yesterday you saw Śhrī Durgā's Nine Forms, also. In that, one is <b>Kuṣhmāṇḍā, is one of the forms, that you absorb all the filth in yourself, in your stomach.<br />
But the Devī does that, not you. What the Devī can do, you should not do, that's Her job</b>, that She is supposed to do this, not you.<br />
What you have to do is to only be in silence so that you absorb whatever will increase that silence, will increase your depth. The Devī will look after all the rest of the things, She'll look after all the filth, all the anger, all the temper, all the everything that's going on in this world. She will absorb all that, but what you have to do is to just enjoy everything that is pure.<br />
Enjoyment is only possible when you are beyond your mind. With your mind you can never enjoy, it is like a big load. It will not act, it will not help. Enjoyment comes when you are in complete silence, in a rippleless lake, the reflection of all the joy that is created on the shores of that lake are completely reflected, they are not deflected, if they were repulsed it would have been a different image altogether, and would have been something nowhere near the image of reality."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0061.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So to recognize Me, what should we do? If we recognize, then you are protected.</b><br />
...... if you could recognize Me, to understand Me, that I am Divine Personality. It's an Incarnation. That's all the Deities want. Then they'll look after you in every way. They'll give you all the powers. They'll give you all the satisfaction, all the protection that you want."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkSlateBlue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt<br />
Śhrī Kuṣhmāṇḍā sākshāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Kuṣhmāṇḍā, the one whose void contains the universe!<br />
Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font> 
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<a href="https://vimeo.com/video/597702902"> video</a><br />

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ankhe band karu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>The Kavach of the Devi (read in English)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ZRWM3jB01JU">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Kushmanda" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 3: “She protects your life, She protects your body, She protects all organs of your body, She is the One who gives you all the security of life.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 3: “She protects your life, She protects your body, She protects all organs of your body, She is the One who gives you all the security of life.”" /><published>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_05_Navaratri_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you are worshiping today the Durgā, or all the Nine Forms of the Goddess.</b> She came nine times on this Earth, according to this, that She fought all the people who were destroying the seekers, who were trying to make a mess of their lives. And these tortured Saints, when they prayed to the Goddess -- because none of the Gods could do anything, and Sadāśhiva is never interfering with what the Goddess is doing -- so they worshiped the Bhagavatī, and then the Incarnation of Hers came nine times, according to the need of the time.<br />
So every time you find Her confronting people who are extremely arrogant, self-opinionated, thinking no end of themselves. And the bhaktas are tortured by these self-opinionated horrible rākṣhasas."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0054.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Mahālakṣhmī. 

She has Three Powers. She is one is at Mahākālī, with which She is the one who exists, and when She gets angry, She can kill also. That's the point. That's Mahākālī. And from Her two other powers came out. Was Mahāsaraswatī, who is the creative power. And the third one is the evolutionary power, is Mahālakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Room, Home of a Sahaja Yogi, Staten Island, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mahāmāyā Mahākālī, Jay Śherawālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now we must understand the Mahākālī is in totality is the reflection of Ādi Śhakti, in totality. Or we can call it that Ādi Śhakti is in charge, She's managing all these Three Powers, but Her manifestation in totality is Mahākālī, in the sense that it is the Desire of God Almighty.<br />
So first She's Ādi Śhakti in charge of all the Three Powers, and that's why we can say that, when She is in a potential stage, She is Mahākālī.<br />
And then She divides Herself into two other forces: as Mahāsaraswatī and the ascending force that we call, or as a parasympathetic nervous system expressed in us is the Mahālakṣhmī Principle.<br />
So She has actually all these forces in Herself. But Kālī has all these forces but She manifests, She desires to act, and when She wants to act Her potential force becomes these two other forces."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0619 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Desire and Our Goal Is to Ascend, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0055.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font></font> <font color="DarkRed">I say that before going out please take a bandhan. It’s a kavach, we call it a kavach. Means, kavach, in English there’s a word for that?</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogis [suggest]:</b> Protection.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font></font> <font color="DarkRed">That’s rather, protection is abstract, but this is a protection of the Mother is a concrete stuff, you see, kavach. So you take the kavach. Kavach is something you can say that people wear those armor, inside, you see that sort of a thing, is kavach. So you must take that before going out or talking to somebody. That you don’t do.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0704 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Viṣhṇumāyā's Powers, Āśhram, Everbeek, Belgium</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Drushyanté rathmãrudhã devyah krodh-samãkulãh.<br />
Shankham chakram gadãm shaktim halam cha muslãyudham. Khétakam tomaram chaiv parshum-pãsha-méva cha.<br /> 
Kuntãyudham trishulam cha shãrangam-ãyudham-uttamam. Daityãnãm deha-nãshãya bhaktã-nama-bhayaya cha.<br />
Dhãryantãya-yudhaneet-tham devãnãm cha hitãya vai.<br />
<b>All these Goddesses are seen mounted in chariots and are on warpaths.<br />
They are wielding conch, discus, mace, plow, club, javelin, axe, noose, barbed dart, trident bows and arrows.<br /> 
These Goddesses are wielding their weapons, for destroying the bodies of demons, for the protection of their devotees, and for the benevolence of Gods.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Kavacha of the Devī)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/5rxFdl2DsN0">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So when we do the Pūjā of Mahākālī, we must understand that inbuilt within this force within us is desire.</b><br />
So we can desire anything! If you want you can desire everything: you can desire, say, the joy, we can desire the knowledge, we can desire to be compassionate and love, and we can desire also the destruction of those which are negative forces.<br />
But the Mahākālī Force is the one which is working out the constructive force. But in that constructive force only there has to be destruction. Because if you are constructing something and there is destruction which is trying to destroy your construction, then you have to destroy that destructive person.<br />
And this is what <b>people sometimes misunderstand and they think that Mahākālī Force is negative force or is a force of destruction. It is! But in a very positive way. And if you understand this part of Mahākālī Force then you will understand that if you have desires to construct yourself properly in Sahaja Yoga, then you should also have the desire to destroy whatever is standing against your construction</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0619 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Desire and Our Goal Is to Ascend, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0056.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"For your ascent it is important first of all to have no desires to create desire in your kith and kin. <b>This is the first Principle of Establishment of Mahākālī Power.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1219 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), The Whole Universe Should Be Enlightened with Your Desires (We Have to Establish Our Desire within Ourselves that We Are Seekers and that We Have to Achieve Our Full Growth and Maturity), Lonavala (67 kms NNW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Hinasti daitya tejamsi swanena pooryaya jagat,<br />
Saa ghanta patu no devi papebhyo nah sutaniva.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Devī, may Your bell which fills the world with its sound and destroys the power of asuras, protect us from sins, just as a mother protects her children</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Devī Māhātmyam, Chapter 11)</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"First and foremost thing She does is to protect us. Wherever you may be, whatever you may be doing, in whatever peril you may be, howsoever dangerously you may be placed in life, She protects you. First thing, She protects you.<br />
......<br />
So, when you worship Her, what do you want? You want Her to protect you. In your discrimination, in your mistake, you might do something wrong. May do something that is not good for you, could be very dangerous for you. But She is the person who guides how to avoid all the dangers. Now, She protects your life, She protects your body, She protects all organs of your body, She is the One who gives you all the security of life. 

In Her Realm, you feel completely secure. You are never afraid of anything. Because you have left Her Realm, you have come out of it, that is why -- that is the reason you are afraid. But if you are under Her beautiful guidance and Her blessings, you will never feel afraid to do anything. You will never do anything wrong also. As soon as you'll try to do wrong, She will hold your hand. She is really the guiding person.<br />
<b>She is the One who actually gives us our existence. Without Her, we cannot exist, because She is the One who is the Power of Śhrī Śhiva.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), The Powers of Śhrī Mahākālī, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0057.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Kamala-dal’āmala komala kāntī<br />
Kalā kalit’āmala bhāla-late,<br />
Sakala vilāsa kalā nilaya-krama<br />
Keli chalat-kala haṁsa kule,<br />
Ali-kula sañkula kuvalaya mandala<br />
Mauli milad bakulāli kule, Jaya, jaya, he</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Like a tender, lovely spotless Lotus-petal the crescent Moon adorns Your forehead;<br />
Your movements are like a graceful and playful group of Swans;<br /> 
Like a swarm of bees to fragrant flowers, the stars adorn Your forehead.<br />
Victory to You!</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini:</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā sākshāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namaḥ</b></font><br />
<b>O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā, the one Who use the Moon as Her bell,
Salutations to You!</b><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Chandraghaṇṭā who rides a lion or tiger.  She has a half-moon shaped like a bell on Her forehead or uses the moon as Her bell.   
During the battle between Her and the demons, the horrible sound produced by Her bell sent thousands of demons to Hell.)</font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (8th Day), The Powers of Śhrī Mahākālī, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/81553860"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tere Charana De Hainth</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Chandraghanta" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 2: “these vibrations establish Holiness, auspiciousness through Mahākālī; then these same vibrations also comfort us through Mahākālī Power”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/04" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 2: “these vibrations establish Holiness, auspiciousness through Mahākālī; then these same vibrations also comfort us through Mahākālī Power”" /><published>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_04_Navaratri_Day_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/04"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>"The Devī incarnated on this Earth to kill the demonic personalities who try to destroy all the good qualities of women.<br />
We also have those demonic personalities within us and they are to be destroyed -- not physically, but mentally.</b><br />
How you accept them and how you deal with whatever they try is very surprising.<br />
You must understand that the goodness of a person is very important. If you are trying to be nasty or dominating then you'll be definitely destroyed. That's why this Devī has come on the Earth. That is the assurance of this Devī, the Goddess."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1004 Pūjā (9th Day of Navarātri), House, 268 Overpack Avenue, Ridgefield Park, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0050.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"And that is why, <b>today is the day when the Virgin, Gaurī, sat down to worship Śhiva. She made a Śhiva Lingua and was sitting and putting Her sindūr on that: "That you look after this, which is the mark of my Union with you. I leave it to you, to look after" -- to Śhiva. "You look after me. I surrender to you."</b> With this, <b>that's how Gaurī your Kuṇḍalinī surrenders to the Spirit: 'Now You look after this connection.</b> I forget everything else. I leave it into Your hands. Lift Me up. You raise Me up. I forget all that was Me before. Everything I have dropped out. No other desire. But just lift Me higher and higher. Make Me Yourself. The rest of it is not important. All other manifestations of this, desires are over. Now, I am absolutely surrendered to You, My Spirit. Lift Me higher and higher. Higher and higher, away from all the things that were not the Spirit. Make Me complete Spirit, full Spirit.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Salutations to You O Devī Nārāyanī, 
who took the form of Brahmanī (the Śhakti of Brahmadeva) 
and sprinkled water with kuśha grass while riding in the heavenly car (aeroplane Vimāna) of the swan</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Mahālakṣhmī Hymn, Chapter 11 of Devī Māhātmyam)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now first of all you get your Realization, all right. Now you must know that Kuṇḍalinī Itself is the Mahākālī Śhakti because She's the Primordial. <b>Mahākālī Śhakti is the Primordial Śhakti within us. And is the Kuṇḍalinī is the Mahākālī Śhakti. And She remains as a virgin within you. Means She's purity: She has a power to purify. All that happens when you get your Realization. She starts manifesting Her all beautiful aspects on you.</b>
Now the one who is sitting there is Śhrī Gaṇeśh. Now people don't understand what is innocence is. Śhrī Gaṇeśha is sitting there and He is the One who presides [pronounced as prĭsīds] all Mūlādhāra, even over His Mother, because He's like a guard."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0912 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Qualities of Mahākālī and You Have to be Collective (Purity Means Chastity and For the Saints the Main Thing Is Their Ascent), Centre Culturel Thierry Le Luron, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0051.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"But Goddess Herself has done so many things for us already, within us, though we are not aware of it. Is said that, <b>"Yā Devī sarvabhūteśhu"</b>: "All those whom You have created," means mostly the human beings, "What do You do? As what do You exist inside the human beings?"<br />
Now, just introspect if you have these qualities within you or not, because they are given to you by the Goddess, by the Śhakti within you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-1005 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), Your Beautiful Qualities Will Prove the Truth of Sahaja Yoga, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><font color="green"><b>Yā Devī sarvabhūteśhu (2000-1008 Navarātri Pūjā, Cabella)</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So sincerity, though it is the quality of the left side, can be dominated by the right side, this way.<br />
The second thing about your desire, that it should be a pure desire. And the pure desire is very simple for you because I'm sitting before you. <b>The pure desire of a seeker is to see God, to be in the company of God, to be uh in association with God. As they call it Sālokya, Sāmīpya and Sanīḍya [Sanīḍa]: there are three words describing this.</b><br />
Va [but] without asking, without thinking of it, you have been given the fourth dimension called as the Tādātmya [sameness of nature]: means becoming one with My body, My being. So, that you become protected, absolutely cleansed and nourished in My being. But when you are not aware of it, then what happens: that I have to suffer in My body to cleanse you. So all other desires can create problems within you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0518 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, French Seminar, Dourdan (47 kms SW of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0052.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
When I am alone with my God (in meditation)<br />
<font color="indigo">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<font color="indigo">MALA PĀHĪ PRABHUSANGE, DUI ATMA TAI PALE DURĪ</font><br />
<b>When I am in the company of God, evil runs away</b><br />
<font color="indigo">GALE SAMARTHYA MOHACHE NURE RUNT KUTHE VAIRĪ</font><br />
No temptation can dominate me and nobody can confront me<br />
<font color="indigo">MALA BODHĀMRUT PĀJĪ, SADA JAEI NAVI TRUPTĪ</font><br />
Every time I experience the Divine knowledge, I feel more satisfaction and Divine Joy<br />
<font color="indigo">KUTHE CHINTA KUTHE DUKHHE KSHANE SĀRI LAVA JĀTĪ</font><br />
All moments of concerns and sorrows vanish<br />
<font color="indigo">PRABHUSANGE MILE JĪVA, NASE KOTHE TASHI SHANTĪ</font><br />
Nowhere else can my soul find peace except in the company (in union) with God Almighty<br />
<font color="indigo">PRABHU MAZA SWAYE NĪTĪ, PRABHU MAZA SWAYE PRITĪ</font><br />
My God himself is Truth and Love<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Mahākālī is the left side power in us. So, actually She is Ādi Śhakti. Only <b>when She enters into the left side of the Virāṭa we call Her Mahākālī, but She is the Power of Pure Desire of God. Then She establishes Śhrī Gaṇeśha Herself</b>. Then She goes to the right side as Mahāsaraswatī, and then She enters into the center [navel] where She is Mahālakṣhmī. That is how Ādi Śhakti takes three forms. But Mahākālī is the pure form, because She's not yet deep in [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] I mean from Ādi Śhakti, She's Mahākālī. So first thing She, before creating this universe or anything, She created Śhrī Gaṇeśha. And first to spread, manifest not only holiness but also auspiciousness, and purity. So before anything was created, these spiritual forces were created, to protect the creation that was to follow. So this Mahākālī force was specially in the purest form to protect people from the negative side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1014 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Salvador, Bahia, Brazil</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The first destroying factor that is within us is the Śhrī Gaṇeśha's Power and this Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the Power of Mahākālī.</b><br />
She first planted Śhrī Gaṇeśha to emit holiness on this Earth, so the whole thing could be vibrated and as you know one aspect of Śhrī Gaṇeśha is also Oṃkāra, means this vibratory awareness which flows everywhere.<br />
So these vibrations have four sites in it: one is that <b>these vibrations establish holiness, auspiciousness through Mahākālī; then these same vibrations also comfort us through Mahākālī Power</b>. Vibrations do not give you desires as such, if you see, they do not give you desires, but they give you proof of your desires in fulfillment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0619 Śhrī Mahākālī Pūjā, Desire and Our Goal Is to Ascend, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0053.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"You cannot make anyone brahmachārī or brahmachāriṇī. It is a state, avasthā, where a person has to rise, like Yogeśhwara, like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
......<br />
It is a state of mind where you are not involved. It is a different thing, that you just load somebody with an idea that You should become, absolutely a brahmachārī or a brahmachāriṇī or you should lead a celibate life, forcing them.<br />
......<br />
<b>Celibacy must come from within, the purity must come from within.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0203 Public Program (English + Hindi + English), Day 5, The Āgñyā Chakra, N.D.M.C. Park, Hanumān Road, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MidNightBlue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Brahmachāriṇī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devyai namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Brahmachāriṇī, the One who observes the State of Celibacy!<br />
Salutations to You!
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0">1982-1017 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Innocence and Virginity (Your Śhakti Is Your Kuṇḍalinī and She Is Virginity or A New Page Has Been Turn), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/76011764"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Kinaryala Lau</b> (Australian Songbook, Marathi 62)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī Vandu Tav Charaṇa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/4__6MBE5AZc">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Lalitā Sahasranām</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/PKNAgirTBr4">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Brahmacharini" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 1</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/03" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Navarātri Celebrations, Day 1" /><published>2024-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/2024_10_03_Navaratri_Day_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/10/03"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In the first Advent of the Holy Ghost came on this Earth this day. That was about fourteen thousands years back. And today is the day that is celebrated as the first Advent. And there are Nine Advents She has had before She came as the Mahālakṣhmī. She first, today I will be telling you about it -- how She is placed within us, where She resides, what is Her work, how She protects us. I'll be today telling you on the Heart chakra. And that's why today they celebrate this special day of Her worship."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), Room, Home of a Sahaja Yogi, Staten Island, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0046.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>Stuta Sūraih Purvam bhishts Samshrayattatha<br />
Surendrena Dineshu Sevita<br />
Kaotu Sa Nah Shubha Hetur Ishwari<br />
Shubhani Bhadranya Bhihantu Cha Padah</b></font><br />
<b>Invoked of yore by the Devas for the sake of their desired object,<br />
and adored by the lord of the Devas every day,<br />
may She, the Ishwari, the source of all good, accomplish for us all auspicious things and put an end to our calamities!</b><br />
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0047.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo"><b>Namo Devyai Mahādevyai</b></font><br />
The Gods said: Salutations to the Devi, to the Great Goddess.<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Śhivāyai satataṃ namaḥ</b></font><br />
Salutations always to Her who is ever auspicious<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Namaḥ prakṛutyai bhadrāyai</b></font><br />
Salutations to Her who is primordial cause and the sustaining power.<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Niyyatāḥ praṇatāḥ sma tām</b><br />
With complete reverence and full attention, we make obeisance to Her.</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nav Durga ki</b></font><br />
(Devī Suktam)<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So, it was-s ... such a worshipful country, where people worshipped the Gods with their heart and with their devotion, that there were Incarnations of the God many times on this Earth. And They uh did that part, of that aspect, tried to protect the people who were in danger, specially the Mother. Mother came many a times out of which we celebrate nine special times when She came and killed very horrible devils on this Earth.<br />
<b>Now the same Mother, according to Sahaja Yoga, has got three types of action.</b> She is a Mahālakṣhmī because She is in the center, by which She ascents. And <b>She is the desire of God as Ādi Śhakti, the Primordial Being ... the Primordial Mother, who becomes first the desire. So She is the Mahākālī.</b> And then She becomes the creative force or the creative energy, so She is the Mahāsaraswatī. So first we have the Mahākālī, who becomes Mahāsaraswatī, and then ultimately the Mahālakṣhmī. So the first the desire, then the action, and then thirdly the as... ascent, or you can say the uh sustainance [sustenance].<br />
First, you were sustained as human beings. Now you have become as human beings, now you have to ascent higher, into that superhuman state where you start feeling the Divine, the Power of the Divine, and also the Divinity within yourself. Then gradually as you grow up, you settle down into the kingdom of God by which you are completely blessed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1015 Navarātri Pūjā (10th Day), Āśhram, Boston, MA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0048.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Gaṇas are the workers on the left-hand side. They are like, we can say Saint Michael is their leader, but their king is Gaṇapati, Gaṇeśha.<br />
<b>So first She has done is the ghaṭasthāpanā.</b><br /> 
Ghaṭasthāpanā means -- you have done here now, this is the ghaṭasthāpanā. This is the Kumbha.<br />
Now this Kumbha She has established first: that is the triangular bone. Now this is Her first work, that to establish this, your Mūlādhāra. So She established within you is innocence. She established innocence within you to begin with. So She has put this ghaṭa in which She is staying as Kuṇḍalinī now. So the first is that to establish the Kuṇḍalinī in the triangular bone, and then to establish Śhrī Gaṇeśha. This is the first work, by which whatever She is going to create now -- all the universes, the Earth, everything -- whatever She is going to create has to be filled with innocence. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Similarly with God Almighty. <b>When He desired to create this nature, He collected a desire, we may say a wave or vibration, and filled within a container or Ghaṭ. It is that Ghaṭ. And this Ghaṭ means the God Almighty.</b><br />
If we can separate God Almighty and His power of desire for our understanding, then it will be easy to understand.<br />
You, people, are similar but with a slight difference. You and your desire powers are different. First, the power of your desire is born. Until you have a desire for anything, nothing is executed.<br />
This means [that] this beautiful universe is created because of someone's desire. Everything is executed after a desire. To execute the desire of God Almighty it has to be separated from Him. We will call it Ādi Śhakti.<br />
<b>When this first stage arrived this Ghaṭasthāpanā happened. This happened so many times in ancient times and even today when we have Ghaṭasthāpanā we memorize that aboriginal happening. So on the first day of Navarātri, we do Ghaṭasthāpanā, means, remember, what an important thing it is.</b><br />
Whatever God Almighty desired at that time collected and filled in a Ghaṭ before its execution. Today we are worshiping that desire, we worshiped it today. God Almighty had that desire and brought us up to human being-ness, up to this height stage he brought us, now it is your duty to bow in front of His desire.<br />
<b>In our Sahaja Yoga, this desire is called Śhrī Mahākālī's Desire or Mahākālī's Power.</b> This is Mahākālī's Power and these nine special days of Navarātri are about the incarnations of Śhrī Mahākālī."</font><br />
<font size="+0">1979-0922 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī and Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Navarātri Celebrations (1st Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India<b></b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0049.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we worship the Himalayas and the seven Goddesses whose blessings are here, and pray to them to bless us with Devī Śhakti. We have received the blessings of the Devī Śhakti from a Mother. That is why, in the form of Mother, let us come to the feet (śharaṇāgat) of the Himalayas.<br />
<b>Keep your attention on your Self.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed "><b>O Daughter of the King of the mountains!
The sages say that the world has its dissolutions and Genesis
With the closing and opening of Thine Eyes,
Thine Eyes are bereft of winking,
With a view to save from dissolution this entire universe,
Which has its origin in the opening of Thine Eyes.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Saundaryalaharī</b> by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), The Discipline, Hampstead Town Hall Centre, 213 Haverstock Hill, London NW3 4QP, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/185243549"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ghane Ghane Jangala mein</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jay Jagadambe </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇapati Vandan Gan nayak</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Shailaputri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>