<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-03T19:23:56-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Christmas: “His Message of Love and Forgiveness is the same even today. Preached by all, all the Saints, all the Incarnations, all the Prophets.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/12/25" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Christmas: “His Message of Love and Forgiveness is the same even today. Preached by all, all the Saints, all the Incarnations, all the Prophets.”" /><published>2023-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/12/2023_12_25_Christmas_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/12/25"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are celebrating the birth of Jesus Christ.</b><br />
The birth of Jesus Christ is very symbolic, because He was born in such a manner that even the poorest of poor won't be bornt [born] in the stable. And He was put in the bed which was made of dried grass.<br />
He came on this Earth to show people that for a person who is an Incarnation or who is a highly evolved soul, is not bothered about the comfort of the body. His Message was so great and so deep, but He had disciples who were not prepared for the battle they had to fight. Is the same thing that sometimes happens with Sahaja Yoga. He had only 12 disciples, we too have 12 types of Sahaja Yogis, and all of them, though [they] try to dedicate themselves to Christ, fell a trap, some of them, to the worldly aspirations or to their own hankerings.<br />
<b>His Message of Love and Forgiveness is the same even today. Preached by all, all the Saints, all the Incarnations, all the Prophets. They all have said about Love and Forgiveness.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1225 Christmas Pūjā, Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India]</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1305.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You have compassion for those who love You,<br />
and it is for those who love You that You come to this Earth.<br />
You are the force that creates, the energy that pervades, and the Spirit that protects.<br />
Those who seek union with God pray through You;<br />
those who seek union with God worship You.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">('To the Divine Essence of the Prayer')</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The reason for celebrating this auspicious day is the birth of the Christ. Very little is known about Jesus Christ because in young age he left his house and after returning he lived only up to the age of thirty year. But during this short period he did tremendous work.<br />
......<br />
<b>So He told two things, the first is to "forgive everyone." Knowingly or unknowingly if someone troubles you, you should forgive him.</b> You will not get tortured but if you do not forgive then you torture yourself because another person is sitting nicely. So you must develop the habit of forgiveness.<br />
<b>Second thing that He told us is that, "You are the Spirit." Know this Spirit, the Self. No one can touch the Spirit, can destroy it, no one can torture it.</b> If you are that Spirit then you should be established in it. But to achieve this Ātmā Tattwa the awakening of Kuṇḍalinī is necessary. First is to work out the awakening of the Kuṇḍalinī and then to get established in it. Until you are established, you will remain entangled in stupidities. So one should know how to be established within, to remain within thyself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1225 Christmas Pūjā (Hindi + English), Success in Sahaja Yoga Is What Will Last Forever and Everybody Will Remember It (Try to Learn Sahaj Culture), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1306.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Bāla vadana tava baghuni Khristā</b><br />
I see Lord Christ as an eternal child<br />
<b>Sakala durita bhaya bhāle astā</b><br />
When the world was drowning in sin<br />
<b>Tava divya rupa jaga lyāle</b><br />
The new Divine form took birth on this Earth<br />
<b>Mama zhāle, mana dhāle</b><br />
My mind exulted with joy<br />
<b>He sarva jagi sancharale</b><br />
This love had now spread throughout the world<br />
<font size="+0">(He Prem Murti)</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The aim of Jesus Christ was to open the center of your Āgñyā and to achieve that purpose He got Himself crucified and then He resurrected. It appears to be a miracle but for the Divinity there is no miracle as such. He proved that human beings could rise above the center of Āgñyā and on this center <b>He told two mantras which we call Bīj Mantras: Ham and Kṣham. Kṣham means to forgive. Kṣham is the biggest mantra. The ego of the person who knows how to forgive, gets destroyed</b>.<br />
One is proud of small-small things. For example, if you tell someone to sit on the earth, his ego gets hurt. If someone is told to sit in the chair, he will reply, 'This chair is very small, why have you given it to me?' Everyone has some expectation about him and if his expectations are not fulfilled, his ego immediately comes up. Unknowingly, sometimes such things could be done but the egoistical people take it as their insult.<br />
Such people make their condition very miserable. All the time they think they are being insulted and humiliated. He is always obsessed with this thought and he draws negative meaning of whatever is told to him.<br />
So we have to think of what Jesus Christ had thought. He said, "Forgive those who have trespassed against you."<br />
Now see the results if you forgive everyone. You will neither suffer nor get disturbed mentally. You will not think of the person whom you have forgiven. Nothing could go against you because you forgive everyone.<br /> 
We get this power from the center of Āgñyā. The person whose Āgñyā is clear forgives everyone. If we do not forgive we torture ourselves and play in the hands of others, who assume power over us. Forgiveness is the greatest message that Jesus Christ has given to mankind.<br />
<b>Second is Ham, it has altogether different meaning. Ham means 'To know thyself'. You have to know that you are the Spirit. You are not this body, mind, brain or ego. You are the Spirit. When you know this Ham then it will be clear to you that you are the Ātmā.</b> The Spirit means that all the ego, foolishness, ignorance that we have in our mind, are meaningless. All these negativities have absolutely no place in the pure Spirit. You are very pure."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1225 Christmas Pūjā (Hindi + English), Success in Sahaja Yoga Is What Will Last Forever and Everybody Will Remember It (Try to Learn Sahaj Culture), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1307.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Putra Vatsalā Kalyāni Mahāpātaka Nāshini</b></font><br />
<b>Most lovingly showers blessings on Her children,<br />
Destroys the greatest of sins</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Yoga Kshema Nivardini Nirānanda Pradāyini</b></font><br />
<b>Taking care of spiritual and material well-being, Bestowing eternal bliss</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mahārupā Mahāpujyā Ādimātā Nirmala Mā,Jaya He</b></font><br />
<b>Awesome form, worthy of great worship, Primordial Mother</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Jai He Jai He Jai He Devī)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It is said in Marathi that: "Forgiveness is the decoration of a vīra." Vīra is the brave. Only the brave could forgive.<br />
Now, how many of us really know how to forgive others [laughing:] and to love others?<br />
So many write that, "Mother, my heart is like a stone." So now you jump in the sea! What are you doing here? Stones must go to the sea. Or they say, "My heart is not open." I say, "Why do you write like this?" "Because I'm very, very frank and honest." With whom are you honest? For such people there is no Sahaj Yog. They should really leave Sahaja Yoga and go away.<br />
Sahaja Yoga is meant for people who have a very large heart where [laughing:] Christ could be adorned. He's to be restored upon that great heart of yours. In every way one has to enlarge the heart.<br />
That's why I think William Blake very clearly said that, "England should be the Jerusalem." But only by saying that, 'William Blake said so,' one should know that it's complete [darkness], complete [darkness]. He is hoping against hopes. Large heartedness is missing among the people who live on the heart.<br />
As you know about the French, they call themselves Christians. Italians, who have so-called Christianity, have the worst pictures; so licentious, so horrible, so much against Christ. It's very surprising. How we can do such things to bring bad name to Him and to the whole world where you represent Him?<br />
People think Christianity means licentiousness, permissiveness, drunkenness, abandonment of all the values, while Christ was just the opposite of.<br />
Absolutely, He did not need any values. He was guṇātīt. He is dharmātīt, everything. But how He lived on this Earth, such an ideal!<br />
So before us we have got a great ideal. We don't have to follow the ideals of these horrible kings who lived there. But we have to follow the ideal of Christ and those kings who followed the ideal of Christ. Because if you are following Him, the path that you are following has to be, the essence of Christ's life is a pure life of love and sacrifice. This is what one has to follow.<br />
Throughout His life, He has been using this essence just to establish Himself in our Āgñyā chakra and that's what He's worked very, very hard to do that. Let us not do anything to let Him down in our character."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1224 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Christmas Eve), before the Evening Program, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1308.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, they say 'Merry Christmas' is enjoyment for joy. Out of peace comes the joy, the light of joy, the happiness.</b><br />
I wish peace for the whole world, for the whole nation, to understand to give up all the strives, all the false battles, for money and for power, all wrong ideas that they are different from each other, and come under the banner of Sahaja Yoga and enter into the Kingdom of God, where they are invited with all respect and love.<br />
I wish peace to all of them, to all the countries, all the human beings: in their families, in their hearts, with their children, with all of them. Let there be peace, let their heart emit peace, their tongues speak with peace, their eyes see nothing but peace.<br />
All this has to change, tremendous change has to take place. ......<br />
<b>I bless all of you to be the channels of that peace, to be beautiful channels of that peace, to be glorious channels of that peace, to be great children of your Mother, who is so proud of you.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1225 Christmas Pūjā, You Have to Be Peaceful, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Jesus Mary Mātā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1225 Christmas Pūjā, Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/430281659"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Reciting Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jagi Tarak Janama Ala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namo Namo Moria</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zExNokrpbF0">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ek Gaṇapati</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/cpAg0HUPE9M">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1309.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="Red"><b>Wishing you all a Merry Christmas!!!</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Christmas Day" /><category term="orange @ Christmas Puja" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Jesus Christ" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti: May God bless you all! This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/27" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti: May God bless you all! This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery”" /><published>2023-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_27_Shri_Guru_Nanak_Birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/27"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is a special day of Guru Nāṇaka's birthday.</b><br />
Uh we have celebrated one Guru Pūjā uh-uh-uh ... and the, as you know that Guru Nāṇak was also the Incarnation of the Primordial Master, the same Spirit came on this Earth. And the He's the One who tried to re-establish the work of Muhammad.<br />
......<br />
All the religions were established on this Earth to create the seekers. You are the seekers: you are the Men of God. Now, all of you have to become Prophets. And to become Prophets, today's Sahaja Yoga has taken the form of Mahā Yoga. All of you have to become Prophets.<br />
The Prophets have two special qualities, as all the Prophets had: first of all, they have to talk about spiritual education. All of Them did that: Muhammad Sāhab did it, Rāja Janaka did it, Nāṇaka did it, Moses did it, Abraham did it. All of Them prophesized and taught you how to lead yourself in the right path, by the right action, by leading a right life."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1300.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"May God bless you all!<br />
This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery, which you all should become the Great Prophets who are going to change all the men of God into Prophets.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Teal"><b>Know that in every heart that beats<br />
The Lord of Life has His mansion.<br />
It is through the guru’s teaching<br />
We merge in the Formless One.<br />
By the gentle path of Sahaja<br />
Attain God, Purest of the Pure.<br />
A disciple who serves his guru and no other<br />
Will succeed, says Nanak, that is sure.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The bliss that I feel is beyond words</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the birthday of Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka. It is being celebrated throughout the world with so much of zeal that I have not seen in India.</b> For the first time it has been advertised in so many papers and by different means.<br />
Guru Nāṇaka always talked of Sahaja Yoga. "Everything else," He said, "is just showing off." About religion He said that, "Observing fasts, going on pilgrimage, etc., are just meant to show off. Now you have to discover the power that is within you and establish it." Guru Nāṇaka kept on repeating the same thing again and again.<br />
He never talked of rituals."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1123 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1301.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"See the brotherhood of all mankind as the highest order of yogis, conquer your own mind, and conquer the world."<br />
"In the calm of Sahaj’s cave, You can discover the True One, Sayeth Nanak, the True One loves the truthful."<br />"
--Guru Nanak</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"You have to educate yourself spiritually. 

And Guru Nāṇaka prophesized, just like William Blake, that, "The Men of God are going to come during Kali Yuga, and there will be many Prophets who will be transforming Prophets, who will be transforming people into Prophet State," He had prophesized.<br />
They have all prophesized about you! Now you have to prophesize about those who are going to be Prophets.<br />
......<br />
When Nāṇaka came in, He saw that Hindus and Muslims were fighting. So He started His theme with Kabīra, saying that, "Rām and Raḥīm are both the same, and how can you differentiate between the two?" <b>All their theme was like this, of integration of these two main religions which existed in India.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then came, you know Nāṇaka who preached that there should be no enmity between Hindus and Muslims, He preached that, because He saw the Muslims behaving in such a manner, they were such fanatics and they had become so funny that He could not understand, 'How is it? These are the people whom I have made Muslims and what are they doing here?'<br />
Actually <b>Mussulman means the person who is realized and Pīr is a person whose Realization is established</b> so much so that He [Prophet Muhammad] said that, 'Those who have become Mussulman should be buried and not burnt,' because He thought they are all realized Souls, but Realization finished off with His son-in-law and His daughter, after that He had two sons [grandchildren] who were great Souls who are really the Reincarnation[s] of Lav and Kuśh."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1302.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Ikoaŉkār saṯ nām karṯā purakẖ nirbẖao nirvair akāl mūraṯ ajūnī saibẖaŉ gur parsāḏ.</b></font><br />
There is One and only One God who is transcendent as well as immanent.<br />
True and Eternal Name. Creator and Person. Without Fear and without Enmity.<br /> 
Timeless Form, Unborn, Self-existent.<br />
Realized by Divine Grace.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka's Mool Mantra</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
<p><a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/19801123-guru-nanaks-birthday"> audio</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ (1993-0704 Guru Pūjā Cabella) </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nāṇak Mohammad</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiya Tere Charano Ki (2008-1113 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, Noida)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/iOXcrlduLNM">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavil by Nirmal Sangeet Sarita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/I1nxKFe8QOU?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guruon kī Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhaiyakayataya (When we belong to God what is to fear) by Nirmal Sangeet Sarita (1990-0310 Australia)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/47fMsue7fs8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Guru Nanaka Birthday" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Guru Dattatreya" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity”" /><published>2023-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_14_Diwali_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/14"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>it was a beautiful surprise. It's very joy-giving it.<br />
...... joy was dancing in your eyes. I could see the lights in your eyes. And this is the real Diwālī.</b><br />
Diwālī word comes from two words: dīpa and āwali. Dīpa means, you know, lights, and āwali means rows, rows and rows of lights. Seems it's a very, very ancient idea and all over in the world, you see, whenever they have to celebrate something then they put lights. And lights because light gives joy, gives happiness. So to overcome the darkness of ignorance also we have to enlighten ourselves. And that is why is important that everybody should get Self-realization to feel the light within themselves. And you must have noticed that after Realization the eyes also sparkle. There's light in the eyes of every Sahaja Yogi."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia (50 kms S of Venice), Veneto, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1295.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is a day we celebrate in India where relationship between brothers and sisters have to be established.</b> They're very pure. Brothers and relationsh... sisters relationship is without any lust or greed. Is pure relationship, where the sister prays for the protection of the brother and brother play ... pray ... prays for the self-sufficiency of the kṣhema, well-being, of the sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You are all, as I said, you are My light. And the light is there which is an eternal light. These lights will be finished. We'll have to light them every year. Not you people. You have eternal light and this light is going to spread Joy. What's the problem of this world? The whole problem, you take it. There's no joy. Simple as that -- there's no joy. If they had joy, they would not have done all these nonsensical things. There's no joy. When you have joy, you don't want to fight, you don't want to do anything that is harmful. You don't want to say anything after anyone, not only that but you do not want to have something that will spoil this Mother Earth or which will bring ecological problem. No, you just don't want it, don't want to do anything because it harms harms others. People feel unhappy about it whether it is here, India, anywhere. You just feel that `Why should I do such a thing which is not so congenial to others?' I mean, it's not joy-giving.<br />
<b>So when you have joy, you have to be joy-giving. And if you are not joy-giving, that means there's something lacking in your Sahaja Yoga and that's why we have to come up now. We have to become Sahaja Yoginīs and Sahaja Yogis. That is joy-giving society. We can change our name, if you like, if not Sahaja Yoga is good: `Joy-giving Association'.</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1296.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Rakṣhābandhan Day, they give a symbolic expression to their desire that their brother should be good. <b>But on this day they worship their brothers, actually worship them.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Bābā Māmā (on 1990-0310):</b> <b>This is what the brother has written for the sister: "O Nirmalā, my Sister, how much should I praise You? Because You have given the human being the experience of God."</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But for a gṛuhalakṣhmī, the brother is very important.<br />
<b>And the brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity.</b> If you understand that brotherhood and sisterhood is love which is very pure, there is no expectation, is just love: is giving love and taking love. And Absolute Purity within us should exist between our relationships when we call them as Sahaj Yogi brothers and sisters. And as there is understanding, complete understanding between the brother and sister, in a family, one has to know we are all part and parcel of a family, born out [of] the same Mother.<br />
Nobody has to shoot off, you know, nobody has to become something great, nobody has to correct others, nobody has to uh say that, `I'm something unique.' All of you have to work it out together and find out the solution working out together, in complete friendship and unison. Anyone who cuts off himself and goes out or becomes anything else, goes out of circulation and useless for Sahaj Yoga. Such a person is completely useless: the one who tries to get out of the family. All of you have to be supporting as each other, helping to each other, not shouting at each other, [not] getting angry with each other, trusting each other, not finding faults, treating each other with respect and love.<br />
This is the most important thing, which Sahaj Yogis don't understand, that you are Saints and you have to respect each other. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1297.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Bhogya Lakṣhmī. Bho-gya. Bhogya means: the One by which you enjoy, by which you enjoy.</b><br />
Now, I mean, it's like the whole ocean of joy is around you and you are like a bird who cannot drink it. Only through the Grace of Bhūmī Lakṣhmī ... Bhogya Lakṣhmī, you can enjoy that [ocean].<br />
So, the Spirit, though it is manifesting, you are not enjoying your Spirit. Even that. Anything that you see, say, see a flower, you should be able to enjoy. You cannot enjoy because there is thought. Anything you do there is thought: you cannot enjoy.<br />
<b>When there is no thought, when the Spirit is flowing, you get the complete enjoyment.<br />
Actually, I should say, I am the Enjoyer.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, the last day is very important: is a very universal day, I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj. is the ... or they call it also in Marathi Bhāūbīj, the ... different names. Is the: brothers' and sisters' day.<br />
Now, the brothers' and sisters' relationship has to be very, very strong. And the purity of that relationship is to be maintained. Is not necessary that you should be born as brothers and sisters, not necessary. But you are born, because if you are realized Souls you are born as brothers and sisters. So that purity must be maintained in the society of Sahaja Yoga. Very important it is. That we should try to develop this situation that brothers and sisters are something very pure. Their relationships are very pure. And they should not be at all challenged.<br />
It is so much so that even if you call somebody your brother, he is your brother and the more you develop this relationship, the better your left Viśhuddhi will be. Because left Viśhuddhi is the relationship with God as a brother or with a Goddess as a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So, for compassion, it has to have decency as fragrance in the oil. So how do we express our compassion? We have rākhī sisters, rākhī brothers, but I know of a lady who became friendly with rich boys as rākhī brothers. Or the other way round also, that many boys became rākhī brothers of rich women.<br />
<b>So one has to understand that it is not for money that you should become rākhī brothers and sisters and to exploit, but for compassion.</b> You have to express your rākhī relationship just for the protection of each other. <b>The compassion is so joy-giving that you should have not such conditions of money or any other stupid conditions which will kill your joy.</b> But another thing also is that you express your love you use some things as presents that gives you joy. That doesn't mean, by any chance, that you just give it to your rākhī sister and not even to your wife, some present."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1105 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Lights of Pure Compassion, Istanbul, Turkey</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1298.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The Mahālakṣhmī is the channel of the Kuṇḍalinī, so there are Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmīs. Then Mahālakṣhmī and lastly the Dakṣha Lakṣhmī. We have got one after another these powers within us which are expressed on the Mahālakṣhmī channel."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1018 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (8th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, for today's New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1231 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Year's Eve, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano mein aya hu</b></font><br />
Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon,  Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font><br />
Morning and evening I sing Your Praise<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font><br />
Śhrī Mātājī I Have received a Second Birth from You<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/53370260"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā - Rang De Jhini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zcAvt3cDa0Y">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuzhe Rupa Pāhuniyā Mi danga zhalo ai</b></font><br />
(Seeing Your serene and majestic look, we stand stunned and astonished))<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Awaz Uthayenge</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Ttp3KyI2rew">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Bhai Duja Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/13" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.”" /><published>2023-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_13_Diwali_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/13"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now the Mahālakṣhmī. <b>Mahālakṣhmī is the evolutionary state.</b> In the evolutionary state, when the evolutionary state starts, then the Mahālakṣhmī starts asserting Herself and that comes when your well-being is established fully. I mean, if you are still worried as to how to get a cup of tea for yourself, you cannot get to Mahālakṣhmī state.<br />
So, once that is little bit established and you feel that peace within yourself and that dignity, then the Mahālakṣhmī's Power starts acting on you. And the Mahālakṣhmī Power is that it really makes you the light. You have now become the light. Don't have to have any lights. You are the light. When you go anywhere, when people see you they take guidance from you. They use you as a torch which guides them. They will come and consult you and ask you how to do it. It is you who are the light.<br />
So, this is what it is. <b>One has to know that Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa is represented here as the light. And, you see these lights when enlightened, even a small light, how it reacts and how it shows. And now, you have become the light, you see. Even this light can do it. You see, I put My hand to it and it recognizes and knows that because it is now enlightened. It is put before the Photograph, it's enlightened. It works that way. Now what about you? You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.<br />
Diwālī means the, the rows of lights. So, you are going to make this beautiful mansion of God full of Diwālī light. You have entered into the Kingdom of God and you have to enlighten it. So you are the decoration of God on one side, you are the glory of God and also, on the other side you are the guide, guidelines</b> - you are like the torches, you can say, you are like the, what you call them, which are used by ships those ...<br />
......<br />
You have to become lighthouses."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1291.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"That's the first day of the Moon. That is the forefathers of your Mother, Śhālivāhanas, they started the calendar, from that date. And so, on the first, that means the first day of the Moon, the New Year is celebrated.<br />
Now, see symbolically, Christ is born and the New Year is celebrated, next day. As soon as He is born, New Year starts with. So next year it starts, the New Year."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"So uh, first of all <b>I wish you all a very Happy Diwālī and a prosperous whole year, after this New Year Day.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1106 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Apollon Camping, Delphi, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then the day of the New Year comes in afterwards, because in India in the north, that's the time people finish their crops and they found that day was very good to celebrate the New Year. And, that is actually more, sort of, we can say is a social thing in India ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that's how we start understanding the value of human dignity</b>. We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It's against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody's life miserable. It's against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time. And if you nag that's not a Gṛuhalakṣhmī; that is not a Gṛuhalakṣhmī. You should not nag, `Do this, do that, stand up, what are you doing, stand this side, do, go that side.' It's all a nonsense. You leave the person to be; <b>the human dignity is the most important thing</b>. But respect everybody. And that's possible because now you have the Mahālakṣhmī Principle. Those who do not have the dignity also will get it from you because you are dignified now."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1292.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Satya Lakṣhmī. That is, that you get the awareness of Truth</b>, but apart from that, the awareness of Truth is there but to put the Truth forward in a gracious manner. Not to, `Now this is the Truth -- have it!' -- Not like that! You don't have to hit people with the Truth, you have to put it in a flower and give it to them. <b>That is Satya Lakṣhmī.</b> Of course, the all Lakṣhmī Tattwas are the parasympathetic powers within us but they are actually expressed in our brain. <b>Brain is the Virāṭa, is the Viṣhṇu when He becomes the Virāṭ, the Akbar.</b> So all His Powers, are, specially these powers, are in the brain. So, the brain itself spontaneously behaves in such a manner that people think that this is a special type of a personality.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Eh ... <b>is the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā nights, not only of Lakṣhmī Pūjā</b>. There's a difference between the two.<br />
Mahālakṣhmī is one of the powers of the Three Powers, Main Powers, of Ādi Śhakti. As you know Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī. Now these powers have powers at a material level also, at a subtler level also. So Mahālakṣhmī Power is achieved after Lakṣhmī Power ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So the whole idea of celebrating today the Lakṣhmī's Day is to understand that in us She has become the Mahālakṣhmī.</b> By that we have so many powers of which we are not aware, I mean we do not know that we are realized Souls. Some of us, we do not know and that we have those powers within us that we can permeate into others. We can project our personalities to others. We can find out what's wrong with them. We can find out about ourselves. We can go into ourselves, we can go into -- our permeation is like water is moving, is flowing all the time. And this is a very important thing that we should be aware of: our powers that we have achieved.<br />
Then we will start respecting ourselves then the Rājalakṣhmī comes in and then the Gṛuhalakṣhmī comes in and everything comes within when we become aware of what we have achieved of our self-esteem, of our dignity.<br />
So it gives us dignity, Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that's how we start understanding the value of human dignity.<br /> 
We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It's against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody's life miserable. It's against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1293.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Yoga Lakṣhmī. The Lakṣhmī's power which gives you Yoga. Is Lakṣhmī [who] supports your power of Yoga by giving you awareness. The power by which you take to Yoga is all combined as Yoga Lakṣhmī.</b><br />
Like your affluence: you are not satisfied and you want to have Yoga. The dissatisfaction you get till you have got Yoga is coming from the Yoga Lakṣhmī.<br />
<b>So, Yoga Lakṣhmī is: the power which gives you or takes you to your grace, by which you go to Yoga. That's Yoga Lakṣhmī. Means the kind of a satisfaction that you seek is manifested in you through this power of Yoga Lakṣhmī.</b><br />
And then once you have achieved your Yoga, you get the Grace. Lakṣhmī is the Grace. So, you get the grace of a Saint.<br />
You should have the grace of a Saint. You should look like a Saint! You are a Saint! I think better write it on your mirrors: ``We are Saints. We are `Men of God.' We have to behave like Saints. We are Saints." You are! No doubt! You are, "Men of God," no doubt, but you have turn your faces this way.<br />
So, this is the Yoga Lakṣhmī.<br />
For example, a person who has got Yoga Lakṣhmī doesn't quarrel like a madcap. If he quarrels or dominates someone in a foolish way, then he's still lacking that Lakṣhmī point. There's a grace about it: whole way of talking and ... How you talk to a Saint?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... [in] Sahaja Yoga we believe that the Lakṣhmī must became [become] Mahālakṣhmī. A man has to become greater man: mahā mānav. What does that mean? That She has to become the Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
<b>Mahālakṣhmī is a Deity which makes you absolutely satisfied with whatever you have. Complete satisfaction.</b><br />
......<br />
...... when the Mahālakṣhmī Principle shines in you, then you do not want any more. You want to give it to others, and you want to enjoy your generosity. That is the first sign that you are moving now from Lakṣhmī to Mahālakṣhmī. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1294.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is the day to take an oath, to think of something great, to visualize something big, to ask a boon, to do a big Pūjā, is one of the greatest uh day."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Padm‛āsana sthite Devi, Para-brahma swa-rūpiṇī,</b></font><br />
O Devī, seated on the Lotus, who is the Supreme Consciousness,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Parameśhi jagan-mātar, aah; Mahālakṣhmī namō‛stu-te.</b></font><br />
Supreme Ruler and Mother of the Universe, O Great Mother, Obeisance to Thee.
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), What State You Have to Reach, Quinta do Mar, Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25922658"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parabrahma Rūpinī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Ch-wz0NR08">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa, Music Of Joy</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tere hi Gun gate hai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumPurple">Wishing you all a very Happy Diwali and a Happy New Year!</font><br />  
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Padava" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the blessings of Kingdom of God is that you get drenched in joy – joy which has no duality”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the blessings of Kingdom of God is that you get drenched in joy – joy which has no duality”" /><published>2023-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_12_Diwali_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It was to celebrate the coronation of Śhrī Rāma also, that is to say, symbolically, to celebrate the establishment of a kingdom which has a benevolent administration.<br />
......<br />
<b>So today is a special day to celebrate the Kingdom of God on Earth.</b> As we have ... used to pray, ``Thy kingdom come [......] on this earth" and it has come today on this mountain and we are here to celebrate the coming of the Kingdom of God as we have been praying for ages. And <b>the blessings of Kingdom of God is that you get drenched in joy -- joy which has no duality, like happiness and unhappiness</b>. Is an experience of Absoluteness and just that joy is sufficient, you don't want any food, you don't want to sleep, you don't mind where you are, just in joy drenched completely. There's no place for unhappiness, we have no heart for it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1024 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Bhāūbīj Day), The Light of Love, before the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1286.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"And, today's day is a very great day for us because the Saints are celebrating Diwālī. I'm celebrating My Diwālī enlightening light in your hearts that you enjoy your own joy and your own beauty; that you are now the Spirit. Enjoy it. That you are there. Now, you are in the Kingdom of God. No doubt."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Rāma's crowning or any other aspect of Śhrī Lakṣhmī here now becomes your own crowning, that is now you have entered into the Kingdom of God and once you are there then automatically as the citizens of God's Kingdom you are blessed and as you become the lotuses then you start spreading your fragrance all around. Now you do not keep this joy to yourself but you become generous about it and you go all out to give it to others."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1287.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Then the fifteenth day is the day when the Moon is absolutely missing from everything. Is absolute darkness, where you put these lights to suggest that: `There are lights, now let Lakṣhmī come within us.' So, there is no spot that should be left which is dark, so everywhere the Lakṣhmī resign ... resides, and give us the glory of Her blessings.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1114 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Deeper Wealth, Divine Temperament, Fondness of Generosity, Keep your Suṣhumṇā Open and Real Days of Diwālī Celebration (The Greatest Generosity a Human Being Can Do Is to Forgive, All of Us Have to Go Together, Discretion to Improve Your Value System and Universal Theme for People), Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Lakṣhmī is the Goddess, is the power within us, by which we balance, lead a very balanced life, by which we are satisfied.</b><br />
Now they have made a beautiful picture of this Lakṣhmī also one should understand this power -- is a Lady, is a Mother and She stands on a lotus. Now these are all symbols which suggest that these symbols are carved out with such deep significance. She stands on a lotus. Means imagine, who can stand on a lotus? And She's a very healthy woman, very healthy woman and She stands on a lotus. It means that, that She is never putting pressure on anyone.<br />
......<br />
Then, it has got two red, <b>pink flowers in the hand, that are lotus flowers again.<br />
Now the lotus is regarded as a very holy flower in India, because it is so receptive to everything that is crude and funny.</b> First of all it is born in the mud. Just think of it, in the mud, in the filth, where the horrible smell is coming out, the lotus is born. And the one lotus gives the fragrance, the beautiful fragrance to the whole atmosphere, and kills all that's filth and everything, and covers the whole pond with its big, big leaves so that it looks a beautiful pond. That's what is the lotus for.<br />
But this lotus is a pink lotus, means pink, you know, is the sign of love. <b>Pink is the sign of love. So such a person has to have tremendous love and that softness of the lotus.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0327 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 3, Nābhī Chakra (Must Have a Balanced Attitude Towards Life), Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"For <b>your good luck, you should say let us say for your good luck, saubhāgya, for your good luck</b>. Is given to the ladies, always given to the ladies. Because in India the women are regarded as the śhakti and women who lead a married life and who have been mothers, who have been daughters and also wives and things like that are respected very much as only it is believed that <b>only the respectable women when they exist in any country the Gods also reside there. If they are not respectable the Gods don't reside there</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0210 Talk to Sahaja Yoginīs, About Tradition, Pimpri (17 kms N-NW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1288.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Am-ṛu-ta. <b>Amṛuta means the thing that does not die. If in this world the Lakṣhmī exists as your wealth.</b><br />
Now the wealth that does not die, which is that wealth? Is the Spirit. So, the Grace of the Spirit is the Amṛuta Lakṣhmī. Grace of the Spirit is the Amṛuta Lakṣhmī. The rest of the things all will die out. And whatever is done through the Spirit, to please the Spirit, is the Amṛuta Lakṣhmī.<br />
For example: loving others. Loving others has a different meaning in the symbolic way as you people understand this thing. Loving means giving. Doing without any expectation: just doing it, and enjoying.<br />
The greatest is giving vibration[s]. That is Amṛuta: vibrations do not die. That's the Lakṣhmī: they are giving Amṛut."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"Now Saubhāgya Lakṣhmī. She's the one who gives you good fortune. Good fortune doesn't mean money, but it means: the grace of money. Many people have money but it's like money on a donkey. You do not find any grace in that person. Or it doesn't also mean, saubhāgya doesn't mean only money, it means all the good luck. All the good luck in everything in a very gracious manner, is this. To [give] you the blessings so that you also are blessed as well as those people who'll meet you will be blessed, with saubhāgya."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1289.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Chandraam Prabhaasaam Yashasaa Jvalantiim Shriyam Loke Deva-Jussttaam-Udaaraam 
Taam Padminiim-Iim Sharannam-Aham Prapadye-[A]lakssmiir-Me Nashyataam Tvaam Vrnne</b></font><br />
Who is the Embodiment of Sri and Whose Glory Shines like the Splendour of the Moon in all the Worlds; Who is Noble and Who is Worshipped by the Devas.<br />
I take Refuge at Her Feet, Who Abides in the Lotus;<br />
By Her Grace, let the Alakshmi (in the form of Evil, Distress, and Poverty) within and without be Destroyed.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(from Śhrī Sūktam)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><b>"This is the promise of Diwālī to you all, that you will reach highest and the noblest way of life. Every word I say will be there to prove what I say is there. Whatever petty problems you have, they'll all be washed off. All these are the messages from the Divine, you don't have to worry about petty things, about money, about jobs, that's not your job. Your destiny will work it out. You have a promise that you'll be looked after. I hope you believe in that promise and are joyous in the highest way.<br />
I bless you all from My heart, all of you, for a very happy and prosperous Diwālī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (16th day after Diwālī Day), The Need for Sincerity, Holiday Inn Express and Suites, 1080 Navigator Drive, Ventura, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1103 Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), The Importance of Meditation, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/29517118"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi, Ayi, Āj Diwālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hum Āj Rāth</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1290.png" /></div>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />  
Wishing you all a very <font color="DeepPink"><b>Happy and Prosperous Diwālī!</b></font><br />   
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the second part of the Diwali you have to open your heart.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the second part of the Diwali you have to open your heart.”" /><published>2023-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_11_Diwali_Day_2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/11"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So there are so many aspects for this that, after Rāma had killed Rāvaṇa, another satanic force, this Diwālī was celebrated. Also, this was celebrated much earlier, when Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed. And this is how we express our joy and happiness, our gratitude to God that He has protected us always with His Power, with His Śhakti and has destroyed all the rākṣhasas and all the evil forces of this world.<br />
<b>This is the time of Thanksgiving. On this day we have to go to our elders and give thanks to them for whatever they have done for us. To all those people whom we have to give thanks, today is the day when we have to ask God to bless all these people.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1282.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Then the fourteenth day is very important, because that is the day the Goddess as a power, as a power, because it was Kārttikeya who killed Narakāsura [Tārakāsura], the devil.</b> And he was one of the worst of all, could not be killed. So Śhiva and Pārvatī were married for this special purpose to produce this powerful Śhakti Putra, means the Son of the Śhakti, known as Kārttikeya. And He was just born to kill this horrible devil, called as Narakāsura [Tārakāsura]. And He killed. That is the day, fourteenth day. It is something like Halloween, that day. Because that is the day they opened the gates of hell and put all the devils into Hell."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then there is, the second day is where Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was killed. Now Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was the one who was the devil from the Hell, let's say -- very cunning, very clever -- and he was killed by the Goddess. Actually he was killed by a, another Incarnation, Kārttikeya, but Goddess gave Him the power to kill. So when he was killed it was celebrated because the evil was killed. But we don't find that these days the evil people are getting peace awards. So what is the reason for this kind of a perverted brain? How is it they are using perversion? Just the opposite of it. What has worked out these things? So again we find the same so-called freedom to become also evil. So we have freedom to become evil. First of all we have freedom not to be benevolent, and secondly to become evil we have freedom.<br />
So <b>the Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] within us must be killed, the one which teaches us evil, to do evil to others. If you are busy doing evil to others you can never enjoy. Because you enjoy doing evil to others. So that has to be faced within ourselves, not in other people. It's very easy to say that this Sahaja Yogi is caught up, that Sahaja Yogi is like that, but very difficult to say, `Mother, I am caught up. I have got this problem within myself.' So when you start seeing yourself your heart opens out. Unless and until you learn how to open out your heart how can you enjoy? Open your heart.</b><br />
Many people live on very superficial level. All right, some of them might say that, `I am possessed, Mother. I've got this possession.' Why? `I've got this conditioning, that conditioning.' But why? You don't want to enjoy. So watch yourself, see for yourself. This is my conditioning, `All right, I'll put you right.' See in the mirror. Tell yourself, `This kind of a useless conditioning I've got it from where? Because I'm Indian, because I'm French, because of English.' Open the heart. And opening the heart is only possible if Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] sitting on your heart is killed, finished, once for all.<br />
In small, small things there is joy. In very little things also there's a ripple of joy. If you are sensitive you can catch it. And why not enjoy? Why to have these stupid conditioning on our heads for nothing at all that we can't enjoy? Enjoyment is only possible if you take out this one, sitting on your heart.<br />
<b>So that is the second part of the Diwālī that you have to open your heart.</b> Forget your nationality, forget your race, forget everything. It's a funny kind of things Sahaja Yogis have. They must be respected, they must be treated like this or maybe that we are something great and they are no good. If you cannot mix up with the collective it's something wrong with you. Nothing wrong with others. Easy to find faults with others. But what's the use? If you start finding faults with others you do not become clean."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Pāḍavā), Be Honest to Yourself, Auditorium, Gymnasium, Montecatini Terme, Tuscany, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1283.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Rājalakṣhmīs are the Goddesses who are looking after the country.</b><br />
Like England has a Rājalakṣhmī, too. Now, the, say, we can say the princess now is ... is a Rājalakṣhmī, he's a ... she's a woman with dignity, she carries herself with that bashful sweetness and all that, she's a Rājalakṣhmī.<br />
Our Queen is very good, too.<br />
......<br />
<b>A Rājalakṣhmī is a dignified woman: she is the one who is the glory of the country.</b> She has to be a glorious woman. She has to be a woman with all the attributes of a queen. And that is the Rājalakṣhmī: is the, is the queen, or the Goddess, that is the queen. And She resides in every country. Every country has a Gṛuhalakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1114 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Deeper Wealth, Divine Temperament, Fondness of Generosity, Keep your Suṣhumṇā Open and Real Days of Diwālī Celebration (The Greatest Generosity a Human Being Can Do Is to Forgive, All of Us Have to Go Together, Discretion to Improve Your Value System and Universal Theme for People), Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Rājalakṣhmī is the one where collectively, collectively you enjoy your well-being</b>, collectively, on the right-hand side, you can say. Like, we have some places which are for public usage here, public well-being.<br />
......<br />
So, we have the essence of Lakṣhmī and then we have, when we evolved, we started having our homes, houses, our own family, our own private life, our this thing. So, we had Gṛuhalakṣhmī. And then we started having collective, like we can say the Queen represents here Rājalakṣhmī. The Queen represents here the Rājalakṣhmī of England. She is a symbol of that. Our Queen here is the symbol of that Rājalakṣhmī. You know, the word Rāj means the kingdom or you can say the royal, royal side of the -- regality. <b>So, when the Lakṣhmī is a regal Lakṣhmī, She is for collectivity. So, the Queen doesn't live for herself, she lives for all the Collective Being. In the same way, this Rājlakṣhmī is the One that is for all of us.</b><br />
For example, this place we got here is through the blessings of Rājlakṣhmī. She gave us.<br />
Her power gave us this place to live because you are all Sahaja Yogis. You are the epitome of the evolution, you are highest people in the evolution, you are the ones who are looked after by God, you are the most important people.<br />
It's true! And you must be provided for. You should have no problem of money, you should have no problem of housing, you should have no problem of anything.<br />
So, it is She, the Rājalakṣhmī who gives you all these thing[s]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1284.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Maroon"><b>O Mother! We have come out of the darkness and have entered into Enlightened world.
We could get pure knowledge from your Divine lap which the mortal world could not give so far.
all the three lokas respect you from heart.
You, the originator of pure knowledge,
have given us true rebirth.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Song to the Devī from Prayers, Praises and Protocols)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Vidyā! Vidyā: is the art of Sahaja Yoga</b>, which you know. That is Vidyā. The rest is all avidyā. How to raise the Kuṇḍalinī, how to awaken all the Deities, how to cleanse yourself, how to cleanse others, all the knowledge, <b>all the science about that is called as Vidyā. The Lakṣhmī of that.<br />
Lakṣhmī is the Grace, is the Grace.</b> Awareness that is gracious. <b>The awareness that is gracious.</b> So, that Lakṣhmī should be with you, is that not only to know the Vidyā, you know that, but to have grace about it. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Then the second one is Vidyā Lakṣhmī.</b> She's the one who teaches you the technique of handling the Divine Power. Now this [is] to be understood very well. What is a Lakṣhmī. Lakṣhmī is graciousness. So She teaches you how to use this power with graciousness.<br />
......<br /> 
Now, the Vidyā Lakṣhmī is the one, as I told you, gives you knowledge, knowledge how to handle the Divine Power graciously. I'll give you an example. I've seen many people when they give bandhan, it's such a crude way, that ... No! It is not to be done! It's a Lakṣhmī's blessing. So how you do it, very carefully. You see Me, how I give always. I never do that way! I cannot! With respect, with grace. She represents the respect part of it. And that you get, that knowledge, how to do it gracefully. Everything to be done gracefully, in a manner that looks gracious. See, some people who talk have no grace, some people who give knowledge of Sahaja Yoga also have no grace and they talk in a disgraceful manner. So all the grace, how to use the knowledge of the Divine, is given by Vidyā Lakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1285.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Pranatha sureswari, bharathi, bhargavi<br />
shoka vinasini, rathna maye,<br />
Mani maya bhooshitha karma vibhooshana,<br />
Santhi samavrutha hasyamukhe,<br />
Nava nidhi dhayini kalimala harini,<br />
Kamitha phalapradha hasthayuthe,<br />
Jaya Jaya he madhusoodhana kamini<br />
Vidhyalakshmi sada palaya maam</b><br />
Victory to the Goddess!<br />
Who is the daughter of the Bhṛigu Mahaṛiśhi<br />
Who chases away all our sorrows.<br />
<b>Who radiates with all her ornaments containing precious gems<br />
Who blesses us with nine kinds of wealth</b><br />
Who grants boons with Varada hastam (hand)<br />
Please protect us all the time&lt;/b&gt;</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>From Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī (praise of Śhrī Vidyā Lakṣhmī)</b></font>&lt;<br />
<br />  
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahaja Yogi is a special character of a soldier who fights for the Truth. That kind of a personality, when you will have, there will be lights all over.<br />
In this Diwālī Day, I bless you all from My heart and I want you to respect yourself and understand what is the position of your being</b> in this l... something ... organization we can call or a, in this Movement of Sahaja Yoga, and how are we working it out. The attention should move from all this nonsensical, mundane things to your Self. It should be a very dynamic force that should work out. And I am sure next year it will be very different. We'll have all the beautiful blessings of the Divine. We must do it collectively, understandingly.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1118 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Soldiers of Divine Power and Sahaja Yogi Is a Special Character of a Soldier Who Fights for the Truth, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumSlateBlue "><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāksho-bala Vimardana sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.<br />
(Victorious over the Asuric forces)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2001-1118 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Soldiers of Divine Power and Sahaja Yogi Is a Special Character of a Soldier Who Fights for the Truth, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/78313893"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Andhar Phar Ahe (Śhrī Mātājī gives the meaning of the bhajan and sings along)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ādimāyā Ambābai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mateche Gondhaḷī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/6HVszNo1EBo">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DeepPink"><b>Wishing</b> </font><font color="Maroon"><b> You</b></font><font color="Purple"><b> all</b></font><font color="Orchid"><b> a</b></font><font color="PaleVioletRed"><b> very</b></font><font color="DarkGreen"><b> Happy</b></font><font color="DarkRed"><b> Diwālī!</b></font><br />  
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Naraka Chaturdashi" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “The first day is the thirteenth day …… the day when the gṛuhalakṣhmī is worshiped”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/10" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “The first day is the thirteenth day …… the day when the gṛuhalakṣhmī is worshiped”" /><published>2023-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_10_Diwali_Day_1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/10"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="Red"><b>"Diwālī means the, the rows of lights. So, you are going to make this beautiful mansion of God full of Diwālī light. You have entered into the Kingdom of God and you have to enlighten it. So you are the decoration of God on one side, you are the glory of God and also, on the other side you are the guide, guidelines -- you are like the torches ......"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1278.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"The first day is the thirteenth day where it is the gṛuhalakṣhmī's day. Is a ṛughalakṣhmī's [gṛuhalakṣhmī's] day, that is the day when the gṛuhalakṣhmī is worshiped."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Ahaṃ sākṣhāt Gṛuhalakṣhmī - ah!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0313 Public Program, The Meaning of Sahaja Yoga, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Now today is the Pūjā, as you know there are five days they celebrate Diwālī.</b><br />
<b>The first day is the thirteenth day where it is the gṛuhalakṣhmī's day. Is a ṛughalakṣhmī's [gṛuhalakṣhmī's] day, that is the day when the gṛuhalakṣhmī is worshiped.</b> But a gṛuhalakṣhmī has to be worship ... worthy of the worship, and then some utensil is given to the gṛuhalakṣhmī. Some sort of a utensil is to be given to the gṛuhalakṣhmī as a present. That is the day Lakṣhmī was born, Lakṣhmī was born out of the Mother Earth ... a ... out of the, we should say, Mother Earth, but She came out of the sea, a... after the churning. So that is the birth of the Lakṣhmī, She is the giver of wealth: wealth which is material as well as spiritual."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1279.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Now first is the Ādya Lakṣhmī. Ādya is the one who is the Primordial, Primordial Lakṣhmī.</b> As I told you about, that She came out of the Sea. So that's what we call Christ's Mother was called as Mary, Maria, because She came from Marine. People don't know why she was called as Mary. My name also is, as you know, is Nirā, meaning coming from water."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"This Lakṣhmī was born, who came out of the sea, the great sea, which was churned thousands and thousands of years back. And She came out of the sea because She is the daughter of the sea. That's why She's called as Nīrajā. Nīr it means water and ja means `born out of it'. This has happened thousands and thousand years back that She was born.<br />
Now what is that? What is this Lakṣhmī? Is symbolically, what is it expressing? It is expressing the awareness. <b>Lakṣhmī e... expresses aware[ness]. And She came out of the sea. You know that: the awareness first started growing in the sea.</b> The life started existing in the sea, to begin with, and then it grew up. Without the life there is no awareness. First the life, because everything is jaḍa [void of life, inanimate, unintelligent], everything is dead. And when it becomes life it means it has awareness. So the awareness started growing in the sea. This is the symbolic expression. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1280.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"The Deity of Gṛuhalakṣhmī is Fāṭimah Bi, the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0131 Public Program, Day 2, The Nābhī Chakra, N.D.M.C. Park, Hanumān Road, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Gṛuhalakṣhmī is the woman who should know that she has the great responsibility of creating a very great society of Sahaja Yoga."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0428 Śhrī Haṃsa Chakra Pūjā, The Source of Discretion, Queens, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
<br />
<font color="Sienna"><b>Bolo Śhrī Gṛuhalakṣhmī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī kī!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Then you have your wife as gṛuhalakṣhmī. So we have to have a wife as gṛuhalakṣhmī. These two things one should understand very, very clearly because we confuse them. Wife is the gṛuhalakṣhmī, is the one, she is the goddess of the household. Now she has to be the goddess also, I mean she just doesn't become goddess just by becoming. You have to become again. You have to become the goddess. And, <b>the Goddess of the Gṛuhalakṣhmī is, we can say, that the Deity of the Gṛuha -- of the house -- is a Gṛuhalakṣhmī.</b><br />
Now, this Deity must become one with the housewife. Then the blessings of the Lakṣhmī essence is of well-being comes to you. If she is not the Goddess, you will always suffer.<br />
You will always have problems; you will always have all kinds of untold miseries. It is Her blessings which brings you solace, peace and redemption -- redemption is the word -- of anything. So, that's why the left Nābhī is very important as we know and that is always bad in the West.<br />
So, I would say that the whole society is responsible for spoiling that because housewife is not respected. First of all, we should blame our society. Our housewives are not respected. <b>Housewife is the one who is a dedicated wife even placed higher than Yatis. Yatis are the highest evolved you can say, Avadhūtas, are the highest evolved Seers. And, a dedicated wife has got more powers than even a Yati, it is said so.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>So the first is the form of a Gṛuhalakṣhmī.</b> She is born as a Gṛuhalakṣhmī, to begin with. That means the awareness, of human beings also, started really getting into evolutionary process when they started their family life. When they were vagabonds, moving about, then the awareness was just like animals. Though they had become human beings, but they were like animals. Then when they established their families, then the Gṛuhalakṣhmī started working and that's how the first Advent of Gṛuhalakṣhmī was felt.<br />
So She is the first Lakṣhmī who was born, and that's why on that thirteenth day is the day of the Gṛuhalakṣhmī, of the housewife. And so, one has to go in the market and buy some utensils or something that she uses for cooking in the house. In India on the thirteenth day everyone goes and buys a pot or, say, we can say, what you call, a cooking utensil or something. Or they may buy a sāṛī or something or gold or something for the gṛuhalakṣhmī. That is the day of the housewife.<br />
So, to reach the Lakṣhmī one has to understand that motherhood is very important. The motherhood as a gṛuhalakṣhmī is important. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1281.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"...... Mahālakṣhmī is also Annapūrṇā. And She, She, She supplies food, you see, to people. You can say Mahālakṣhmī is the grandest Gṛuhalakṣhmī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0908 Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Münich, Bavaria, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0814 Śhrī Fāṭimah Pūjā, Saint-George (40 kms W of Lausanne), Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/575624651"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Pavan Utsav ayya re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hasat Ali</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kanakadhara Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmī Storam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Dhanatrayodashi" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: The five days of Diwālī</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/09" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: The five days of Diwālī" /><published>2023-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_09_Diwali_The_Five_Days</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/09"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>My dear Sahaja Yogis, My dear children,<br />
Let this Diwālī enlighten you with light of love.</b> You yourself are the lamps which burn high and don't get pressed by the cover. They become much more powerful than the cover. It is their own asset. When they are hit upon, they are disturbed and extinguished.<br />
Why are our lamps disturbed? You should think over it. Is there no transparent sheath around them? Have you forgotten your Mother's Love and therefore you are so disturbed? <b>As the glass protects the lamp, in the same way My love will protect you.</b><br />
But the glass should be kept clean, how can I explain? Have I to say like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, "Leave all religions and surrender to Me" or as Śhrī Jesus, "I am the way, I am the door."<br />
I want to tell that I am that Man̄jil (Destination). But will you people accept it? Will this fact go to your hearts?<br />
Although what I say is distorted, the Truth will always stand. You cannot change what It is. Only you will remain ignorant and backward. I am unhappy because of that.<br />
<b>Diwālī is the day of real aspirations. Invoke the whole universe. Many lamps have to be lit, and looked after. Add the oil of love, Kuṇḍalinī is the wick and awaken the Kuṇḍalinī of others with light of the Spirit within you.</b> This flame of Kuṇḍalinī will be kindled and one within you will become the torch. Torch is not extinguished. Then there will be spotless sheath of My love. It will neither have any limits nor any end. I will be watching you.<br />
My love for you is showering as many many blessings.<br />
Yours always loving Mother<br />
Nirmalā"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1021 Letter to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Diwālī, 2, Parklands, Ice House Wood, Hurst Green, Oxted, Surrey, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1275.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"This well-being is brought forth with this Lakṣhmī, <b>with one hand that is giving, the another is the protection</b>. This hand which gives, should not, the other hand should not know. It should be so done so gracefully, graciously."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0327 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 3, Nābhī Chakra (Must Have a Balanced Attitude Towards Life), Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Dear All,<br />
We wish you all a Very Happy and joyful Diwālī Festival that will be starting tomorrow for five days.<br />
The significance and the days of Deepavali are listed below:</font><br />
<br />
<b>Day 1 (Friday, November 10th) – Dhanteras or Dhanvantri Jayanti</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"The first day is the thirteenth day where it is the gṛuhalakṣhmī's day. Is a ṛughalakṣhmī's [gṛuhalakṣhmī's] day, that is the day when the gṛuhalakṣhmī is worshiped. But a gṛuhalakṣhmī has to be worship ... worthy of the worship, and then some utensil is given to the gṛuhalakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Romania</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">It is the first day of the five days celebration of Diwālī. The day when Śhrī Lakṣhmī is worshiped in Her form of Śhrī Gṛuhalakṣhmī. It is also called the Dhanvantri Jayanti, the day when Goddess Dhanvantri is born.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Day 2 (Saturday, November 11th) – Naraka Chaturdaśhī</b><br /> 
<font color="DarkRed">"Horrible Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] as you know him. But actually that day many rākṣhasas are killed in many ... That's a day fixed for killing rākṣhasas."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">The day when, according to Śhrī Mātājī, the Goddess gave Her Power to Śhrī Kārttikeya to kill Narakāsura. Hell's gate is open in the early morning hours (the real Halloween) when Narakāsura is pushed into Hell, so it's advisable to sleep early on the 2nd night and not get up early on Diwālī Day (i.e., not to meditate at 4 a.m. or get up early to eat Diwālī sweets!), but to get up after sunrise and also leave a lamp burning safely overnight so that Narakāsura's influence is dispersed.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Then the fifteenth is that darkest night. That's the darkest night when there is no Moon. Absolutely that's the day when they celebrate this Diwālī. But symbolically, in India also, Śhrī Rāma returned to Dvārika ... to this place on that day, and was crowned on that day. So the significance of Diwālī is expressed in this manner: that this is the day when Narakāsura [Tārakāsura] was on doubt the martyric, they have all gone to Narak, they have gone to the Hell, and the people now are safe from them and they are celebrating the joy, this thing.<br />
And that is the time when Christ was born. That's why lights are being put in the night, 'cause He was born at twelve o'clock in the night."</font><br />
<b>Day 3 (Sunday, November 12th) – Diwālī/Śhrī Lakṣhmī Pūjā</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">This is the third day of celebrations of Diwālī.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Day 4 (Monday, November 13th) – Diwālī Pāḍavā</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"And so, on the first, that means the first day of the Moon, the New Year is celebrated.<br />
Now, see symbolically, Christ is born and the New Year is celebrated, next day. As soon as He is born, New Year starts with. So next year it starts, the New Year."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">This is the fourth day of Diwālī celebrations. This day is one of the three and a half most auspicious days of the year. It is a very auspicious day to begin new things.</font><br />
<br />
<b>Day 5 (Tuesday, November 14th) – Bhāī Dūj or Bhāūbīj</b><br />
<font color="Purple"><b>"So today is the second day. Second day is the Bīja, is the, they call it the Bhaiyā Dvija or Bhāūbīj, is the day when the brother and the sister, who are the seeds of one tree, have that pure exchange of affection."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">This is the last, the fifth day of Diwālī celebrations. On this day the brother and sister relationship is celebrated.</font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1276.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">During the Diwālī Festival, we will worship Śhrī Mātājī in Her forms of Śhrī Lakṣhmī, Śhrī Mahāhakṣhmī, and Śhrī Ādi Śhakti. We would like to begin by offering Śhrī Mātājī the welcome song that was sung to Her before the evening program during the 1987 Diwālī Festival in Italy.</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Lakṣhmī Welcome Song 1987:</b></font> <a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1277.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Trayanam devanam triguna-janitanam tava Śhive,<br />
bhavet pooja pooja tava charanayorya vira chita I<br />
Tatha hi tvat-padod vahana-manipeethasya nikate,<br />
Sthita hyete shash vanmukulita karottamsa-makutah II</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O Spouse of Śhiva! The homage rendered to Thy Feet becomes by itself the homage rendered to the Three Gods of Thy Three Guṇas.<br />
It is, therefore, that these three Gods, Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, and Rudra, ever stand by the jeweled seat on which Thy Feet rest, with Their folded hands, adorning Their crowns.</font><br />
  (Verse 25, Saundaryalaharī by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti.”" /><published>2023-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_24_Navaratri_Day_10</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Don't worry about anything, just know that I am the Ādi Śhakti. That all the Powers of God and Goddesses and all that are within Me and they are within Me and they are all looking after you. But if that recognition is not there, they are not going to recognize you either.<br />
<b>So for today's Navarātri, I have to tell you that -- just try to keep in mind that today you are worshiping the Ādi Śhakti and not only Durgā.</b> And you are worshiping Durgā and all these Goddesses to thank them because, if they had not saved you that time, you had been so frightened, you would have become bad people and would not have been here. That is why we are thankful to them for saving us and giving us this protection at that time when we were very helpless.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1013 Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), False Religion and Recognize Me, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1269.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Navy"><b>We should devote ourselves to that Devī<br />
Who resides at the center of our lotus hearts,<br />
Whose glory is like that of the rising sun,<br />
Whose face is pleasing,<br />
Who grants all boons and protection,<br />
Who is three-eyed, Who wears red clothes, and<br />
Who fulfills the desires of Her devotees.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now the tenth Navarātri today is to celebrate actually the Ādi Śhakti.</b> So today we are really going to worship the Ādi Śhakti. On one side the Ādi Śhakti is Mahākālī, on the other side She is Mahāsaraswatī, in the center She is Mahālakṣhmī, and also She is the Ambā, the one who is the Kuṇḍalinī. But She's also beyond that. She's Parāśhakti, She's beyond all the powers because She is the Generator of Power, so She has to be beyond all that. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you enter into the Kingdom of God. Then the Śhakti makes you sit on different beautiful positions, and some are sitting in the Heart of God, some are sitting in the Sahasrāra of God, in the Kingdom of God.</b><br />
Now you should assume your power. On Navarātri now, you should understand that it has now crossed the limit and now we are on the tenth position, where you must assume. I have told you many a times, now believe that you are Sahaja Yogis. Believe that you are, you have entered into the Kingdom of God. You cannot judge God, you cannot say why She does that, why She does that, why He does that. You cannot say that -- that's different. But when you sit there, then it is not an assembly, it is not like a politician fighting, no; it is that you have entered into the Kingdom of God, blessed by God, looked after, protected, nourished, and made knowledgeable.<br />
......<br />
So Navarātri's -- <b>now, the tenth day of Navarātri, which is the most important for all of you, is where this Paramachaitanya has become active. And by its activity you should know it is become very powerful, and that now anybody who tries to be nasty with you, tries to trouble you -- "I don't have to worry at all." It will take care of it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1270.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... on this day of this Pūjā, <b>it's such a combination that it's the Dussehra, I am here and also you can call it the last day of the Devī Pūjā</b>. We have to see within ourselves, introspect, 'What have I done for Sahaja Yoga?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1024 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Reintrospect Yourself, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Jay jay Raghuvīra Samartha</b><br />
Victory to the all-powerful Śhrī Rāma!<br />
<b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāma sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Rāma. Salutations to You! 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"><b>So today is Dussehra, is a very big day in India.</b> They say on this day Rāvaṇa was killed. He was the worst enemy of human beings, and he was killed. But whatever it is then, as a memory of that great man, Śhrī Rām, they celebrate today Dussehra. And on this day, they say, those who are duṣhṭas, means bad people or we can say negative, they are killed. Can you imagine? [Chuckles.]<br />
So this day is regarded as a very important day in India, and they make a big statue of Rāvaṇa. You all know who was Rāvaṇa, ...</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogis:</b> Yes, Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">... whom Śhrī Rāma killed. He was a horrible fellow and he took away the wife of Śhrī Rām, Sītā, by force. But she was such a chaste woman that he couldn't touch Her. He tried, he couldn't touch Her. He couldn't achieve any power over Her. On the contrary, She was very powerful.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1271.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"That's why I have to tell you that on this day of Dussehra, let us decide that we are going to have Rām Rāj in Sahaja Yoga, where there is benevolence, there is love, compassion, security, peace, joy, discipline among ourselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau manasā smarāmi</b></font><br />
I worship the feet of Shri Rama-chandra in my heart.<br />
Shrī Rāma-chandra charanau vachasā gṛunāmi<br />
Through my songs and prayers I praise the feet of Shri Rama-chandra.<br />
Shrī Rāma-chandra charanau shirasā namāmi<br />
I bow at the feet of Shri Rama-chandra.<br />
Shrī Rāma-chandra charanau sharanam prapadye<br />
I surrender at the feet of Shri Rama-chandra.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Shri Rama-raksha stotram)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0923 Navarātri Pūjā (4th Day), The Deities Are Watching You, Hall, Arzier-Le Muids, Nyon, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76751298"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Nirmal Prān Karo</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi Giri Nandini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/dSIEMZflZa0">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Jagadambe Ayi Re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/BUcvc6e_9-E">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Durgati Harini Durgā Ambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0"><b>Jay He Jay He Jay He Devī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Mangala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātā O Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kindle My Heart</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Raghu Pati Raghav</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Man Ram Rangi Rangle By Bhimsen Joshi</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/o-_qx6VXMA4">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1272.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>When you offer Me flowers or anything else like water then the elements are happy, and the Deities are happy within their chakras so that they emit vibrations of their qualities and their blessings upon you.</b> They will give you their qualities and their blessings because this is how the Divine acts, and gradually after a Pūjā you will feel the whole thing is working out."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0524 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, The Importance of Pūjā, House of Juan Antonio Delgado, Madrid, Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>I've told you before also but again today I want to tell you the significance of Pūjā. The significance is this: that when you do the Pūjā you recognize Me. By your recognition, and your surrendering, the Deities get happy.</b> They're overjoyed that you have recognized it, you are fully identified yourself, that you are understanding Me in My full form, that you are coming closer to Them. Like elder brothers feel happy when the younger ones are coming to meet them. So, They start releasing My vibrations with a greater force, much greater force.<br />
You have seen that after Pūjā, sometimes when you do not absorb the vibrations, I get little tired because the vibrations start coming out of all the chakras and you do not absorb, so the give-and-take process is not balanced.<br />
The identification in the West is very slow because of mental activity. Your attachment to your mental activity and to your rationality is very great. With Pūjā, the vibrations try to detach you from your mental activity, from your rationality. And then you ... you are station into the Realm of Divine Existence."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0420 Pūjā, Significance of Pūjā, Flat of Marie Rouger, 175 Av. Ledru Rollin, 11th Arrondissement, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/23" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Navarātri Festival: “This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation.”" /><published>2023-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/2023_10_23_Navaratri_Day_9</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/10/23"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is <b>the last day of Navarātri</b>. And this should be the culminating point for all of us. As you see, within us lie, as you know that there are seven chakras for you ascent and two above it. So all these Nine Chakras are to be crossed in this lifetime. That should be your destiny.<br />
But if you people go only on the Āgñyā move on Āgñyā, you cannot rise any higher. People have been lost on that chakra. So, that's a very important chakra for ......<br />
Sixth, Ṣhaṣhṭhī of the Goddess, is regarded as a very important thing and they say that, `Goddess comes on a nāv,' on a boat, Calcutta [Kolkata] people believe it because the sixth day is very big to cross it. That is what today is the problem with all of us that we have this sixth day still sitting on our heads and we cannot get out it. So to come to the ninth stage, though we may do Pūjā, we may do anything, but we are still on the sixth. So it is just outwardly that we are doing Pūjā. Seventh day is the day, where I am there. But 7th and 8th and 9th has to be achieved by crossing your sixth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Nav Durgā Kī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1265.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogi [reads]:</b> <font color="Maroon"><b>What is Your prowess to be compared to? Where can one find this beauty (of Yours) most charming, (yet) striking fear in enemies? Compassion in heart and relentlessness in battle are seen, O Devī, O Bestower of boons, only in You in all the three worlds!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0719 Comments on the Reading from Devī Māhātmyam, before the Talk on the Meaning of Pūjā, House of Pamela Bromley, 22 College Gardens, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Siddhidātrī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Siddhidātrī, the One who is the bestower of Siddhis (Divine Powers), Salutations to You!
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now you are worshiping today the Durgā, or all the nine forms of the Goddess.</b> She came nine times on this Earth, according to this, that She fought all the people who were destroying the seekers, who were trying to make a mess of their lives. And these tortured Saints, when they prayed to the Goddess -- because none of the Gods could do anything, and Sadāśhiva is never interfering with what the Goddess is doing -- so they worshiped the Bhagavatī, and then the Incarnation of Hers came nine times, according to the need of the time."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1266.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"The siddhis that people attempt to achieve are: Aṇima, Laghima, Mahima, Īśhatva, Vaśhitva, Prākāmya, Bhukti, Icchā, Prāpti, Mukti. Aṇima is to become like a small particle. Laghima is to become small, Mahima is to have a big form, Īśhatva is to create Gods out of human beings, Vaśhitva is the attraction, Prākāmya is the manifestation, Bhukti is the enjoyment, [Icchā] fulfillment of desire. Prāpti is the attainment, Mukti is the salvation.<br />
<b>These are all the siddhis that Sahaja Yogis can have."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0907 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Bīja Mantras, Śhrī Lalitā, Śhrī Chakra, 56 Ashley Gardens, Ambrosden Avenue (near Victoria Station), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"These are the things you must understand. Why are you doing that and try to get rid of it and try to improve yourself, be alert and to receive it. Receive it as much as you can. This is what is the Pūjā is made for.<br />
Now you have had nine Pūjās here and out of these nine Pūjās have we improved more, have we got more? Did we fill ourselves more with greater love, with greater joy, with greater understanding and with greater satisfaction?<br />
<b>This is the last day, so you have to think like that, then tomorrow is the day of jubilation.</b> Because we have done what? That is what. So today you should go and make a complete picture of yourself. What have I got in these nine days? What have I got? Let us see, have I got this? Have I got that? All these things, you should just within yourself see and then enjoy that you have got all these things. It is the victory. Tomorrow is the day of victory. That you have become victorious about yourself and about your ignorance."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (9th Day), Raise above Āgñyā (Left Āgñyā and Right Āgñyā), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1267.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"This Pūjā is very special, many will go deep and receive tremendous blessings. But first make your attention steady. In your attention pray for peace, 'Mother, please bestow peace upon me.' <b>Pray for peace so that you may spread peace in the Universe. Then Joy will come. Joy cannot come without Peace.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0329 Śhrī Śhailaputrī Devī Pūjā (English + Hindi) (7th Day of Chaitra Navarātri), Exhibition Hall, Basement of the Puruṣhottam Hotel, Talnoo, Naddi (11 kms NNE of Dharmaśhālā), Himachal Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1027 Navarātri Pūjā (13th day after Dussehra Day), Develop Wisdom through Meditation, Bhakti and Śhraddhā, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/251307065"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Devī Sūktam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/K7he8axOgfw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Durgā Ādi Śhakti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/IZxG3j1wUyE">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī playing harmonium as Sahaja Yogis sing Devī Bhajans</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1268.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"...... 'God has given you so much, why should you try to show that you haven't got anything?' Just to show off that you have not got anything, God has given.<br />
<b>This is just a sort of a thanksgiving to God that, 'God, you have given me so much.' You have to wear the best, like in Pūjā if you see ladies here wear all their nose rings and all their ornaments and everything, in the temple</b>, everything they wear, and in the same way, men also wear their very clean dresses, very clean things, whatever they have, they wear simple clean dresses, whatever they have but no ostentatious, it is just a thing by which you express. <b>The God has given this, 'O God, I thank you.'</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0101 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Mahālakṣhmī Principle of Our Ascent (Try to Develop that Innocence which Is the Basis of Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa and Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa Is Strengthened through Guru Principle), Nirmalā Kuṭīr (Cottage), Lakṣmī Nārāyaṇa Mandir, Shahupuri, Kolhapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Indigo"><b>We should devote ourselves to that Devī<br />
Who resides at the center of our lotus hearts,<br />
Whose glory is like that of the rising sun,<br />
Whose face is pleasing,<br />
Who grants all boons and protection,<br />
Who is three-eyed, Who wears red clothes, and<br />
Who fulfills the desires of Her devotees.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Devī Atharva Śhīrṣha)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, you have to understand that you cannot rationalize the Pūjā. You should have the maximum advantage on your chakras.</b> For that, you must fully just concentrate on the Pūjā and how the Wind is blowing. And the Wind will see to it that they drive out all the clouds.<br />
So your only work is, or your only method is just to concentrate on the Pūjā and witness. You are a Seer. Seer has double meaning. The one who sees only, just sees, and is only knowledge is a Seer. Without any thought, without any reaction, just sees and absorb[s] automatically, spontaneously -- is the Seer. And so, that is the best way to perform a Pūjā.<br />
For Me sometimes it's burdensome, because there should be some parity between you and the Deities. Some balance must be there."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0618 Havan, Importance of Pūjā and Havan, before Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā, Garden, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Siddhidatri" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>