<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-16T18:50:52-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Festival of Holī: “You should have faith in God”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/07" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Festival of Holī: “You should have faith in God”" /><published>2023-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/2023-03_07_Holika_Dahana</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/07"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, the great day of Holikā Dahana</b>, where the symbolism of this occasion is that the satanic forces were burnt by the innocence of Prahlāda. And that is what we have to remember, that when the Sahaja Yogis take to innocence and complete dependence on to their vibratory awareness, which is the indication of God’s Manifestation through them, they are completely protected, and even a satanic person like Holikā could not burn him [them].<br />
And this is the day today, we have to recognize that, as Sahaja Yogis, we stand no dangers in life. We are fearless people, but we are humble people, loving people, and anxious to save as many as possible. To raise the whole humanity into another awareness, in the process of your evolution, you have to achieve ghaṭ, for which you have to work hard."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0328 Public Program (Holikā Dahana) (English+Hindi), Concept and Reality, Birthday Celebration, Ajwan-E-Ghalib, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1125.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Sahaja Yogis all over the world are doing very important work. They are doing very vital work of God of giving Self-realization. This is the need in this Time of Resurrection.<br /> 
Everyone must help in every way possible to deepen and expand the experience of Divinity so that all the human race could be saved and glorified as the great children of God Almighty."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0328 Message (Holikā Dahana), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Śhrī Rāma incarnated before Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. He was Maryādā Puruṣhottama and as such lived a very austere life. As a result of the austerities practiced by the King Himself, the whole society turned sober and serious. The element of joy and gaiety was completely missing. In Dwāpara Yuga, when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa incarnated, He wanted to put an end to this extreme seriousness prevalent in the society. He thought of having a festival in which everyone could laugh heartily and have fun and joy. So the festival of color Holī, was started with this purpose. People, however, took undue liberties and misused the festival to the extent of defaming it. I had also to tell that “I do not play Holī at all.”<br />
The myth behind it is that there was a demoness named Holikā. She was the sister of Hiraṇyakaśhipu, the father of Prahlāda. Since Prahlāda was the devotee of Lord Viṣhṇu, his father, the demon king, used to harass and trouble him. Hiraṇyakaśhipu wanted to kill Prahlāda. Holikā had the boon that fire won’t burn her. Hiraṇyakaśhipu asked Holikā to take the boy Prahlāda in her lap and sit on the burning pyre, thinking that she could not be burnt. But to his surprise Holikā was burnt to ashes and no harm done to the child devotee of Śhrī Viṣhṇu! It was a significant incident which proved that it is sin to be cruel, arrogant and aggressive. Despite her boon, Holikā was burnt down and no harm done to the innocent child – devotee!<br />
Such is the myth and traditionally we burn Holī every year. There lies a lot of truthfulness in all our traditions. We have to understand that misdeeds, cruelties and troubling others are evil tendencies. Right-sided people develop these devilish traits in them. We should not allow such thoughts to dominate our brains and should give no significance to them. We should love all. It is very important to understand otherwise we shall all be demonic like Holikā. Now right-sided people develop this problem. It is a big lesson for them. No harm was done to the innocent child Prahlāda. God Almighty saved him, but this demonic woman, who got a boon as a result of her severe penance was reduced to ashes. One should understand that all these demonic tendencies are destructive. We should give them up and be generous and loving towards all. Quarreling and fighting with each other are not virtues. These are demonic tendencies.<br />
We should not take to these evil traits, we are Sahaja Yogis. <b>We are special people, we have incarnated to change this world, to transform it completely. We should put our attention on that. We are very highly placed, higher than all others. We have to save this world from falling to these tendencies.</b> These are much in vogue these days. It is unworthy to say these abhorrent things and to be cruel and dominate others. It is unnecessary in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
You are powerful enough. You have such powers within you that if someone endeavors to trouble you, you will be protected like Prahlāda. No one could destroy you. You are so much protected! No such thing could destroy you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0329 Holī Pūjā (Hindi) (Holī Raṃgavalī), Palam Vihar, Gurgaon, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1126.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"You should have faith in God that is the main thing which people don’t understand what it means to have faith in God. 
That He is almighty, He does everything, He looks after everything, why should we worry?"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0625 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Picnic, Richmond Park, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>As you know, on the Day of Holī, Holikā was burnt.</b> Agni [God of Fire] had a very big blessing and task, because Agni Devatā had given Holikā a boon that in any circumstance, she will not burn, that death could come to her in any form, but not by fire. And after giving this boon, he regretted a lot because she took Prahlād in her lap and sat in the fire. And Agni Devatā had a big dilemma, that ``I have given this promise to her, that I will not burn her and how can I fulfill this promise? <b>And Prahlād, is Himself innocence personified, He is Himself an Incarnation of Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b> and how can I burn Him? Nobody can burn Him. And He is also beyond my powers. He is formed from my power." So he thought, ``What is this ego? that in front of such a Great Power what can I talk about my power? I have no such power which can face Him. His Power is so great that I cannot burn Him whatsoever I may try. But at this time I have a very big dilemma in front of me.""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebrations, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1127.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"So, today, on the Holī Day if you only say the mantra of Holikā Dahan, then with the mantra of Holikāmardinī you can wash My Feet. And the children should worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha and while worshiping Him, they can wash My Feet. Saying the three great mantras you can wash My Feet. No need to do anything more."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebrations, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"I think we have had a nice time in this Holī, and we should always have such a nice time. Always with Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa’s blessings, you all should enjoy your Holī. But the greatest Holī is within yourself when you fill yourself with all kinds of colors.<br />
Your nature should be such that everybody should enjoy that color. That color that is within you, color of beauty – not artificial, just showing off, just giving something without any love."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0317 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (English+Hindi+English), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebration, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1128.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"He started playing with colors and so on.<br />
<b>All the colors also, if you see, are the colors of the Devī Holi is played with the colors of the seven chakras.</b><br />
Put all the colors of the chakras onto you! play with joy, enthusiasm, and happiness."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebrations, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumPurple">"Then the</font> <b>colors</b> <font color="MediumPurple">are, the</font> <font color="brown">colors</font> <font color="MediumPurple"><b>are all representing your chakras</b>. These are all the chakras as you know. Every chakra has</font> got <font color="MediumPurple">a</font> different color. <font color="MediumPurple">So what happens? These colors just get distributed in the air, in the atmosphere. During Holi time you [Unclear know you] are representing those colors which are completely permeating into the atmosphere. So this is another thing when you play colors. When you color another person, you are just expressing that these, your chakras will be blessed.</font> <font color="DarkRed"><b>Red color is of the Mūlādhāra.</b></font> <font color="MediumPurple">All those colors that you use here are of different chakras. So just you are making the whole expression of your love that let it be you become completely filled with red color, means innocence, means innocence. Because as a child in the womb of the mother just sees the red color of the mother, color of the blood.</font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple">So like that, you see different colors are spread on the face. And</font> <font color="DarkGreen"><b>abhira is the green color of the Guru Tattwa</b>.</font> <font color="MediumPurple">Like that all these colors have got significance that they are the colors of your chakras which you are spreading all over to your friends, to your other brothers and sisters who are Sahaja Yogis. So it has that symbolic expression that you are spreading your – actually the essence of your chakra, the basis of your chakra,</font> <font color="bluee">the colors of your chakra, the fragrance of those chakras to other Sahaja Yogis.</font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple">You just permeate, permeating. I don’t know in Hindi language if there is a better word like in Marathi ‘ud-har’, udahr. ‘Udhar’ means just ... [Hindi.]<br />
...</font> <font color="DarkRed">red color, is the sign of innocence.</font> <font color="MediumPurple">So Kabīra</font> says that, <font color="MediumPurple">“You put me into such a color. Oh, the one who is going to color me is the One.” Rangaraj is the one who colors things. So He says, “Oh Rangaraj, make me so that the whole thing becomes red – innocence, fills me up with complete innocence.” And innocence is the one he has asked for to be filled in. And same is with Shrī Kṛiṣhṇa that He played with all these different colors to show that there are different</font> chakras <font color="MediumPurple">within us apart from the red and the others that are there. All of them play a part to create a beautiful joyful personality."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0317 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (English+Hindi+English), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebration, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1129.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The Main Power of Rādhājī was to give joy.<br />
Her Main Power was to give joy to everyone.<br />
And that's why She then started this festival of Holī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebrations, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Tere ranga me aise range ham, dujā ranga nā lāge,</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>We are colored so deep and complete in Your color</b></font><br />
<font color="MediumPurple">Tum bin koi nazar nā āe, in naino ke āge</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>No other color will reflect through us, We are unable to see anything but You</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkCyan">Jala ko sthala ko sāre jagata,Rangā ranga banāyā</font><br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>Through these eyes, You have made not only water and land But the whole universe very colorful</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed">Ranga de jhini Hari, Mā ke ranga me kāyā,</font> <font color="MediumPurple">(kāyā)</font><br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>God (Hari) please color my body (kaya) in the color of my Holy Mother</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkOrange">Ranga nā de ise, chanchala mana ko, Apne ranga me māyā</font><br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>Let my body not be adorned, By the hideous color of materialism</b></font><br />
<font color="Maroon">Ranga de jhini Hari, Mā ke ranga me kāyā, (kāyā)</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>God (Hari) please color my body in the color of my Holy Mother</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zcAvt3cDa0Y">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0329 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Raṃgavalī Holī Celebrations, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/136679884"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="Red"><b>Holi Khelat</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Śhrī Mā Hain Rang Raij Chunar Mori Rang</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mātājī Playing with Dandiya Sticks (1990-0819 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Ipswich, UK)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="orange"><b> Āj Rang Hai Sahaj Ka</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/kAeQs-Xga_Q">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Kṛiṣhṇa Govinda</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Holika Dahana" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Mahāsamādhi Day: “I am the Holy Ghost, I am the Holy Spirit, who has incarnated on this earth for your Realization.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/02/23" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Mahāsamādhi Day: “I am the Holy Ghost, I am the Holy Spirit, who has incarnated on this earth for your Realization.”" /><published>2023-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/02/2023-02_23_Paramachaitanya_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/02/23"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Many Sahaj Yogis are sitting here. I am telling something new for them. If you are Sahaja Yogis, then it should be expressed in your behavior. Every one should know that you are Sahaja Yogis. We should know that a person is either a Sahaja Yogi or a non-Sahaja Yogi. We should know the art of integrating all. With this Sahaj Swabhāv you should conquer the whole world.<br />
Register in your heart what I have said.<br />
<b>This is My vision. You people could fulfill and relieve Me of My heartache.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0407 Śhrī Bhūmī Devī Pūjā (Hindi), Inauguration of the H.H. Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī Foundation, Nirmal Dham, Behind BSF Camp Chhawala, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1118.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">Thank You for revealing to us within the human body the reflection of the Vishwa-rupa (universal form).<br />
Thank You for revealing to us the primordial principles of creation.<br />
Thank You for revealing to us the reality of human nature.<br />
Thank You for revealing to us the meaning of true religion.<br />
Thank You for teaching us the divine knowledge of Sahaja Yoga.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>MAVENA NAYANI ANAND  
MAVENA NAYANI ANAND, HRUDAYAT SATCHITANAND</b></font><br />
I am unable to contain the Joy in my eyes when in my heart resides the joy of the Spirit<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">ANAND KITI HA MOTHA, SAUKHYAS KHADHI NA TOTA</font><br />
How great this joy is, which brings limitless bliss<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">KANA— KANAT NIRMALANAND HRUDAYAT SATCHITANAND</font><br />
For every particle is manifesting sheer joy, when in my heart resides the joy of the Spirit<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>SAGUNAT MAULI ĀLI, NIRGUNAT JANĪV DIDHALI</b></font><br />
Mother incarnated to raise our awareness to feel the formless,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">NIJARUPI RANGALE DHYAN, JADATET MATE CHAITANYA </font><br />
As we meditate upon Her, we discovered the chaitanya in this mundane world<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1119.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>My vision for Sahaja Yoga</b> is that, that all the good people, righteous people,<br />
God-loving people will rise above all that is useless, worldly, and reside in the Heavens with all the blessings of God, forever and ever."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0506 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Need to Go Deeper and Questions and Answers, Āśhram, 10 Clarence Street, Burwood, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Thank You for giving Sahaja Yoga to a confused and self-destructive humanity.<br />
Thank You for revealing to us the meaning of creation and evolution.<br />
Thank You for revealing to us the actual existence of God.<br />
Thank You for giving divine meaning to human existence.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Ap.Ne Dil Me</b><br />
Ap.Ne Dil Me Sahaj. Ko Basaya Karo</font><br />
Let the Sahaj settle in your heart<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Rachaita Ki Tum. Rach.Na Rachaya Karo</font><br />
Let the Creator's creation be created again in you<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Pah.Le Dhyan. Dharo Chit. Kabhu Karo</font><br />
First be in meditation then take command of your attention<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Kuṇḍalinī Tum Ap.Ni Jagaya Karo</font><br />
Then awaken your Kuṇḍalinī<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Thand. Chaitanya Swayam Bahaya Karo</font><br />
then allow the cool vibration to flow through you<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r45K0f-LKyc&amp;ab_channel=ThePrawah">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1120.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">Thank You for giving us meditation.<br />
Thank You for giving us inner peace.<br />
Thank You for giving us inner joy.<br />
Thank You for giving us enlightened attention.<br />
Thank You for giving us, detachment.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">MALA PĀHĪ PRABHUSANGE, DUI ATMA TAI PALE DURĪ</font><br />
When I am in the company of God, evil runs away<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">GALE SAMARTHYA MOHACHE NURE RUNT KUTHE VAIRĪ</font><br />
No temptation can dominate me and nobody can confront me<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">MALA BODHĀMRUT PĀJĪ, SADA ]AEI NAVI TRUPTĪ</font><br />
Every time I experience the Divine knowledge, I feel more satisfaction and Divine Joy<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">KUTHE CHINTA KUTHE DUKHHE KSHANE SĀRI LAVA JĀTĪ</font><br />
All moments of concerns and sorrows vanish<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">PRABHUSANGE MILE JĪVA, NASE KOTHE TASHI SHANTĪ</font><br />
Nowhere else can my soul find peace except in the company (in Union) with God Almighty<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">PRABHU MAZA SWAYE NĪTĪ, PRABHU MAZA SWAYE PRITĪ</font><br />
My God himself is Truth and Love<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1121.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"I am with you at every step, at every place. Everywhere. Wherever you are, at whichever place you are, I am with you, completely, in person, by My Spirit and by My word completely. This is My promise to you.<br />
......<br />
But you have to be Mine. It's important you have to be Mine, then in just seconds I will be with you. Let Paramātma give you joy (sukhī) and give you pure knowledge (subuddhi). Immense blessings!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0529 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Dhyān Kaise Karein (How to Meditate), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"> Thank You for Your continuous attention.<br />
Thank You for being the mirror.<br />
Thank You for being ever present.<br />
Thank You for being gentle.<br />
Thank You for being wonderful.<br />
<br />
Thank You for guiding us.<br />
Thank You for comforting us.<br /> 
Thank You for counselling us.<br />
Thank You for correcting us.<br />
Thank You for never abandoning us.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>HE PRABHO TU DNYANA RUPE, KALPAVRUKSHA LAVILE</b></font><br />
O God, You in the form of knowledge have planted the tree that fulfils all desires (kalpataru)<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">BAHARALYA SHAKHA TAYANCHYA, CHINTANI MAN. RANGALE</font><br />
The branches of the tree have blossomed; my mind has completely dissolved in it<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">VISHWA HE SAMAVILE</font><br />
It has completely embraced the whole universe<br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>SANSKRUTI GANGAUGH VAHE, TYAMADHE AWAGAWUNI</b></font><br />
The river of pure Sahaj culture is flowing and in that we are immersed<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">SHODHANYA SHIV. SATYA. SUNDAR. , DIVYA SHRADDHA GHEVUNI</font><br />
We are in search of the truth, beauty and the spirit with an enlightened faith<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">CHALALE PATH. SADHANECHA, GURU PADATE PAVALE</font><br />
We are on the path of seeking, following the Holy feet of the Guru<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">VISHWA HE SAMAVILE</font><br />
It has completely embraced the whole universe<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1122.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Tere Charan.kamal. me Rehnevalo me Likh.le Mera Nam</b></font><br />
May my name be added to the one of those who are seeking refuge at Thy Lotus Feet,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Ye Hai Sukh. Shanti Ka Dham</b></font><br />
For this is the heavenly abode of Joy eternal and Peace,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Nirmal Dham, Nirmal Dham, re</b></font><br />
The abode of Divinity and Purity.<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Aya Tha Shraddha Suman. Charhane Dale Jholi Me</font><br />
I have come to offer the flowers of pure faith at the Lotus Feet of Our Mother,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Ma Se Paunga Mai Kuchh. Dan. Bhi Dalu Jhole Me</font><br />
Expecting to be rewarded for my offering,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Saumya Prakash. Chet.na Dekhi</font><br />
But I found myself overwhelmed by the pleasant Chaitanya,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Jaise Bhor.ki Lali Me</font><br />
Radiating like a rising sun.<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Swar.pan. Kar.ke Bola Mai</font><br />
Surrendering myself to Her, I humbly requested<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Kuchh. Na Dalu Jholi Me</font><br />
That no reward should be given,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed">Nir.peksh. Yahi Bhakti Kutir Hai Chaitanya Ka Aisa Dham</font><br />
As I realized that worship can only exist through selfless surrender to the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī, the very abode of Chaitanya.<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mKrVNKlY7Hg">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>Supreme Source of Love</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/60342739"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>BHAYA KAY. TAYA PRABHU JYATZA RE</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Mā tere Nirmal prem ko</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Mother, we adore You</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LsWaC7NktHA?list=PLuAVZW42aaCnQ3JW90xymBbcyS-gt6SE1">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Ankhe band karu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Mā Nirmal Tere Yogi Hum</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Tum Asha Vishwas Hamare</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Paramachaitanya Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Mahāśhivarātri: “What else are you going to give to your children, but God?”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/02/18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Mahāśhivarātri: “What else are you going to give to your children, but God?”" /><published>2023-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/02/2023-02_18_Shivaratri_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/02/18"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are here to celebrate Mahāśhivarātri.</b><br />
It’s a very great privilege for all of us to understand about Śhrī Mahādeva. Unless and until you have got your Self-realization you cannot understand what is the great personality, the character, and the Powers of Śhrī Mahādeva.<br />
Is not easy to conceive, also to reach the depth, of His greatness unless and until we are humble. We have to be very humble to reach at the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mahādeva. As you have seen that one has to cross even the Sahasrāra to be at the Lotus Feet of this great personality. He is beyond, beyond all our conception, but He resides in our hearts as the Spirit, and is reflected very well when you get your Realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0225 Śhivarātri Pūjā, The Destructive Power of Śhrī Mahādeva, Śhrī Śhiv Chhatrapati Sports Complex Stadium, Balewadi, Mahalunge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1112.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"I have told you about the origin before.<br />
<b>Because on the Day of Mahāśhivarātri, when there is a talk about Śhivjī, then it has to begin with origin.<br />
How much He is Primordial, means when there is a first manifestation of form of God Almighty.</b><br />
He is called as Sadāśhiva when He is enlightened from Brahma.<br />
That is why the one who is Śhivjī is called as Ādi [Primordial].<br />
You see, before the complete manifestation of any tree its seed has to be seen first and that is why it has to be called ‘Bīj Swarūpa’ – form of the seed.<br />
That is why the glory of Śhiva is very important.<br />
After that, after His manifestation, the power within Him gets Her form and is called as Ādi Śhakti."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0229 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Utpatti -- Ādi Śhakti aur Śhiva ka Swarūp (Genesis -- Ādi Śhakti and Śhiva in Form), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are going to worship Śhiva Tattwa within us, Principle of Śhiva.</b><br />
For all Sahaja Yogis it’s very important, for [as] Śhiva is the ultimate we have to achieve. Śhiva is represented in our Spirit, so to become Śhiva is the ultimate aim of everything else. The rest of it is all created, like Viṣhṇu Tattwa and Brahmadeva, just to create human beings, to evolve them, and then ultimately lead them to Śhiva. That’s the Ultimate.<br />
But human beings get so involved into the Brahmadeva’s Tattwas that even to get into Viṣhṇu Tattwa is difficult. They get into involved into the five elements which have created us. That is the outermost being within us. All the chakras have the outermost, we can say, the ... just the vessel. But the desire to be the Spirit is of primal importance in Sahaj Yog."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0211 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English+Hindi), Śhiva Tattwa within Us and No Alternatives to Your Mother's Ideas, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1113.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Śhiva Tattwa is innocent, absolutely innocent it is. It’s very powerful and extremely innocent. And the secret to achieve it is only just to please, just please Him. If you please Śhiva, then you may be a rākṣhasa or anything, He grants all kinds of boons. But <b>to a rākṣhasa, He can only grant the boon of longevity, of long life. But to a Saint, He’ll grant the Sat-chit-ānanda State</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0211 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English+Hindi), Śhiva Tattwa within Us and No Alternatives to Your Mother's Ideas, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Pranava swaroopaya, chidakasaya,  Aakasa dik swaroopaya, Graha nakshatra maline,<br /> 
Sakalaya, Kalanka rahithaya, Sakala lokaika karthre, Sakala lokaika bharthre,<br />
Sakala lokaika samharthre,  Sakala lokaika gurave,<br />
Sakala lokaika Sakshine,  Sakala nigama guhyaya,</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><font size="+0"><b>He who is the form of “Om”, He who is the divine ether, He who is the personification of sky and directions, He who wears stars and planets as Garlands, He who is everything, He who does not have any dark spot, He who creates all the world, He who manages all the worlds, He who destroys all the worlds, He who is the teacher of all the world, He who is a witness of all the world, He who is hiding in all reasoning,</b><br />
Śhiva Kavach<br />
Sage Ṛiṣhabha, from Skanda Purāṇa</font></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"We have all assembled here to worship Lord Śhiva. <b>Śhiva Pūjā is a very great and special Pūjā. The ultimate aim of human beings is to attain that Śhiva Tattwa.</b> Śhiva Tattwa is beyond the brain. It cannot be known through the brain. Till you have got your Self-realization you cannot know the Self, Ātmā or the Śhiva Tattwa.<br /> 
Too much falsehood, myth, and blind faith has taken place in the name of Lord Śhiva. Till a person is self-realized he cannot know Lord Śhiva because his nature is such that to know him, a person has first to attain that height where all the great virtues themselves enshrine within.<br /> 
...... These Śhaktis reside within us through the Śhiva Tattwa. To attain the Śhiva Tattwa Self-realization is essential. Kuṇḍalinī is the Śhakti and the chakras are the steps. One has to ascend all the steps to attain the Śhiva Tattwa. This is the revelation of all the Gods and Deities. This is their job and they are completely absorbed in it. Unlike human beings, they do not think about themselves or their rank, etc. They are a part and parcel of Lord Śhiva. To facilitate human ascent to the Śhiva Tattwa is their nature.<br /> 
They need not be lectured or told anything, they are completely submerged in their task. They work in karma. They do not think they are doing anything. They are thoughtless and unmindful for their powers, like sugar gives sweetness to food, but is unaware that it is sweet. Similarly, when Sahaja Yogis act they are not aware of the Śhakti within which is behind their actions. If the consciousness comes that I am the doer, I am a leader, etc. then you are not a Sahaja Yogi. Through Sahaja Yoga one becomes a karmi. He keeps performing without even remembering that he is doing anything. He does not even realize that he is loving though others find him very loving."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0219 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Kyukī Mānava kā Aṃtima Lakṣhya yahī hai kī Vo Śhiva Tattwa ko Prāpta Kare (The Ultimate Aim of Human Beings Is to Attain that Śhiva Tattwa), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1114.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Except for Śhiva Tattwa, what other friend you need?</b> Think of it, without God, what is your life?<br />
So the detachment must start, the priorities must change and <b>you must know that God is the One who is your Friend, who is your Father, who is your Mother, who is to be worshiped, there is nothing else.
Tana, mana, dhana, everything is for God.</b><br /> 
Of course, I don’t want anything from you, you know that.<br />
But that should be the attitude of a person."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0211 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English+Hindi), Śhiva Tattwa within Us and No Alternatives to Your Mother's Ideas, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Auṃ Śhivam Śhivakaram Śhantam Śhivakaram
Śhivot-tamam Śhivamarga Pranetaram Pranatosmi Sadāśhivam</b></font><br />
<font color="indigo">Auṃ to the auspicious One, the bestower of auspiciousness, the One who is peace, who is the auspicious Spirit, the highest, most auspicious, and beautiful one, who is the path of auspiciousness, before whom everyone prostrates,<br /> 
I bow to the Lord God Almighty.</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I had told that Śhiva Pūjā means more explanation, more understanding, more this thing; because in other Pūjās we do all these mantras, this, that, but <b>in this Pūjā is to know the knowledge, it’s God.</b><br />
And to know that you know God itself is so great. Whatever it is – She may be Mahāmāyā, She may be anything, but I know Her. It cannot be described in one book, it cannot be described in hundred books.<br />
It cannot be described in words, but to know that’s God – after all, that’s God, God Almighty. And that gives you that beautiful surrender, where you just feel absolutely secured in that Ocean of Love.
I wish you all to achieve that state.<br />
May God bless you".</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0216 Śhivarātri Pūjā, Four Nāḍīs of the Heart, Cinema Garden Theater, Chianciano Terme, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The aspect of Śhrī Śhiva is found in our heart. Whenever somebody becomes the Spirit, I am not saying gets enlightened, but when the <b>Kuṇḍalinī gets awakened this Principle of Śhrī Śhiva gets enlightened. This light first comes into our brain and our heart and thus for the first time there is Yoga, i.e., Union of the brain and the heart</b>. Otherwise, normally there is no relation between man’s heart and his brain. They each run in separate directions. This light which is emitted from the Spirit flows through our hands and fontanel bone areas as vibrations."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0316 Śhivarātri Pūjā, These Rudras Are to Be Satisfied (Channels of the Divine and Torch on the Path of Truth, Love and Joy), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhiva is your Guru. Guru is the one that gives you the gravity to go straight down, deep into it.</b><br />
That is very important.<br />
And all this, I hope with the Pūjā today, we’ll try to settle your ... into that Great Principle of Śhiva. Let your attention, every particle of your attention be filled, sparkled and rejoice by that blessing of Śhiva Tattwa.<br />
I bless you all. May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0211 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English+Hindi), Śhiva Tattwa within Us and No Alternatives to Your Mother's Ideas, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1115.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Mahādeva is helpful in this, too. When your Kuṇḍalinī pierces the Sahasrāra, Śhrī Mahādeva is seated there. That is why He is called Mahādeva, the God of Gods ......"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2004-0215 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi+English), Kalyāṇ and Kaiyvalya, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="indigo"><b>Sat-chid’ānanda rūpah, Shivo’ham, Shivo’ham </b></font><br />
<font color="indigo">I am in the form of Sat (truth, Self or existence), Chit (awareness or consciousness) and Ananda (bliss or pure joy), I am Śhiva, I am Śhiva!</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But when He finds that in the play of Ādi Śhakti, the people or the world as such, try to disturb Her or to spoil Her work, then He gets into His wrathful mood, and He destroys all such people, and maybe, He destroys the whole world.<br />
<b>On one side He’s wrathful, no doubt, on the other side, He is the Ocean of Compassion and Joy. That’s why, when He is reflected within us, we get our Self-realization, we get the light of our Spirit and we get into the Ocean of Joy.</b><br />
Also He is the Ocean of Knowledge, so those who get self-realized get the Knowledge of the Divine, which is very subtle, permeating into every atom and molecule, the Power of this Knowledge is there. His style is such that, in his compassion, He forgives even very cruel rākṣhasas, if they dedicate themselves to Him. Because His Compassion has no limits and sometimes the same people who are blessed by Him try to trouble the devotees of Ādi Śhakti – but it is just to create a drama, an event."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0303 Śhivarātri Pūjā, Motivate Your Attention or God's Realization, Bundilla Scout Camp, 6 Baden Powell Pl, Winston Hills (35 kms E of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1116.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"And I am sure after this Śhiva Pūjā, you will dedicate yourself to Śhiva Principle within you.<br />
Śhiva Principle doesn’t ‘stir out’, it’s very, very stern, it’s very powerful. You have to dedicate, and you have to surrender.</b><br />
Above every other job, above every other performance, the highest is this.<br />
So, with this, I ask Śhiva to give you blessings, complete blessings, so that you get transformed into the personality of Śhiva.<br />
May God bless you all."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0317 Śhivarātri Pūjā, The Power of Love, Śhrī Śhiv Chhatrapati Sports Complex Stadium, Balewadi, Mahalunge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"...... <b>we will give Him what He likes the most: is the belapatra, which is at ... leaf which has got three leaves on one stem. 
Which means: His Three Powers, Triguṇātmika, Threesh Powers.<br />
So, with our Three Powers, our Triguṇās, our Three Powers, we surrender ourselves to Śhiva.<br />
And, by that, we show that: ‘We give our triguṇas to You so that we become Guṇātīt.’<br />
This is what is the Śhiva Pūjā.</b><br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0225 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Marathi+English) (Śhivarātri Day), Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0211 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English+Hindi), Śhiva Tattwa within Us and No Alternatives to Your Mother's Ideas, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/119649836"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gaiye Gaṇapati Jagvandan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhiva Manasa </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhiva Aṣhṭakam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhole baba Chale Kailash</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhambho Śhaṅkara</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Dum Dum Damroo, Om Namah Śhivaye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Lalat.Pe Hai Chandra Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bolo Śhiva Śhambhu Śhiva Śhaṅkara</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bolo Śhiv Śhiva Śhambhu Bam Bam Bam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhiv Bhola Bhandari</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Śhiva Āratī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1117.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="indigo"><b>O Most Auspicious and Compassionate Lord, beloved of Śhrī Pārvatī, father of Śhrī Gaṇeśh and Śhrī Kārttikeya, not even one blade of grass moves without Your willing it so. Śhrī Ādi Śhakti has created all these planets, worlds, rivers and seas, humans, animals, and plants, in the eternal play of creation - only to be pleasing to You. And in complete joy, and complete detachment, You witness it all. She did all of this out of great kindness and mercy so that we, Your bhaktas, could find You again and again in the depths of our being.</b><br />
O Lord, You are the Absolute, the Fundamental Principle, the Transcendent and Unchanging Truth. You have neither beginning nor end. You are the very origin of the Self, You are both formless and omnipresent in every form. We worship You as the first syllable Auṃ. Verily You are the Creator and the Preserver. You are the Source of all knowledge. All sublime Arts and aesthetics flow from You.<br />
<b>Salutations to The Eternal Yogi, whose pale skin has the dazzling brilliance of ten million suns. You are eternally and blissfully in meditation. You reside in the snowy white peaks of Mount Kailasha, and You reside in our heart chakra; Your love sustaining each particle of creation. Verily You are the embodiment of innocence, utterly beautiful to behold.  Salutations to The Ascetic One, detached from all worldly comforts, whose radiant form is smeared with ashes. The skin of a fierce and majestic tiger adorns You. Your trident is poised to destroy all evils. And the rhythmic drum beat of Your damaru controls the beating hearts of each living soul.</b><br />
Verify You are Śhrī Neelkant whose throat has turned blue from consuming all the poisons of this entire world. You are the one who defeats the seven enemies of the soul, thus ending all worldly desires and delusions. You wear a rosary of holy Rudraksha seeds said to be made from Thine own tears of compassion. Salutations to Trilochana whose Lotus Eyes brim with love.<br />
<b>To meditate upon You is to drop into the ocean of Sachchidānanda, so that the meditating Saints and Sages of all times sing Your glories. Salutations to the One with disheveled and matted locks that billow in the mountain breezes carrying forth Thy divine fragrance; for verily You are the Lord of the Wind. You are our life breath and our lifeline. The shining crescent moon is worn as a jewel in the midnight black of Your hair, and You wear a necklace of glittering stars. From the sacred crown of Your topknot, the River Gaṅgā cascades in a joyful, purifying stream into our upturned palms as Cool Vibrations.</b><br />
We praise You as Śhrī Paśhupati, Lord and protector of animals. Your faithful servant Nandi, the bull calf, is Your Vāhana.  All creatures great and small seek Thy refuge, even those animals most feared by man. In Thy benevolence, You offer even the serpents the warmth of Your body to protect them from the icy chill of the Himalayas. Verily You are Śhrī Nnāgabhūṣhaṇa wearing a garland of snakes in three coils, representing the primordial Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
<b>We praise the One who stands on one foot, poised beyond and above the three worlds. The wise beings of all kalpas, lokas and yugas, who only exist by Your will, bow down in great thankfulness and ask for forgiveness at Your Lotus Feet. We worship Lord Naṭarāj whose cosmic Tāṇḍava Dance, in the never-ending cycle of time, eventually brings the whole universe to an end.  And we pull our ears now, we seek forgiveness for any mistakes we may make in this Pūjā. We pray that Śhrī Gaṇeśha and all the deities be present. We ask forgiveness for our attention straying from the blissful realm of spirit. And pray, please remove all ignorance, egoism, attachments, and delusions, that hinder our spiritual growth as Sahaja Yogis. Oh, Mahādeva, O Giver of Boons, please bestow auspiciousness, wisdom, and peace upon us all, may we be completely drenched by the pure joy of Bhakti.</b></font><br />
<br />
(Śhrī Śhivarātri Invocation Prayer 2019, by Sahaja Yogis of the United Kingdom)
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shivaratri Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Vasant Panchami: “Saraswatī was born as the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/26" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Vasant Panchami: “Saraswatī was born as the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa”" /><published>2023-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/2023-01_26_Vasant_Panchami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/26"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The right one is the Mahāsaraswatī Power. This one gives you the right sympathetic nervous system.</b><br />
The central one is the Suṣhumṇā. This is the path of our evolution. Throughout we have evolved through this path of the Suṣhumṇā, where you ascend up to the Sahasrāra, and when you cross that, then you become a realized Soul. This is called as the Mahālakṣhmī's Power.<br />
Mahākālī, Mahāsaraswatī and Mahālakṣhmī, and three of Them put together in the brain, then become the Ādi Śhakti, the Primordial Mother. And that also we call it as the Ādi Śhakti's Seat, that is above your head."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-1205 Public Program (English+Marathi), Day 2, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1103.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have the idea to do Saraswatī’s Pūjā.</b><br />
[<font color="orange">unclear</font>] I have seen that here people worship Mahākālī and Saraswatī, people worship Devī and people are simple natured.<br />
We should worship Saraswatī as well.<br />
Saraswatī’s work is very great. First, Mahāsaraswatī created the entire universe.<br />
The earth element is special in this. The earth element has been placed in such a way between the Sun and the Moon that any living work can easily happen on it.<br />
From this living work, slowly and gradually human beings have been generated.<br />
But we should know our own great power.<br />
That power is what we call creation power, it’s also called creativity.<br />
This creation power is the blessing of Saraswatī by which many arts have been generated. The evolution of art is due to the blessings of Saraswatī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0403 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Emerlin College, Yamunānagar, Haryana, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumPurple"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Hiraṇyagarbha (Prajāpati) is the creator aspect of God Almighty. It acts in the stomach of the Primordial Being which is a Void, also referred to as the Ocean of Illusion (Bhavasāgara). (The way this Void was created is covered later.) <b>Hiraṇyagarbha’s Power incarnates as Mahāsaraswatī, and the entire material creation is the product of Her power and activity:</b> She created all the galaxies, stars, and planets including our own Sun, Moon, and Earth. She also functions as the thinking power of the Primordial Being, and this process generates the Cosmic Ego (Ādi Ahaṅkāra). The channel carrying this power is the Ādi Piṅgalā Nāḍī, and it expresses the Primordial Preconscious Mind (Ādi Chitta). It acts like a postman who carries messages to the intellect of the Almighty."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Mahāsaraswatī Principle is on the right side as I’d ... you all know. First is the Brahmadeva’s Principle, which is the Saraswatī Principle, and then this Mahāsaraswatī takes you to the Principle of Mahābrahmadeva called as Hiraṇyagarbha.<br />
Now, <b>this Hiraṇyagarbha Principle is very important for Sahaja Yogis</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0223 Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī Pūjā, Modern Art and Literature, 24 Pukenui Road, Epsom, Auckland, New Zealand</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But ... <b>the Power of Saraswatī becomes Mahāsaraswatī when It is manifested by the Mahābrahmadeva, which is called as Hiraṇyagarbha.</b> For that She has to cross through the Haṃsa. She crosses through Haṃsa and becomes the Viṣhṇumāyā Śhakti. I mean, She ... <b>She is the Viṣhṇumāyā Śhakti. So Saraswatī becomes the Viṣhṇumāyā. She crosses at two points: one at Haṃsa and another at Viśhuddhi. So, She is the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
So Saraswatī was born as the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1104.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"The second power, which He gave us, which He sent to us, was Mahāsaraswatī and to this Mahāsaraswatī Power, <b>He called Counselor, the one who will counsel you – that means, who helps us for Yoganirūpaṇ [to see the form of Yoga]</b>.<br />
With the help of this second power, we will get Gyān [Knowledge], we will know the subtle knowledge."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0414 Easter Pūjā (Hindi), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Only the Sahaja Yogis, those who are enlightened people, can worship Mahāsaraswatī. Otherwise, people can only worship Saraswatī because with worship of Saraswatī you can read books, you can create dances, music, for the amusement of human beings, but actually the Saraswatī Pūjā is meant for people of ordinary awareness, means ordinary or normal human awareness. But for Sahaja Yogis, it is the Mahāsaraswatī which is to be worshiped."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So today’s Pūjā is going to be especially for you all to develop that creativity of talking, behaving in every way in a fiery way.</b> That is going to put them right, nothing else.<br />
In creative work also when we create something or we sing something and all that, if you go on singing say in our Indian style, some music which is [unclear] very slow tālas, that won’t go.<br />
...... So this is My understanding of today’s happening that in this natural surrounding, these natural surroundings where we are blessed by the work of Brahmadeva and Saraswatī, and where we can feel the capacity of these Deities, to what extent They can create. The nature is absolutely one with the Divine.<br />
...... <b>Just like the nature is one with Me, you are also one with Me. And that will should start happening when you will really become absolutely drawn into Sahaja Yoga, surrendered into Sahaja Yoga. Then only it will happen.</b><br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1105.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Only for hymns to be sung in the praise of God. All music should be in the praise of God. 
All rāgas should be in the praise of God."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0202 Public Program (English+Hindi), Day 4, The Viśhuddhi Chakra, N.D.M.C. Park, Hanumān Road, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tu swar ki Devī, ye sangīt, tujh se,</b><br />
You are the goddess of music, and this song,<br />
<b>Har Shabd tera hai har geet tujh se,</b><br />
all its words and the tune, comes from You.<br />
<b>Ham paar Sahaj mein, teri kripa se</b><br />
Only with Your compassion we become paar in Sahaj.<br />
<b>Nirmal Vidya ka vardan de ma</b><br />
Please grant us the boon of Śhrī Nirmala Vidyā.</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/v7T1xpKkYFU"> video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"And then is in the left hand She has a book, so She – that means that the Power of Saraswatī gives you the full creativity by which you can create books. That also means that, but must have in the books means that whatever you’re doing now – supposing you’re doing Sahaja Yoga, Sahaja Yoga is say concerning the Divine. So we must know what are in the books, means in the Scriptures. We must know how it relates to the Scriptures like it should not be something just coming like a mushroom knowledge, but it should be related to the books, means which is already written down, which is already being typed, being printed.<br />
But that doesn’t mean that it is a bookish knowledge, but it is whatever you have found out, whatever you have discovered has to be related to the books. And that is the Power She gives us, that She relates.<br />
Like when you must have read many books where there are quotations, even I use many quotations, and I give you now this all this knowledge is already part of it, I should say not the all, but part of it from the books in the sense it is written about Saraswatī and everything.<br />
So <b>one must learn how to respect the books, specially the Scriptures.<br />
And She’s the One Who gives you the penetration power into these books: to know what is the truth and what is not, penetration power to understand what is written between the lines, what is the subtle meaning of the whole thing, that is the Power of Saraswatī</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In school, our kids are absorbing knowledge. But we should be careful that without Self-realization whatever knowledge you get will be impure knowledge. Without Self-realization, whether you study science or economics, you will neither understand it completely nor you will be able to bring it in your creation power.<br />
Kids are of two types: one loves studying and the other don’t enjoy studying. Some kids have less brain and others have more.<br />
<b>Brain is also the gift of Saraswatī but the Ātmā gives us wisdom. Whatever knowledge you get from your brains, until you weigh it on your wisdom, then that knowledge becomes harmful.</b><br />
...... <b>With the realization of the Ātmā, itself, the brain gets the incandescent of Śhrī Saraswatī</b>, and even the children who are weak in reading and writing start doing good work. After this, the growth of art begins.<br />
If one wants to develop art without Self-realization the art is not treated with respect [is unrecognized] and there is no name or sign of it and is eventually lost.<br />
So, <b>first of all, getting the Self-realization and then doing Saraswatī Pūjā is in itself a great thing</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0403 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Emerlin College, Yamunānagar, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1106.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>O! Mother, Śhrī Mātājī Devī!<br />
Please grant us that Pure Knowledge<br />
which Keeps our attention always at Your Lotus Feet<br />
O ! Mother, please teach us knowledge of devotion since you are only realized by devotion.<br />
O, dearest Mother, show us the path of Nirmala Dharma,<br />
Please take us under your protection as we are unknowledgeable</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Pg. 109 of <b>Prayers, Praises and Protocol</b>)</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/85858039"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>108 Names of Śhrī Saraswatī</b> (with meaning and subtitles)</font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=s4LFP7LoF6A&amp;ab_channel=SahajayogaCulture">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Aisa Do Hamein Gyan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gyan De, Ma Nirmal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātā Saraswatī Sharda</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ObgRifcW6ao">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Pt. Bhimsen Joshi - Jai Jagdishwari Mātā Saraswatī - Savai Gandharva</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/JgZ9Muu3qaA">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1107.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Now the second one is Mahāsaraswatī, is at Māhūragaḍ. We always sing Māhūragaḍ. Wari song, that is the one – is Mahāsaraswatī, which is also called as Reṇukā Devī, that’s the right-sided Mahāsaraswatī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1221 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (Hindi+English), Hall, Kolhapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0"><b>Mahur Gadawari, Mahur Gadawari ga Tujha Vasa,<br />
On the hill of Mahur (village close to Nagpur), O goddess You stay,<br />
Bhakt. Yetil. Dar.Shanas.</b><br />
Devotees all come to receive your darshan.<br />
<b>Pivle patal ga, Pivle patal Buttedar</b><br />
You wear a yellow sari with golden design,<br />
<b>Angi Choli hi hirvigar.</b><br />
And a blouse of an intensely green color,<br />
Pitambarachi ga, pitambarachi Khowuni kas<br />
Dressed with pitambaras (yellow dhotis)<br />
<b>Bhakt. Yetil. Dar. Shanas.</b></font></font><br />
Devotees all come to receive Your Darśhan<br />
<font color="green"><font size="+0"><b>Mahur gadavari:</b></font></font> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EWoUoau4BOw&amp;ab_channel=SahajayogaCulture">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Vasant Panchami" /><category term="orange @ Shri Mahasaraswati Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Śhrī Vināyaka Chaturthī: “Today is a very big day because the actual Pure Spirit has taken birth today”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Śhrī Vināyaka Chaturthī: “Today is a very big day because the actual Pure Spirit has taken birth today”" /><published>2023-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/2023-01_24_Shri_Vinayaka_Chaturthi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha was made out of the, they say, it is a beautiful poetic way of saying it, out of the mud that was covering the Mother Pārvatī</b> or you can say the Gaurī at that time. Because She was not married in the sense that She was a virgin just finished her marriage and She was to meet her husband and this virgin wanted to have a bath before meeting her husband, so She cleanses her hands properly and makes this Deity of Śhrī Gaṇeśha which is bestowed on this center. If you really develop your proper insight through meditation you can see Śhrī Gaṇeśha settled down there very clearly.<br />
<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the Embodiment of Innocence</b> and that’s why He is a child, that’s why His head is that of an elephant because an elephant being an animal doesn’t grow into ego and superego like human beings do. That’s why He is a child. <b>He is the Embodiment of Childhood</b> and He incarnated on this Earth once which is described in Devī Bhāgavat[am] if you read as Mahāviṣhṇu."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0507 Public Program, Sahaja Yoga and Christianity, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1099.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"It is such a fortunate day today that we should come on the birth of Śhrī Gaṇeśha – today
is Vināyak Chaturthī, today – that we should celebrate this Pūjā."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0118 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (Vināyaka Chaturthī Day), House of Dr. Ramesh Adinath Saṃghavī, B.N-1, Sapt Shrung, Krishnanagar Housing Society, Saharanpur Road, Nasik, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0"><b>Abodhita dena sab. Sahaji ko</b><br />
Lord Gaṇeśha, please give us innocence<br />
<b>Nirmal bhakti dena sab ko</b><br />
Lord Gaṇeśha, please give us devotion<br />
<b>Shri Gaṇeśhaji ki puniya bhoomi par,</b><br />
In this land of Shri Gaṇeśha<br />
<b>Ek.ta ki Shakti sab ko</b><br />
Please grant us the power of collectivity<br />
<b>Jai Jai Bolo Nirmal Gaṇeśh. ki</b><br />
Victory to Shri Gaṇeśha!<br />
<b>Jay Jay Bolo Nirmal Gaṇeśha Kī</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a very important day for all of us Sahaja Yogis because today Shrī Gaṇesha was born.</b> Shrī Gaṇesha is whom we worship and because of whom we got our realization. However much you may remember Him, until you do not know His special qualities, you cannot attain Him. His special quality is that He is the embodiment of purity (shuddha swarūp) and complete Master of the Universe. He is the incarnation of the Supreme, of Brahman.<br />
By coming into this world He has created music (sangeet), rhythm (tāl), and notes (sur). By His Grace, only people become one with music (talleen)(engrossed). A small boy who came into the world and did such great work! He has given so many things to everyone and even today He is active. Shrī Gaṇesha’s Pūjā, no matter how much you do it, it is not enough. A lot of people say we don’t see Shrī Gaṇesha, even after worshipping Him so much, we do not attain Him."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0210 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>But when Pārvatī made Śhrī Gaṇeśha, He was the Son of Pārvatī alone.</b> There was no Father. Pārvatī Herself wanted to have a child of Her own. There were angels who were dedicated either to Viṣhṇu or to Śhiva like gaṇas were dedicated to Śhiva alone. So, She wanted to have Her own Son who can permeate Her Powers on this Earth.<br />
So to begin with when the Śhakti created this universe and Sadāśhiva was watching Her creation, <b>the first thing She created on this Earth was innocence and the Embodiment of that Innocence was Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Holmes Lodge, YMCA Camp Marston, 4761 Pine Hills Road, Julian (near San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1100.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>You cannot feel joyous until you worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
By worshiping Śhrī Gaṇeśha, your joy increases, you become joyous, because He is the personification of joy</b> (Ānand Swarūp).<br />
Because of this, both things are today, His birthday and His help.<br />
We take His help in any work what we do. Such is our way. But we don’t see what we have to do to awaken Him.<br />
In that direction our attention does not go. We do not feel that we should become like Him, that we should have a state in which Śhrī Gaṇeśha is awakened within us.<br />
 With which we may never venture on the wrong path."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0210 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0"><b>Jay Gaṇeśha, Jay Gaṇeśha, Jay Gaṇeśha Deva</b><br />
Jay Lord Gaṇeśh<br />
<b>Mata Teri Pārvatī, Pita Mahādeva</b><br />
Your Mother is Pārvatī, Your Father is Mahādeva<br />
<b>O Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva</b><br />
O Jai Jay Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva<br />
<b>Ek. Danth. Devadant. Char. Bhujadari</b><br />
O God, You are single toothed with four hands,<br />
<b>Mas.Tak. Sindhur Shobhe Chuhe Ki Sawari</b><br />
the red sindoor suits Your forehead, and You are mounted on a humble mouse.<br />
<b>O Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva</b><br />
O Jay Jay Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva</font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LtqNdCxPQI0">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we are going to worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
As you know, in the whole of Europe, America, England, they have lost faith in Śhrī Gaṇeśha. Nor do they care for His Powers and for His blessings. As result, all His blessings are not on these countries.<br />
The first blessing of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, which is, I think is the highest, is the wisdom, that we learn what is good for us and what is bad for us, what is constructive and what is destructive, what should we do to achieve our Self-realization. Those people who have got wisdom are very lucky people."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0721 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Qualities of Śhrī Gaṇeśha (Giver of Wisdom), Berlin, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is a very big day because the actual Pure Spirit has taken birth today.</b> And He already had such an eternal state, that many people could not comprehend it or write about it. They wrote only what they understood, but now that you are realized you can understand that by the Power of Śhrī Gaṇeśha’s name, you can get your Realization. By taking His name alone any disease or any pain will disappear. He is eternal. He is always present within us, when you get your Realization, you can feel Him.
And if you are not realized, you cannot understand Him. That is why people get misled and do wrong things. But with Śhrī Gaṇeśha’s blessings, you can do so many things and neither you will feel greedy, nor will you have any problems. Because He does all the work for you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0210 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1101.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Is so simple to establish Śhrī Gaṇeśh within you.<br />
But understand that it is vital that you people who are Sahaja Yogis should establish Śhrī Gaṇeśh, which is a silent Power within you, doesn’t talk. It’s a silent Power, which acts. Just a Power that’s dynamic, without any noise, without any show.<br />
And that is what I would say that today when I have said all these things from My heart, you the Sahaja Yogis will establish Śhrī Gaṇeśha within you. And from you, you will emit such powers that others will be able to establish their Śhrī Gaṇeśha in this country."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Holmes Lodge, YMCA Camp Marston, 4761 Pine Hills Road, Julian (near San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Sukh. Na Hi Kothe Ale Hya Sansari</b><br />
O Śhrī Gaṇeśha, there is no happiness in the world without You<br />
<b>Saumsaratsa Bhar. Sara Doyiwari</b><br />
You are the support of the whole world<br />
<b>Tu Dakhav. Maz. Mala Gao</b><br />
Please direct us to the village that is the Kingdom of God (kingdom within/in my heart)<br />
<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Kinaryala Lau</b><br />
Śhrī Gaṇeśha please steer our boat to that shore</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0721 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Qualities of Śhrī Gaṇeśha (Giver of Wisdom), Berlin, Germany</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25269437"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Oṃkār Pradhana Rūp Gaṇeśhache by Saint Tukārām</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hemaja Sutam Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mGvUq8-ebXo">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇarāyā Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>108 Names of Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sukhkarta dukhharta Śhrī Gaṇeśh Āratī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HNv44APLhL8?list=PL8E57180C36478F98">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1102.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"For Sahaj Yogis, it is very important, because if say, there’s a cloth or a sāṛī which is blown off by the wind, even if you can hold it on one corner, you can hold it, and after some time the whole thing can subside.<br />
And this is what has to happen actually to the world, when Sahaj Yogis will hold the sāṛī, we can call, or this Universe with their wisdom and firm faith in Sahaja Yoga.
Otherwise, they can be blown off also. If they are not rightly placed, if they are not grounded, if they are not fixed to their own enlightened faith of Sahaja Yoga,<br />
they can be blown off with this wind which is there to torture the whole world, to destroy the whole world.<br />
<b>So the responsibility of Sahaja Yogis is very important that their Gaṇeśh Principle should be all right.<br />
If it is not all right, then the whole of Sahaja Yoga movement can collapse.<br />
For ladies and for men, I have to make a humble request: that they should try to put their Śhrī Gaṇeśh in a very respectable position in their lifestyle.<br />
That should be the highest, the most important, and also every day to be remembered that we are very much blessed by Śhrī Gaṇeśh to get your Self-realization.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0721 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Qualities of Śhrī Gaṇeśha (Giver of Wisdom), Berlin, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Vinayaka Chaturthi" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Ganesha" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Makar Saṅkrānti: “Today we have come together on the occasion of Saṅkrānti to perform Pūjā to Sūrya.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Makar Saṅkrānti: “Today we have come together on the occasion of Saṅkrānti to perform Pūjā to Sūrya.”" /><published>2023-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/2023-01_14_Makar_Sankranti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/01/14"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating here a special day called Makar Saṅkrānt.</b> For the information of the foreign Sahaja Yogis, I will explain to you what it means.<br />
......<br />
It means the day, today is the day the Sun crosses over from the Tropic of Capricorn to the Tropic of Cancer. It is a very big day for us because, now during the summertime we have the harvest, and we look forward to the rain and so many things that happen in every country. The Sun falls at right angles in this country during the summer season and so we welcome the Sun. We eat something -- that you must have eaten already -- what we call as tīḷ and jaggery. It is to prepare your body and your mind to give it sufficiency to receive the Sun. Because if you are living in the cool season, then all your body, mind becomes lethargic and you become also sometimes very lazy about things in the sense, that the day is so small, that you cannot achieve many results. So the body has become cold as we call it. We take these things, which give us heat so body is prepared to receive the heat of the Sun to welcome."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), We Are Going to Make Peace with Ourselves and with Others (We Will Take to Peaceful Methods), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1092.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Today we have come together on the occasion of Saṅkrānti to perform Pūjā to Sūrya."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Hindi+English+Marathi), Importance of Saṅkrānti and Śhrī Sūrya Devatā, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="orange">"Now the Sun is so much respected in this country,<br />
that in early morning time all the people get up and say namas-kārs to Sūrya with all His names<br />
and do a particular type of exercise to show that they are completely surrendered to the will of the Sūrya."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), We Are Going to Make Peace with Ourselves and with Others (We Will Take to Peaceful Methods), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>12 Names of Śhrī Sūrya</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/jqmPOEnU9tg">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The meaning of Makar Saṅkrānti is saṅkramaṇ, that is, the day that brings about some change. <b>On this day the Sun starts its movement toward the Northern Hemisphere. In India, all the festivals are according to the position of the Moon. That’s why their dates are different in different years. Makar Saṅkrānti is based on the position of the Sun and that is the reason this festival is celebrated every year on fourteenth January.</b><br />
Makar Saṅkrānti indicates the day when the Sun becomes warmer. The heat of the Sun is benevolent for the human race. It is because of this heat that we can walk, we can talk. The heat of the Sun makes a human being angry. This is the reason why we take jaggery on this day so that we talk sweetly. The heat of the Sun is responsible for all the vegetation and wealth of the Earth. On this day we offer fruits and vegetables to the Devī and receive Her blessings. With the blessings of Ādi Śhakti the earth element cools down and the human race progresses."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi), Gain Self-confidence from the Light of the Sun and Become Radiant, House of Mrs. Kalpana Srivastava, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1093.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>This special day today is a day of Saṅkrān-ta. Saṅkri you know, saṅ means good, holy, and krānt means ......<br />
Revolution! Holy revolution. Holy.</b> And that’s what I’m telling them.<br />
What is the Holy Revolution is? <b>That your own dharma is established now through Sahaja Yoga. You know what is your dharma.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi+English), Ahitagni Rajwade Maṅgal Karyalaya, 840 Sadashiv Peth, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is Saṅkrānti. <b>Saṅkrānti means that today there is something new going to happen. Kuṇḍalinī has awakened within you and you have become a new person compared to what you were before. But on the day of Saṅkrānti, you should know that you have to please the Goddess who is sitting within you.</b><br />
What should you do to make Her happy? You distributed sesame seeds and jaggery. That is for love. To increase the love between each other, we give sesame seeds and jaggery.<br />
Today the Sun left its place and, in its northward movement, came towards us. At this moment we should be very thankful to the Sun. It is by the grace of the Sun that so many things take place in our country. <b>We have to do namaskār to the Sun today and His Power and His knowledge should come to us.</b><br />
I would say that all of you have become realized and vibrations are flowing through you. Now you should make use of these vibrations, establish the śhakti within you, establish the peace within you and show the world that this power is within us and we have to acquire it. We have to nurture this, improve this with your good qualities and truthful speech."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0117 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Hindi), Hall, Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1094.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="orange"><b>"Saṅkrānti means Power of the Sun.<br />
Sun power means self-confidence. Sun gives us heat and light.<br />
Now it depends on us whether to get scorched from the heat of the Sun<br /> 
or gain self-confidence from the light of the Sun and become radiant.<br />
Eternal blessings to all of you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi), Gain Self-confidence from the Light of the Sun and Become Radiant, House of Mrs. Kalpana Srivastava, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Your Face Shines like a thousand suns,<br />
You have given us more than we have asked for,<br />
Bliss and peace and Harmony</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the day they give you a sweet thing to say that: ‘You must speak sweetly,’ which is very important for Western people.</b> That when you are doing and organizing, you become heated up, there’s tension and you develop the temperament which is dry, emotionless, you know the heart goes into a tantrum. At that time, they say that, ‘You take the sweet.’<br />
This sweet is a heated thing because now the Sun is moving towards the other side. That time, also they, to give it a balance, they say: ‘Speak very sweetly. Use sweet words, use sweetness. Bring sweetness in your language.’ Which is very important, you understand that.<br />
And this is one of the religions we have to accept: that we will not use harsh words to each other, and then later on to others."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi+English), Ahitagni Rajwade Maṅgal Karyalaya, 840 Sadashiv Peth, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1095.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is the day to make joy and to enjoy everything and to feel the blessings of God all around us. 
The Sun has come back in His own glory and we have to wish Him all success in the coming year, ......</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), Carry the Sun with You, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā, The Revolution Within Ourselves and Feel Your Subtler Sensitivities (It's Only the Spirit that Can Save the World), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/71464483"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātājī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/6ByVzklhnWU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute Namostute</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Brahma Shodile</b> (1988-0110 Music after Śhrī Sūrya Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sarva Mangala Mangale</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1096.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The most important thing in Sahaja Yoga is that you have to change<br />
and that’s what you should do to the Goddess with changed heart, full of love, affection, and kindness.<br />
Therefore, hope you will spread Sahaja Yoga.<br />
It is very important because you know My vision is too big and you have to really work hard to fulfill My vision.<br />
And to give Realization to people as many as possible.<br />
You have to think what is your mind doing. There are many people who are waiting to come in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
You should have the light of spirituality: you have to feel that you are spiritual, you have to grow it, and also make others grow."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English+Marathi), You Have to Change, Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="orange"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sūrya sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<b> Wish You All A Happy Makar Saṅkrānti!<br />
<br />
"Tīḷ-guḷ ghyā āṇi goḍ goḍ bola.”</b>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Makar Sankranti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya’s Jayanti</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/12/07" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya’s Jayanti" /><published>2022-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/12/2022-12_07_Shri_Adi_Guru_Dattatreya_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/12/07"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is Śhrī Dattā Jayanti [birthday]. Today is a very great day. I think this day has come only because of His blessings that Sahaja Yoga has been blossomed in you people. The Guru of all the Gurus -- Ādi Guru Śhrī Dattā Mahārāja. I bow to Him, He is My Guru also. He has taught Me quite enough on Sahaja Yoga all through My many births. And because of that only I have been able to do some work in this birth also, continuing to do.<br />
<b>"Gurūr Brahmā Gurūr Viṣhṇu Gurūr devo Maheśhwara, Gurūr sākṣhāt Parabrahma tasmai Śhrī Guru dev namaḥ." The Guru is Brahmā [creator], Viṣhṇu [sustainer] and Maheśh [destroyer] and the Guru who is Himself God, I offer My obeisance to Him.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1086.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"That's My own. I have no guru, neither I ever had, <b>but I have the Guru, I call him as Dattātreya, if that is so, but that is also within Me. In My stomach is the Guru.</b> You ask this question, 'Mother, have You any Guru?' Just ask this question in your hand, and you will know it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="Peru">Aei maan Guru Sharan. me rahio, rahio,<br />
He man Ma ki Sharan. Me rahio rahio<br />
<font size="+0"><b>O my heart, please stay under the Guru’s Protection,<br />
O my heart, please stay under the Mother’s Protection</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/qRDLZNVcF6M">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"All your ancient Scriptures are singing praise of the Incarnations as Gurus. Dattātreya, the three fold innocence that guides the Path of Dharma. There are Ten basic Dharmas of human beings. They must be guarded, respected and are to be identified with Tādātmya.<br />
<b>There is no compromise but human intelligence gives ideas by which human societies have gone into horrible conditions.</b> They play of mind takes us to sin and we become insensitive to sin.<br />
<b>Today I want you to resolve that you all will become absolutely dhārmik. It is hard to be a dhārmik. The society and the environment forces you to be adhārmik. You are born in innocence and later you go on compromising and accepting adhārmik patterns as normal.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0600 Letter to Children Sahaja Yogis on Guru Pūrṇimā (Marathi), London, UK from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 1 and 3</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1087.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"And this G... Dattātreya is the One who is comprising all these forces: say, the existence force and the evolutionary force and the creative force, all of them, in Its innocence.<br />
I don't know if you understand it, but there is a story about Them is, that there are Three Deities, which belong to these Three Forces: the left one is Śhiva's Force, then the right one is Brahmadeva's Force, and the center one is Viṣhṇu's Force."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><font color="Peru">Guru Vandana</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"All these people can feel it within themselves: is the religion in their stomachs, they can feel it. <b>They can find out where is the religion. Because, I say, there, religion in the stomach is looked after by the Deities of Primordial Master whom we call as Dattātreya, in the Sanskrit language.<br />
But does't mean Hinduism. It doesn't mean Hinduism at all. But it is called as Dattātreya in the Sanskrit language, in English is Primordial Master.</b><br />
He is the same who incarnated on this earth: as Moses, as Abraham, and, say, incarnated as Muhammad Sāhab, as Rāja Janaka, as Nāṇaka, and also as Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. Can you believe that Muhammad Sāhab is the same as our Nāṇak?<br />
......<br />
...... the living religion is within us ...... So your religion automatically awakens and you just don't have to bother. Nobody has to tell you ......<br />
So this is a religion that is within you which is enlightened through Kuṇḍalinī and then it works out. But it is an Absolute Religion in the sense that you all feel the same thing. If you feel one finger the other is also going to feel the same thing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0507 Public Program, Sahaja Yoga and Christianity, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1088.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Today is the day of Guru Pūrṇimā. It is a Full Moon Day. That's why ... it is called as Pūrṇimā. The guru has to be like a Full Moon. Means completely grown, completely matured.<br />
There are sixteen kalās or the phases of the Moon, and when the complete Pūrṇimā comes in, the Full Moon Day, all the sixteen kalās are completed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0708 Guru Pūjā, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Dattātreya is the innocence of all these Three Powers.<br />
And this Guru uh was the One whose ... who then had a big tradition of Gurus.</b><br />
In the same tradition we had many Gurus in our country and specially in the area near Bombay [Mumbai], which is called as Maharashtra.<br />
They came as Nāth. <b>They were called as Nāth.</b> So the first one was Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], then Dattātreya, then Macchindranāth, then Gorakhnāth, like that a tradition of these Gurus came.<br />
But all their knowledge was kept as a guarded secret. It was a Gupta Vidyā, is absolutely guarded secret, a secret knowledge about Kuṇḍalinī. They never talked about it; they never told about it. Because they thought that, 'Just now let us experiment with it fully and then we will give some idea about it to people.'<br />
But as you see everywhere it happens, even it happens with us here sometimes that we get people who do not get Realization or are half-baked and they cannot rise much higher. Then they get, sort of you see, very angry or sometimes they take this half-baked knowledge and start working on it and they go absolutely wrong on this side or that side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1089.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Though you pursue no pleasures,<br />
Derive no joy from wealth or wife,<br />
Reject the powers of Yoga,<br />
and scorn the fruits of sacrifice,<br />
Yet if the mind be not absorbed in the Guru's Lotus Feet,<br />
What will it all avail you?<br />
What, indeed, will it all avail?</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(In praise of the Guru, from Self-knowledge, by Śhrī Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya)</b></font><br />
Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0727 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day), Statutes of the Lord (You Do Not Harm Anyone, The Testimony of the Truth, Develop Detachment, Lead a Moral Life) and Promise that You Will Be a Guru Worthy of Your Mother (Today I Authorize You to Be the Gurus and You Have a Very Supreme Guru), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/zm8FLJxSaas"> audio</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Paramātma Pareśhu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Oṃkār Swarūpa (1991-0406 Bhavasāgara Pūjā, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru kī Mahima</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namanat Karo (I bow to Lotus Feet of my Guru)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavi Kara Mazha (1999-0801 Guru Pūjā)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1090.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Maheśha (Śhiva), Viṣhṇu and Brahmadeva form the Trinity which incarnated as one teacher God, the Primordial Master, Dattātreya.</b> He came onto this Earth to teach people the secrets of the Divine, to reveal God, and to help them cross the Ocean of Illusion themselves within their own identity. Evolution could not go further in the hands of human beings who were in the bondage of ignorance, so they were given guidance through this Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) again and again in different lives. He was created as the three-headed child, Dattātreya, by Ādi Śhakti who appeared on Earth during the Tretā Yuga as Satī Anasūyā, wife of the Sage Atreya.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations<br />
– Ambassadors of God</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Brahmā Viṣhṇu Maheśh kī Abodhita hai Ādi Guru<br />
Dattātrey hai Maitreya hai<br />
Dattātreyhai Maitreya hai Trigunatmika Nirmalā mayi<br />
Ādi Guru Janak Laotze<br />
Socrates Sāī Nirmalā mayi</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Adi Guru Dattatreya Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇak Jayanti: “we are worshiping today Guru Nāṇaka, that’s Me, that may you become Great Guru Nāṇakas”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/11/16" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇak Jayanti: “we are worshiping today Guru Nāṇaka, that’s Me, that may you become Great Guru Nāṇakas”" /><published>2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/11/2022-11_16_Shri_Guru_Nanak_Birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/11/16"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Is a great thing we are worshiping today Guru Nāṇaka, that's Me, that may you become Great Guru Nāṇakas.</b><br />
All of Them were created by Ādi Śhakti. All these Gurus were created by Her. And today I say that you all become as great as Guru Nāṇaka, as great as Moses, as great as Sāī Nāth, as great as Nāṇaka, Janaka, Muhammad. All [of you] have to become as great as all these Great Incarnations. Just desire, have earnestness in you and alertness to achieve it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1078.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Know that in every heart that beats<br />
The Lord of Life has His mansion.<br />
It is through the Guru’s teaching<br />
We merge in the Formless One.<br />
By the gentle path of Sahaja<br />
Attain God, Purest of the Pure.<br />
A disciple who serves his Guru and no other<br />
Will succeed, says Nāṇak, that is sure.</b><br />
<br />
<b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTEE</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTEE</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a special day of Guru Nāṇaka's birthday.</b><br />
Uh we have celebrated one Guru Pūjā uh-uh-uh ... and the, as you know that Guru Nāṇak was also the Incarnation of the Primordial Master, the same Spirit came on this Earth. And the He's the One who tried to re-establish the work of Muhammad.<br />
Muhammad was the Incarnation of the same Spirit, the Primordial Master. He came on this Earth to establish the religion.<br />
Islam is the name of that religion, is the religion of every Sahaja Yogi, of every Christian, of every Hindu. We all belong to One Religion which believes in expanding our ourne ... awareness to the new perception of collectivity: from human level to the higher level, where you can perceive and manifest the Divine Power. This is the religion we are following.<br />
<b>All the religions were established on this Earth to create the seekers. You are the seekers: you are the Men of God. Now, all of you have to become Prophets. And to become Prophets, today's Sahaja Yoga has taken the form of Mahā Yoga. All of you have to become Prophets.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1079.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b>"See the brotherhood of all mankind as the highest order of yogis, conquer your own mind, and conquer the world."<br />
"In the calm of Sahaj’s cave You can discover the True One, Sayeth Nanak, the True One loves the truthful."<br />
Śhrī Guru Nāṇak</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is the birthday of Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka.</b> It is being celebrated throughout the world with so much of zeal that I have not seen in India. For the first time it has been advertised in so many papers and by different means.<br />
Guru Nāṇaka always talked of Sahaja Yoga. ``Everything else," He said, ``is just showing off." About religion He said that, "Observing fasts, going on pilgrimage, etc., are just meant to show off. Now you have to discover the power that is within you and establish it." Guru Nāṇaka kept on repeating the same thing again and again.<br />
......<br />
But Guru Nāṇaka always talked of the Spirit. He explained it very clearly, but no one heeded what he wrote. They will just put a finger on the couplet and read it out. Could we understand him this way? If we go through his writings properly and absorb it, then the whole śhabda jālam [web of words], in which most of the people are caught, will come to an end. See the condition of Sikhs!<br />
Without looking within and experiencing the innate energy, how could one follow Sikh religion? Only this is the teaching of Guru Nāṇaka, this is what is called `Sikh' [learning]. All the Saints of that age had the discretion to know who is a Saint and who is not. All the gurus incorporated their poems and experiences in Guru Grantha and that is why Guru Grantha is revered so much. Only the renowned gurus contributed to it. They were so spiritual that they did churning of all the religious Scriptures and put the substance in Guru Grantha.<br />
That is what we do in Sahaja Yoga. <b>We do not follow any particular Saint or Incarnation; we respect all of them and strike a balance.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti (Hindi), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1080.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkRed; text-align:center;">
<b><b>Ikoaŉkār saṯ nām karṯā purakẖ nirbẖao nirvair akāl mūraṯ ajūnī saibẖaŉ gur parsāḏ.</b><br />
There is One and only One God who is transcendent as well as immanent.<br />
True and Eternal Name. Creator and Person. Without Fear and without Enmity.<br />
Timeless Form, Unborn, Self-existent.<br />
Realized by Divine Grace.<br />
Śhrī Guru Nāṇak's Mool mantra</b><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Muhammad Sāhib Himself was born [again] as our Great Guru, Guru Nāṇaka.</b> Guru Nāṇak was not a human being, He was not only a Paigambar [Prophet] but He was the Reincarnation of Ādi Guru, the Primordial Master, He was a Divine Personality. Of course, the people who were there at His time were so useless and gross people that they actually tortured His life and nobody followed Him. After His death is a different point. He also has said that it is the Primordial Mother who has created the Universe."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0222 Public Program (English+Hindi) (Śhivarātri Day), Day 5, Lord Śhiva, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then came, you know Nāṇaka who preached that there should be no enmity between Hindus and Muslims, he preached that, because he saw the Muslims behaving in such a manner, they were such fanatics and they had become so funny that he could not understand how is it? These are the people whom I have made Muslims and what are they doing here? Actually Mussulman means the person who is realized and Pīr is a person whose Realization is established so much so that he said that those who have become Mussulman should be buried and not burnt, because he thought they are all realized Souls, but Realization finished off with his son-in-law and his daughter, after that he had two sons who were great Souls who are really the Reincarnation[s] of Lav and Kuśh."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1081.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery, which you all should become the Great Prophets who are going to change all the men of God into Prophets.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/WxZmETTX3_M"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ (1993 Guru Pūjā Cabella) </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nāṇak Muhammad</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiya Tere Charano Ki – Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti (2008 Noida)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/iOXcrlduLNM">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavil</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/I1nxKFe8QOU?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guruon kī Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhaya kāya tayā</b> (when we belong to God what is to fear) (song by Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/47fMsue7fs8">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1082.png" /></div>

<p>
Āratī - Gagan Main Thāl | Śhrī Guru Nāṇak Āratī (recited by Guru Nāṇak)<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jNeQY2lnjko">video</a><br />
Guru Nāṇak Dev has imagined the entire universe decorated as a prayer platter on the altar of the almighty. The starting verses of the Āratī are as follows:<br />
"Gagan mein thaal, rav chand deepak bane, taarka mandal janak moti dhoop malay aan lao, pawan chavro kare sagal ban raai phulant jyoti kaisi Āratī hoye, bhavkhandana teri Āratī.<br />
anhat sabad bajant bheri kaisi Āratī hoye, bhavkhandana teri Āratī."<br />
Means: "The sky is the prayer platter, the sun and the moon are the lamps, and the stars and the constellations are the pearls and jewels. The air coming from the sandal-laden Malay mountain is the incense, the air is the fan, and the entire flora of the earth are the flowers ..... oh ... what an Āratī is it! O Destroyer of Fear!"<br />
(Wikipedia)
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Guru Nanaka Birthday" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Now the last day is very important, is a very universal day I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/26" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Now the last day is very important, is a very universal day I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj”" /><published>2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_26_Diwali_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/26"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Diwālī is supposed to be Enlightenment Day.</b><br />
But enlightenment within is: how much you are in thoughtless awareness.<br />
And everything works out because you are the Ocean of it. You have it within yourself.<br />
Only, you have to tap it. If you don’t tap it, then it doesn’t work out.<br />
You have to just tap it, and you’ll be amazed that you are a source of such joy, source of such happiness, I should say source of real enlightenment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1103 Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), The Importance of Meditation, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1074.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Then the second day is also very important: is the second day is the Moon. That is the Moon came out of the ...... Sea. According to this mythology, the Lakṣhmī came out of the Sea and with Her this Moon came out, which was only a two-day-old Moon, the New Moon but the two-day-old Moon. And this was regarded as the brother of Lakṣhmī, because they were born at the same time from the sea. So He is the brother of Lakṣhmī. It's all symbolic! This is very, very symbolic."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So this is the fifth day is Dvija [Bhāī Dūja]. So from thirteenth to the fifth day they celebrate Diwālī.<br />
For us Diwālī has a very great significance. That is: from one light many lights are awakened and they are put in a line. So they are called as diwālī, means the 'lights put in a line'. So when you hold My hands together, all of us, through that the energy passes and the enlightened Rāsa is established. And the whole world has to become that beautiful dream of your Mother where nothing but the bliss of your Father and His enjoyment when He sees His own Creation dancing in that Ocean of Bliss.<br />
May God bless you!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1075.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Pūrna chandr’ābhā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the radiance of the Full Moon! Salutations to You!<br />
</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Is such a great day today to meet you all. Today is a day we celebrate in India where relationship between brothers and sisters have to be established. They're very pure. Brothers and relationsh... sisters relationship is without any lust or greed. Is pure relationship, where the sister prays for the protection of the brother and brother play ... pray ... prays for the self-sufficiency of the kṣhema, well-being, of the sister.<br />
So this time you have to think of your other Sahaja Yoginīs and Sahaja Yogis who are like your brothers and sisters. You have to think like that. Purify your hearts. Is something funny in these countries, you know that, there's no such relationship may exist. Purify your mind today on that point that, `Everybody else is my brother or sister.' If you are married, is all right. But look at everyone, try to look at everyone as a brother, and a sister. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1076.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now the last day is very important, is a very universal day I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj</b>, this day, or they call it also in Marathi Bhāūbīj, different names.<br />
The brothers and sisters day. Now the brothers’ and sisters’ relationship has to be very, very strong.<br />
And the purity of that relationship is to be maintained.<br />
It is not necessary that you should be born as brothers and sisters, not necessary.<br />
But you are born because if you are realized Souls you are born as brothers and sisters.<br />
So that purity must be maintained in the society of Sahaja Yoga. Very important, that we should try to develop this situation that brothers and sisters are something very pure. Their relationships are very pure. And they should not be at all challenged.<br />
It is so much so that even if you call somebody your brother, he is your brother and the more you develop this relationship, the better your left Viśhuddhi will be.<br /> 
Because left Viśhuddhi is the relationship with God as a brother or with a Goddess as a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But for a gṛuhalakṣhmī, the brother is very important.<br />
<b>And the brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity.</b> If you understand that brotherhood and sisterhood is love which is very pure, there is no expectation, is just love: is giving love and taking love. And Absolute Purity within us should exist between our relationships when we call them as Sahaj Yogi brothers and sisters. And as there is understanding, complete understanding between the brother and sister, in a family, one has to know we are all part and parcel of a family, born out [of] the same Mother.<br />
Nobody has to shoot off, you know, nobody has to become something great, nobody has to correct others, nobody has to uh say that, ‘I’m something unique.’ All of you have to work it out together and find out the solution working out together, in complete friendship and unison. Anyone who cuts off himself and goes out or becomes anything else goes out of circulation and useless for Sahaj Yoga. Such a person is completely useless: the one who tries to get out of the family. All of you have to be supporting as each other, helping to each other, not shouting at each other, [not] getting angry with each other, trusting each other, not finding faults, treating each other with respect [unclear and love].<br />
This is the most important thing, which Sahaj Yogis don’t understand, that you are Saints and you have to respect each other."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1077.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>"So, for today’s New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1231 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Year's Eve, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon,  Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Morning and evening I sing Your Prais</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Mātājī I Have received Second Birth from You</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1113 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), You Are the Dīpas, Tent, Marque, Back Garden, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/573513651"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā - Rang De Jhini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zcAvt3cDa0Y">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuzhe Rupa Pāhuniyā Mi danga zhalo ai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Awaz Uthayenge</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Ttp3KyI2rew">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Bhai Duja Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/25" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2022 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity.”" /><published>2022-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/2022-10_25_Diwali_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2022/10/25"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>It’s the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā night, not only of Lakṣhmī Pūjā</b>; there’s a difference between the two. Mahālakṣhmī is one of the powers of the Three Powers, Main Powers of Ādi Śhakti. As you know: Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī. Now, these powers have powers at a material level also, at a subtler level also. So Mahālakṣhmī Power is achieved after Lakṣhmī Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1071.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"...... the first day of the Moon. That is the forefathers of your Mother, Śhālivāhanas, they started the calendar, from that date.<br />
And so, on the first, that means the first day of the Moon, the New Year is celebrated.<br />
Now, see symbolically, Christ is born and the New Year is celebrated next day.<br /> 
As soon as He is born, New Year starts with. So next year it starts, the New Year."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"So, first of all, <b>I wish you all a very Happy Diwālī and a prosperous whole year, after this New Year Day.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1106 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Apollon Camping, Delphi, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So the whole idea of celebrating today the Lakṣhmī’s day is to understand that in us She has become the Mahālakṣhmī.</b> By that we have so many powers of which we are not aware, I mean we do not know that we are realized Souls. Some of us, we do not know and that we have those powers within us that we can permeate into others. We can project our personalities to others. We can find out what’s wrong with them. We can find out about ourselves.<br />
We can go into ourselves, we can go into – our permeation is like water is moving, is flowing all the time.<br />
And this is a very important thing that we should be aware of: our powers that we have achieved.<br />
Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity. We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It’s against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody’s life miserable. It’s against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1072.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"...... this new awakening within you that you have to achieve God now, is the power of Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
By the power of Mahālakṣhmī only, you achieve your saintliness, your Realization." </b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Jagan-mātā Mahālakṣhmī sākṣhāt Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī, You are the Mother of this Universe and the Power of Evolution.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that’s how we start understanding the value of human dignity.</b> We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It’s against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody’s life miserable. It’s against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time.<br />
You leave the person to be; the human dignity is the most important thing.<br />
But respect everybody. And that’s possible because now you have the Mahālakṣhmī principle. Those who do not have the dignity also will get it from you because you are dignified now."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So what is the Principle of Mahālakṣhmī? Is that first is of sacrifice.</b> Sacrifice their own children on the Altar of Truth. Of course that is not needed in Sahaja Yoga. You are all blessed people, you don't have to sacrifice anything whatsoever. But if you do not develop your children into proper ways, they will hold you responsible and they will say, "Why did you not give us a full scope to develop?"<br />
......<br />
So this Mahālakṣhmī Principle has to grow among men, as well as in women. We have families now and this has to work out, that, do the whole family people sit down and meditate? Do we teach our children the proper protocol of Śhrī Mātājī? Like a lady bringing a perambulator in the hall -- is absurd! I mean, can you bring a perambulator in the church? This is more than a church. Do you realize whom are you facing? <b>And this is what you have to tell your children because this is the greatest time. This is the greatest time when you are here, the greatest time of spirituality, of the complete manifestation of the Powers of the Goddess, where your children have to be the real flowers of beauty.</b> Please don't try to cover them up with their souls dying out there under the cover of so-called love for them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia/Sottomarina, Venice, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1073.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkRed">So now for the whole world you can ask that, `Remove the curse of the negativity and bless them with the Principle of Mahālakṣhmī.'</font><br /> 
<b>Sahaja Yogi</b>: All of us?<br /> 
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkRed">All of you.</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi</b>: [Repeat.]<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font>: <font color="DarkRed">May God bless you.<br />
So we have to do a lot, all of us have to do it. You are My hands, you are My eyes, you are My ears. You have to do. Whatever you are asking for, you have to do yourself. I can just give you power, but you have to move your hands, you have to move your tongue, you have to do everything.<br />
If you don't move your tongue and if you do not talk to people about it, how can I help it? So this is what you have to do, is to know that whatever you ask for, not only to pray, but also to use your instrument.<br /> 
May God bless you all.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Padm‛āsana sthite Devi, Para-brahma swa-rūpiṇī,</b></font><br />
O Devī, seated on the Lotus, who is the Supreme Consciousness,<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Parameśhi jagan-mātar, aah; Mahālakṣhmī namō‛stu-te.</b></font><br />
Supreme Ruler and Mother of the Universe, O Great Mother, Obeisance to Thee.<br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), What State You Have to Reach, Quinta do Mar, Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25922658"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhjya Pujani archani lina vhave </b></font><br />
(We are totally lost in prayer at Your Lotus Feet while performing Your Pūjā)<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parabrahma Rūpiṇī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Ch-wz0NR08">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="BlueViolet"><b>Wishing you all a very Happy Diwālī and a Happy New Year!!</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Padava" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>