<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-01T13:17:39-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2023 Worshiping Śhrī Ādi Śhakti: “Ādi Śhakti is the Power of Love, of pure love, of compassion. There is nothing else She has: only the pure love within Her heart. But this pure love is so powerful, is so powerful”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/06/04" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Worshiping Śhrī Ādi Śhakti: “Ādi Śhakti is the Power of Love, of pure love, of compassion. There is nothing else She has: only the pure love within Her heart. But this pure love is so powerful, is so powerful”" /><published>2023-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/06/2023_06_04_Shri_Adi_Shajti_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/06/04"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are going to do the Pūjā of Ādi Śhakti.</b><br />
It's a difficult subject uuh to talk about Ādi Śhakti, because is not easy to understand that Ādi Śhakti is the Power of Sadāśhiva. Sadāśhiva is the God Almighty. She is His breath, as they some people call it. <b>Some say She is the Desire and some say that She's the Entire Power of Sadāśhiva and Sadāśhiva cannot do anything without Her Powers.</b><br />
......<br />
The first thing is, we must know, that She created a Kuṇḍalinī in the Mother Earth Itself and She created Śhrī Gaṇeśha out of the Mother Earth, it's very interesting.<br />
So, the Mother Earth becomes a very important thing for us. If we do not know how to respect the Mother Earth, we do not know how to respect ourselves.<br />
The expression of Ādi Śhakti within you is the Kuṇḍalinī, no doubt. That is the reflection of Ādi Śhakti in you. But the reflection in the Mother Earth is also expressed, as you all know, in different places, different countries, different cities as the manifestation of chakras and Ādi Śhakti's creations. It was very important first to create a very holy Mother Earth for human beings to be born on them [it]. So the reflection of the Ādi Śhakti as Kuṇḍalinī first was on the Mother Earth.<br />
Kuṇḍalinī is a, we should say, is a wee part of the Ādi Śhakti. <b>Or we can say that She is the desire, pure desire of the Ādi Śhakti. So Ādi Śhakti is the desire, complete desire of Sadāśhiva, and Kuṇḍalinī, Ādi Kuṇḍalinī, is the desire, complete desire of Ādi Śhakti.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0525 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, You Must Give this Love to Others or Respect the Mother Earth, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1191.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Somebody asked Me, uh, "Is it necessary to have this Pūjā?", [laughing:] I think, if there's any Pūjā that you should do, it is this one, is [of] Ādi Śhakti. Is very important that this Pūjā must be performed.</b> Because that is how you grow, this reflection improves, and you grow more and more within yourself, through the Power of Ādi Śhakti or through the power of Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
As you know that: Ādi Śhakti has Her own Kuṇḍalinī, which is the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī, and the reflection of that, within you, is the Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
So you have to worship. And is the best way to please your own Kuṇḍalinī, your own mother, who has given you this birth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0609 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, Get Dissolved into the Divine Power, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Vin.ti Suniye Ādi Śhakti Meri</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Ādi Śhakti, please listen to my request</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pujan. ka adhikar. dijiye</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Please give me the authority to do Your Pūjā</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śharaṇāga. hai Hṛiday. pujārī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Your worshipper is surrendered to You from the heart.</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/hMK6gaaQ1hU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here to do the Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, or the Ādi Śhakti Pūjā.</b><br />
There's a difference between the two: <b>Ādi Śhakti is the Total Power of God, of His Desire, while [Ādi] Kuṇḍalinī is the One that is reflected, part which is reflected in the human beings as Kuṇḍalinī.</b> So there's a difference between the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī and the Ādi Śhakti.<br />
<b>Ādi Śhakti is the Parāśhakti, is the Power which is beyond all the powers, which controls all the powers. And one of the powers of Ādi Śhakti is Kuṇḍalinī.</b><br />
For example, the Kuṇḍalinī which is placed within Me, in the triangular bone, is not [the] totality of Me. In the same way, the Kuṇḍalinī, which is placed within you, is not the totality. Of course, It is the power which is there to give you your Self-realization. Is the power that redeems you, that nourishes you, that enlightens your centers.<br />
But there are two other powers, as you know, very powerful, which are working through Iḍā and Piṅgalā. And the third one is Mahālakṣhmī which is in the center. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0604 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, How to Detach Yourself From This Idea of Money Orientation (Thinking about Money, Saving Money, These Things Are Absolutely Against Sahaja Yoga), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So, in that reflection that you are Me, in that rekflection [reflection] that the Mother Earth is Me</b>, in that beautiful creation within you, you have to become very sensitive to the need of the world, what is the need of the world. <b>Today, if you fail, the whole thing will fail forever.</b> Only very few will be there. So the need for you is: to spread Sahaja Yoga because this love is not only for you. Is not to be enjoyed [only] by you, but is to be enjoyed by as many possible in the whole world.<br />
<b>So, today we have to decide that, as the children of Ādi Śhakti, we have to go all out, everywhere, every corner, we have to shout and we have to tell loudly what is the time in which we are living and what is the responsibility that you have to fulfill as Sahaja Yogis.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0525 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, You Must Give this Love to Others or Respect the Mother Earth, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1192.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">And at this place meet the three chakras, and that is why Śhrī Mahākālī, Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī and Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī, all these Three Powers meet. <b>As these Three Powers meet, they form One Power, that is Śhrī Ādi Śhakti. That is why in Sahasrāra Śhrī Ādi Śhakti resides, but it is said so, that in Sahasrāra Ādi Śhakti exists in a form of Mahāmāyā -- Śhrī Ādi Śhakti exists, but She is in the form of Mahāmāyā.</b> That is why the result of all these Three Powers was like this, that Śhrī Ādi Śhakti comes into this world in the Form of Mahāmāyā (Mahāmāyā Swarūp), and She can penetrate the Sahasrāra of everyone. As you know, She is in front of you and you know all about it, so I need not tell anything more.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0106 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), Ascent Is the Main Attention, Sangli, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Bolo Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Nirmalā Devī kī Jay</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Salutations to the Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Nirmalā Devī</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī kī Jay.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Salutations to Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī, Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī and Śhrī Mahākālī</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This is the first time the Pūjā of the Ādi Śhakti is being done. All the Śhaktis arise from the Ādi Śhakti.</b> And also the Śhaktis of Mahākālī, Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī. All these Śhaktis get absorbed back in her. Only the Ādi Śhakti can do this work, because She has supremacy over all the chakras. She is the one who controls the various permutations and combinations of the chakras, She knows the subtlest of the subtle."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0409 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Now understand that this Ādi Śhakti is the Power of Love, of Pure Love, of Compassion. There is nothing else She has: only the Pure Love within Her heart. But this Pure Love is so powerful, is so powerful!</b><br />
......<br />
So this Ādi Śhakti's Love is something so, so subtle, is so subtle. You cannot understand sometimes. I know you all love Me very much. It's tremendous love for Me, and when I get the vibrations from you, it is like the ripples that reach the shores and again they return back and lots of little, little sparkling drops are there, on the shore also. In the same way in My heart I feel your love echoing the beauty of this Divine Love ... which I cannot la explain to you the experience that it creates. The first thing that it creates is that tears come into My eyes, because it is the compassion which is Sāndra Karuṇā, is ārdra, it's not dry."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0606 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, Incarnation of Divine Love, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1193.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>He Nirmalā Mā,</b></font><br />
O Nirmalā Mā,<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tera pyar moksha ka Anand hai Mā</b></font><br />
Your unbounded love is the bliss of complete fulfillment of Mokṣha<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/v7T1xpKkYFU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Love is the Message of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
Now you think about it. One Ādi Śhakti created the whole world.</b> How She must have done it. What She must have planned. How She must have organized. It is not a[n] easy thing. Only because She loved.<br />
Love is the expression that you are all there. That is why to be one with Her one should learn to love.<br />
Of course in that you have to know that you should forgive. If you don't know how to forgive and find mistakes of other people you won't help. What is your now job is, is to see that you are loving, no hatred for anyone, you don't think of hating anyone and hitting somebody.<br />
This has to work out."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-0624 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, You Have to Become Fragrant, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are all going to worship Me, first time. It has been always the Pūjā of [an] aspect of Me or a part of Me.</b><br />
Now, one has to know very clearly what is Ādi Śhakti. As we say, is the Pure Desire of God Almighty, of Sadāśhiva. But what is the pure Desire of God Almighty?<br />
If you see your own desires, come out of what? Not out of the Divine Love but out of carnal love, out of material love, of out of power love. Behind all these desires there is love.<br />
If you do not love something you will not desire it. So, these mundane types of love that you have, for which we spend so much of our time uselessly, actually they do not give you satisfaction, because that is not true love that you have. Just infatuation for the time being, and then you just get fed up with it, and from there you jump to another thing, to another thing, to another thing.<br />
So <b>Ādi Śhakti is the Embodiment of God's Divine Love, is God's Pure Love, and in His Love what did He desire? He desired that He should create human beings, who would be very obedient, would be sublime, would be like angels. And that was His idea: to create Adam and Eve.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0606 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, Incarnation of Divine Love, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1194.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Dene Zeri Amuchya Shiri,</b></font><br />
You have given us so much<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pari Agnya Jana Tu Par Kari,</b></font><br />
even to those who don't have any knowledge,<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Deshi Jag. Tu Sahaj. Yoga,</b></font><br />
You give Sahaja Yoga to the whole universe<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jan Kotama,</b></font><br />
Verily You are the highest Father of Mankind<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
O Primordial Mother, O Eternal Mother<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Pūjā, as I have told you many a times, is not for My benefit, by any chance, take it from Me. I'm much better off without it. Because when the enthusiastic Deities start emitting vibrations with your im... asking. Because you are Saints, so They just, They are overenthusiastic. And They are sitting there, busybodies, you know [soft laughter]. They are sitting quietly waiting for a chance, you see, to emit vibrations, to save you, you see, They want to just rush. They emit so much [laughing:] that They lose, 'Just wait, just wait.' They want to save you, They want to give you, They're so anxious, in Their anxiety to save you. I like it, to see the way They are anxious. But [laughs] ... but you don't suck it and I have a problem there. Once They've given They don't want to take it back. You don't suck it, so it has to go to the atmosphere, it has to disappear somewhere. Is directed towards you and you don't take it, so where does it go? It hangs into My tissues, it pains Me.<br />
So, sucking should be more. Sucking should be more. <b>And just before the Pūjā you should say: 'Mother, make me such that I suck more of the Divine!' Just pray that, with sincerity from your heart, just say that.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0801 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, The Privilege of this Worship, Seminar, Day 2, Cowley Manor, Cheltenham, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Pūjya Mahārāj [Gaganagirị̄ Mahārāj] used to say to Me that, <b>"You are [the] Goddess and [the] Goddess likes the praise [Stutipriyā]. So without praising [the] Goddess one cannot achieve anything."</b> But I see that without properly inviting Deities chakras never work. And these Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, and Maheśh they never listen to [if not properly invited]. Even until you all human beings accept Me [as Śhrī Ādi Śhakti], Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Christ, Hanumāna or Bhairavnāth, no one gets awakened, too. Then every time I have to request Them all [to get awakened]. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0914 Letter to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar Raul (Marathi), 56 Ashley Gardens, Ambrosden Avenue (near Victoria Station), London, UK (other years 1980 and 1981)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1195.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon,  Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Morning and evening I sing Your praise</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Mā I Have received Second Birth from You</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0609 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, Get Dissolved into the Divine Power, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/44290246"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Śhakti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>THE 64 ADORATIONS OF SHRI ADI SHAKTI</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/wj74gNpcy0s?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sare Jag Mein tere Dhūm</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Mā Jagdambe Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Shri Adi Shakti Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Mother’s Day: “The Mother is the source of love.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/05/14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Mother’s Day: “The Mother is the source of love.”" /><published>2023-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/05/2023_05_14_Mother&apos;s_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/05/14"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It's nice today it's Mother's Day, and You find so many people waiting for You.<br />
And also You see Yourself as a Mother, the heart which is pining to meet, then You can't get out of some things. And then You enjoy that pining, that longing to see Your own, Your own children whom You love so much. Is such a great joy.<br />
In these modern times, it is described that in this Kali Yuga everything will go upside down because people will not recognize the motherhood. The mothers won't be respected and won't be respectable either. Is a fact.<br />
And imagine now this has brought this Mother's Day to this country. It's something, such a recognition from the Divine that one has to remember that motherhood is very important.<br />
......<br />
<b>So the power that your Mother has, of giving birth, the spiritual birth, be bestowed upon all of you so that you do this work with the same grace and with the same patience and love and enjoyment.<br />
May God bless you.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0316 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother’s Day in UK),  Āśhram, Dollis Hill, North London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1184.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is ... I like the day when it is the Mother's, I should say, Mother's Day also. Because I think only a Mother can work it out that way. One has to have a lot of patience with people."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Blessing of the Divine Pours Only if the Sahasrāra is Open (Meditation Is the Only Way You Can Enrich Yourself with the Beauty of Reality), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>The most beautiful word on the lips of mankind is the word "Mother," and the most beautiful call is the call of "My mother."<br />
It is a word full of hope and love, a sweet and kind word coming from the depths of the heart. </b><br />
(Kahlil Gibran)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"[Mother's is] a very special institution ...... especially in this country [Italy], they have such respect for their mothers.<br />
<b>Mother is the Source of Love.</b> In the Qur'ān they asked Muhammad Sāhab whom should we bow after Allah? So He said "to Mother" -- "to the Mother."<br />
Then again they asked Him, He said: "Only the Mother." Again they asked Him, He said: "Only the Mother."<br />
I'm sure He must have said about the Divine Mother, because worldly mothers may not be complete mothers, perhaps. They are a[n] embodied, or, we can say, examples of Mother's Love, of the Divine Mother's Love, but they are human.<br />
So they can be conditioned, influenced or could be egoistical, especially if they are living in a particular country for a long time and have no idea of Divine Love.<br />
<b>In Divine Love there is no expectations, it just flows, it doesn't think how to judge a person or what to do for a person, it just flows.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0513 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother’s Day), Living Room, Palazzo Doria, Cabella Ligure, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1185.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>May I this day be what You'd have me be.<br />
May I this day say what You'd have me say.<br />
May I this day be part and parcel of the whole<br />
And may my thoughts be of a realized soul.<br />
May I this day have love for all mankind.<br />
Mother, be in my heart and in my mind.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is ... I like the day when it is the Mother’s, I should say, Mother’s Day also. Because I think only a Mother can work it out that way. One has to have a lot of patience with people.<br />
.......<br />
But mother’s position is different. She’ll go on struggling and fighting for her child. She’ll fight it out to the last to see that the child gets all the benefits and this patience and this love and this forgiveness is innately built-in in a mother, because her attitude is very different. Not any achievement, not any big name or what you call a sort of an award or anything. It is just she does it because she is a mother. And that is what is the sign of any mother, if she is a real mother, at least for her own children, she will go all out, she will work out everything for day in day out and to save the child from disaster. But Sahaja Yoga is a much bigger family and for that you really had to be worked out through the Mother’s Principle. You cannot take any other principle.<br />
......<br />
So, in your own way, when you are doing Sahaja Yoga, there also you have to be a mother. <b>More mother’s quality than the father’s quality, that there’s no ambition, there’s no competition, there’s no jealousies, nothing.</b> Just you want your children to come up and to grow into their spirituality. If that is the only attitude we have then you’ll be amazed how satisfied you’ll feel, because this is a very, very joy-giving thing, to see people growing in spirituality. Not only talking about it, not only reading about it, but actually happening, actualizing within yourself. So this quality is very helpful and that really helps every Sahaja Yogi to be patient, to be kind, to be humble."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā,  Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1186.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Thank you for Showering Your blessings endlessly upon us.<br />
Thank you for never abandoning us.<br />
Thank you for being our Mother.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Uh <b>I would like to thank all of you</b> [laughing:] <b>but thanking is coming with a big</b> [referring to the weather; laughter] <b>uh for celebration of this Mother's Day</b>. It's a very good idea that this Mother's Day has been established in your country, ah ... and that it coincides with My visit here.<br />
In India, surprisingly, we don't have anything like Mother's Day. Is very surprising. We have all the Goddesses this but not for mother.<br />
And we have to remember also the mother who gave us birth, and then only you can realize what it is to give a spiritual birth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0510 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother's Day), Gifts and Bhajans Offering, After Picnic, Tent, Ranch of the Parents of John and Wendy Brownscombe, Galston (36 kms NW of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1187.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>The Mother is everything</b> — She is our consolation in sorrow, our hope in misery, and our strength in weakness.<br />
She is the source of love, mercy, sympathy, and forgiveness.<br /> 
And this Earth is the Mother of the trees and flowers.<br />
It produces them, nurses them, and weans them.<br />
The trees and flowers become kind mothers of their great fruits and seeds.<br /> 
And the Mother, the prototype of all existence, is the Eternal Spirit, full of beauty and love.</font><br />
<b>(Kahlil Gibran: "Broken Wings")</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Mother, I adore You</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LsWaC7NktHA">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0510 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother's Day), On Creativity, Entertainment Program, Living Room, Nirmala House, Sant'Angelo Romano (7 kms N of Guidonia), Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/127101640"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>She's got the whole world in Her Hands</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mataji hamko</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Matajila</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ybCnMcQi2ZQ">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1188.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Thank You</b> for descending from Your heavenly abode, Mātā Dvīpā, to bring light into the darkness of Kali Yuga.<br /> 
<b>Thank You</b>, Śhrī Mātāj, again and again.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for giving Sahaja Yoga to a confused and self-destructive humanity.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing to us the meaning of creation and evolution.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing to us the actual existence of God.<br /> 
<b>Thank You</b> for giving divine meaning to human existence.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing to us within the human body the reflection of the Viśhwa-rūpa (universal form).</font><br />
<br />
<b>The 108 Thank Yous were offered to Śhrī Mātājī on the occasion of Sahasrāra Pūjā in Cabella on 1996-0505</b><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/wP_R9tpOVag">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Mother&apos;s Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day on Lord Buddha Jayanti: “Sahaja Yoga is the power of compassion and love of God Almighty.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/05/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day on Lord Buddha Jayanti: “Sahaja Yoga is the power of compassion and love of God Almighty.”" /><published>2023-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/05/2023_05_05_Sahasrara_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/05/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a very great day, I must say, to celebrate Sahasrāra, the Pūjā of Sahasrāra.</b><br />
It’s a very unique thing that has happened, that your Sahasrāras were opened out.<br />
......<br /> 
So it's a very great day because collectively this Sahasrāra has been opened. Every one of you have got it. Also all over the world, you have many people who have got their Sahasrāras open. Of course, we need many more for them to understand what is this great event of such a collective opening of Sahasrāra.<br />
Some have grown very much, after getting their Realization, very much. They have understood Sahaja Yoga very well, and they have developed their depth, and their consciousness is really a great awareness of Oneness with the Divine.<br />
<b>To be one with the Divine is the greatest blessing for human beings.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Watch Yourself, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1177.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"When your Mother is the Deity of Sahasrāra, the only way to be able to keep the Sahasrāra open has to be complete surrendering."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0504 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirvikalpa, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi</b>: <font color="RebeccaPurple"><b>Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
Nothing ever had a meaning nor a life, everyone so dry and so weak, then You came,<br />
O Mother, so caring, so sweet.<br />
You taught Your children even to walk and to speak.<br />
We thank You, O Mother, for bringing us up, and opening the doors of Heaven for all of us.<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks.<br />
Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
We were the clay but You all the Supreme Creator ......<br />
......<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations again and again to the Queen of the Seven Peaks.<br />
Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Mahāmāyā Swarūpa, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>O Queen of Universe</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Y2Z3tNAs0I">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I have to tell ... I'll have to tell you the story about the Sahasrāra Day, about which it was decided, long time back, before I incarnated. They had a big meeting in the Heavens, all the thirty-five karoṛs [350 millions] of Gods, the Deities were there present to decide what is to be done. <b>'This is the ultimate that we have to do to human beings: is to open their Sahasrāra, to open their awareness to the Spirit, to the Real Knowledge of the Divine, to remove the darkness of ignorance.'</b> And it had to be spontaneous because it has to work the living force of God. Also, it had to be very quick. So all the Gods requested that now, I, the Ādi Śhakti has to take the birth.<br />
They all tried Their best. They did whatever was possible. The Saints were made by Them but very few. They incarnated and people made religions out of Them which were perverted, brought Them bad name. No reality in those religions. These religions were money-oriented or power-oriented. There was no Divine Force working, actually, it was all anti-Divine."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, How it Was Decided (Nothing Is More Important Than Your Ascent or Our Ascent Is the Only Concern, Tent, Finanziari Colonia Marina, Fregene (40 kms E of Rome), Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1178.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Just to say, ‘Mother, it’s all Yours,’ to start it – 'It’s all Yours.<br />
I am Yours, my heart is Yours, all my things are Yours, my life is Yours.'<br />
Even saying that is a big mantra for Sahasrāra.</b><br />
The deity of Sahasrāra is a very simple person, extremely simple, and can be moved with very little actions,<br />
can be pleased with very few little actions here and there.<br />
Not much is needed to please the deity of Sahasrāra.<br />
It’s a very simple person. Little things make Her happy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0503 Sahasrāra Pūjā, You Must Obey Me, Yogis in the Body of the Ādi Śhakti and The Ghost of Materialism, Thredbo Village, Kosciuszko National Park, New South Wales, Australia</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tuzhya Krupe Nid.Rit. Śhakti Urdhvamukhe Yei</b></font><br />
The energy which is awakened with your blessings start to rise<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sat. Chakre Tichya Sparshe Jagrut. Ti Hoi</b></font><br />
As it touches the seven chakras, they become enlightened<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Adnyasthani Yeta Mate</b></font><br />
When it reaches the agnya chakra<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ka Ga Visawa<br />
Ughad. Sahastrar. Mate</b></font><br />
O Mother, please open the Sahasrāra!<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It has been such a great pleasure and glorification of Sahaja Yoga today, I remember the day when it started, on the 5th May 1970. And today I see all of you so much engulfed in the Divine Love and Divine Power.<br />
<b>The whole thing shows one very great, fundamental thing, of Sahasrāra: that people from so many countries integrated together.</b><br />
Integrated. It was Sahaj, spontaneous, but every way and there was no confusion, there’s no quarreling, no fighting, nothing. Such an integration, spontaneous, whether it is on the stage or stage of life.<br />
Now, as we are all global personalities, we are all integrated and those who were acting were enjoying as well as the ones who were looking at them were also enjoying in the same manner.<br />
It was such a good also integration between the one who was acting, or the all those who were there, and all those who were watching – I couldn’t understand whether the people who are seeing them are also acting, or also those who are acting are also seeing.<br />
It was a beautiful blending I must say, and I congratulate all the leaders of all these five countries, who have contributed so well to this deep sense of integration.<br />
Not that is the integration within that is important – of course that’s very important for a personality, but for our work, for our global emancipation we need integration of all the nations, and understanding of all the nations, because these barriers are created by human beings, not by God Almighty.<br />
So we have transcended those barriers, and the way we are all sitting together in a complete integrated mood is – you don’t know what your Mother feels, I, I just can’t believe that in such a short time this we have achieved, in My lifetime I can see all these things happening.<br />
So it was such a beautiful sahaja, spontaneous, creation of the Spirit of this integration, and I congratulate all the leaders for this, and we all should thank them, for giving us this beautiful integrated, Sahaj spontaneous illustration of [the] Sahaj character.<br />
Thank you very much.<br />
May God bless you all."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0504 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1179.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we are celebrating the Sahasrāra Day.<br />
Perhaps we have not realized what a day it must have been.<br />
<b>Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth,<br />
all talk about Divinity was a myth.</b><br />
People believed in it but it was just a belief. And the science, as it was put forward,<br />
was about to obliterate all the value system, all the proof of God Almighty."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrār. Dwari<br />
Mukhi Naam . Gheta<br />
Nirmalā Hi Tari<br /> 
Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrār. Dwari</font><br />
O Mother we are enjoying our meditation in Sahasrāra<br />
Whenever we take Your name, You are always there to help us<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Charani Tujhya Baisat. Mate, Man. Te Nivale<br />
Sushumnachya Marge,<br />
Swarupachya Tiri</font><br />
When we are at Your Lotus Feet our attention is settled,<br />
we are in the path of Sushumna and very close to Your Divine form.<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/U0w8QSa7zNY">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>When we enter into the Realm of Sahasrāra, then only we have [a] right to do the Sahasrāra Pūjā.</b> Before this nobody talked about Sahasrāra, nobody did any Pūjā to Sahasrār. This is your privilege that you are in the Realm of Sahasrāra and that you can do this Pūjā, perform it, is your right, you are chosen for this. It’s a very privileged place for you to enter into the Sahasrāra of the Virāṭ, to reside in the brain as cells of that Sahasrāra.<br />
Let us see what is the quality of the cells of Sahasrāra. These are specially created cells through the working of the Swādhiṣhṭhāna. Passing through all the chakras, when they arrive at Sahasrāra they are equipped to handle the brain’s activity without getting involved into other elements in the body.<br />
In the same way, the Sahaja Yogis are not to be involved in the other cells, human beings, of the body of this Universe."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, State of Absolute (Nirānanda Absolute Joy, Absolute Love, Absolute Compassion, Absolute Power), Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1180.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So today is the day we are celebrate [celebrating] by which we have opened absolutely a new dimension, 
a[n] absolutely a venue of Great Divinity, of the proofs of Divine.<br />
And this is something so great that we can really finish all the illusions they have about themselves, about their ego. We can manage them. 
That power you all have.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tucha Kharokhar. Hya Vishwachi, Karati An Karaviti</b></font><br />
You verily are the Creator of the Universe<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tucha Kharokhar. Hari Apada, Deun. Dhan. Sampatti</b></font><br />
You verily are the One who takes away all the sorrows by granting us wealth<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Samarth. Tuchi Samarth. Kari Maj. Divyatvachi Murti </b></font><br />
O, most omnipresent! Please make me powerful too<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Param.mangala Yugandhara Tu, Tuchi Ādi Śhakti</b></font><br />
O, embodiment of total Auspiciousness through ages, only You are Ādi Śhakti<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tujhya Thayi Man. Lago Deun. Sahaj. Yog. Mate</b></font><br />
Having granted this Sahaja Yoga to me, please keep my attention forever on You.<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Namostute, Namostute<br />
Śhrī Nirmalā Devī, Namostute</b></font><br />
Śhrī Nirmalā Devī, Salutations to You<br />
<br />
<font size="+0">[The 350 Sahaja Yogis present had just finished singing ‘Namostute’.]</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Beautifully rendered! It’s a song written much before, I think just after the first Sahasrāra Day. 
I mean, it’s a very ancient song. And still is maintained so well."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0502 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Thredbo Village, Kosciuszko National Park, New South Wales, Australia</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0">Namostute</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So after so many days, the Sahasrāra has been opened out. We have to open out our Sahasrāra again.<br />
Through our meditative processes, through understanding ourselves and others, maybe logically reaching that point: ‘There’s no way out now. We have reached to the end of it now. The whole logic has ended up now. Jump in the Ocean of Love. Finished!'<br />
<b>Once you jump in the Ocean of Love there’s nothing to be done! Just to be enjoyed: every wave of it, every hue of it, every touch of it. That is what one has to learn by reasoning that, ‘Sahaja Yoga is nothing but is Love.'</b><br />
May God bless you all."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0506 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Sahaja Yoga Is Nothing but Is Love (Whole Power of Sahasrāra is Love and Jump in the Ocean of Love), Theater Cinema della Rosa, Via delle Rose, 35, Sorrento, Italy</b></font>
<br />

</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahaja Yoga is the power of compassion and love of God Almighty. But it's not just talk, just not giving you a lecture or a sermon, but it is the actualization of the experience of this Divine Love. It is spirit-oriented, not money-oriented, nor is power-oriented.</b> All the religions have failed outside because they are not Spirit-oriented."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0801 Public Program, Sala Polivalentă, Bucharest, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1181.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Prana-tanam prasida twam</b><br />
O Devī, the remover of the afflictions of the universe,<br />
<b>Devī Vishw'arti-harni</b><br />
Be pleased with us who are prostrating at Your Lotus Feet.<br />
<b>Trailokya vasinam'idye</b><br />
O Devī, who is worshipped by the dwellers of the three worlds<br />
<b>Lokanam varda bhava</b><br />
Please grant boons to all the people.</font><br />
<font color="FireBrick "><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sahasrāra Swāminī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mokṣha Pradāyinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Tu Ādi Śhakti, Sahasrār virajī</b><br />
You are Śhrī Ādi Śhakti seated on the cosmic Sahasrāra<br />
<b>Chaitan lutati, Saty.yuga jagati</b><br />
Showering Divine vibrations and heralding the beginning of Satya Yuga<br />
<b>Vishwa ki Janani, tu Mahādevī</b><br />
You are the Mother of the universe and the Great Goddess<br />
<b>Tere Putra banne ki Patrata de Mā</b><br />
Mother please grant us all the qualities by which we can be Your children in reality.<br />
<b>He Nirmalā Mā, He Nirmalā Mā<br />
Tera pyar. moksha kā Anand. hai Mā</b><br />
O Divine Mother, Your unbounded love is the bliss of liberation</font><br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=v7T1xpKkYFU&amp;ab_channel=108Victoria">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/23094142"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Savera Aya Hai, Mata Ne Jagaya Ha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lUNkxcIAEs4">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharanam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1182.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today's Pūjā is very important</b>, because I feel Western countries have gone off with their ego, and they need Buddha very much, and they like also this so-called Buddhism very much, because you see, they can then just hide behind that camouflage. "We are Buddhist, you see." They'll worry about Afghanistan and they'll worry about lama. They'll worry about all other people, because, 'You see, we are Buddhist.' But there's no truth in it, no truth.<br /> 
<b>Sahaja Yogis have to establish that truth, that dedication.<br />
So Buddha has said: "Buddham śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi." ``I bow to all those who are realized Souls." "Dhammam śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi." "I bow myself, to my dharma," that is Vishwa Nirmala Dharma. And then lastly is: "Saṅghaṃ śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi." "I bow to collectivity."</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0520 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Gautama, The Lord of the Ego, Open Air near El Farell Hotel, Barcelona, Spain</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Buddham śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkSlateBlue ">I surrender myself to my Self-realization and to all those who are realized Souls (Buddhas)</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Dhammam śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkSlateBlue ">I surrender myself to dharma, to the innate religion that is Vishwa Nirmala Dharma</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Saṅghaṃ śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkSlateBlue ">I surrender myself to collectivity and to the collective community of realized Souls.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Ādi Śhaktyai Nirmalā Mātaram śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkSlateBlue ">I surrender myself to Śhrī Ādi Śhaktī Mātājī</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Buddham śharaṇaṃ gacchāmi</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Sahasrara Puja" /><category term="maroon @ Sahasrara Say" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Akṣhaya Tṛitīya: “today is a day where, whatever you want to know of eternal nature, you can ask Me. And we’ll ask for eternity.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/22" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Akṣhaya Tṛitīya: “today is a day where, whatever you want to know of eternal nature, you can ask Me. And we’ll ask for eternity.”" /><published>2023-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/2023_04_22_Akshaya_Tritiya</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/22"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Had a very nice Pūjā in Pune which I had to perform on the thirteenth because it is the date called Akshaya Tritiya, means un-destructible [indestructible] third day of the moon. That’s actually nobody knew, but it is the Pūjā of the Kundalinī. That day everybody felt very, very clear. Very clear. Pūjā was hardly for about half an hour, the real Pūjā of the Kuṇḍalinī.</b> But everybody felt extremely clear and beautiful. So, that sort of Pūjā we should do tomorrow also, if possible, so that we’ll have the feelings of Sahasrāra completely opened out because even if Sahasrāra is opened, the rest of the chakras, if they are caught up then you have problems. It’s better to clear out all the chakras and then the Sahasrāra. So, tomorrow we’ll do the Pūjā in that fashion and I hope it will work out very well for all of you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0502 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On Arrival before the Evening Program, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Thredbo Village, Kosciuszko National Park, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1172.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Akṣhay Tṛitīya Pūjā.<br />
That's the day, when, I mean it is regarded as the most auspicious day to start anything."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0610 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, About Music, Photographs and False Gurus, Lunch before the evening Public Program in Graz, Gleißenfeld (75 kms S of Vienna), Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>She knows you very well and that is the reason why today we are here to worship our Kuṇḍalinī, to give Her all the credit, that ‘Oh, Mother, You have given us these great powers.</b><br />
You have given us this subtle knowledge within ourselves. You have given us the love which encompasses the whole world.’ And the more and the more you become aware of her connections – very, very delicate connections – then you’ll be amazed."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0811 Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, The Power of Pure Desire, Weilburg, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So this is what it gives you discretion, and Love is Truth.</b> So to this Kuṇḍalinī, which is nothing but, is the River, as yesterday they described Nirvaj, which doesn’t accept any compensation. The River of that Pure Love which has awakened us with such love, kindness and tenderness, we should try to use that power within ourselves to be like that because our job is, She has given us Realization for the emancipation of the whole world, not only our own."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0621 Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, Pure Love, Compassion, and Morality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"So what we should ask for is that beautiful, soft, compassionate nature, and then the Kuṇḍalinī will supply because She only has that. Kuṇḍalinī doesn’t have anything else. <b>All Her Power is of love, nothing but love.</b> So how can She give you something She doesn’t have? Supposing you hate someone, what can She do? She can’t do anything because She cannot give you powers to hate. So what She says, ‘You hate someone. Hold or forgive.’ She gives you the power to forgive."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0811 Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, The Power of Pure Desire, Weilburg, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1173.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Today we have assembled here to do the Pūjā of the Mother Earth. We call it as the Bhūmī Pūjā, Śhrī Dharā Pūjā. She’s called as Dharā. As you know, ‘dhā’ means ‘sustain’. Rā-dhā. 
The One who sustains the energy is Rādhā. And Dharā, which is the One which is sustenance itself, She sustains us. On Her we live."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0803 Śhrī Bhūmī (Dharā) Pūjā (Inauguration of Śhuddhi Camp Pūjā), Mother Earth, Tent, Marque, Back Garden, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we have to know something about the connection of Sahaja Yoga with this Mother Earth. <b>It is very important, that we must understand the value of the Mother Earth. She has been very kind to all of you, She has been sucking your vibrations, She has been ..., otherwise also, She has given you everything that you see around. So today, we have to understand the connection and the symbolic expression of the Mother Earth within ourselves.</b><br />
I’ve told you before also that Kuṇḍalinī, which is in three and a half coils, is placed within the triangular bone. Now, this abode of the Kuṇḍalinī is called as Mūlādhāra. And is represented in this Universe as this Mother Earth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0821 Mother Earth and Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Garden, Āśhram, 102 Ditton Road, Surbiton, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1174.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Āratī Nirmalā Mā</b></font><br />
Āratī of Nirmalā Mā<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Charani Thevila Me Matha  </b></font><br />
I bow my head at Your Feet<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Āratī Nirmalā Mā</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Ādi Śhakti Kuṇḍalinī</b></font><br />
Primordial Energy Kuṇḍalinī<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Sarva Vishwachi Jananī</b></font><br />
Mother of the entire Universe<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Nirguna He Rupa Tuzhe</b></font><br />
Your Form is Formless,<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Zahli Saguna Tu Ata</b></font><br />
Now You are in form.<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/2btBuq4VYL4">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0619 Śhrī Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, The Advent of the Primordial Kuṇḍalinī, Mödling, Austria</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/545736371"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Sat Janam Jo Punya kiye Hai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Pinjare Wali Munia</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/en_WVhHFufI">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Kuṇḍalinī Chadi Badhi Jay Mori Nirmalā Mātā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/KOKeT0HOmXU?list=RDKOKeT0HOmXU">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Jay Ambe Kuṇḍalinī Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/7dqX2ZNiG5I">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1175.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"And I [unclear] also, I just explained to you, <b>today is a day where, whatever you want to know of eternal nature, you can ask Me. And we'll ask for eternity.<br />
But many people think that today is a day when, whatever you ask, God has to give you. Is true.</b> Whatever you ask, you'll get it. But [is] just a temptation.<br />
Beyond that, is eternity. So whatever you have to ask, you should ask for something that is eternal, is indust ... indestructible. That higher state, we should call the Permanent State of Joy and Bliss, is to be asked today. Because all other askings are useless. And you again go back to the position where you were.<br />
Is important to understand, that this time, today, you have to ask something eternal for yourself, something eternal for your family, something eternal for your country, and something eternal for this world and universe.<br />
<b>You all are Sahaja Yogis, and of a very high level, and I'm happy that the all of you have come here for that Eternal State of Devī.<br />
And, if it works out, you should get that Eternal State [with]in yourself. You should get that state where you don't want anything anymore. and reside in that beautiful condition of complete peace and bliss.</b> That's what is available to you, but I ... you can easily achieve it.<br />
I cannot say this to people who are not Sahaja Yogis. But I can definitely say this to people who are Sahaja Yogis and who have achieved already Self-realization.<br />
So, today I hope, you all .. of you will pray and ask for that Eternal Love of God. It should flow to you all, all the time.<br />
May God bless you all."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0419 Akṣhaya Tṛitīya Pūjā (Hindi + English), Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="maroon @ Akshaya Tritiya" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Easter: “Your Resurrection has to be complete and you have to mature in Sahaja Yoga.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/09" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Easter: “Your Resurrection has to be complete and you have to mature in Sahaja Yoga.”" /><published>2023-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/2023_04_09_Easter_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/09"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating the Resurrection of Christ. With ... with it we also have to celebrate the Resurrection of human beings, of Sahaja Yogis who have been resurrected as realized Souls.</b><br />
With that we have to understand that we enter into a new awareness. There was no need for Christ to enter into any new awareness, He had to come down and again to show to this world that you are the eternal life, that you ml ... lead a life that is spiritual, which never perishes. You have to rise into that new realm, which is the Realm of God Almighty, what you call the Kingdom of God.<br />
And He said it very clearly to Nicodemus that, "You have to be born-again." And when he asked: "Am I to enter back into my mother's womb to be born again?" And He said it so clearly! It's so clear! Those who don't want to see can remain blind! But he said it very-very clearly that, "No! That is, whatever is born of the flesh is the flesh, but whatever is born of the Spirit is the Spirit."<br />
I mean, nothing could be more clear than that, that it has to be born of the Spirit."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0422 Easter Pūjā, The Way of Our Full Spiritual Growth and Sahaja Penance, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1166.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today we are here to worship the Resurrection of Christ and also to thank Him for giving us an ideal life of a Saint who has to work for the benevolence of the whole world."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0422 Easter Pūjā, To Be in Connection with Christ Is to Be Enjoying Your Meditation (What You Have to Receive Is the Qualities that He Had and Be Aware of Your Responsibilities), Hall, School, Eastbourne, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Navabalala namana karuya</b><br />
In resurrection, Christ was reborn and to this newborn we bow down and salute in reverence.<br />
<b>Nave sumananachi mala arpuya</b><br />
By garlanding Him with fresh flowers full of fragrance.<br />
<b>Gani manohar tyasa gavuya,</b><br />
We will adulate Him by singing His praises<br />
<b>Hrudi mam basale prabhu majhe vijayi zhale</b><br />
He has now created a permanent abode in my heart because of His glorious victory over death.</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, as you know that He created all the Brahmāṇḍas. Brahman means an [a] universe.<br />
Now, the universe of the Sun, out of that universe has come out this Earth. Out of that you have come out.<br />
And in your Āgñyā chakra He has created a small Virāṭa, as they call it. He exists within your Āgñyā chakra.<br />
<b>This sacrifice is very, very significant. And, though it is gross, in subtle it has happened. To take the awareness through this center of Āgñyā was done by Christ, by His crucifixion.<br />
He came as a gross person, just like a gross human being.<br />
His body died, but did not die, because that body was also made of that imperishable Divine Vibrations, as you call, a Radiations or this Brahma. They did not die. And that's why the body did not die and He resurrected with His body.<br />
He had to die to show that the body though [it] dies, can be saved. That's why He had to be crucified.</b> Otherwise He could not have shown you.<br />
But it's actually it was experimented in the Vaikuṇṭha, as you call it, that He died and then resurrected to show that this does not die.<br />
Kṛiṣhṇa has said, "Nainaṃ chindanti śhastrāṇi, nainaṃ dahati pāvakaḥ" [Bhagavad Gītā 2.23, line 1]. "It is not killed by any weapon, neither it is burned by any fires, nor it is blown by any wind." "Na chainaṃ kledayanty āpo, na śhoṣhayati mārutaḥ"[Bhagavad Gītā 2.23, line 2]. "Neither, nothing can suck in." That Spirit is He.<br />
......<br />
But again you cannot crucify Him. Now He has become Ekādeśha Rudra as described, the Eleven Rudras as you know very well. These are all the Powers of Śhiva given to Him.<br />
<b>Up till now, till He was born, Kṛiṣhṇa had given Him His Powers, and that He became Mahāvirā[ṭ]. He was even placed above Kṛiṣhṇa.</b><br /> 
But now, when He will come, He'll be bestowed with the Destructive Powers of Śhiva, eleven of them. One is sufficient to finish all the universes. And that's what is described as the coming of the Christ. You cannot crucify Him anymore.<br />
And the time has come for all of us to be prepared for us to receive Him. We are not yet ready to receive Him. Unless and until you are realized, you cannot receive Him, because if you remain unrealized till He comes, you'll be finished, you'll be gone, you'll be destroyed. He'll just come to destroy all the nonsensical things. So this short time should be used for your emancipation and for your development.<br />
......<br />
<b>For us, Sahaja Yogis, it is important to understand the significance of Christ's life. That His body was the only body who was made of these Radiations.</b><br />
All other bodies were human bodies. All the Incarnations, even that of Kṛiṣhṇa's when He came on this Earth, were having human qualities that Mother Earth existed in the body."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0406 Easter Pūjā, Significance of Christ (Easter Is a Special Day Because in Our Lives the Death has Died and We Are Resurrected), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1167.png" /></div>

<p style="color:MediumPurple; text-align:center;">
You were crucified and resurrected in pure Spirit.<br />
You rose after three days.<br />
You are peace.<br />
You absorb all thought.<br />
You abide in the Adi Agnya chakra.<br />
<br />
You are hallowed by Your Father.<br />
Your name is holy.<br />
You are Intelligence.<br />
You are wisdom.<br />
You are perfect humility.<br />
<br />
You guard the gate of our Mother.<br />
You are the Son of God.<br />
You are the only way to the Kingdom of God.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Happy Easter to you all.</b><br />
So we celebrate Easter to show Christ resurrected Himself. The Spirit that is Christ has to resurrect out of the material manifestation of the Divine Itself. The matter is manifested because we ourselves have created it. Not that we are born out of matter, our body, but we are attached to it, we want it, we want to have it. Whatever you want, that sustains itself, by your desire, because now you are on the stage. If you want to sustain the matter, if you want to keep the matter as the first priority, it will remain. It cannot disappear. It has to go out of your mind that matter cannot hold you any further.<br />
Christ rose out of the matter, came out of the tomb which symbolizes the matter which has enclosed us within, which has to be opened out with our spiritual power. Throw away the stone that is covering this grave. Get out of that and stand outside it. This is the message of Christ's Resurrection."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0408 Easter Pūjā, Montague Hall, Montague Rd, Hounslow TW3 1LD (Outer London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is the day we are celebrating Easter. Easter is extremely symbolic, of – not only of Christ, but also for all of us. In that, the most important day is that of resurrection. The resurrection of Christ has the message of Christianity, not the cross. Through resurrection, Christ had shown that one can be resurrected with the body that you have. <b>And without His resurrection, we could not have managed the crossing of Āgñyā chakra, no doubt.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0414 Easter Pūjā (English + Hindi), You have to Crucify Your Ego, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1168.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Easter is something like our birthday we celebrate;</b> when we became a bird out of the cage, of the shell. So Easter is our birthday we are celebrating, of our Realization, and every day we must grow with our birthday. While in a human form you decrease your age as your birthday comes, but with this you increase your age."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0422 Easter Pūjā, The Way of Our Full Spiritual Growth and Sahaja Penance, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Granthi Vibhedinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">(Śhrī Mātājī is breaking our shells of ego and superego through Easter egg breaking and mentions that the mantra for this is Sarva Granthi Vibhedinī)</font><br />
<b>Breaking Easter Eggs</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The other day at the Āśhram I spoke to you about Easter, about the birth of Christ and His Resurrection, and the message of Christianity, that is Resurrection.<br />
<b>An egg is a very significant thing and it is written in one of the ancient Scriptures in India [as to] why Easter should be celebrated with an egg -- is most surprising. It's clear, it's very clear there, if one can see, how Christ is symbolized as an egg.</b><br />
Now what is an egg?<br />
In Sanskrit language, a Brahmin is called as dvijaḥ. Dvīji jayati: means the one who is born twice. And a bird is also called, any bird, is called as a dvijaḥ. Means twice-born. Because first the bird is born as an egg, and then reborn as a bird.<br />
In the same way, a human being is born as an egg, and then is born as a realized Soul."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0410 Public Program, Christ Is Symbolized as An Egg (The Egg and Rebirth), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Christ came on this Earth to say that we have to seek our Spirit. <b>The message of His life is His Resurrection.<br /> 
On the Easter Day we give eggs to each other. It is very symbolic.</b><br /> 
In Indian language a bird is called as khaga -- kha-ga -- and also dvijaḥ. The first one means the one which goes in the sky, flies in the sky. The second one means the twice-born. And a realized Soul is also called as dvijaḥ.<br />
<b>Christ has talked about your Second Birth throughout. He has said, "You are to be born-again."</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1002 Public Program, Day 1, Geneva, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1169.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This Resurrection of yours is much more blessed than that of Christ. He was alone, people wouldn't recognize Him. He had to show His marks where they had put nails on His hands and Feet. But today that is not the situation. Only thing is, first of all you have to recognize Me. That's all.</b> Need not know Me. It's not easy. It's difficult to know Me, but if you recognize Me, that's all. And it all depends on your sensitivity. <b>Your Resurrection has to be complete and you have to mature in Sahaja Yoga.</b><br />
If you cannot mature, I will say you should leave Sahaja Yoga. Go out for a while, where you will understand what's going on, then you'll come back."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0414 Easter Pūjā (English + Hindi), You have to Crucify Your Ego, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādhi vyādhi maranā varati</b><br />
All the diseases and problems get completely dissolved<br />
<b>Pāy. ashā purushāchā re</b><br />
Where the Feet of God reside<br />
<b>Bhaya kāy. tayā prabhu jyātzā re</b><br />
When we belong to God, what is there to fear?</font><br />  
<a href="https://youtu.be/47fMsue7fs8">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0422 Easter Pūjā, To Be in Connection with Christ Is to Be Enjoying Your Meditation (What You Have to Receive Is the Qualities that He Had and Be Aware of Your Responsibilities), Hall, School, Eastbourne, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/69820092"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gajānana Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maranache mela</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Eka Gaṇapati Eka Īsā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Dg41OjGhrU8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Easter Puja" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Jesus Christ" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Śhrī Hanumān Jayanti: “Hanumāna is a special Deity, a typical Deity full of qualities. There was a perfect balance between his devotion and power.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/06" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Śhrī Hanumān Jayanti: “Hanumāna is a special Deity, a typical Deity full of qualities. There was a perfect balance between his devotion and power.”" /><published>2023-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/2023_04_06_Shri_Hanuman_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/06"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating Hanumāna's Jayanti [birthday].</b><br />
What to say about Hanumāna? <b>The more powerful and wise, he was equally devoted and dedicated.</b> Generally, such a powerful person becomes right-sided and considers himself so high that he would not listen to anyone else. But <b>Hanumāna is a special Deity, a typical Deity full of qualities. There was a perfect balance between his devotion and power.</b> How could he achieve this balance is a thing to be understood.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga, when we are enlightened, we get many powers. Then we have to keep balance. We love others and with the power of the love, we keep on doing our duties.<br />
Śhrī Hanumāna was very powerful. He had many Divine Powers in Him Navadhā, that is Garima, Laghima, etc. He could be as big as he wanted to be and as small as an atom. He had achieved all these powers. Without attaining balance and coming to the central path. Such a powerful person generally goes crazy.<br />
<b>Each cell of Śhrī Hanumāna’s body was filled with power and devotion.</b> Because of this specialty today we worship Śhrī Hanumāna all over the world."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1160.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">"<b>Today we have come here to do Hanumāna’s Pūjā.</b><br />
Śhrī Hanumāna is a great character in our being and He runs all the way from Swādhiṣhṭhāna to your brain 
and He supplies all the necessary guidance we need in our futuristic planning or in our mental activities. <b>He gives us guidance and protection.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā, Electromagnetic Force, Schloss Schwetzingen, Frankfurt, Germany</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="chocolate"><b>You control people who have too much right side.
You bring down the speed of right-sided people (by giving them lethargic heaviness).
You hold a mace (the gada) in Your hand to reduce our illusions.
You are the source of enthusiasm.
Through Your bhakti (ocean of love) we may use Your fire. 
In this way, we may act without heating up our right side.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b> The 108 holy qualities of Shrī Hanumāna 
(Nirmal Vidya: Sahaja Yoga Mantra Book)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue">"<b>What we have to learn from Śhrī Hanumāna is this devotion (bhakti) and the power that he has given to you. If your devotion is real, then no one dares touch you. No one could touch.</b><br />
There are thousands of examples in Sahaja Yoga. People call them miracles. But I say that it is no miracle, it is the blessing of Śhrī Hanumāna.<br /> 
<b>So My blessings and Love to you all. Love yourself, also love others.</b><br /> 
Do not confine your love to “my son, my this, my that.” No! Love means selfless love (Nirvāja Pyār) love that expects no return, love that is not confined to relations only. You have been blessed with such unfathomable Power of Love. Use it.<br />
Infinite blessings."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1161.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">"It is such a joy today, and the whole atmosphere seems to be bubbling with it as if the angels are singing.<br />
And <b>the specialty of Hanumāna was that He was an angel.</b> Angels are born like angels. They are angels, and they are not human beings.<br /> 
They’re born with the angelic qualities. But now, you all have become angels from the human beings. It’s a very great achievement of Sahaja Yoga.<br /> 
The qualities that are born with the angels are seen from their very childhood."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="maroon"><b>Sada Sarvada Yog Tujha Ghadava</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">May each and every moment of my life be connected with you (for you)</font><br />
<font color="maroon"><b>Tujhe Karni Deha Majha padava</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">even my last breath be for you<br />
(for Divine purpose let my being{physical body} serve you till my last breath)</font><br />
<font color="maroon"><b>Upekshu Nako Gunvanta Ananta</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O God Almighty, please never disconnect from me.</font><br />
<font color="maroon"><b>Raghunāyaka Magane Hechi Āta</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">O Raghunāyaka, that's all I ask of You.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(by Śhrī Samartha Rāmadās Swāmī)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Hanumāna’s whole life was spent in serving Śhrī Rām. And He was such a dedicated bhakta of Śhrī Rām.</b><br />
Now here the contrast is also that Hanumāna had Navadhā, Navadhā uh-uh Siddhis, Navadhā Siddhis, Nine Siddhis: the Aṇima, Garima, Raguma [Laghima], and all sorts of things, that He could become small, He could become big, He could ... it so many things He had. Despite all these siddhis and the amount the [of] power He had, that Śhrī Rāma once asked Him that, “My s... My ah-ah-ah brother now, uh Lakṣhmaṇa, is being hit and He’s very sick. I mean, He’s just dying, so you go and get a particular kind of a sañjīvanī, a kind of a[n] herb, is which I want to rub on His head.” So He went there and He found He couldn’t find it so He brought the whole of the mountain on His hand and [laughing:] gave it to Rāma, “Now You select! I don’t know, I can’t find it.” [Soft laughter.]<br />
<b>That is the Hanumāna Śhakti! And with all that power, He was such a humble person and such a dedicated person.</b><br />
<b>This is the sign of a powerful Sahaja Yogi. Anybody who is powerful has to be humble and nonviolent.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1162.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Bhima rupi Maha-rudra</b></font><br />
You are huge in form; the greatest and most formidable;
the final manifestation of Śhrī Śhiva's eleven destroying powers.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Vajra Hanumāna Māruti</b></font><br />
You are known as the invincible one after being struck on the chin (hanu) by the thunderbolt of Indra. You are he who was born of the lord of the wind (Marut).<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Vanari Añjanī Suta</b></font><br />
You destroy the outward forms of illusion such as the beautiful gardens and forests of Lanka. You are the son of Añjanī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Rāmduta Prabhanjana</b></font><br />
You are the messenger and divine energy of Śhrī Rāma. You are like the stormy hurricane wind, and to Your Mother, the radiant dawn light that dissolves the individual soul into Paramchaitanya.<br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Maha-bali Prana-data</b></font><br />
Of mighty power, the giver of life;<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Sakala Uthavi Bale</b></font><br />
Your strength awakens all.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Saukhya-kari Dhukha-hari</b></font><br />
You are the bestower of benevolent happiness and the destroyer of sorrows.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Dhurta Vaishnava Gayaka</b></font><br />
You are the mischievous angel. You are the essence of Śhrī Viṣhṇu.<br />
You are the greatest among singers.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Māruti Stotra<br />
(Verses in praise of Śhrī Hanumān by Śhrī Samartha Rāmadās Swāmī)<br />
(Nirmala Vidya: Sahaja Yoga Mantra Book)</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I hope by today’s Pūjā, that enthusiasm, that venturesome nature will vibrate your Piṅgalā, and without feeling any ego about it, in the most humble manner as Hanumāna was, you will do the jobs.<br />
Obedience is the only thing that helps to carry out your work and you’ll become humbler and humbler.<br />
But if you think, ‘Oh I am doing this,’ then finished. <b>But if you know that it’s done by the Divine – ‘Paramachaitanya is doing everything, I am just an instrument,’ the humility will be there and you will be an effective instrument.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, <b>He’s the one who protects also all the deities, He protects.</b> Now, there’s a difference between Shri Ganesha and Him. The Shri Ganesha gives energy Shakti, but the one who protects is Shri Hanumana. So you’ll find that when Shri Krishna was the chariot[eer] of Arjuna then on top of the chariot was sitting Hanumana, not Shri Ganesh. Hanumana was sitting there looking after Him. Also in a way that Shri Rama Himself becomes Shri Vishnu, so He has to look after Him."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā, Electromagnetic Force, Schloss Schwetzingen, Frankfurt, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1163.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="maroon"><b>"Only after Realization you can put the fruits of your work at the Lotus Feet of the Divine, 
and only after Self-realization you can have Ananya Bhakti, means the Devotion, which is singular."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0905 Śhrī Virāṭa Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Devadūta sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
(The messenger of God, You are the Archangel Gabriel)</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Jay Hanumān!</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/65376957"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Jay Hanumāna gyāna guṇa sāgar</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Victory to Śhrī Hanumāna, the ocean of knowledge and virtue.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Jay Kapisa tihun-loka ujagara</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Hail, Great lord of the monkeys who illuminates the three Worlds!</font><br />
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Hanumāna Chalisa y Tulasīdās</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Hanumāna Chalisa translation in English</b> (1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>He Ale Kiti Gele Kiti, Sampale Bharara</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">So many have come and so many have gone.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Tujhya Pari Nawatsare, Azuni Darara, Ha!</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">But Your name is ever so powerful</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>He Dhavat.Ye Lav.Kari, Amhi Zhalo Re hairana</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">Please come quickly, as we are growing tired of fighting this negativity!</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Ek Mukhana Bola, Bola Jay, Jay Hanumān</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">With one voice let us praise, victory to Hanumān.</font><br />
<b>Śhrī Hanumān Stuti (Anjanichya Suta)</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nām Gheta mukhi raghavache</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhar de itni bhakti Ma</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Mā de bhakti ka dān</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1164.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Pavan Tanay Sankat Haran</b><br />
O Son of the Wind God, remover of misfortunes,<br />
<b>Mangal Murati Rūp</b><br />
Most auspicious figure,<br />
<b>Rām Lakhan Sītā Sahit</b><br />
With Śhrī Rāma, Śhrī Lakṣhmaṇa and Śhrī Sītā,<br />
<b>Hridaya Basahu Sur Bhūp.<br />
O Protector of Heaven and Earth, please reside in my heart.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Hanumana Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Śhrī Mahāvīr Jayanti: “we all should increase our bhakti and growing bhakti in the work of Mahāvīr. I am happy that on this day of Mahāvīr Jayanti you all are doing Mahāvīr’s work”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/04" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Śhrī Mahāvīr Jayanti: “we all should increase our bhakti and growing bhakti in the work of Mahāvīr. I am happy that on this day of Mahāvīr Jayanti you all are doing Mahāvīr’s work”" /><published>2023-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/2023_04_04_Shri_Mahavira_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/04/04"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Even though Saraswatī has created all the Swaras, so what! <b>But the emotions it contains, the bhakti it contains it is due to the blessings of Mahāvīr.</b> Mahāvīr has really worked hard for this because he scared people that if you go to the wrong way, you go to hell, and on taking this correct way you will be overwhelmed and you all are actually witnessing it. Like this <b>we all should increase our bhakti and growing bhakti in the work of Mahāvīr. I am happy that on this day of Mahāvīr Jayanti you all are doing Mahāvīr's work</b> ......<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George [the Guardian angel of London]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0404 Śhrī Mahāvīra Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1156.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are going to do the Pūjā of Mahāvīra, and we never had this Pūjā before.</b><br />
Uh the reason for this was that Mahāvīra's life was an ascetic's life, ah just like Buddha -- even more than Buddha it would be -- uh because at the time when these two were born, the Brahminism of the Hinduism had taken a very funny form. People had become extremely ritualistic and they worsh... [were] worshiping all kinds of stones and all kinds of things instead of worshiping only the swayambhu."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are going to celebrate the birthday of Mahāvīra.<br />
Mahāvīra is the Incarnation of Bhairavanāth, or you call Him as Saint Michael.</b> Now these two Saints as you know one as the Gabriel, Hanumāna, and another is Saint Michael. One is placed on the Piṅgalā nāḍī and another one, Saint Michael, on the Iḍā nāḍī.<br />
So, Mahāvīra had to go through lots of search. Of course He was a[n] angel, but came as human being and He had to find out the thing of the left side, and how the left side acts. It's a very complicated thing, left side, is much more complicated than right side. On the left side we have also seven nāḍīs, and these seven nāḍīs are placed one after another. They are described in books and given different names to them. Now these seven nāḍīs that are on the left side, as you know, they cater to our past. Say for example, every moment becomes a past. Every present becomes a past. Then we have past of this lifetime, and also we have past of our previous lives. Then all the past is built in within us since our creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Mahāvīr resides on our Iḍā nāḍī and rules it. All the saṃskāras that we have in us are corrected by Him.</b><br />
He has defined and explained what is Hell. What happens when human go to Hell and what and how they suffer in Hell, He has explained this in very detail.<br />
Buddha and Mahāvīr were samakālīn [contemporary] and both of Them had a life of penance. Both of Them were prince. But still both of Them dedicated themselves in tapasyā. And They found out that, 'When human make mistakes and go to the left side then how he goes in Hell and how he suffers.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0404 Śhrī Mahāvīra Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India&lt;</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1157.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>After they get their Realization, that He called as Kevalagyān: only the knowledge, only knowledge, means Pure Knowledge.</b> They will develop some Samyak Darśhan, means Integrated Personality and all the Collective Consciousness. He talked of all, all these things.<br /> 
But as He belonged to the left side, He has described Hell very clearly. Fundamentally, basically there are Fourteen Hells according to Him. And is horrible to read all that, what He has described about Hell. Because He wanted to tell people that, 'If you do all these wrong things, you'll go to Hell.'<br /> 
And He talked about, not about Form, Formly God, but Formless God, because He didn't want people to again start ritualism but get to right ... right to the position where they could get their Self-realization to cleanse themself.<br />
So you can imagine: how difficult, in those days at Mahāvīra, was even to be one of the candidates for Self-realization. It's frightening for you! <b>That's why I never had this uh Pūjā. Because to do all these things, first of all, and to become absolutely pure, then only He would give Realization.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>&gt;1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>In Sahaj we very much respect and understand Mahāvīrjī and we also accept that He is the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth and not only this, [but] He took birth many times and later also came as Hasan and Husayn. In Bible Bhairavnāthjī is addressed as Saint Georg and some refer Him as Saint Michael.</b><br />
It is very surprising that London which we understand as Heart has Saint George as its angel. That is! They accept Bhairavnāth so it's correct. Because if Śhivjī resides in heart then having Bhairavnāth is important.<br />
There are so many things which if we read with understanding then they are all interconnected and how is there relation automatically established.<br />
<b>In Sahaj Śhakti you get overwhelmed and you enjoy it and this makes Me happy. God has created this universe for you so you should enjoy it, what else do you want?</b> In you there are many powers and you use them and you have also shared it with others.<br />
In this way <b>the family of our Sahaj should grow. We should save as many possible, most important our children. We should take care of them because a wrong type of culture has started and the children are getting affected. So we should pay attention to it and to them and take care of them.</b> When they are established in Sahaj, then they will not go around."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0404 Śhrī Mahāvīra Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The ascetic life of Mahāvīra was of a very, very extreme nature. He was the one who was born in a ... uh ... clan of warriors, Kṣhatriyas. And then He was also married, also He had a daughter. And then He decided, because He knew He had to do the work of the Divine, He decided to take a saṃnyāsa. So He took uh the permission of His brother because His parents were dead. He was a king, so He gave up all His uh material wealth, everything and He beg ... became a complete saṃnyāsī. And the He left His family, His left His ... house, everything behind and went alone with a little bowl for begging alms. And there people who joined Him were very few, and He asked them that, "You have to also become ascetics," Munis.<br />
He was a Reincarnation of Saint Michael and He resides on the left side, on the Iḍā nāḍī. And He looks after the whole of it, right from Mūlādhāra onwards up to the Sahasrāra. <b>So Saint Michael was born as Mahāvīra, meaning The Greatest Warrior. But when He was born, the whole place got lot of uh prosperity, that's why He was called as Vardhamān, to begin with.</b><br />
But His asceticism was there because of the Brahminism that was so prevalent in those days, and people were absolutely drowned into it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1158.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Sahaj Yoga is the integration of all these Great Prophets and these Incarnations.<br />
So, I have to tell you that, whatever were your conditionings and all that, to get rid of them, you must get out of this Ocean of Illusion."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Aum twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāvīra sākṣhāt<br />
Shrī Ādi Shakti Mātājī Shrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!<br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Mahāvīra. Salutations to You!</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76399695"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hemaja Sutam Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mGvUq8-ebXo">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>21 names of Śhrī Bhairava recited during Śhrī Mahavira Mahāvīra Pūjā in Perth.</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Vina</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jarī Asel Anta</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirbhay Nirgun gun re</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/_buuncAm9Ts">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1159.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>""So we have to thank really very much Mahavira, who has given us this power to remove our left-sided problems, who has given us this light in our hand, which He Himself vibrates, and He Himself tries to throw some light on the obscure things about Me also.<br />
Because of Him only, we can get cured of so many physical and mental troubles.<br />
You know that the left side can be easily cured if you use three-candle treatment.<br />
That shows Mahavira is only fond of light. He doesn’t like darkness.</b><br /> 
And His idea is, I think that way, is to now fully go all the way to clear the left side as far as possible, to help Sahaja Yoga to establish in countries where I find still lot of this negativity is there – a lot of it.<br />
So He’s working it out, everywhere, and the psychosomatic diseases and all these diseases also, we can work it out with candle-light and all that, with three candles we can do this treatment.<br />
So you have to be very thankful to Him that He has achieved this kind of entry into the left side and has found out for us what sort of problems exist on left side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Mahavira Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Rāma Navamī: “the head of every state has to be the father of his subjects, that’s what He has tried to show by His life.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/30" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Rāma Navamī: “the head of every state has to be the father of his subjects, that’s what He has tried to show by His life.”" /><published>2023-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/2023_03_30_Day_9_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/30"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Rāma came on this Earth to establish the institution of benevolent king.</b> The political development and the political evolution started from this [right] side. <b>He is the one who gave leadership as a benevolent king, the one who represents God and who is a king. The idea of a king related to God came from Śhrī Rāma.</b><br />
But the modern kings are not like that, they have no relation with God. On the contrary, they are horrid people. Some of them are nothing but satanic people, absolutely Satan is there and you can see from the way they lead their lives, and they have led their life before. So the benevolence of Śhrī Rāma is here [shows the right Heart] to be followed by all the political leaders and all the people who are at the helm of affairs. He is the ideal that was created for human beings, to run their authority as the head, or the loving compassionate benevolent leader of the people, who has to govern them by making them respectful, by respect. And if human beings create such things who are not respectable, those who have no human values, those who have no moral courage, those who are selfish, those who are self-centered, then they have nothing to do to be there.<br />
<b>So this is the position of Rāma who is the Father. So the head of every state has to be the father of his subjects, that's what He has tried to show by His life.</b> So much so that He had to sacrifice His beloved Wife, whom He loved so much."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Public Program (1st Day and 2nd Day of Navarātri), Self and Heart Chakra, Day 6, East West Center, 141 5th Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1151.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today I said that Śhrī Rāma was born at twelve o’clock</b> hence the Pūjā should be at time as such it is not long Pūjā but we have to understand 
that the human form within us in form of humanity in which we understand and make changes in our mind, curiosity and thoughts.<br />
Through the medium of Śhrī Rāma can bring change in our thoughts, he can bring change in our behavior because he is ideal for us, reaching this ideal we can reach other ideals since he is ideal of human being.<br />
<b>This is big thing that the God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal.<br />
We don’t leave our dharma ‘Vishwa Nirmala Dharma’ even if we have lot of difficulties.</b><br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Mātā Rāmo matpitā Rāma-chandrah Swāmī Rāmo matsakhā Rāmachandrah</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Rāma is my mother and my father; He is my lord and my friend,</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>sarvaswam me Rāma-chandro dayālur nānyam jāne n’aeva jāne na jāne</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b> So also the ever-compassionate Shri Rama is everything to me and I know nothing else at all</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Rāma Kavach in praise of Śhrī Rāma)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We have gathered here on the occasion of Rām Navamī.</b> Everybody has said, “Mother please tell us about Śhrī Rām.”<br />
You know that Śhrī Rāma has a very important place on our chakra, He is situated on our right Heart. Śhrī Rāma has taken the place of father hence if there is lack in the responsibility or love from father this chakra is caught. In Sahaja Yoga, we to understand that Śhrī Rāma and all other Deities have taken the form to fulfill their divine work, in all Śhrī Rāma had a special task. As it was said by Socrates that the Benevolent King has to come the same way Śhrī Rāma had come on this Earth as benevolent king, He came in the form of human being, He even forgot that He was Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, forgot about Him but for all world, He was Puruṣhottama Rāma.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we need to know when we pray any Deity, we have imbibed the specialties and qualities of the particular Deity within us, Śhrī Rāma had many qualities.<br />
You all know his childhood life and you have already heard about his qualities, he was Puruṣhottama he had another quality that in his ruling, he did not care for his wife or children in front of his subjects view."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Śhrī Rāma was born at midnight so let’s have Pūjā late. Śhrī Rāma Pūjā is not a specially long one. As He is in a human form He is humanity within us by which we understand our intellect and our thoughts get changed. Śhrī Rāma is that through Him we can change our thoughts. Our nature can change because He is our ideal.<br />
After achieving His ideals, we reach another because He was human ideal. <b>It is great that God came to this world in a human form to became our ideal. He has gone through all the hardships to show us strength to keep dharma. That is Viśhwa Dharma and the State of Yoga.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1152.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"Rāma was studying with this Vasiṣhṭha and they used to come for holidays to father’s place. 
Then, he had the capacity to kill a demon with only one arrow. 
It’s called as Eka-bāṇi."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0402 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī Day), Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Only Sahaja Yogis can bring his light to their attention of Śhrī Rāma residing in them, he was impartial. As such all the Deities are above sins and puṇyas like Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa killed so many demons Śhrī Rāma killed Rāvaṇa with our worldly views it might be sin but according divine views it is not because they killed the negative peoples, they took out the negativity for this they had all rights to do whatever was necessary, as like <b>the Goddess killed the demons some people will think that it was sin but it was not for the protection of Saints</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Śhrī Rāma Himself was born on the right side.<br />
Great example for all of you is Śhrī Rām who was on the right side, who works the right side. When He was born and He was a child ...... <b>He is a Sūryavaṃśhi, He is the son of Sūrya. I mean Sūrya – everything comes from the Sun to Him.</b> When He was born and was a little child, He asked His mother that “I would like to have the Moon.” He started crying, and nobody knew how to satisfy. He said “I want to have the Moon.” They gave him any toys – he’d throw away. They said, “What a child it is, funny thing ... He wants to have the Moon, now how to get Him the moon?” They did not know how to solve the problem.<br />
He said, “Somehow you get Me the Moon. I don’t want to eat or anything, I want to have the Moon.”<br />
Here the Moon represents the Ātmā, the cooling capacity. He asked for the Moon. You are all on the right side, so ask for the Moon. Ask for the Spirit. And they didn’t know how to satisfy this Śhrī Rāma, who was the Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, asking for the Moon of all the things, not for anything else. What is so important? So, the mother has always a[n] intuition. She brought a ... it’s a, it’s a Rāmāyaṇa, it is a beautiful drama. She brought a mirror and showed Him the Moon in the mirror. He said, “Now you can get the Moon here.” So sweet! And He was satisfied. Even the reflection of that can satisfy. You are like the mirrors and I want to see the reflection of Moon in you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0125 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Growth of the Being on the Subtler Plane (Count Your Blessings, Take Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga, Understand the Subtler Values of Everything, The Greatest Thing for a Sahaja Yogi Is the Living Energy, Be Sweet in Your Tongue, Just Open Your Heart, Great Power of Love, Take Up Love as Your Worshiping), Seminar, Day 3, Session 1 (morning), Lonavala, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1153.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Blue"><b>Thumak chalat Rāmachandra<br />
Thumak chalat Rāmachandra<br />
Bājat painjaniyān</b></font><br />
<font color="DeepPink">(Baby) Śhrī Rām walks, swaying unsteadily<br />
(Baby) Śhrī Rām ...... His anklets ring in tune with his steps</font><br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Kilaki kilaki uthat dhāy girat bhūmi latapatāy<br />
Dhaay māt god let dasharath kii raniyān</b></font><br />
<font color="DeepPink">Laughing joyously he stumbles around on the ground<br />
He is fondly picked into the laps of King Dasharath’s queens</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Thumak Chalat</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That is a very beautiful song was written by him. But still, the description of a child, how when he runs when he runs, when he jumps when he walks it’s a beautiful song about Śhrī Rāma. Ṭhumko atta hai who – Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra, atta hai kya?<br />
[In Hindi:] <b>Do you know the song ‘Ṭhumaka chalat  Rām[a]chandra’ ...</b><br />
[In English:] Now these words are such that we cannot explain in English, but when they walk, you know, with – started walking, so their body, you know, moves in a way that’s called ‘ṭhumakanā’ [toddle, waddle] in Hindi language. <b>So described by Tulasīdāsa, as Śhrī Rāma is walking in that way. ‘Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra’. And His anklets are singing and then He’s looking round and every pebble on which He’s walking is reflecting Him, like the souls in which He’s reflected.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0405 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Picnic, Lane Cove National Park, Lane Cone Valley Walk, West Pymble, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Now His coming on this Earth gave us the development of the right side and so the Yagñyas were also on the right side. Because first of all when human beings came on this Earth, they were frightened of all the animals who would invade them and all kinds of horrible rākṣhasas and all those people, and negative forces they would trouble them. <b>So, in that state they needed to create a king, a ruler, who was an ideal king and he who would rule according to the Laws of Dharma.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0402 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī Day), Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1154.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Red"><b>"On the night of Full Moon, you should meditate on Śhrī Rāma and surrender yourself to Him for protection.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen">The meaning of the word rāmachandra is ‘creativity'. You should completely dedicate your creative powers to Him.</font><br />
Thus you have to take special care of yourself on these two days.
<font color="Red">However, <b>on the seventh (Saptamī) and ninth (Navamī) days of Lunar fortnights, you have My special blessings. 
Remember that you are specially blessed by Me on these two days. 
Make some special arrangements so that you can have proper meditation on these days.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0529 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Dhyān Kaise Karein (How to Meditate), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Śhrī Rāma-chandra charanau manasā smarāmi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"> I worship the Feet of Shri Śhrī Rāmachandra in my heart.</font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Śhrī Rāma-chandra charanau vachasā gṛunāmi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Through my songs and prayers I praise the Feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra.</font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau shirasā namāmi</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">I bow at the Feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra. </font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau śharanam prapadye</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">I surrender at the Feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Rāmo Rāja-manihi sadā vijayate Rāmam Ram’esham bhaje</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">I worship the husband of Śhrī Sītā, Śhrī Rāma, the King of kings, who is forever victorious.</font><br />
<font color="blue"><b> Rāmen’ābhihatā nishāchara-chamū Rāmāya tasmai namah</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">I bow to Śhrī Rāma who has killed the army of rākṣhasas.</font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Rāmānn’āsti parā-yanam para-taram Rāmasya dās’osmy’aham</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">I consider no-one greater than Śhrī Rāma and I am His servant.</font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Rāme chitta-layah sadā bhavatu me bho Rāma mām-uddhara</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Rāma, let my attention be always on Your Being and may You help me to evolve.</font><br />
(Few verses from Śhrī Rāma Kavach in praise of Śhrī Rāma)<br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0402 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī Day), Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://youtu.be/geTIFWA_qX4"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vaishnav Jan To Tene Kahiye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī singing the bhajan with Sahaja Yogis</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kahe Samjhaye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Rama Navami" /><category term="green @ Vasant Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Worshiping Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī during Vasant Navarātri: “It’s an individual journey towards God when you meditate. And when you reach there, then you become collective.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/29" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Worshiping Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī during Vasant Navarātri: “It’s an individual journey towards God when you meditate. And when you reach there, then you become collective.”" /><published>2023-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/2023_03_29_Day_8_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/29"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>It's an individual journey towards God when you meditate. And when you reach there, then you become collective.</b> Before that it's an absolute individual journey within, absolutely individual journey.<br />
You should be able to see this that, in this journey, nobody is your relation, nobody is your brother, nobody is your friend. You're absolutely alone, absolutely alone. You have to move alone within yourself.<br />
Don't hate anyone, don't be responsible. But in meditative mood you are alone. No one exists there, you alone. And once you enter into that Ocean, then the whole world becomes your family, the whole world is your own manifestation, all the children become your children and you treat all people with equal understanding.<br />
The whole expansion takes place when you enter inside your Spirit and see through the eyes of the Spirit. There's such calm, such peace, such bliss exists within you.<br />
You have to be ready for that journey. That journey is alone in your meditativeness. And the more you find something in your meditation the more you want to go and distribute it to others."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0314 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, The Individual Journey towards Collectivity and Bliss, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1147.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Now, we always try to relate Sahaja Yoga from our own terms, not from the terms that belong to God.<br /> 
God is what He is, He cannot change Himself. You have to change. So whatever we think about God, we want to put on that."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0121 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, Keep Your Mother Pleased, Vaitarna, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">MALA PĀHĪ PRABHUSANGE, DUI ATMA TAI PALE DURĪ</font><br />
When I am in the company of God, evil runs away<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">GALE SAMARTHYA MOHACHE NURE RUNT KUTHE VAIRĪ</font><br />
No temptation can dominate me and nobody can confront me<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">MALA BODHĀMRUT PĀJĪ, SADA ]AEI NAVI TRUPTĪ</font><br />
Every time I experience the Divine knowledge, I feel more satisfaction and Divine joy<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">KUTHE CHINTA KUTHE DUKHHE KSHANE SAARI LAVA JĀTĪ</font><br />
All moments of concerns and sorrows vanish<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">PRABHUSANGE MILE JĪVA, NASE KOTHE TASHI SHANTĪ</font><br />
Nowhere else can my soul find peace except in the company (in the union) with God Almighty<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">PRABHU MAZA SWAYE NĪTĪ, PRABHU MAZA SWAYE PRITĪ</font><br />
My God Himself is Truth and Love<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, as far as Sahaja Yoga is concerned, the basic thing is Kuṇḍalinī. And <b>the Kuṇḍalinī, as I have told you, is the pure desire. Again it, listen to it carefully: pure desire.</b> That means all other desires are impure. <b>There’s only one pure desire. And that is to be one with the Divine. One with the Brahma, one with God</b>, that’s the only pure des... desire. All other desires are impure. So, train your mind gradually to achieve that desire as the main thing. If you train your mind in that fashion, then you can develop pure desire, so all other desires will negate, gradually. All right.<br />
Now, this desire to be one with the Divine is the purest and the highest. And to achieve that, what have you to do? <b>To achieve that you have to keep your Mother pleased, very simple.</b> Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has said that “You don’t bother about anything, just keep your Mother pleased.” You have to be simple person, not try to be cunning with Me or clever with Me, I know everyone very well. Try to tell yourself that, ‘I should say things, I should behave in a manner that will please my Mother.’ Supposing you are in Sahaja Yoga and you are doing wrong things, it is not going to please Me at all. So, ‘How to please Mother,’ that you should try to see for yourself, what kind of a thing pleases Me the best. I am also a very simple person. So I want a simple-hearted person, who is simple-hearted."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0121 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, Keep Your Mother Pleased, Vaitarna, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1148.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Kul’angana Kul’anta-stha, Kaulinı Kula-yoginı,<br />
Akula Samayanta-stha, Samayachara-tatpara.</b><br />
O Chaste Lady, residing in the Sacrum bone, whose creation is the chakras, and who knows all the secret techniques of the path to Self-realisation;<br />
You are beyond all categories and reside in the Sahasrara, and are to be found through inner worship You are devoted to those who worship You internally.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Lalitā Sahasranāma, verse 37)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So She is the Redeemer and She connects you to God.</b> In the sense, She is the bridge. And the Kuṇḍalinī rises over the bridge. And Kuṇḍalinī is the Mahākālī. Now we have a temple in India which you have visited of Mahālakṣhmī in Kolhapur; and there, when they sing, when they worship Mahālakṣhmī at that time they say “Udho, udho, Ambe.” That time they say: <b>“O Ambe, the Kuṇḍalinī, You rise.”</b><br />
But Kuṇḍalinī is the potential of all the three powers: Mahākālī, Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī because it is the Primordial Desire. Because She is the Holy Ghost, you see, so She contains all these three powers in it. Like Ādi Śhakti has all the three powers of Mahākālī, Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0908 Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Münich, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, in the Mahālakṣhmī channel, we have to talk about Gaurī. Because Gaurī is the one which is the Kuṇḍalinī. So they have to talk that’s why they say “Ude, ude hey Ambe.” They say in the Mahālakṣhmī temple. Why because, in the Mahālakṣhmī temple only they have to say that now you rise, we are ready, we are prepared, we have got the Mahālakṣhmī Principle within us and now you can rise,’ the Kuṇḍalinī and that’s why the āvāhana."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1018 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (8th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1149.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b>Adimaya Ambabai, Sarya Duniyechi Ai </b><br />
Primordial Goddess of illusion, Mother Kuṇḍalinī, Mother of the whole world<br />
<b>Tichya Eka Darshanat. Koti Janmachi Punyai</b><br />
Being in Her attention for a brief moment brings blessings for millions of lifetimes<br />
<b>Ude Ga Ambabai! Ai! Ude Ga Ambabai!</b><br />
Rise O Mother Kuṇḍalinī, rise<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/niuCWTNKu0k">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here to worship the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī and your own Kuṇḍalinī, both of them because your Kuṇḍalinī is the reflection of the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī.</b> We have understood a lot about Kuṇḍalinī and also we know that through Her awakening only, through Her ascent only, we have ascended into a very higher realm of consciousness. It’s not only that we have risen to a very higher realm of awareness but that it has granted us so many powers that, never before in the history of spirituality people had this power of awakening of Kuṇḍalinī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0621 Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, Pure Love, Compassion, and Morality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>First of all, I think this is the most important thing to understand about your own Kuṇḍalinī, as Self-realization is Self-knowledge. And the one who gives you Self-knowledge is this, your own Kuṇḍalinī</b>, because when She rises She points it out what are the problems on your chakras. Now, we say that it is pure desire, but we do not know what purity means. It means your chaste desire. It means it has no lust, greed, anything in it. That power is your own mother and is settled in your triangular bone. She’s your own mother. She knows everything about you, it’s like a tape recorder. She knows everything about you and She is absolutely the knowledge – because She’s so pure. And whatever chakras She touches, She also knows what’s wrong with that chakra – beforehand. So She’s quite prepared, and She adjusts Herself fully so that you do not get a problem by Her awakening. If any chakra is constricted, She waits and goes on slowly opening that chakra. Now, this Kuṇḍalinī is the Primordial Power which is reflected within you. And within you, in a human being it is like many strands of energy. So it’s like a rope and these energies are all twisted together to form this Kuṇḍalinī. In a human being these strands are three into seven – that is twenty-one – raised to power 108. But when your Kuṇḍalinī rises, one or two strands out of this come up and pierce the fontanel bone area – only one or two. Because it has to pass through the innermost nāḍī, known as Brahma nāḍī. It’s all a spiral throughout because Kuṇḍalinī is a spiral and these nāḍīs are also – are like a spiral like this. So the innermost nāḍī is the Brahma nāḍī. The outermost nāḍī is the right side and the second innermost is the Iḍā nāḍī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0811 Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, The Power of Pure Desire, Weilburg, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1150.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> <font color="DarkRed"><b>Shrī Mātājī, we all the Sahaja Yogis here, we pray to You and we promise You that we will be one, just one flower so that when You can see us, 
You will see only one flower, one color, one perfume, and one flower offered at Your Divine Lotus Feet. 
And we pray Shrī Mātājī in our heart that Your Divine Lotus Feet will dwell forever in our being. Amen.<br /> 
Jai Shrī Mātājī!</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0614 Small Pūjā, Farewell, Āśhram, Route de Courte Raye, Founex (19 kms N of Geneva), Switzerland</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">Naman Kare Barambar Śhrī Mātājī<br />
We bow to You Shri Mataji again and again<br />
Gaye Mil Jayjaykar Śhrī Mātājī<br />
We all sing Your glory together</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0621 Śhrī Ādi Kuṇḍalinī Pūjā, Pure Love, Compassion, and Morality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/674360493"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jagadambetza Jogwa</b></font><br />
<font size="-1">Jagadambetsa Jogawa magate<br />
We ask for Self-realization from Śhrī Jagadambā<br />
Ayi Ambetsa Jogawa magate<br />
We ask for Self Realization from Shri Ambe<br />
Ayi Nirmala Mahalakshmitsa Jogawa magate<br />
We ask for Self-realization from Śhrī Nirmalā who is Mahālakṣhmī</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa, Music Of Joy</b></font><br />
<font size="-1">Jog.Wa Magen., Aicha Jog.Wa<br />
Ai Ude G’ambe Ude!<br />
Mother we ask for Self Realization,<br />
So you rise, O Mother Kuṇḍalinī, You rise<br />
Ude, Ude, Ude, Ude, Ude, Ude, Wo!<br />
Rise, rise, rise, rise, rise,rise, ho!</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Gangaur festival during Vasant Navarātri: “We are the worshipers of Śhakti. …… The name of the Deity of this place is also different, it is Gangaur.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/24" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Gangaur festival during Vasant Navarātri: “We are the worshipers of Śhakti. …… The name of the Deity of this place is also different, it is Gangaur.”" /><published>2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/2023_03_24_Day_3_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/03/24"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here to do the Pūjā of the Śhakti.</b> Till today many Saints have written and spoken a lot about the Śhakti. Those who could not explain the Śhakti in their texts they did it in their poems.<br />
Additionally, they learned different meanings of the Śhakti. But one thing probably we may not know is that inside every human beings, these powers are present in a dormant state, and all these powers human beings can awaken within himself. All these powers which are present in the dormant state are endless, nor anybody can guess their limit because as an example there are 35 crores [350 million] Deities seated within you. Apart from that, there are several powers that are running them, but at least we can understand that the Self-realization that we received today, certainly <b>some Śhaktis must have worked this out. Without this work, you cannot get your Self-realization. When we are receiving our Self-realization we think that we got it very easily</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1009 Śhrī Devī Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1143.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we’ll worship the Śhakti</b> - very much needed – the Śhakti who destroyed all the devils, all the rākṣhasas.<br /> 
That is what you are going to worship today – the Śhakti within you and without.<br /> 
It’s your desire which is going to work. So today we are going to worship the Śhakti Itself – Mahākālī.<br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1209 Śhrī Śhakti Mahākālī Pūjā, Auditorium, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today it’s such a great day for Me to be with you all, again this year. It’s so very joyous and full of fragrance. <b>Today we have decided to have a Pūjā of Śhakti that is the Power, that is the Devī.</b> You know within us there are many Powers of Mahākālī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahālakṣhmī, Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
All these Powers are there for us to ascent. If these Powers are properly used and understood, then your ascent can be permanent. Once you achieve your ascent and enter into the Kingdom of God, all these Powers get enlightened. And these Powers which are enlightened are absolutely filled with Love."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The way different Deities manifest themselves to do certain thing, similarly <b>the Goddess manifests Herself as Their Power, Śhakti. Without the Śhakti no Deity could work out things</b>, whether it is Incarnation of Rāma, Kṛiṣhṇa, Jesus Christ or anyone else. All of them had a Goddess as Their Power (Śhakti). That is the reason so much importance and respect is given to mother in our country. Indians are worshipers of Śhakti, irrespective of all the differences and problems. They are the worshipers of Śhakti.<br />
Those who follow Viṣhṇu or Śhiva are also worshipers of Śhakti because Śhakti is the Mother and mother belongs to all. Mother is a very significant institution in our country. So we should always respect the mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0405 Guḍhī Pāḍavā Pūjā (Hindi), Noida Bhavan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1144.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Prabhavatı Prabha-rupa, Prasiddha Parameśhwarī,<br /> 
Mula-prakritir-avyakta, Vyakt’avyakta-swarupinı. </b></font><br />
Full of light, as light is Your form, You are the Established, Supreme Ruler of the Universe;<br /> 
You are the Kundalini Shakti, imperceptible,<br />
both the manifest and the unmanifest are Your forms.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Lalitā Sahasranāma, verse 86)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"While you can see that once the Ambā, <b>this Kuṇḍalinī who is the reflection of the Holy Ghost, of the Ādi Śhakti within you, when She rises through these different chakras, She gives them power because She’s the Power, She’s the Śhakti.</b> She is the Desire Power of Sadāśhiva. She is the Complete Power of Sadāśhiva. And so She gives the power totally to every chakra, by which all these chakras are enlightened and all the Deities are awakened. Supposing we have no power of life, we’ll be like dead people. So these centers when they receive this Power, this Śhakti, then they are awakened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0927 Navarātri Pūjā (1st Day), 10th Position or Divine Knowledge is the Reality, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We are the worshipers of Śhakti.</b> Here we are Śhakti Dharmi [religiously devoted to Śhakti] and many kings have been worshiping Ādi Śhakti. Everyone has different Deities and the names of each Deity is different. <b>The name of the Deity of this place is also different, it is Gangaur.</b> But Ādi Śhakti was once born in Rajasthan state whose name was Satī Devī. It is Her Grace that we find our culture the dharma of wife, dharma of husband, dharma of ruling, etc. which are nourished by Her Śhakti.<br />
You all know the story of Satī Devī, I don’t have to tell you in new way but she was Gangaur. She was married and while She was returning after marriage with Her husband some of the bad elements surrounded them and killed Her husband. She came out of the bride’s carriage, took the Rudra Form and destroyed all of them who attacked Her husband and then She finished Herself also. We should see in this that since childhood till marriage She did not disclose that She was Mahāmāyā in any condition."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Version 1: 1994-1211 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Mahāmāyā, Mahākālī, Śhāradā Devī, Mahālakṣhmī, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1145.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
he Mahārāṇī adorned Śhrī Mātājī in a traditional Rajasthani ghagra (skirt) of vibrant colors. The Rajput women worshipped Her with flowers and Āratī.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>From "The Tenth Incarnation", Volume 1 Chapter 40, Page 178, by Yogi Mahajan.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>They have one festival called Gangaur: that is a thing where they uh uh worship Gaurī.</b> That's the biggest festival where the Queen ... Mahārāṇī has to worship the Gangaurī: is a statue, which goes round the whole of Jaipur state and everybody celebrates it. Is regarded as the biggest festival. So she, in the morning she came and touched My Feet. And she said, ``Mother, can I'p worship You?" I said, ``Why?" ``Because You are my Gangaur, really. That's just a statue." She made Me stand the same way, she did everything, she made Me eat betel. Uh I don't eat all that, but he, she said, ``You have to, You are Gangaur, so You have to eat it." [Smiles, laughter.] And she worshiped Me and all her whole rituals she did for about f... forty-five minutes, and the ... then she said, ``Now I'll go and worship that statue."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0421 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Vertical Ascent, the day before Easter Pūjā, Before Dinner, The Burlington Hotel, Eastbourne, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1146.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon,  Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Morning and evening I sing Your Praise</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Mātājī, I Have received Second Birth from You</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Russia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/26181854"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bolo Ādi Śhakti Śhrī Mātājī, Śhrī Nirmalā Devī kī Jay</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Ādi Mā, He Anti Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kuṇḍalinī Kuṇḍalinī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī Mā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shri Gangaur Festival" /><category term="green @ Vasant Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>