<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-02-18T16:35:55-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Vasant Pañchamī: “a person who is Sahaja Yogi should permeate – like music”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/02/14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Vasant Pañchamī: “a person who is Sahaja Yogi should permeate – like music”" /><published>2024-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/02/2024_02_14_Vasant_Panchami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/02/14"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have the idea to do Saraswatī's Pūjā.</b> ...... I have seen that here people worship Mahākālī and Saraswatī, people worship Devī and people are simple natured. We should worship Saraswatī as well.<br />
Saraswatī's work is very great. <b>First, Mahāsaraswatī created the entire universe. The earth element is special in this. The earth element has been placed in such a way between the Sun and the Moon that any living work can easily happen on it.</b> From this living work, slowly and gradually human beings have been generated.<br />
But we should know our own great power. That power is what we call creation power, it's also called creativity.<br />
<b>This creation power is the blessing of Saraswatī by which many arts have been generated.</b> The evolution of art is due to the blessings of Saraswatī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0403 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Emerlin College, Yamunānagar, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1326.png" /></div>

<p style="color:green; text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Yā kundendu tushāra hāra dhavalā</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>She who is as fair as fragrant white Kunda flowers, the moon,<br />
the fine misty spray of the waterfall and the white garland; </b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Yā shubhra vastrā vṛutā</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>She who is covered with white garments;</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Yā vīnā vara danda mandita karā</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>She whose hands are decorated with the vina’s slender neck;</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Yā shweta padm’āsanā</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>She who resides in a white lotus;</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Yā Brahm’āchyuta Shaṅkara Prabhṛutibhir </b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>She whom Śhrī Brahmā, Śhrī Viṣhṇu, Śhrī Śhiva and all the Deities</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Devaihi sadā vanditā</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Constantly praise and worship;</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Sā mām pātu Saraswatī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O You, who are that Goddess Saraswatī Bhagavatī,<br />
please bless us and protect us.</b></font><br />
Nishesha jādy’āpahā<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Destroy all our ignorance.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">Śhrī Saraswatī Vandanā (Prayer to Śhrī Saraswatī)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/FlidFeYNuI8">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today I thought we should have Mahāsaraswatī's Pūjā, would be a good idea. Because we did Mahālakṣhmī, let's have Mahāsaraswatī's.<br />
So, Mahāsaraswatī Principle is on the right side as I'd ... you all know. <b>First is the Brahmadeva's Principle, which is the Saraswatī Principle, and then this Mahāsaraswatī takes you to the Principle of Mahābrahmadeva called as Hiraṇyagarbha.<br />
Now this Hiraṇyagarbha Principle is very important for Sahaja Yogis.</b><br />
First of all, those who think too much or those who create too much without Realization, those who express themselves in poetry or in literature or in music, you can say, in paintings, in all kinds of arts; if they are not realized Souls, then they go to the left to the extreme or to the right."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0223 Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī Pūjā, Modern Art and Literature, 24 Pukenui Road, Epsom, Auckland, New Zealand</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"With the realization of the Ātmā, itself, the brain gets the incandescent of Śhrī Saraswatī and even the children who are weak in reading and writing start doing good work. After this, the growth of art begins. If one wants to develop art without Self-realization the art is not treated with respect [is unrecognized] and there is no name or sign of it and is eventually lost.<br />
So, first of all, <b>getting the Self-realization and then doing Saraswatī Pūjā is in itself a great thing</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0403 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Emerlin College, Yamunānagar, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1327.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Because Saraswatī had a <b>vīṇā in Her hand. And that vīṇā is the Primordial Instrument which She plays, like music. And the music penetrates into the heart.</b> You don't know how it goes into you and how it works out. <b>And that's how a person who is a Sahaja Yogi should permeate, like music, into everything.</b><br />
She has so many qualities as I told you which cannot be described in one lecture. But one of the greatest quality of Hers is: that She ends up into subtler things.<br />
Like the Mother Earth will end up into fragrance. Music will end up into melodies. Like that, whatever She creates ends up into something greater."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0114 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā (English + Marathi) (Makar Saṅkrānti Day), Śhrī Saraswatī's Blessings (The Basis of All Creativity of Saraswatī is Love, Permeating Spirit, The Purest Form of Nature Is within Us and Subudhi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Violet">Tu swar ki devi, ye sangeet, tujh se,</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>You are the goddess of music, and this song,</b></font><br />
<font color="Violet">Har Shabd tera hai har geet tujh se,</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>all its words and the tune, comes from You.</b></font><br />
<font color="Violet">Ham pār Sahaj mein, teri kripa se</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Only with Your compassion we become pār in Sahaj.</b></font><br />
<font color="Violet">Nirmal Vidyā ka vardan de ma</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Please grant us the boon of Nirmala Vidyā.</b></font><br />
<a href="">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Saraswatī cleanses all that is impure in nature, while with our brain activity we are spoiling all that.<br />
All our brain activity goes against pure intelligence. And that's what one has to understand: that this pure intelligence is not to be soiled by our thinking. Our thinking can make us so bumptious, so ego-oriented, so impure that we can really eat the poison and say, `What wrong?' Just the opposite of Saraswatī. If Saraswatī will be in u ... is within us, <b>She gives us subuddhi, wisdom.<br />
And that's why, to worship Saraswatī, to worship Sūrya, we must have that clear vision as to what we have to be, what we are doing, what filth we are living in, what our mind is getting into. After all, we are here for emancipation and not for just pampering our ego and living with our filth that is with us.<br />
So, this Light has come within us and we should try to rise above our own mental filth, which is being created around us</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0">1983-0114 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā (English + Marathi) (Makar Saṅkrānti Day), Śhrī Saraswatī's Blessings (The Basis of All Creativity of Saraswatī is Love, Permeating Spirit, The Purest Form of Nature Is within Us and Subudhi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India<b></b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1328.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="red"><b>"Now another blessings of Saraswatī is that you can have knowledge of Sahaja Yoga."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"And as love will increase, your creativity will develop. So the basis of all creativity of Saraswatī is Love. If there is no love there's no creativity.<br />
It's even in the deeper sense, if you see, people who have created all the scientific things are also out of love to the masses, not for themselves. Nobody has produced anything for themselves. If they make something for themselves, it has to become for universal use, otherwise it has no meaning.<br />
......<br />
<b>So, all the activity on right-hand side of Saraswatī, basically has to end up in love: starts with love and ends up in love. Whichever does not end up in love, coils up and finishes off. It just disappears. So you can see that even matter which is not used for love just finishes off. The basis has to be love.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0114 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā (English + Marathi) (Makar Saṅkrānti Day), Śhrī Saraswatī's Blessings (The Basis of All Creativity of Saraswatī is Love, Permeating Spirit, The Purest Form of Nature Is within Us and Subudhi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The second power you see on the right-hand side, yellow one, is the power to create. This has called as Mahāsaraswatī Power. In the Sanskrit language these are expressed much clearly, we can call it the creative power. <b>The Creative Power of God descends within us through this and is effective in giving us creative powers: of thinking power, of mental effort, and physical effort. So we put in our mental and physical efforts through this power, which is called as Mahāsaraswatī Power.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1203 Public Program, Session 1 (morning), Realization Is Not of the Intellect, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1329.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>Sura-Asura-Sevita-Pāda-Pangkajā<br />
Kare Virājat-Kamanīya-Pustakā |<br />
Virin.ci-Patnī Kamala-asana-Sthitā<br />
Sarasvatī Nrtyatu Vāchi Me Sadā</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b><i>(Salutations to Devi Saraswati) Whose Lotus Feet is Served by the Devas and Asuras,<br />
On Her Hand Shines a Beautiful Book,<br />
Who is the Consort of Lord Brahma and abides on a Lotus Seat,<br />
O Devi Saraswatī, please dance on my speech, always.</i><br />
(composed by sage Agastya)</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="SaddleBrown ">"The second power, which He gave us, which He sent to us, was Mahāsaraswatī and to this Mahāsaraswatī Power, <b>He called Counselor, the one who will counsel you -- that means, who helps us for Yoganirūpaṇ [to see the form of Yoga]</b>. With the help of this second power, we will get Gyān [Knowledge], we will know the subtle knowledge."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0414 Easter Pūjā (Hindi), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="color:RebeccaPurple; text-align:center;">
<b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0223 Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī Pūjā, Modern Art and Literature, 24 Pukenui Road, Epsom, Auckland, New Zealand</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/33003684"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mahur gadavari</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/EWoUoau4BOw">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Aisa Do Hamein Gyan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Gyan De, Ma Nirmal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Pt. Bhimsen Joshi - Jai Jagdīśhwarī Mātā Saraswatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/JgZ9Muu3qaA">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātā Saraswatī Śhāradā: By Ajit Kadkade</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/g6WFX08bB6E">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1330.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b></b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>I bow to Śhrī Saraswatī, the One who holds the vīṇā and the book of knowledge.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Vasant Panchami" /><category term="orange @ Shri Mahasaraswati Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Vināyak Chaturthī: “Today is a very big day because the actual Pure Spirit has taken birth today”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/02/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Vināyak Chaturthī: “Today is a very big day because the actual Pure Spirit has taken birth today”" /><published>2024-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/02/2024_02_12_Shri_Vinayaka_Chaturthi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/02/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is a very big day, because the actual Pure Spirit has taken birth today.</b> And He already had such an eternal state, that many people could not comprehend it or write about it. They wrote only what they understood, but now that you are realized you can understand that by the Power of Śhrī Gaṇeśha's name you can get your Realization. By taking His name alone any disease or any pain will disappear. He is eternal. He is always present within us, when you get your Realization, you can feel Him. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0210 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1323.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is a very important day for all of us, Sahaja Yogis, because today Śhrī Gaṇeśha was born.</b><br />
Śhrī Gaṇeśha is whom we worship and because of whom we got our Realization. However much you may remember Him, until you do not know His special qualities, you cannot attain Him. His special quality is that He is the Embodiment of Purity (Śhuddha Swarūp) and Complete Master of the Universe. He is the Incarnation of the Supreme, of Brahman.<br />
By coming into this world He has created music (saṅgīt), rhythm (tāl) and notes (sur). By His Grace only people become one with music (tallīn) [engrossed]. A small boy who came into the world and did such great work! He has given so many things to everyone and even today He is active.<br />
<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha's Pūjā, no matter how much you do it, it is not enough.</b><br />
A lot of people say, `We don't see Śhrī Gaṇeśha, even after worshiping Him so much, we do not attain Him.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0210 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><font color="Maroon"><b>Gaiye Ganapati Jagavandan</b></font><br />
Let us sing the praise of the leader of the Ganas who is respected by the whole world<br />
<font color="Maroon"><b>Shankara Suvana Bhavani Nandan</b></font><br />
He is the son of Śhiva and the Devī</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha was made out of the, they say, it is a beautiful poetic way of saying it, out of the mud that was covering the Mother Pārvatī</b> or you can say the Gaurī at that time. Because She was not married in the sense that She was a virgin, just finished her marriage and She was to meet Her husband and this virgin wanted to have a bath before meeting her husband, so she cleanses her hands properly and makes this Deity of Śhrī Gaṇeśha which is bestowed on this center. If you really develop your proper insight through meditation you can see Śhrī Gaṇeśha settled down there very clearly.<br />
<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the Embodiment of Innocence</b> and that's why He is a child, that's why His head is that of an elephant, because an elephant being an animal doesn't grow into ego and superego like human beings do. That's why He is a child. <b>He is the Embodiment of Childhood</b> and He incarnated on this Earth once which is described in Devī Bhāgavat[am] if you read as Mahāviṣhṇu."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0507 Public Program, Sahaja Yoga and Christianity, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1324.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="red"><b>"It is such a fortunate day today that we should come on the birth of Śhrī Gaṇeśha -- today is Vināyak Chaturthī, today -- that we should celebrate this Pūjā."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0118 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (Vināyaka Chaturthī Day), House of Dr. Ramesh Adinath Saṃghavī, B.N-1, Sapt Shrung, Krishnanagar Housing Society, Saharanpur Road, Nasik, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><font color="Maroon"><b>Jay Gaṇeśh., Jay Gaṇeśh., Jay Gaṇeśh. Deva</b></font><br />
Jay Lord Gaṇeśh<br />
<font color="Maroon"><b>Mātā Teri Pārvatī Pita Mahādeva</b></font><br />
Your Mother is Pārvatī, Your Father is Mahādeva<br />
<font color="Maroon"><b>O Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva<br />
O Jai Jai Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva<br />
Ek. Danth. Devadant. Char. Bhujadari</b></font><br />
Oh God, You are single toothed with four hands,<br />
<font color="Maroon"><b>Mas.Tak. Sindhur Shobhe Chuhe Ki Sawari</b></font><br />
the red sindoor suits Your forehead, and You are mounted on a humble mouse.<br />
<font color="Maroon"><b>O Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva<br />
O Jai Jai Gaṇapati Deva, Gaṇapati Deva</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LtqNdCxPQI0">video</a>
&lt;/p&gt;

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"But when Pārvatī made Śhrī Gaṇeśha, He was the Son of Pārvatī alone. There was no Father. Pārvatī Herself wanted to have a child of Her own. There were angels who were dedicated either to Viṣhṇu or to Śhiva, like gaṇas were dedicated to Śhiva alone. So, She wanted to have Her own Son who can permeate Her Powers on this Earth.<br />
So to begin with when the Śhakti created this universe and Sadāśhiva was watching Her creation, the first thing She created on this Earth was innocence and the Embodiment of that Innocence was Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
The whole Universe was covered with innocence, which we call as Oṃkāra. This innocence protected all the creation of the world and penetrated into all that is matter."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Holmes Lodge, YMCA Camp Marston, 4761 Pine Hills Road, Julian (near San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"I have said a lot about Śhrī Gaṇeśha and His importance in our life.<br />
He is the giver of wisdom. But this wisbom ... wisdom comes from our innocence, innocence that is innate within us. As children, we are innocent, but as we grow we start exerting ourselves in a manner that we start losing our innocence.<br />
We lose it in two ways. Once we have lost our innocence, we cannot believe that others could be innocent. Another is that we think innocence is not important.<br />
Innocence is the sustainance [sustenance], is the basis of spirituality. If a person doesn't have innocence, we [he] cannot rise in spirituality.<br />
<b>That's why the first job of Sahaja Yoga is to establish Śhrī Gaṇeśha within you, to awaken Him. As soon as the Kuṇḍalinī awakens, you must know that Śhrī Gaṇeśha comes into being. Without His awakening within you, Kuṇḍalinī cannot be raised.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0121 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, First Job of Sahaja Yoga Is to Establish Śhrī Gaṇeśha Within You and We Have to Have Certain Maryādās, House of Dr. Ramesh Adinath Saṃghavī, B.N-1, Sapt Shrung, Krishnanagar Housing Society, Saharanpur Road, Nasik, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1325.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="red"><b>"This is the importance of this day. Today if you ask for any wish, then Śhrī Gaṇeśha will fulfill it. It is His right to fulfill all your desires, because you are all realized. Ask Him with all your heart and He will help you in every way, every moment, every instant."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0210 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Abodhita dena sab. Sahaji ko</b><br />
Lord Gaṇeśha, please give us innocence<br />
<b>Nirmal bhakti dena sab ko</b><br />
Lord Gaṇeśha, please give us devotion
<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśhaji ki puniya bhoomi par,</b><br />
In this land of Śhrī Gaṇeśha
<b>Ek.ta ki Śhakti sab ko</b><br />
Please grant us the power of collectivity
<b>Jai Jai Bolo Nirmal Gaṇeśh. ki</b><br />
Victory to Śhrī Gaṇeśha!</font><br />
<b>Jai Jai Bolo Nirmal Gaṇeśha Ki</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font> 
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Establishing Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Holmes Lodge, YMCA Camp Marston, 4761 Pine Hills Road, Julian (near San Diego), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<a href="https://vimeo.com/423426996"> video</a><br />

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Oṃkār Pradhana Rūp Gaṇeśhache by Saint Tukārām</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hemaja Sutam Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mGvUq8-ebXo">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇarāyā Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>
 
<p>
<font color="green"><b>108 Names of Śhrī Gaṇeśha recited at the Pūjā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Sukhkarta dukhharta Śhrī Gaṇeśh Ārati</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HNv44APLhL8?list=PL8E57180C36478F98">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>
</font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Vinayaka Chaturthi" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Gaṇeśha" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Calendar</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/21" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Calendar" /><published>2024-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/2024_01_21_Calendar</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/21"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
Dear Brothers and Sisters,<br />
<br />
Here is the link <a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1i9zAcYKFqfv00mwtewHvtVy_UoZ0PyFR/view?usp=sharing"> 2024_Sahaja_Yoga_Festivity_Team_Calendar.pdf</a> to the 2024 Sahaja Yoga Calendar of Festivity Days we would like to celebrate together.<br />
<br />
Jai Shri Mataji!<br />
<br />
The Festivity Team
</p>

<iframe src="/pdf/?usedownload=true#/files/2024_Sahaja_Yoga_Festivity_Team_Calendar.pdf" width="1000px" height="1000px"></iframe>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="blue @ Calendar" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Makar Saṅkrānti: “Those who fear God will never speak rudely to another person, because in another person also the same Spirit is shining”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/15" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Makar Saṅkrānti: “Those who fear God will never speak rudely to another person, because in another person also the same Spirit is shining”" /><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/2024_01_15_Makar_Sankranti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/15"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"T<b>oday is Saṅkrānti. Saṅkrānti means that today there is something new going to happen.</b> Kuṇḍalinī has awakened within you and you have become new person compared to what you were before. But on the day of Saṅkrānti, you should know that you have to please the Goddess who is sitting within you. What should you do to make Her happy? You distributed sesame seeds and jaggery. That is for love. To increase the love between each other, we give sesame seeds and jaggery.<br />
Today the Sun left its place and, in its northward movement, came towards us. At this moment we should be very thankful to the Sun. It is by the grace of the Sun that so many things take place in our country. We have to do namaskār to the Sun today and His Power and His knowledge should come to us. I would say that all of you have become realized and vibrations are flowing through you. Now you should make use of these vibrations, establish the śhakti within you, establish the peace within you and show the world that this power is within us and we have to acquire it. We have to nurture this, improve this with your good qualities and truthful speech.<br />
Today is very special day because the Sun is particularly benevolent towards us on this day. And we should thank Him for all this. You have received a lot, there is more to come and you will get much more. We should increase it. All of you did so many Pūjās to Me. I am surprise to know what you want from all these Pūjās?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2008-0117 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Hindi), Hall, Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1316.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Chocolate"><b>Saṅkrānti means Power of the Sun. Sun power means self-confidence. Sun gives us heat and light. Now it depends on us whether to get scorched from the heat of the Sun or gain self-confidence from the light of the Sun and become radiant.<br />
Eternal blessings to all of you.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi), Gain Self-confidence from the Light of the Sun and Become Radiant, House of Mrs. Kalpana Srivastava, 84 Somerset House, Bhulabhai Desai Road, Breach Candy, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the day where we celebrate the change of the axis of the Sun and that He moves towards the Tropic of Cancer.<br />
Tropic of Cancer is the one which represents the motherhood, the motherhood of the Earth.</b> This Tropic of Cancer has passed through quite a big area of land while the Tropic of Capricorn has not. And the area through which it has passed it has created different beautiful manifestation of the motherhood qualities on this Earth.<br />
We celebrate this change because the Sun has now moved into the new dimension so that all over the world there will be the warmth of the Sun. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English + Marathi), Carry the Sun with You, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1317.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"To speak in a very sweet manner is a sign of good breeding, good culture and fear of God. <b>Those who fear God will never speak rudely to another person, because in another person also the same Spirit is shining</b> and why should we be sharp or angry with another person who is created by God Almighty as we are created.<br />
So this loving, beautiful relationship that we have with each other, after Sahaja Yoga especially, let us express in talking to each other sweetly. There are so many ways by which we could be sweet. There are little, little things if you do, you can create lot of sweetness, but you need not a sharp tongue, but a sharp memory."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English + Marathi), Carry the Sun with You, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"As we consider <b>Sun's appearance as a very great thing, it is much more important, that the Sun of Sahaja Yoga comes on this Earth</b>. Because whatever creativity is in this Universe, the creativity is nourished by the Sun. The Sun gives it the energy, and the Creative Power of the Paramachaitanya, its aspect of action, has got activated through Sahaja Yoga. Till now Paramachaitanya was not successful in any task. The reason was, that the Sun had not yet appeared in its courtyard. But now this Sun has risen in the courtyard of Paramachaitanya. And because of that you all have the light of it within you. Because of that light, your Kuṇḍalinī has awakened, and within you, the field of creation has fully blossomed. And this field of creation you all are developing, in a way that the whole world can benefit from it. And it's a very great and divine thing. This could not take place earlier. <b>In our country many Sages have expressed many ideas about, that such a day will come, when collectively this creation will get awakened.</b><br />
That creation has awakened now. And that's why this is not only an occasion for Earth's creation but a great occasion for Sahaja Yoga's creation also. This year specially is considered to be a very important year for Sahaja Yoga, and the light of Sahaja Yoga will establish very deeply in the people. When something starts to establish deeply, then we must understand that along with it, some other important events also take place."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Hindi + English), We Have to Take a Very High Flight and The Sun of Sahaja Yoga Has Risen to the Zenith (Give Up All the Burdens within Us and a new flight we have to take Fully Dedicate Yourself to Meditation and Surrender Yourself to Collectivity), Mukand Steel Works, Kalwa, Thane, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1318.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="Chocolate">"<b>Now the Sun is so much respected in this country, that in early morning time all the people get up and say namaskārs to Sūrya with all His names and do a particular type of exercise to show that they are completely surrendered to the will of the Sūrya.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English + Marathi), We Are Going to Make Peace with Ourselves and with Others (We Will Take to Peaceful Methods), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India<br />
12 names of Śhrī Sūrya</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/jqmPOEnU9tg">video</a><br />
<font color="Orange"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Sūrya sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"For India, today is a very important day because the Sun is coming from the south to the north side.<br />
<b>The most important thing in Sahaja Yoga is that you have to change and that's what you should do to the Goddess with changed heart, full of love, affection and kindness.<br />
Therefore, hope you will spread Sahaja Yoga. It is very important because you know My vision is too big and you have to really work hard to fulfill My vision.</b> And to give Realization to people as many as possible. You have to think what is your mind doing. There are many people who are waiting to come in Sahaja Yoga. You should have the light of spirituality: you have to feel that you are spiritual, you have to grow it, and also make others grow.<br />
Sahaja Yoga is not limited with you. It's not meant for one individual, not at all for one person but for the whole world. We have Sahaja Yogis all over the world, but they don't spread Sahaja Yoga. They are satisfied with their own motives. This is not Sahaja Yoga. You must openly talk about and say about it. But Sahaja Yogis are very shy, they don't talk about Sahaja Yoga. They can do it, no doubt.<br />
The Sun changes its direction, everybody knows about it, everybody prays for it.<br />
People take bath in the River Ganges for purification. This is all right.<br />
<b>Now it is a time for purification, identification and also of understanding the importance of Sahaja Yoga.</b> I don't know how many people really understand the importance of Sahaja Yoga. If that is understood, one can do a lot of work in Sahaja Yoga. It is such a noble work, which you all have to do it collectively. And then you feel your life has a meaning, otherwise there is no meaning and no light in your life. So you have to work out in that manner which gives inspiration to others."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English + Marathi), You Have to Change, Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1319.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, today's special day, a very great day, let us ask that, when you are doing this Pūjā, ask: for new religions within you, `to be enshrined, to be sustained within ourselves.' And try to imbibe them. They will be permeating but you have to accept them.<br />
And [you] should know it's a big fight. And it's a very different type of a fight: of peace and love.<br />
That's why they say: `Speak sweetly, be sweet to each other.'<br />
Not to be sarcastic by any chance, nor to be harsh, but be sweetch [sweet]. Sweetness which is genuine: not outward and showy and formal, but genuine sweetness.<br />
May God bless you all."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (Marathi + English), Ahitagni Rajwade Maṅgal Karyalaya, 840 Sadashiv Peth, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā, The Revolution Within Ourselves and Feel Your Subtler Sensitivities (It's Only the Spirit that Can Save the World), Suryavanshi Hall (near Śhivajī Park), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/71464483"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mātājī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/6ByVzklhnWU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="OrangeRed"><b>Sarva Mangala Mangale</b> (1987-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Brahma Shodile</b> (1988 Music after Sakranti Puja)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="OrangeRed"><b>Navgraha Strotra</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Chocolate"><font size="+0"><b>Wishing you all a very Happy Makar Saṅkrānti!</b></font></font><br />  
<b>Tīḷ-guḷ ghyā āṇi goḍ goḍ bola.</b><br />
<font size="+0">(eat sesame and jaggery and speak sweetly)</font>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Makar Sankranti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating New Year’s Day: “So, for today’s New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/01" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating New Year’s Day: “So, for today’s New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished.”" /><published>2024-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/2024_01_01_New_Year_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/01/01"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, again, is a New Year's Day.<br />
Uh every new year comes because we have to take to something that is new. It has been so arranged that the Sun has to move for three hundred and sixty-five [365] days and again a new year has to come.</b><br />
Actually the whole solar system is moving in a spiral way. So, there is definitely a higher, higher state, of this solar system. Every year it is rising higher in a spiral way. So it is not only that: it is because three hundred and sixty-five [365] days have passed because it has moved a step forward, higher than whuh ... what it was.<br />
Now, we can see that in awareness, human beings have definitely risen much higher than what they were, say, about two thousand years back.<br />
But the first system that started, the whole universe was the first model, one can say, was created. And that model has to be perfect. And that was a perfect model, which then started perfecting the rest of it. So that is the perfect model which is in the Principle of this Ascent, and that is working out this ascent.<br />
Now, the perfection of the rest of the universe takes place in various directions. But today we have to consider the Mahālakṣhmī Principle.<br />
Now Mahālakṣhmī, as I told you, is a perfect principle. Is a perfect principle, it's perfect in it. It's born as perfect, will remain as perfect, will be always eternally perfect. So, that is not necessary to be corrected."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0101 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Mahālakṣhmī Principle of Our Ascent (Try to Develop that Innocence which Is the Basis of Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa and Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa Is Strengthened through Guru Principle), Nirmalā Kuṭīr (Cottage), Lakṣmī Nārāyaṇa Mandir, Shahupuri, Kolhapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1310.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"So, for today's New Year, <b>let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished.</b> Now the drop has become the ocean. Live like an ocean and like a lion. Don't roar at others, I mean [be] generous and don't be afraid of anything. Everything is taken care of, but believe that everything is taken care of. Sometimes you might feel you are let down, sometimes you'll feel, "Oh, this should have happened." Do not desire for anything! Whatever is your desire is not correct, that's all. If the desire is correct and is deserving, it will happen -- hundred per cent [guaranteed]!<br />
So all the best, and the greatest year, and happiness and joy.<br />
Feel your responsibility, understand each other. And now I'm going, tomorrow I'll be gone, so-called. [Laughter.]<br />
Don't worry about anything else but worry about the Sahaja Yoga that has to be established all over the world. Very great work one has done."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1231 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Year's Eve, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So today is a day of a new year and we should think why do we have new years -- what is the need to have a new year? We want something new that you start something afresh to ourselves, to others, to your Mother, to your Guru. That you have to get out of the clutches of ignorance and darkness. That you have to get out of the bondages of ego. That you have to become absolutely a free glorious personality. And that you have to fight the superego influences and all the bad conditionings should be thrown as torn clothes and should wear new beautiful clothes of Sahaja Yogis.<br />
Let all the people, let all the Sahaja Yogis raise their voices from the top of their houses and top of their mountains, the top of their higher positions. Broadcast to the whole world, inform the whole people that you have found the Truth and everybody has to find the Truth, otherwise there is no escape. That you have found the joy and that everyone has to find it and everybody must work to get to it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1116 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Racism, during the Evening Program, after dinner the day before Diwālī Pūjā, Tivoli, Lazio, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1311.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So then, everybody should, today, decide and take an oath, that, 'We'll do everything to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility.' "</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are going to worship Mahālakṣhmī Principle within us.</b><br />
As you know very well that Mahālakṣhmī Principle resides in the central path of our being, through which Kuṇḍalinī has to rise. But Kuṇḍalinī enters into our body through the left side. In the sense that is the residual power of creating everything, left side, right side, and then She enters into our sacrum bone.<br />
So, in the Mahālakṣhmī temple, in Kolhapur, they sing a song of Kuṇḍalinī Ambe that, "Oh Ambā, please rise," "Kuṇḍalinī, please rise." In the Mahālakṣhmī temple they have to do it because through Mahālakṣhmī channel only She rises.<br />
Now the Mahālakṣhmī Principle within us starts manifesting when our Lakṣhmī Principle is complete. Mahālakṣhmī Principle is to ascend above all material seekings."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0809 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Saint Petersburg, Leningrad Oblast, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1312.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"So today the <b>first and the foremost vow is</b>, as I told you, that we have to get cleansed up in such a way that we become free of ego and superego. We should get rid of our ignorance and darkness. <b>And the second vow as I have said</b> that you have to become the light to remove the darkness and ignorance of others. By sharing My problems, by sharing My anxieties about them -- those who are lost -- and not to be involved into your own personal anxieties and petty things. My problems should be your problems now because you all belong to Me, to My body, to My being.<br />
And I request you to join hands with Me, with full determination and complete attention and the heart of a lion."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>&gt;1985-1116 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Racism, during the Evening Program, after dinner the day before Diwālī Pūjā, Tivoli, Lazio, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This Mahālakṣhmī Principle when manifests in your Sahasrāra, then there are no words that one can express how it brings a divine light in you.</b> You know you are knowing the Truth, you know it very well. You know what is reality. You are so knowledgeable. Still you don't look down upon people who are ignorant. So in Sahasrāra it manifests compassion, tremendous compassion. Now one may say how can brain have compassion? But the Kuṇḍalinī comes out of the Heart center. That Heart center enlightens your heart and the first thing that shows in you is the feeling of tremendous compassion. You don't worry about yourself, you do not think about yourself, you all the time you are thinking about others' Realization. And as soon as you start paying attention to that, that person gets all right. You are on solid grounds and you are so confident but at the same time we are extremely humble, kind and gentle."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0809 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Saint Petersburg, Leningrad Oblast, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Whenever a new year starts, then a new thing, a new concept, a new understanding awakens inside a human being. It automatically happens. Whosoever started the concept of new year must have been a great visionary so that on this occasion symbolically, inside human beings a new ambition, a new thought, a new revolution should awaken. Like today many new years have come and gone, new ambitions came, new concepts came and finished."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1103 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day) (Hindi), Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
<b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</font><br />
The bliss that I feel is beyond words<br />
<font color="DarkRed">MALA PAAHĪ PRABHUSANGE, DUI ATMA TAI PALE DURĪ</font><br />
When I am in the company of God, evil runs away<br />
<font color="DarkRed">GALE SAMARTHYA MOHACHE NURE RUNT KUTHE VAIRĪ</font><br />
No temptation can dominate me and nobody can confront me<br />
<font color="DarkRed">MALA BODHĀMRUT PĀJĪ, SADA ]AEI NAVI TRUPTĪ</font><br />
Every time I experience the Divine knowledge, I feel more satisfaction and Divine Joy<br />
<font color="DarkRed">KUTHE CHINTA KUTHE DUKHHE KSHANE SĀRI LAVA JĀTĪ</font><br />
All moments of concerns and sorrows vanish<br />
<font color="DarkRed">PRABHUSANGE MILE JĪVA, NASE KOTHE TASHI SHANTĪ</font><br />
Nowhere else can my soul find peace except in the company (in union) with God Almighty<br />
<font color="DarkRed">PRABHU MAZA SWAYE NĪTĪ, PRABHU MAZA SWAYE PRITĪ</font><br />
My God himself is Truth and Love<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Every moment is a New Year for a Sahaja Yogi because he lives in the present and neither in future nor in the past gone by. For him every moment is a New Year, a new surge of joy (umang), a new wave.<br />
Just as one, while already swimming in the Ocean of Love is lovingly tossed every moment by the love all around, so also every Sahaja Yogi is to live in complete joy (ānand), love (prem), peace (śhānti) and blissful delight (āhlād). The question is whether we have learnt to swim thus.<br />
......<br />
Only he should be called a Sahaja Yogi who has achieved complete satisfaction and tranquility [samādhān] and his pure desire has been fulfilled.<br />
......<br />
He should now enjoy the supreme and unique bliss of his immense capacity to give this to others."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0103 New Year Pūjā (Hindi), Sahaja Yogi ki Pahachān (Who Is a Sahaja Yogi), Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1313.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"This is going to be your vow on the New Year day, that, 'Now we are going to start Sahaja Yoga in a new way, in a bigger way, in a more dynamic way.' "</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1231 New Year Pūjā (English + Marathi), You All Have to Become Masters in Sahaja Yoga, Kalwa, Thane, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Sarva-śhakti-mayī Sarva- māñgalā Sad-gati-pradā,<br />
Sarveśhwarī Sarva-mayī, Sarva-mantra-swarūpiṇī. </b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">All power and energy are You, all auspiciousness, and our guide to the right path;<br /> 
Supreme Ruler of everything, everything is in You, and all mantras are Your forms.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Sarva-yantr’ātmikā Sarva- tantra-rūpā Manon-manī,<br />
Maheśhwarī Mahādevī, Mahā-lakshmī Mŗiḍa-priyā.</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are the Essence of all Yantras, the Subject of all sacred treatises, and You uplift the mind;<br />
The Great Goddess, Śhakti of Śhrī Sadāśhiva, the Power of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, the Beloved of Śhrī Śhiva.</font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0"><b>Mahā-rūpā Mahā-pūjyā, Mahā-pātaka-nāśhinī,<br />
Mahā-māyā Mahā-sattwā, Mahā-śhaktir Mahā-ratiḥ.   </b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0">You are the Mightiest Form, the Highest Object of worship, and You destroy the greatest of sins;<br /> 
You are the Great Illusory Power, as well as the Highest Reality;<br />
You are the Supreme Energy, and the Greatest Bliss.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Lalitā Sahasranāma Stotram)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0220 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Mahālakṣhmī Principle and Understand What Is Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/33890994"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Dil Me Sahaj Ko</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Apne Panah Mein Hame Rakhna</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āwāz uthāeńge</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Ttp3KyI2rew">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa, Music Of Joy</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tum Asha Vishwas Hamare</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1314.png" /></div>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ New Year Day" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Mahalakshmi Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Christmas: “His Message of Love and Forgiveness is the same even today. Preached by all, all the Saints, all the Incarnations, all the Prophets.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/12/25" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Christmas: “His Message of Love and Forgiveness is the same even today. Preached by all, all the Saints, all the Incarnations, all the Prophets.”" /><published>2023-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/12/2023_12_25_Christmas_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/12/25"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today, we are celebrating the birth of Jesus Christ.</b><br />
The birth of Jesus Christ is very symbolic, because He was born in such a manner that even the poorest of poor won't be bornt [born] in the stable. And He was put in the bed which was made of dried grass.<br />
He came on this Earth to show people that for a person who is an Incarnation or who is a highly evolved soul, is not bothered about the comfort of the body. His Message was so great and so deep, but He had disciples who were not prepared for the battle they had to fight. Is the same thing that sometimes happens with Sahaja Yoga. He had only 12 disciples, we too have 12 types of Sahaja Yogis, and all of them, though [they] try to dedicate themselves to Christ, fell a trap, some of them, to the worldly aspirations or to their own hankerings.<br />
<b>His Message of Love and Forgiveness is the same even today. Preached by all, all the Saints, all the Incarnations, all the Prophets. They all have said about Love and Forgiveness.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1225 Christmas Pūjā, Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India]</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1305.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>You have compassion for those who love You,<br />
and it is for those who love You that You come to this Earth.<br />
You are the force that creates, the energy that pervades, and the Spirit that protects.<br />
Those who seek union with God pray through You;<br />
those who seek union with God worship You.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">('To the Divine Essence of the Prayer')</font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The reason for celebrating this auspicious day is the birth of the Christ. Very little is known about Jesus Christ because in young age he left his house and after returning he lived only up to the age of thirty year. But during this short period he did tremendous work.<br />
......<br />
<b>So He told two things, the first is to "forgive everyone." Knowingly or unknowingly if someone troubles you, you should forgive him.</b> You will not get tortured but if you do not forgive then you torture yourself because another person is sitting nicely. So you must develop the habit of forgiveness.<br />
<b>Second thing that He told us is that, "You are the Spirit." Know this Spirit, the Self. No one can touch the Spirit, can destroy it, no one can torture it.</b> If you are that Spirit then you should be established in it. But to achieve this Ātmā Tattwa the awakening of Kuṇḍalinī is necessary. First is to work out the awakening of the Kuṇḍalinī and then to get established in it. Until you are established, you will remain entangled in stupidities. So one should know how to be established within, to remain within thyself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1225 Christmas Pūjā (Hindi + English), Success in Sahaja Yoga Is What Will Last Forever and Everybody Will Remember It (Try to Learn Sahaj Culture), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1306.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Bāla vadana tava baghuni Khristā</b><br />
I see Lord Christ as an eternal child<br />
<b>Sakala durita bhaya bhāle astā</b><br />
When the world was drowning in sin<br />
<b>Tava divya rupa jaga lyāle</b><br />
The new Divine form took birth on this Earth<br />
<b>Mama zhāle, mana dhāle</b><br />
My mind exulted with joy<br />
<b>He sarva jagi sancharale</b><br />
This love had now spread throughout the world<br />
<font size="+0">(He Prem Murti)</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The aim of Jesus Christ was to open the center of your Āgñyā and to achieve that purpose He got Himself crucified and then He resurrected. It appears to be a miracle but for the Divinity there is no miracle as such. He proved that human beings could rise above the center of Āgñyā and on this center <b>He told two mantras which we call Bīj Mantras: Ham and Kṣham. Kṣham means to forgive. Kṣham is the biggest mantra. The ego of the person who knows how to forgive, gets destroyed</b>.<br />
One is proud of small-small things. For example, if you tell someone to sit on the earth, his ego gets hurt. If someone is told to sit in the chair, he will reply, 'This chair is very small, why have you given it to me?' Everyone has some expectation about him and if his expectations are not fulfilled, his ego immediately comes up. Unknowingly, sometimes such things could be done but the egoistical people take it as their insult.<br />
Such people make their condition very miserable. All the time they think they are being insulted and humiliated. He is always obsessed with this thought and he draws negative meaning of whatever is told to him.<br />
So we have to think of what Jesus Christ had thought. He said, "Forgive those who have trespassed against you."<br />
Now see the results if you forgive everyone. You will neither suffer nor get disturbed mentally. You will not think of the person whom you have forgiven. Nothing could go against you because you forgive everyone.<br /> 
We get this power from the center of Āgñyā. The person whose Āgñyā is clear forgives everyone. If we do not forgive we torture ourselves and play in the hands of others, who assume power over us. Forgiveness is the greatest message that Jesus Christ has given to mankind.<br />
<b>Second is Ham, it has altogether different meaning. Ham means 'To know thyself'. You have to know that you are the Spirit. You are not this body, mind, brain or ego. You are the Spirit. When you know this Ham then it will be clear to you that you are the Ātmā.</b> The Spirit means that all the ego, foolishness, ignorance that we have in our mind, are meaningless. All these negativities have absolutely no place in the pure Spirit. You are very pure."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1225 Christmas Pūjā (Hindi + English), Success in Sahaja Yoga Is What Will Last Forever and Everybody Will Remember It (Try to Learn Sahaj Culture), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1307.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Putra Vatsalā Kalyāni Mahāpātaka Nāshini</b></font><br />
<b>Most lovingly showers blessings on Her children,<br />
Destroys the greatest of sins</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Yoga Kshema Nivardini Nirānanda Pradāyini</b></font><br />
<b>Taking care of spiritual and material well-being, Bestowing eternal bliss</b><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mahārupā Mahāpujyā Ādimātā Nirmala Mā,Jaya He</b></font><br />
<b>Awesome form, worthy of great worship, Primordial Mother</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Jai He Jai He Jai He Devī)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It is said in Marathi that: "Forgiveness is the decoration of a vīra." Vīra is the brave. Only the brave could forgive.<br />
Now, how many of us really know how to forgive others [laughing:] and to love others?<br />
So many write that, "Mother, my heart is like a stone." So now you jump in the sea! What are you doing here? Stones must go to the sea. Or they say, "My heart is not open." I say, "Why do you write like this?" "Because I'm very, very frank and honest." With whom are you honest? For such people there is no Sahaj Yog. They should really leave Sahaja Yoga and go away.<br />
Sahaja Yoga is meant for people who have a very large heart where [laughing:] Christ could be adorned. He's to be restored upon that great heart of yours. In every way one has to enlarge the heart.<br />
That's why I think William Blake very clearly said that, "England should be the Jerusalem." But only by saying that, 'William Blake said so,' one should know that it's complete [darkness], complete [darkness]. He is hoping against hopes. Large heartedness is missing among the people who live on the heart.<br />
As you know about the French, they call themselves Christians. Italians, who have so-called Christianity, have the worst pictures; so licentious, so horrible, so much against Christ. It's very surprising. How we can do such things to bring bad name to Him and to the whole world where you represent Him?<br />
People think Christianity means licentiousness, permissiveness, drunkenness, abandonment of all the values, while Christ was just the opposite of.<br />
Absolutely, He did not need any values. He was guṇātīt. He is dharmātīt, everything. But how He lived on this Earth, such an ideal!<br />
So before us we have got a great ideal. We don't have to follow the ideals of these horrible kings who lived there. But we have to follow the ideal of Christ and those kings who followed the ideal of Christ. Because if you are following Him, the path that you are following has to be, the essence of Christ's life is a pure life of love and sacrifice. This is what one has to follow.<br />
Throughout His life, He has been using this essence just to establish Himself in our Āgñyā chakra and that's what He's worked very, very hard to do that. Let us not do anything to let Him down in our character."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1224 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Christmas Eve), before the Evening Program, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1308.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, they say 'Merry Christmas' is enjoyment for joy. Out of peace comes the joy, the light of joy, the happiness.</b><br />
I wish peace for the whole world, for the whole nation, to understand to give up all the strives, all the false battles, for money and for power, all wrong ideas that they are different from each other, and come under the banner of Sahaja Yoga and enter into the Kingdom of God, where they are invited with all respect and love.<br />
I wish peace to all of them, to all the countries, all the human beings: in their families, in their hearts, with their children, with all of them. Let there be peace, let their heart emit peace, their tongues speak with peace, their eyes see nothing but peace.<br />
All this has to change, tremendous change has to take place. ......<br />
<b>I bless all of you to be the channels of that peace, to be beautiful channels of that peace, to be glorious channels of that peace, to be great children of your Mother, who is so proud of you.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1225 Christmas Pūjā, You Have to Be Peaceful, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Jesus Mary Mātā sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1225 Christmas Pūjā, Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/430281659"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Reciting Devī Mahātmyam</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jagi Tarak Janama Ala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namo Namo Moria</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zExNokrpbF0">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ek Gaṇapati</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/cpAg0HUPE9M">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1309.png" /></div>

<p>
<font color="Red"><b>Wishing you all a Merry Christmas!!!</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Christmas Day" /><category term="orange @ Christmas Puja" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Jesus Christ" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti: May God bless you all! This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/27" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti: May God bless you all! This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery”" /><published>2023-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_27_Shri_Guru_Nanak_Birthday</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/27"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today is a special day of Guru Nāṇaka's birthday.</b><br />
Uh we have celebrated one Guru Pūjā uh-uh-uh ... and the, as you know that Guru Nāṇak was also the Incarnation of the Primordial Master, the same Spirit came on this Earth. And the He's the One who tried to re-establish the work of Muhammad.<br />
......<br />
All the religions were established on this Earth to create the seekers. You are the seekers: you are the Men of God. Now, all of you have to become Prophets. And to become Prophets, today's Sahaja Yoga has taken the form of Mahā Yoga. All of you have to become Prophets.<br />
The Prophets have two special qualities, as all the Prophets had: first of all, they have to talk about spiritual education. All of Them did that: Muhammad Sāhab did it, Rāja Janaka did it, Nāṇaka did it, Moses did it, Abraham did it. All of Them prophesized and taught you how to lead yourself in the right path, by the right action, by leading a right life."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1300.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"May God bless you all!<br />
This day, in the name of Nāṇaka, I bless you all with that great spirit of mastery, which you all should become the Great Prophets who are going to change all the men of God into Prophets.<br />
May God bless you."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Teal"><b>Know that in every heart that beats<br />
The Lord of Life has His mansion.<br />
It is through the guru’s teaching<br />
We merge in the Formless One.<br />
By the gentle path of Sahaja<br />
Attain God, Purest of the Pure.<br />
A disciple who serves his guru and no other<br />
Will succeed, says Nanak, that is sure.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>PRABHU MAZA MALA JEVHA BASE GHEUNI EKANTĪ</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>When I am alone with my God (in meditation)</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>MITI VARNU MALA TEVHA GHADE JI HO SUKHAPRAPTĪ</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The bliss that I feel is beyond words</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the birthday of Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka. It is being celebrated throughout the world with so much of zeal that I have not seen in India.</b> For the first time it has been advertised in so many papers and by different means.<br />
Guru Nāṇaka always talked of Sahaja Yoga. "Everything else," He said, "is just showing off." About religion He said that, "Observing fasts, going on pilgrimage, etc., are just meant to show off. Now you have to discover the power that is within you and establish it." Guru Nāṇaka kept on repeating the same thing again and again.<br />
He never talked of rituals."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1123 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1301.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"See the brotherhood of all mankind as the highest order of yogis, conquer your own mind, and conquer the world."<br />
"In the calm of Sahaj’s cave, You can discover the True One, Sayeth Nanak, the True One loves the truthful."<br />"
--Guru Nanak</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"You have to educate yourself spiritually. 

And Guru Nāṇaka prophesized, just like William Blake, that, "The Men of God are going to come during Kali Yuga, and there will be many Prophets who will be transforming Prophets, who will be transforming people into Prophet State," He had prophesized.<br />
They have all prophesized about you! Now you have to prophesize about those who are going to be Prophets.<br />
......<br />
When Nāṇaka came in, He saw that Hindus and Muslims were fighting. So He started His theme with Kabīra, saying that, "Rām and Raḥīm are both the same, and how can you differentiate between the two?" <b>All their theme was like this, of integration of these two main religions which existed in India.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then came, you know Nāṇaka who preached that there should be no enmity between Hindus and Muslims, He preached that, because He saw the Muslims behaving in such a manner, they were such fanatics and they had become so funny that He could not understand, 'How is it? These are the people whom I have made Muslims and what are they doing here?'<br />
Actually <b>Mussulman means the person who is realized and Pīr is a person whose Realization is established</b> so much so that He [Prophet Muhammad] said that, 'Those who have become Mussulman should be buried and not burnt,' because He thought they are all realized Souls, but Realization finished off with His son-in-law and His daughter, after that He had two sons [grandchildren] who were great Souls who are really the Reincarnation[s] of Lav and Kuśh."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1302.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Ikoaŉkār saṯ nām karṯā purakẖ nirbẖao nirvair akāl mūraṯ ajūnī saibẖaŉ gur parsāḏ.</b></font><br />
There is One and only One God who is transcendent as well as immanent.<br />
True and Eternal Name. Creator and Person. Without Fear and without Enmity.<br /> 
Timeless Form, Unborn, Self-existent.<br />
Realized by Divine Grace.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka's Mool Mantra</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
<p><a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/19801123-guru-nanaks-birthday"> audio</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ (1993-0704 Guru Pūjā Cabella) </b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nāṇak Mohammad</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mBnW3jwrIwA?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Maiya Tere Charano Ki (2008-1113 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, Noida)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/iOXcrlduLNM">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavil by Nirmal Sangeet Sarita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/I1nxKFe8QOU?list=PLUEtF2j9oNtnS3rwo7C8qwWtuiJDbbtEx">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guruon kī Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Bhaiyakayataya (When we belong to God what is to fear) by Nirmal Sangeet Sarita (1990-0310 Australia)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/47fMsue7fs8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Guru Nanaka Birthday" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Guru Dattatreya" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/14" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity”" /><published>2023-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_14_Diwali_Day_5</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/14"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>it was a beautiful surprise. It's very joy-giving it.<br />
...... joy was dancing in your eyes. I could see the lights in your eyes. And this is the real Diwālī.</b><br />
Diwālī word comes from two words: dīpa and āwali. Dīpa means, you know, lights, and āwali means rows, rows and rows of lights. Seems it's a very, very ancient idea and all over in the world, you see, whenever they have to celebrate something then they put lights. And lights because light gives joy, gives happiness. So to overcome the darkness of ignorance also we have to enlighten ourselves. And that is why is important that everybody should get Self-realization to feel the light within themselves. And you must have noticed that after Realization the eyes also sparkle. There's light in the eyes of every Sahaja Yogi."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1021 Diwālī Pūjā (4th day after Diwālī Day), Touch Your Depth, Chioggia (50 kms S of Venice), Veneto, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1295.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is a day we celebrate in India where relationship between brothers and sisters have to be established.</b> They're very pure. Brothers and relationsh... sisters relationship is without any lust or greed. Is pure relationship, where the sister prays for the protection of the brother and brother play ... pray ... prays for the self-sufficiency of the kṣhema, well-being, of the sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1106 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Become the Ideals (Unless and Until You Become Your Ideals You Are Not a Sahaja Yogi), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"You are all, as I said, you are My light. And the light is there which is an eternal light. These lights will be finished. We'll have to light them every year. Not you people. You have eternal light and this light is going to spread Joy. What's the problem of this world? The whole problem, you take it. There's no joy. Simple as that -- there's no joy. If they had joy, they would not have done all these nonsensical things. There's no joy. When you have joy, you don't want to fight, you don't want to do anything that is harmful. You don't want to say anything after anyone, not only that but you do not want to have something that will spoil this Mother Earth or which will bring ecological problem. No, you just don't want it, don't want to do anything because it harms harms others. People feel unhappy about it whether it is here, India, anywhere. You just feel that `Why should I do such a thing which is not so congenial to others?' I mean, it's not joy-giving.<br />
<b>So when you have joy, you have to be joy-giving. And if you are not joy-giving, that means there's something lacking in your Sahaja Yoga and that's why we have to come up now. We have to become Sahaja Yoginīs and Sahaja Yogis. That is joy-giving society. We can change our name, if you like, if not Sahaja Yoga is good: `Joy-giving Association'.</b> "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1296.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Rakṣhābandhan Day, they give a symbolic expression to their desire that their brother should be good. <b>But on this day they worship their brothers, actually worship them.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Bābā Māmā (on 1990-0310):</b> <b>This is what the brother has written for the sister: "O Nirmalā, my Sister, how much should I praise You? Because You have given the human being the experience of God."</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But for a gṛuhalakṣhmī, the brother is very important.<br />
<b>And the brotherhood and sisterhood is the base of our Sahaj Yoga collectivity.</b> If you understand that brotherhood and sisterhood is love which is very pure, there is no expectation, is just love: is giving love and taking love. And Absolute Purity within us should exist between our relationships when we call them as Sahaj Yogi brothers and sisters. And as there is understanding, complete understanding between the brother and sister, in a family, one has to know we are all part and parcel of a family, born out [of] the same Mother.<br />
Nobody has to shoot off, you know, nobody has to become something great, nobody has to correct others, nobody has to uh say that, `I'm something unique.' All of you have to work it out together and find out the solution working out together, in complete friendship and unison. Anyone who cuts off himself and goes out or becomes anything else, goes out of circulation and useless for Sahaj Yoga. Such a person is completely useless: the one who tries to get out of the family. All of you have to be supporting as each other, helping to each other, not shouting at each other, [not] getting angry with each other, trusting each other, not finding faults, treating each other with respect and love.<br />
This is the most important thing, which Sahaj Yogis don't understand, that you are Saints and you have to respect each other. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1297.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Bhogya Lakṣhmī. Bho-gya. Bhogya means: the One by which you enjoy, by which you enjoy.</b><br />
Now, I mean, it's like the whole ocean of joy is around you and you are like a bird who cannot drink it. Only through the Grace of Bhūmī Lakṣhmī ... Bhogya Lakṣhmī, you can enjoy that [ocean].<br />
So, the Spirit, though it is manifesting, you are not enjoying your Spirit. Even that. Anything that you see, say, see a flower, you should be able to enjoy. You cannot enjoy because there is thought. Anything you do there is thought: you cannot enjoy.<br />
<b>When there is no thought, when the Spirit is flowing, you get the complete enjoyment.<br />
Actually, I should say, I am the Enjoyer.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, the last day is very important: is a very universal day, I should say, called as Bhāī Dūj. is the ... or they call it also in Marathi Bhāūbīj, the ... different names. Is the: brothers' and sisters' day.<br />
Now, the brothers' and sisters' relationship has to be very, very strong. And the purity of that relationship is to be maintained. Is not necessary that you should be born as brothers and sisters, not necessary. But you are born, because if you are realized Souls you are born as brothers and sisters. So that purity must be maintained in the society of Sahaja Yoga. Very important it is. That we should try to develop this situation that brothers and sisters are something very pure. Their relationships are very pure. And they should not be at all challenged.<br />
It is so much so that even if you call somebody your brother, he is your brother and the more you develop this relationship, the better your left Viśhuddhi will be. Because left Viśhuddhi is the relationship with God as a brother or with a Goddess as a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So, for compassion, it has to have decency as fragrance in the oil. So how do we express our compassion? We have rākhī sisters, rākhī brothers, but I know of a lady who became friendly with rich boys as rākhī brothers. Or the other way round also, that many boys became rākhī brothers of rich women.<br />
<b>So one has to understand that it is not for money that you should become rākhī brothers and sisters and to exploit, but for compassion.</b> You have to express your rākhī relationship just for the protection of each other. <b>The compassion is so joy-giving that you should have not such conditions of money or any other stupid conditions which will kill your joy.</b> But another thing also is that you express your love you use some things as presents that gives you joy. That doesn't mean, by any chance, that you just give it to your rākhī sister and not even to your wife, some present."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1105 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), Lights of Pure Compassion, Istanbul, Turkey</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1298.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"The Mahālakṣhmī is the channel of the Kuṇḍalinī, so there are Aṣhṭa Lakṣhmīs. Then Mahālakṣhmī and lastly the Dakṣha Lakṣhmī. We have got one after another these powers within us which are expressed on the Mahālakṣhmī channel."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1018 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Navarātri Celebrations (8th Day), Pratiṣhṭhān, NDA Road, Warje, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"So, for today's New Year, let us vow within ourselves, that the selfishness or the self-centeredness or the smallness in you is finished."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1231 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Year's Eve, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano mein aya hu</b></font><br />
Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon,  Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font><br />
Morning and evening I sing Your Praise<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font><br />
Śhrī Mātājī I Have received a Second Birth from You<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), Life Is For Giving Joy to Others, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/53370260"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Nirmal Saṅgīt Saritā - Rang De Jhini</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/zcAvt3cDa0Y">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuzhe Rupa Pāhuniyā Mi danga zhalo ai</b></font><br />
(Seeing Your serene and majestic look, we stand stunned and astonished))<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Awaz Uthayenge</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Ttp3KyI2rew">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Bhai Duja Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/13" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.”" /><published>2023-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_13_Diwali_Day_4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/13"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now the Mahālakṣhmī. <b>Mahālakṣhmī is the evolutionary state.</b> In the evolutionary state, when the evolutionary state starts, then the Mahālakṣhmī starts asserting Herself and that comes when your well-being is established fully. I mean, if you are still worried as to how to get a cup of tea for yourself, you cannot get to Mahālakṣhmī state.<br />
So, once that is little bit established and you feel that peace within yourself and that dignity, then the Mahālakṣhmī's Power starts acting on you. And the Mahālakṣhmī Power is that it really makes you the light. You have now become the light. Don't have to have any lights. You are the light. When you go anywhere, when people see you they take guidance from you. They use you as a torch which guides them. They will come and consult you and ask you how to do it. It is you who are the light.<br />
So, this is what it is. <b>One has to know that Mahālakṣhmī Tattwa is represented here as the light. And, you see these lights when enlightened, even a small light, how it reacts and how it shows. And now, you have become the light, you see. Even this light can do it. You see, I put My hand to it and it recognizes and knows that because it is now enlightened. It is put before the Photograph, it's enlightened. It works that way. Now what about you? You are the light now; you are the Diwālī of God.<br />
Diwālī means the, the rows of lights. So, you are going to make this beautiful mansion of God full of Diwālī light. You have entered into the Kingdom of God and you have to enlighten it. So you are the decoration of God on one side, you are the glory of God and also, on the other side you are the guide, guidelines</b> - you are like the torches, you can say, you are like the, what you call them, which are used by ships those ...<br />
......<br />
You have to become lighthouses."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1291.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"That's the first day of the Moon. That is the forefathers of your Mother, Śhālivāhanas, they started the calendar, from that date. And so, on the first, that means the first day of the Moon, the New Year is celebrated.<br />
Now, see symbolically, Christ is born and the New Year is celebrated, next day. As soon as He is born, New Year starts with. So next year it starts, the New Year."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen">"So uh, first of all <b>I wish you all a very Happy Diwālī and a prosperous whole year, after this New Year Day.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1106 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), Apollon Camping, Delphi, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Then the day of the New Year comes in afterwards, because in India in the north, that's the time people finish their crops and they found that day was very good to celebrate the New Year. And, that is actually more, sort of, we can say is a social thing in India ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... <b>Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that's how we start understanding the value of human dignity</b>. We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It's against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody's life miserable. It's against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time. And if you nag that's not a Gṛuhalakṣhmī; that is not a Gṛuhalakṣhmī. You should not nag, `Do this, do that, stand up, what are you doing, stand this side, do, go that side.' It's all a nonsense. You leave the person to be; <b>the human dignity is the most important thing</b>. But respect everybody. And that's possible because now you have the Mahālakṣhmī Principle. Those who do not have the dignity also will get it from you because you are dignified now."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1292.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Satya Lakṣhmī. That is, that you get the awareness of Truth</b>, but apart from that, the awareness of Truth is there but to put the Truth forward in a gracious manner. Not to, `Now this is the Truth -- have it!' -- Not like that! You don't have to hit people with the Truth, you have to put it in a flower and give it to them. <b>That is Satya Lakṣhmī.</b> Of course, the all Lakṣhmī Tattwas are the parasympathetic powers within us but they are actually expressed in our brain. <b>Brain is the Virāṭa, is the Viṣhṇu when He becomes the Virāṭ, the Akbar.</b> So all His Powers, are, specially these powers, are in the brain. So, the brain itself spontaneously behaves in such a manner that people think that this is a special type of a personality.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Eh ... <b>is the day of Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā nights, not only of Lakṣhmī Pūjā</b>. There's a difference between the two.<br />
Mahālakṣhmī is one of the powers of the Three Powers, Main Powers, of Ādi Śhakti. As you know Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahākālī. Now these powers have powers at a material level also, at a subtler level also. So Mahālakṣhmī Power is achieved after Lakṣhmī Power ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So the whole idea of celebrating today the Lakṣhmī's Day is to understand that in us She has become the Mahālakṣhmī.</b> By that we have so many powers of which we are not aware, I mean we do not know that we are realized Souls. Some of us, we do not know and that we have those powers within us that we can permeate into others. We can project our personalities to others. We can find out what's wrong with them. We can find out about ourselves. We can go into ourselves, we can go into -- our permeation is like water is moving, is flowing all the time. And this is a very important thing that we should be aware of: our powers that we have achieved.<br />
Then we will start respecting ourselves then the Rājalakṣhmī comes in and then the Gṛuhalakṣhmī comes in and everything comes within when we become aware of what we have achieved of our self-esteem, of our dignity.<br />
So it gives us dignity, Mahālakṣhmī gives us dignity. And that's how we start understanding the value of human dignity.<br /> 
We should have also the idea of human dignity that we cannot insult human dignity, like people who are nagging others all the time. It's against or all the time asserting themselves about something making everybody's life miserable. It's against human dignity. You have to decorate another human, you have to make it beautiful, you have to make it enjoyable and happy, make everyone happy, not to nag all the time."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1293.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Yoga Lakṣhmī. The Lakṣhmī's power which gives you Yoga. Is Lakṣhmī [who] supports your power of Yoga by giving you awareness. The power by which you take to Yoga is all combined as Yoga Lakṣhmī.</b><br />
Like your affluence: you are not satisfied and you want to have Yoga. The dissatisfaction you get till you have got Yoga is coming from the Yoga Lakṣhmī.<br />
<b>So, Yoga Lakṣhmī is: the power which gives you or takes you to your grace, by which you go to Yoga. That's Yoga Lakṣhmī. Means the kind of a satisfaction that you seek is manifested in you through this power of Yoga Lakṣhmī.</b><br />
And then once you have achieved your Yoga, you get the Grace. Lakṣhmī is the Grace. So, you get the grace of a Saint.<br />
You should have the grace of a Saint. You should look like a Saint! You are a Saint! I think better write it on your mirrors: ``We are Saints. We are `Men of God.' We have to behave like Saints. We are Saints." You are! No doubt! You are, "Men of God," no doubt, but you have turn your faces this way.<br />
So, this is the Yoga Lakṣhmī.<br />
For example, a person who has got Yoga Lakṣhmī doesn't quarrel like a madcap. If he quarrels or dominates someone in a foolish way, then he's still lacking that Lakṣhmī point. There's a grace about it: whole way of talking and ... How you talk to a Saint?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"...... [in] Sahaja Yoga we believe that the Lakṣhmī must became [become] Mahālakṣhmī. A man has to become greater man: mahā mānav. What does that mean? That She has to become the Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
<b>Mahālakṣhmī is a Deity which makes you absolutely satisfied with whatever you have. Complete satisfaction.</b><br />
......<br />
...... when the Mahālakṣhmī Principle shines in you, then you do not want any more. You want to give it to others, and you want to enjoy your generosity. That is the first sign that you are moving now from Lakṣhmī to Mahālakṣhmī. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-1029 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1294.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Today is the day to take an oath, to think of something great, to visualize something big, to ask a boon, to do a big Pūjā, is one of the greatest uh day."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1020 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Padm‛āsana sthite Devi, Para-brahma swa-rūpiṇī,</b></font><br />
O Devī, seated on the Lotus, who is the Supreme Consciousness,<br />
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Parameśhi jagan-mātar, aah; Mahālakṣhmī namō‛stu-te.</b></font><br />
Supreme Ruler and Mother of the Universe, O Great Mother, Obeisance to Thee.
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1110 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), What State You Have to Reach, Quinta do Mar, Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/25922658"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Stotram</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Parabrahma Rūpinī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Ch-wz0NR08">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jogawa, Music Of Joy</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tere hi Gun gate hai</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumPurple">Wishing you all a very Happy Diwali and a Happy New Year!</font><br />  
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Padava" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the blessings of Kingdom of God is that you get drenched in joy – joy which has no duality”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2023 Celebrating the Festival of Diwālī: “the blessings of Kingdom of God is that you get drenched in joy – joy which has no duality”" /><published>2023-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/2023_11_12_Diwali_Day_3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2023/11/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It was to celebrate the coronation of Śhrī Rāma also, that is to say, symbolically, to celebrate the establishment of a kingdom which has a benevolent administration.<br />
......<br />
<b>So today is a special day to celebrate the Kingdom of God on Earth.</b> As we have ... used to pray, ``Thy kingdom come [......] on this earth" and it has come today on this mountain and we are here to celebrate the coming of the Kingdom of God as we have been praying for ages. And <b>the blessings of Kingdom of God is that you get drenched in joy -- joy which has no duality, like happiness and unhappiness</b>. Is an experience of Absoluteness and just that joy is sufficient, you don't want any food, you don't want to sleep, you don't mind where you are, just in joy drenched completely. There's no place for unhappiness, we have no heart for it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1024 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Bhāūbīj Day), The Light of Love, before the Evening Program, the day before Diwālī Pūjā, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1286.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"And, today's day is a very great day for us because the Saints are celebrating Diwālī. I'm celebrating My Diwālī enlightening light in your hearts that you enjoy your own joy and your own beauty; that you are now the Spirit. Enjoy it. That you are there. Now, you are in the Kingdom of God. No doubt."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1027 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Day), Lakṣhmī Principle and Relationship between Men and Women, Āśhram, former Hotel, Bramham Gardens, Earl's Court, Kensington, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Śhrī Rāma's crowning or any other aspect of Śhrī Lakṣhmī here now becomes your own crowning, that is now you have entered into the Kingdom of God and once you are there then automatically as the citizens of God's Kingdom you are blessed and as you become the lotuses then you start spreading your fragrance all around. Now you do not keep this joy to yourself but you become generous about it and you go all out to give it to others."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Sala Olimpia (Olympia Sports Hall), Timişoara, Timiş, Romania</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1287.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">"<b>Then the fifteenth day is the day when the Moon is absolutely missing from everything. Is absolute darkness, where you put these lights to suggest that: `There are lights, now let Lakṣhmī come within us.' So, there is no spot that should be left which is dark, so everywhere the Lakṣhmī resign ... resides, and give us the glory of Her blessings.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1114 Diwālī Pūjā (Diwālī Day), Deeper Wealth, Divine Temperament, Fondness of Generosity, Keep your Suṣhumṇā Open and Real Days of Diwālī Celebration (The Greatest Generosity a Human Being Can Do Is to Forgive, All of Us Have to Go Together, Discretion to Improve Your Value System and Universal Theme for People), Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Lakṣhmī is the Goddess, is the power within us, by which we balance, lead a very balanced life, by which we are satisfied.</b><br />
Now they have made a beautiful picture of this Lakṣhmī also one should understand this power -- is a Lady, is a Mother and She stands on a lotus. Now these are all symbols which suggest that these symbols are carved out with such deep significance. She stands on a lotus. Means imagine, who can stand on a lotus? And She's a very healthy woman, very healthy woman and She stands on a lotus. It means that, that She is never putting pressure on anyone.<br />
......<br />
Then, it has got two red, <b>pink flowers in the hand, that are lotus flowers again.<br />
Now the lotus is regarded as a very holy flower in India, because it is so receptive to everything that is crude and funny.</b> First of all it is born in the mud. Just think of it, in the mud, in the filth, where the horrible smell is coming out, the lotus is born. And the one lotus gives the fragrance, the beautiful fragrance to the whole atmosphere, and kills all that's filth and everything, and covers the whole pond with its big, big leaves so that it looks a beautiful pond. That's what is the lotus for.<br />
But this lotus is a pink lotus, means pink, you know, is the sign of love. <b>Pink is the sign of love. So such a person has to have tremendous love and that softness of the lotus.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0327 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 3, Nābhī Chakra (Must Have a Balanced Attitude Towards Life), Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"For <b>your good luck, you should say let us say for your good luck, saubhāgya, for your good luck</b>. Is given to the ladies, always given to the ladies. Because in India the women are regarded as the śhakti and women who lead a married life and who have been mothers, who have been daughters and also wives and things like that are respected very much as only it is believed that <b>only the respectable women when they exist in any country the Gods also reside there. If they are not respectable the Gods don't reside there</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0210 Talk to Sahaja Yoginīs, About Tradition, Pimpri (17 kms N-NW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1288.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Am-ṛu-ta. <b>Amṛuta means the thing that does not die. If in this world the Lakṣhmī exists as your wealth.</b><br />
Now the wealth that does not die, which is that wealth? Is the Spirit. So, the Grace of the Spirit is the Amṛuta Lakṣhmī. Grace of the Spirit is the Amṛuta Lakṣhmī. The rest of the things all will die out. And whatever is done through the Spirit, to please the Spirit, is the Amṛuta Lakṣhmī.<br />
For example: loving others. Loving others has a different meaning in the symbolic way as you people understand this thing. Loving means giving. Doing without any expectation: just doing it, and enjoying.<br />
The greatest is giving vibration[s]. That is Amṛuta: vibrations do not die. That's the Lakṣhmī: they are giving Amṛut."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (Bhāūbīj Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Power, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>"Now Saubhāgya Lakṣhmī. She's the one who gives you good fortune. Good fortune doesn't mean money, but it means: the grace of money. Many people have money but it's like money on a donkey. You do not find any grace in that person. Or it doesn't also mean, saubhāgya doesn't mean only money, it means all the good luck. All the good luck in everything in a very gracious manner, is this. To [give] you the blessings so that you also are blessed as well as those people who'll meet you will be blessed, with saubhāgya."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (3rd day after Diwālī Day), Power of Innocence, Meaning of Nine of the Lakṣhmīs, Lecco (50 kms N of Milan on Lake Como), Lombardy, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1289.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Chandraam Prabhaasaam Yashasaa Jvalantiim Shriyam Loke Deva-Jussttaam-Udaaraam 
Taam Padminiim-Iim Sharannam-Aham Prapadye-[A]lakssmiir-Me Nashyataam Tvaam Vrnne</b></font><br />
Who is the Embodiment of Sri and Whose Glory Shines like the Splendour of the Moon in all the Worlds; Who is Noble and Who is Worshipped by the Devas.<br />
I take Refuge at Her Feet, Who Abides in the Lotus;<br />
By Her Grace, let the Alakshmi (in the form of Evil, Distress, and Poverty) within and without be Destroyed.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(from Śhrī Sūktam)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="Red"><b>"This is the promise of Diwālī to you all, that you will reach highest and the noblest way of life. Every word I say will be there to prove what I say is there. Whatever petty problems you have, they'll all be washed off. All these are the messages from the Divine, you don't have to worry about petty things, about money, about jobs, that's not your job. Your destiny will work it out. You have a promise that you'll be looked after. I hope you believe in that promise and are joyous in the highest way.<br />
I bless you all from My heart, all of you, for a very happy and prosperous Diwālī."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2003-1109 Diwālī Pūjā (16th day after Diwālī Day), The Need for Sincerity, Holiday Inn Express and Suites, 1080 Navigator Drive, Ventura, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-1103 Diwālī Pūjā (Naraka Chaturdaśhī Day), The Importance of Meditation, Lake Piru Recreational Area Campground, 4780 Piru Canyon Rd, Piru (87 kms NW of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/29517118"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Ayi, Ayi, Āj Diwālī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hum Āj Rāth</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Viśhwa Vandita</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1290.png" /></div>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />  
Wishing you all a very <font color="DeepPink"><b>Happy and Prosperous Diwālī!</b></font><br />   
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Diwali Day" /><category term="green @ Diwali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>