<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-20T18:39:43-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/festivity.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Festivity</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Anant Chaturdaśhī: “Gaṇeśh Chaturdaśhī means the day when Gaṇeśha is dissolved in the water, in the ocean or He is created, worshiped for ten days and again given back.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/09/17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Anant Chaturdaśhī: “Gaṇeśh Chaturdaśhī means the day when Gaṇeśha is dissolved in the water, in the ocean or He is created, worshiped for ten days and again given back.”" /><published>2024-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/09/2024_09_17_Anant_Chaturdashi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/09/17"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So, before creating this Creation, before creating the Ādi Kuṇḍalinī, before creating this universe, <b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha was established. Today, being Tuesday, is an auspicious day.</b> He is in reality the Incarnation of Purity. He resides within us but you don't have the eyes to see Him. In the center called Mūlādhāra which is surrounded by the prostate gland [in men] and which is called as pelvic plexus, He is reflected within every person. He might be asleep but He resides there. This Deity is such that He never falls asleep completely. When a person becomes a complete devil, then He disappears from there but He is present within everyone. This is the first center within us which is called as Mūlādhāra chakra."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1223 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Paramātmā ke Prem ke Anubhav (Experiences of Divine Love), Bal Mohan Mandir, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0044.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center;">
<b> You are the One to be worshipped first. Obeisance to You again and again.<br />
You are the Word that was in the beginning. You are the Aumkara.<br />
You are the source of life. You are the source of security.</b>
</p>

<p>
Sahaja Yogi: Today it’s said it’s Anant Chaturdaśhī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> Ah?</font><br />
Sahaja Yogi: Anant Chaturdaśhī.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b> Today? Ah-ah! That’s great! Yes must be. I was wondering Anant Chaturdaśhī. <b>Anant Chaturdaśhī is the day when we visarjan – dissolve Śhrī Gaṇeśha in the water.</b><br />
Gaṇeśhjī ko chodte hai na pani mein – it’s that day we put the Gaṇeśha in to the water.<br />
Because <b>He’s established for ten days and after ten days</b>, He’s born on the fourth, after ten days He’s dissolved in the water so that everywhere His Power is spread through the water.<br />
That’s why no wonder there was a Pūjā.<br />
Gaṇeśha settled down into the water. That is Ananta Chaturdaśhī. Ananta is the, is Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
Ananta means which cannot be destroyed. Innocence cannot be destroyed. And that is why is the Gaṇeśh Chaturdaśhī means the day when Gaṇeśha is dissolved in the water, in the ocean or He is created, worshiped for ten days and again given back. So it’s a very great day today, I should say, like the Resurrection of Christ that you are, you had Christ here, He lived with you, and then went back to His Father. Father is the ocean and that’s what in India they do, <b>establish Him on the fourth day and on the tenth day they put Him back to the ocean</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0920 Guru Pūjā (Anant Chaturdaśhī Day), This Finger Is Nothing but the Sahaja Yogis of America and They Have to Help by Their Dynamic Behavior and by Their Proper Understanding, Responsibility as the People Belonging to this Great Nation of Fatherhood, Houston, TX, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Establish Śhrī Gaṇeśha within you.</b> First of all you must establish Him and then you can use it for others, for yourself and for bettering and bettering the methods of Sahaja Yoga that you have learnt.<br />
That's how Śhrī Gaṇeśha is so important for all the Sahaja Yogis to be understood in all its aspects, but this principle is very enormous I should say. The principle is very spread out, it's very subtle, so to understand in all its aspects is not an easy thing. The only thing you can do is to become One with it, like the Ocean. If you become One with the Ocean you become the Ocean. Just become One with it and that's how it works out."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0301 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Perth, WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0045.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Only in your Āratī, in Marathi</b>, of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, they say that, “At the time when I am getting my Realization you must save me.” That’s the only thing they ask, "At the time of my Resurrection you must save me." It does not say that, 'At the time of my Resurrection you protect me,' no! "You save me."<br />
Because He’s the one who is sitting on every chakra like a vice-chancellor of the university.<br />
Even if you have Viṣhṇu on your side, Mahādeva on your side, but if Śhrī Gaṇeśha is there sitting and He says, ‘No, not his ascent,’ it doesn’t work out, it’s very difficult."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0907 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Italy</b></font><br />
<font color="blue"><b>Sukha Karta Dukha Harta Varta Vighnachi</b><br />
You are the One who offers happiness and removes sorrows at the time of danger<br />
<b>Nurvi Purvi Prem Krupa Jayachi</b><br />
You offer lots of tender love and blessings<br />
<b>Sarvangi Sunder Uti Shendurachi</b><br />
You have red paste on Your body<br />
<b>Kanthi Jhalke Mal Mukta Falanchi</b><br />
and wear a pearl necklace</font><br />
Gaṇapati Āratī in Marathi<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=00&amp;v=UVy3jqPOUrI&amp;feature=emb_logo">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0914 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=0&amp;v=evka13KpP7I&amp;feature=emb_logo"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html"> video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Lavkar Yayi Śhrī Gaṇarāyā, Sakalanshi Bheti Dyaya</b> ((Bhajan in praise of Śhrī Mātājī before Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
</p>

<p> 
<font color="green"><b>Gaiye Gaṇapati Jagvandan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Om Bhur Bhuvah</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Eka Gaṇapati</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Dg41OjGhrU8">video</a><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇarāyā, Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Anant Chaturdashi" /><category term="orange @ Shri Ganesha Puja" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Ganesha" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Gaṇeśha Chaturthī: “My Feet here represent Gaṇeśha, and they are innocent, and so, we are trying to worship those so that, within you, Gaṇeśha should be invoked.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/09/07" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Gaṇeśha Chaturthī: “My Feet here represent Gaṇeśha, and they are innocent, and so, we are trying to worship those so that, within you, Gaṇeśha should be invoked.”" /><published>2024-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/09/2024_09_07_Shri_Ganesha_Chaturthi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/09/07"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here to worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha.</b><br />
<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha is the Deity of Innocence.</b><br />
When we are born as children, it is Śhrī Gaṇeśha who is acting and we are very innocent, and it is such a powerful thing that, with this innocence, children survive under many circumstances. And we love them, because they are innocent. We enjoy them, because they are innocent.<br />
Once we start growing, our Sahasrāra also gets closed and we develop all kinds of funny things that enters into us and doesn't go out. It's just there, it doesn't go out.<br />
Innocence has a great effect on our character and on our sense of chastity. Actually, when you are innocent, you don't know what is not chastity, what is being unchaste, what is being cunning. You are innocent and you are looked after by Śhrī Gaṇeśha Himself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0914 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0040.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>"...... Chaturthī is the day He is established, Gaṇeśha is established on this Chaturthī ......"</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0822 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, House of Charles and Magda Mathys, Chemin des Moulins-de-Drize 5, Troinex (6 kms S of Geneva), Gèneve, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"So the priorities have to change if Śhrī Gaṇeśha is to be worshiped. What are we worshiping today is the innocence within us. We are worshiping that is auspicious, which is innocent. Innocence, which is deep down within us -- that's our character, that's our nature, that's what we are born with -- is the basic of this whole Creation, is the essence of this Creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0804 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Vehicle We Have Is Our Chastity, Brighton Friends Meeting House, Ship Street, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><font size="+0"><b>Invocation to Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b></font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today you have come here to worship Me as Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
We have been singing the praise of Śhrī Gaṇeśha before every Pūjā. And we have such tremendous respect for Śhrī Gaṇeśh, because we have found out that unless and <b>until Śhrī Gaṇeśha, who is the symbol of our innocence, is not awakened within us, we cannot enter into the Kingdom of God. And even to stay there and to enjoy the blessings of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, we have to have our innocence fully blossoming</b>. So we praise Him and He is very easily praised.<br />
And whatever we might have done wrong before coming to Sahaja Yoga, He completely forgives because He is the eternal child."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0808 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, How far to Go with Children, Maison des Congrès Centre Culturel et Sportif, Chem. des Grandes Isles 7, 1865 Ormont-Dessus (Les Diablerets), Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0041.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, we have gathered here to worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
<b>You all know what a powerful Deity He is. His Power comes from His innocence.</b><br />
When we see small children, we [are] automatically compelled towards them and also we want to love them, kiss them and be with us [them]. And very innocent they are, extremely innocent.<br />
And when we worship Śhrī Gaṇeśh we have to know if we have been really innocent or not."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0925 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, You Must Worship Śhrī Gaṇeśh and You Should Be Absolutely Chaste People, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sumukhash-chai'ka-dantash-cha Kapilo Gaja-karnakah<br />
Lambodarsha-cha Vikato Vighna-nasho Ganadhipah<br />
Dhumra-ketur-Ganadhyaksho Bhala-chandro-Gajananah</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/PSSlZT0ddcM">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>The greatest quality of Śhrī Gaṇeśha is joy.</b> It gives you joy, as small children, they may not speak even, but they give us so much joy. Joy-giving quality comes from Śhrī Gaṇeśha.<br />
Even after coming to Sahaja Yoga I've seen people are not full of joy. Are very serious, they don't know how to laugh, how to enjoy anything. That's the sign that they are still lacking in innocence.<br />
So it's important to understand that, if you are Sahaja Yogis, you should be joyous and give joy to others, just like children, how sweet they are. They may be newly born, but how much joy they give you.<br />
But supposing you do not have that capacity to enjoy the innocence of children, then nobody can help you. Gaṇeśha cannot help you. Because that's the innate quality human beings have and if you don't have that quality, no use having any other sense. Like some people like food, they like colors, they like all other things. But if you don't have Śhrī Gaṇeśh you cannot purely enjoy anything.<br />
So it is only [with] Śhrī Gaṇeśha's blessings that we really enjoy everything in its full measure. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0914 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0042.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So today's Pūjā is specially to be done with a prayer in your heart that: 'Śhrī Gaṇeśha, please be kind and merciful and forgiving that You manifest within ourselves. Let all these hypocritical things, all these conditionings and all these wrong ideas we have, or all the wrong life we have had, should just disappear like thin air, and let the beautiful moonlight of your soothing qualities of innocence be manifested through us.'<br />
Let us manifest these qualities. This is what is to be asked."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0826 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Glow of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Lanersbach, Austria</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/HJzi8uu62lc?list=PLuAVZW42aaCkYVG_Ll2jgiRUtS9cC__p1">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In the Sahaja Yoga system, if we say that Gaṇeśha is the One who gives us, He's the Adhyakṣha, means He is the, I call Him as the Chancellor of the University. He is the one who goes on degree to us, 'Now, you have crossed this chakra, that chakra, that chakra.' And He helps us to know that what state we are in. So, the Gaṇeśha gives us say, Nirvichāra Samādhi, which we can call it as the thoughtless awareness, and Nirvikalpa Samādhi. He gives all that and also He gives us joy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā, Electromagnetic Force, Schloss Schwetzingen, Schloß Mittelbau, Schwetzingen, Baden-Württemberg, Germany</b></font><br />
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Oṃkār Pradhana Rūp Gaṇeśhache by Saint Tukārām</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0043.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<b>Sahaja Yogis [recite]</b>: "Jay Gaṇeśha, Jay Gaṇeśha, Jay Gaṇeśha Pāhimām, Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Jay Gaṇeśha, Jaya Gaṇeśha Rakṣhamām."
<font color="DarkRed"><b><br />
Śhrī Mātājī</b>: Now, what you are doing by saying these mantras, you are awakening the innocence within you. <b>Innocence is represented by Śhrī Gaṇeśh.</b> As you know, later on He incarnated as Lord Jesus Christ, but the innocence within us must be first of all invoked, because, before creating the universe, first of all innocence was created, because innocence has the greatest protective power, the greatest destructive power and it is the most powerful. So, first we are trying to invoke the innocence.<br />
<b>Now, My Feet here represent Gaṇeśha, and they are innocent, and so, we are trying to worship those so that, within you, Gaṇeśha should be invoked. Your innocence should be enlightened, all right?</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1012 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (4th Day of Navarātri), Winterthurerstraße, Zürich, Switzerland</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="green">"<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b>, I am going to be worthy of Your attention.<br />
Please make me innocent, so that I am in Your attention.<br />
<b>Śhrī Mother</b>, You are Śhrī Gaṇeśha, please give me wisdom and discrimination."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Prayer to Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Āśhram, Rome, Italy from the 2012 edition of Sahaja Yoga Mantra Book, Page 29</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sukha Karta Dukha Harta Varta Vighnachi</b><br />
You are the One who offers happiness and removes sorrows at the time of danger<br />
<b>Nurvi Purvi Prem Krupa Jayachi</b><br />
You offer lots of tender love and blessings<br />
<b>Sarvangi Sunder Uti Shendurachi</b><br />
You have red paste on Your body<br />
<b>Kanthi Jhalke Mal Mukta Falanchi</b><br />
and wear a pearl necklace</font><br />
<font size="+0">Gaṇapati Āratī in Marathi</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/UVy3jqPOUrI">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0915 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, The Message of Śhrī Gaṇeśha and His Pūjā Is to Give Realization (Without Innocence You Cannot Enjoy Anything and Have Faith in Your Mother), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/25233746"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hemaja Sutam Bhajan</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/mGvUq8-ebXo">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Jay Bolo Nirmal Gaṇeśha Kī</b></font><br />
(Victory to Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Australian song book, Hindi supplement page 66)<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Gaṇarāyā Śhrī Gaṇarāyā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Shri Ganesha Pancha Ratnam</b></font><br />
(Names of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Australian song book Sanskrit song 23)<br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/TxotrB3Gzo0">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Jay Jagadambe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Hasat Ali</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Kinaryala Lau</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Zulzul Vahe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/TbbNsFKL07c">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shri Ganesha Chaturthi" /><category term="orange @ Shri Ganesha Puja" /><category term="deeppink @ Shri Ganesha" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Rakṣhābandhan: “the chaos of the social system of America is because they have no sense of pure relationships. Once you call somebody a sister, she’s a sister. And once you call somebody a brother, he’s a brother.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/08/19" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Rakṣhābandhan: “the chaos of the social system of America is because they have no sense of pure relationships. Once you call somebody a sister, she’s a sister. And once you call somebody a brother, he’s a brother.”" /><published>2024-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/08/2024_08_19_Rakshabandhan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/08/19"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So the relationship between Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and Viṣhṇumāyā is that of a brother and a sister.<br />
And surprisingly, the other day we celebrated the Rākhī Bandhan, the Rakṣhābandhan, which is the same thing as the brothers-sisters relationship.<br />
So now here we are celebrating actually the Deity which is the Sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
Later on She was born as Draupadī. And that's why Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa went to save Her chastity, because is the brother only who is concerned about the chastity and the name of the sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0036.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, <b>the Indian Sahaja Yogis have sent Me three rākhīs</b>. This was by somebody else, but three of them, which is a very, very ... another very poetical situation. That, M... Modi has written that, "You are the protection for all of us. And a how ... what do we do ah to put this onto You? And what are we doing it?"<br />
So, they said that: <b>"All the sisters of Sahaja Yogis are sending this to be tied on all the brothers of Sahaja Yoginīs who are in Your wrist."</b><br />
<b>And that's how they've sent three -- of Mahākālī, Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī</b> -- three things which I will ask one of the child to come and do it because it is the work of a small little child, ......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0826 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Rakṣhābandhan Day), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Rākhī is Protecting Power.</b> Its bond is very strong and extremely tender because it symbolizes the noble love of sister. Customarily, tying a rākhī to someone is establishing a place of Pure Protection. However, man's ability to understand love has become so feeble that tying of rākhī has become merely a mechanical process. All beautiful human traditions become lifeless and dry formalities if there is no warmth of faith in them.<br />
......<br />
<b>Rākhī Pūrṇimā is a day of great significance. On that day you should ask for perfection, make big decisions and keep attention on high ideals.</b> Sahaja Yogis should not destroy their attention on trifle issues. Lot of work has yet to be done."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0817 Letter (Marathi) on Rakṣhābandhan and Pūrṇimā Day (0818), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today in India, we celebrate a set ... special festival. <b>It is called as Rakṣhā-bandhan. Rakṣhā means protection and bandhan means the bondage: the bondage of protection. Is a very nice, good, social custom to have this beautiful festival today.</b><br />
<b>Today is the Full Moon Day, and this day what we do is to tie a band of threads around the person whom you want to protect.</b> But it is done between brothers and sisters. The sisters tie this bondage to the wrist of the brothers, and when they do that, they are putting all their love around the wrist, that it is the day for giving all their love, everything to their brother, as a protection, as a symbol of their protection through that thread. Is a very, very simple thread they use. And uh this is, has to be tied on the left-hand side. But people tie it on the right-hand side, which is a mistake. But it has to be tied on the left-hand side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0826 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Rakṣhābandhan Day), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0037.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">"<b>So, this day is uh extremely important, in a way, for Sahaja Yogis to observe, and I'm happy that I am here, because it's very important also for America.</b><br />
Uh as I told you that, I have already talked to you how the-ee war between Alexander and Puru's was finished because of a sister's intervention.<br />
And, also, how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, whose sister was Draupadī, Viṣhṇumāyā was born as Draupadī, and how He came to save Her chastity, by rushing all the way from Dvārika.<br />
So, we can see that when we ascend in the Collective Consciousness and we have collective living, collective meeting, at the Viśhuddhi chakra, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa establish[ed] this, or He manifested uh this pure relationship of a sister.<br />
In a collective life that we have, in the Āśhram where we live, where we move about as Sahaja Yogis, if we do not have this basic principle within us, there will be a chaos, complete chaos. Once this purity of relationship is established, that apart from my wife, all the rest are my sisters or mothers, it cannot be a proper society and <b>the chaos of the social system of America is because they have no sense of pure relationships.<br />
Once you call somebody a sister, she's a sister. And once you call somebody a brother, she's [he's] a brother. It's not only that you should be born of the same parents, it's not necessary, but this is a very important principle to have a very pure society where everybody can live peacefully.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0807 Rakṣhābandhan Pūjā, Room, House of Dr. Vinod Worlikar, 17301 Maria Avenue, Cerritos (32 kms SE of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Bandhu Rakṣhitā Pavitry sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>(The one whose chastity is protected by her brother)</b></font></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>In our Sahaja Yoga, the significance of left wrist is that it is the left Viśhuddhi.</b> Left Viśhuddhi which is here. And this is the left Viśhuddhi expressed here, you know that very well.<br />
Now, left Viśhuddhi is the place where our relationship of brothers and sisters exist. When they are disturbed within us, we start getting the problem of the left Viśhuddhi.<br />
In these modern times, to talk of pure relationship seems to be quite boring for many people. But is very practical and logical. I would say it is the most scientific thing to do.<br />
For example, every brother has a special feeling for a sister, and her chastity is very dear to every brother, if he is a normal person. If he's abnormal, then forget it. But normally, a brother is very particular about the chastity of the sister, and he doesn't like anybody to, in any way, even pass a remark against the chastity of a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0826 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Rakṣhābandhan Day), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0038.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"This Viṣhṇumāyā is the one who has helped you because <b>She is the Sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa</b>, and because this is the domain of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, She came down here to help you.<br />
Now She's the Sister -- this must be understood very well. Now sisterly relation is a pure relationship."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0809 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Y.M.C.A. Holiday Hills Conference Center, 2 Lakeside Drive, Pawling, NY, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Pāvitrya Dāyinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!
Mahālakṣhmī Mahāsaraswatī Mahākālī Triguṇātmika Ādi Kuṇḍalinī sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>O Divine Mother, You are verily The one who gives chastity, the foundation of all dharmas. Salutations to You!</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0704 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Viṣhṇumāyā's Powers, Āśhram, Everbeek, Belgium</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/674368697"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font size="+0"><font color="blue"><b>Nirmalā, Kiti Varnaavi Tujhiga Stuti:</b></font></font><br />
<font size="-1"><b>Bābā Māmā (on 1990-0310): This is what the brother has written for the sister:<br />
"O Nirmalā, my sister, how much should I praise You? Because You have given the human being the experience of God."</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ErGWNRdwSBE">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Rākhī Bhajan Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>Rākhī offered to Śhrī Mātājī from America 1993-0815 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Dharma, Cabella</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>"I Am Your Rākhī Brother" (1985-0921 Seminar, Sheffield, UK)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="blue"><b>He Govinda He Gopala</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0039.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">"But Rākhī Day, My brother is here. It's nice that we can have it in a way My physical brother is here. It's very good we are having a rākhī program today in his presence. And, all of you should also understand that it's a very subtle, pure, beautiful relationship that exists between a brother and a sister."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0820 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā (1 week before Rakṣhābandhan Day), Cure that Left Viśhuddhi, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><font size="+0"><b>Nirmalā, Kiti Varnāvi Tujhiga Stuti</b></font></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Bābā Māmā (in March 1990): This is what the brother has written for the sister:
"O Nirmala, my sister, how much should I praise You? Because You have given the human being the experience of God."</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Rakshabandhan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Worshipping Śhrī Mātājī as our Guru on Guru Pūrṇimā: “ “Guru is a person who makes you meet God”: he raises the Kuṇḍalinī and makes you one with God.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/07/22" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Worshipping Śhrī Mātājī as our Guru on Guru Pūrṇimā: “ “Guru is a person who makes you meet God”: he raises the Kuṇḍalinī and makes you one with God.”" /><published>2024-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/07/2024_07_21_Guru_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/07/22"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today is the day of Guru Pūrṇimā. It is a Full Moon Day. That's why ... it is called as Pūrṇimā. The guru has to be like a Full Moon. Means completely grown, completely matured.</b><br />
There are sixteen kalās or the phases of the Moon, and when the complete Pūrṇimā comes in, the Full Moon Day, all the sixteen kalās are completed. You also know that in the Viśhuddhi chakra there are sixteen sub-plexuses. When Kṛiṣhṇa is described as Virāṭa, He's called as the Sampūrṇa, the Complete Incarnation of Viṣhṇu's aspect, because He's got the sixteen phases completely done.<br />
So today's number is sixteen. Six plus one: seven.<br />
Now we have to understand the importance of guru. Why should we have a guru when we have God? We've got Śhakti, then why should we have a guru? What is the need to have a guru?<br />
Guru means the weight, the weight. We get our weight from the magnetic forces of the gravity of the Mother Earth. So, guru means gravity: the gravity in a person.<br />
Why do we need a guru?<br />
Because to know God is easy, specially in Sahaja Yoga, to be one with Him. As soon as you get your Self-realization in Sahaja Yoga, the modern Sahaja Yoga, immediately you become entitled to give Realizations to other people.<br />
It was said that, "Guru is the person who makes you meet the Divine." But's not true. Because any self-realized person, in the Sahaja Yoga, can raise the Kuṇḍalinī and king ... can give Self-realization to others, immediately after they have touched the Sahasrāra or opened the Sahasrāra. But normally a realized Soul cannot do it. Any born realized Soul cannot do it on its own: it has to have authority of Me, as I am today.<br />
That's why <b>it was said that, "Guru is a person who makes you meet God": he raises the Kuṇḍalinī and makes you one with God.</b><br />
Because in those days when the gurus were self-realized, ...... when the gurus were self-real... -realized, they had the authority and power of raising the Kuṇḍalinī only after they had reached a very great state of evolution: complete purification, complete detachment."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0708 Guru Pūjā, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0032.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Today we have all gathered here for worshiping your Guru.<br />
As you know that the Principle of Guru resides in the Void. This is the Principle which gives you balance, which gives you the gravity.</b> The gravity that we have in the Mother Earth is expressed through your Guru Principle.<br />
The first point of gravity is that you should have a personality, a character and the temperament that people would see that you are a personality who doesn't get dissolved into worldly things. Is a personality which doesn't get ruined by the skirmishes of life. Is the personality of a guru which sits down deep into his ... into his being and is not easily disturbed or dissolved by any solvent whatsoever.<br />
<b>This is the first Principle of the Guru, is the gravity.</b><br /> 
As I told you, it is something which cannot be dissolved into anything, it settles very deep down into your personality."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0731 Guru Pūjā, The First Principle of the Guru Is the Gravity (First Thing and Foremost Thing Is that We Must Have Gravity in Temperament and Value System of a Balance and You Have to Become the Fruits of Sahaja Yoga), Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Gurū Paramātmā Pareśhu<br />
The Guru is the Supreme Spirit, God Almighty</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0">Guru Aṣhṭakaṃ</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is a day people's ... this is created by human beings and not by God, as Guru Pūrṇimā. Because as God has created days of Their advent, human beings have created days of their surrendering. So this is the day when you have to give something to the Guru, and Guru does not have to give anything to you. This is the time you have to say: 'What you are going to give? What you are going to do for your Guru?' Because so far the Guru has been giving.<br />
If you are in meditation, supposing you say, 'We'll meditate because Guru Pūrṇimā is there,' that's not the way the Guru Pūrṇimā is to be celebrated. Because if you meditate, you are taking from Me. If you try to correct yourself, you are taking from Me. If you are going to get cured, you are taking from Me.<br />
So now what can you do for Me? Is the point, you have to think about it. 'What can you do?'<br />
Now I have sent the same question to India, to find ... I asked them to find out: 'What can you do for Me?'<br />
You will say: 'Mother, what can we do? After all, what are we?' That's a way of evading the issue.<br />
But if you really want to see, <b>you can do a lot. And that is what it is that: you are My witness. You are My publicity!</b><br />
So, today you have to take some vows. And you have to say: that, 'We are going to do these things. We are going to talk about Sahaj Yog, we are going to propagate it, we are going to spread it. And what may come, we are going to surrender ourselves to Mother. Even, if She's supposing, scolds us, or says anything it is for our good. And we are not going to get confused.' And that's how you have to absolutely vow that you are going to dedicate yourself to Sahaj Yog to help others, to e... emancipate, and to create atmosphere for the completion of this universe, of this creation, for that fruitful day when we will say: that the Kingdom of God has been brought on this Earth.<br />
So today is not the day for Me to give, but for you. You have to announce."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0701 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day) (first more formal Pūjā in the West), Self-realization, Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0033.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"Uh in the most auspicious time, that is called as Kṛita Yuga, we all have assembled here to understand the ways and methods of establishing our Principle of a Master. ......<br />
<b>Kṛutan Yuga means the time when you have to do something: kṛita, 'when it was done'.<br />
So, you are the channels of that doing: doing the work of God. You are the channels of God Almighty and His Power. On one side, you have to carry the dignity, the glory, and the assumption that you are a guru, on the other side, you have to be completely surrendered to your God Almighty.</b> All your dignity, your authority comes from Him. And the third thing is: that the way He has created this Universe and you, in a mood of play, you have to see His Play. So, a kind of mood that is cheerfulness should be really bubbling through you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0704 Guru Pūjā, Establishing the Guru Principle, Guru Pūrṇimā Seminar, Day 2 (early morning), Nirmala Palace Āśhram, 99 Nightingale Lane, Balham, London SW12 8LZ, UK</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Gurūr Brahmā, Gurūr Viṣhṇu</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>he guru is Brahmā, the guru is Viṣhṇu</b></font><br />
<b>Gurūr Devo Maheśhwara</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The guru is great Lord Śhiva</b></font><br />
<b>Gurur sākṣhāt Parabrahma</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The guru is truly the Supreme Spirit.</b></font><br />
<b>Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Mā</b><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Immaculate Mother Śhrī Mātājī</b></font><br />
<b>Tasmai Śhrī Guruve namaḥ</b><br />
<font size="+0"></font><b>To you, our true guru, we bow.</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font size="+0">Guru Vandana</font></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>On the day of Guru Pūrṇimā, that in this life I have become a Guru. I had not done this type of work in any other lifetime.</b> It is the first time that I have done the work of the Guru. Maybe it is because the Mother has to be the Guru. This is a matter of the Kali Yuga. That is why the tremendous Śhakti of the Divine which must flow from the heart of a Mother, and by Her Grace and compassion the Kuṇḍalinī should be treasured and It should be taken to that top where She in Her glory, Her joy, and Her splendor be seated, and perhaps that is in My destiny. That is why in this birth this position of the Guru has been created. <b>If the Mother becomes the Guru, it is a very difficult, as a mother is very tender.</b> A male guru will beat up, hit or even scold but for a mother when she utters even one harsh word her heart bleeds and pains a lot. When she sees that her children have come through such difficulties, and how she has to gather them with love and care and take them across, that her responsibility grows so much that her entire character changes. <b>But from ancient times it has been known that no one is greater than the mother as a guru. Only make such a one your guru who is greater than you, the one who is greater than you is God.</b><br />
It was said about Guru Rāmadās Swāmī that make only such a person your guru who himself is Paras [touchstone], and who just by touching others does not make them into gold but makes them elixir [touchstone]. He makes others like himself.<br />
That is how the form of the mother is. A mother lives for her children. Lives in the glory of her children.<br />
That is why perhaps in this lifetime the Divine wanted this that this love and this knowledge should come through a Mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0715 Guru Pūjā (Hindi) (Guru Pūrṇimā), Sahaja Yoga is a New Discovery, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0034.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"Today you have arranged this worship of your Guru, that is your Mother. Perhaps you are very unique people that have a Guru who is a Mother.<br />
<b>Why this Pūjā is arranged? One has to know that it is very important for every disciple to worship the guru.</b> But the guru has to be a real guru, not a one who is just exploiting the disciples and who is not authorized by God."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0727 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day), Statutes of the Lord (You Do Not Harm Anyone, The Testimony of the Truth, Develop Detachment, Lead a Moral Life) and Promise that You Will Be a Guru Worthy of Your Mother (Today I Authorize You to Be the Gurus and You Have a Very Supreme Guru), Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Guru hamari Ādi Śhakt, Karale he man. in.ki bhakti, In. ke hi guna gaye oh ...<br />
<b>My Guru is the Ādi Śhakti, O my heart, please do Her Bhakti, Please sing Her praises only ...</b><br />
He man Guru Sharan. me rahio, rahio , He man Ma ki Sharan. Me rahio rahio<br />
<b>O my heart, please stay under the Guru’s Protection, O my heart, please stay under the Mother’s Protection</b><br />
Har. Pal. Nir.mala Nir.mala kahio, He man Guru Sharan. me rahio, rahio ...<br />
<b>Please say, 'Nirmalā Nirmalā,' every moment, O my heart, please stay under the Guru’s Protection</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/cMewtBZWZlM">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0731 Guru Pūjā, The First Principle of the Guru Is the Gravity (First Thing and Foremost Thing Is that We Must Have Gravity in Temperament and Value System of a Balance and You Have to Become the Fruits of Sahaja Yoga), Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/video/775044004"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha Atharva Śhīrṣha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Paramatma Pareshu</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Stuti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Ek Jagi trata</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Totz Mhanavi</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru bin Kaun</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Oṃkār Swarūpa (1991-0406 Bhavasāgara Pūjā, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guruon kī Guru</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Guru Mauli</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namanat Karo (I bow to Lotus Feet of my Guru)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/KEdz1c-gM_4?list=PL407136734B2B056D">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī</b> (2003-0713 Guru Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/Rhqs-9UTpPw?list=PL407136734B2B056D">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Three Mahāmantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/TBxa1OKh4yw?list=PL407136734B2B056D">video</a> 
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0035.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>On this Guru Pūrṇimā I bless all of you and all those who are realized, are very special people, and I would say to them that just as you have got, give to others. You too have to bring them around. Might be that they may get annoyed with you, hit you, beat you, they may not remain, but this is nothing. I have borne much more than this. That is why with joy and not arguments; they may not believe in you, doesn't matter. Leave them. They may argue, just leave them. The ones who believe in you give them. This is what you have to give and this is all you can give that My love may reach each corner of the world and each house may be lit with it.<br />
May God bless you.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0715 Guru Pūjā (Hindi) (Guru Pūrṇimā), Sahaja Yoga is a New Discovery, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Guru Charnan. ki lagi lagan. hai</b><br />
Now we have got the Divine attachment to the Lotus Feet of our Guru<br />
<b>Tav. Charanan. me utara swarg. hai</b><br />
All the Heavens have come down at Your Lotus Feet<br />
<b>Parmeshwari. hai mangal. kari</b><br />
Goddess is giving the welfare to Her devotees<br />
<b>Khoye sadhak. par. Utari</b><br />
She gives Realization to those who are lost</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/hMK6gaaQ1hU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Guru Purnima" /><category term="orange @ Guru Puja" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Mother’s Day</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/12" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Mother’s Day" /><published>2024-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/2024_05_10_Mother&apos;s_Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/12"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"[Mother's is] a very special institution ... ... especially in this country [Italy], they have such respect for their mothers.<br />
<b>Mother is the Source of Love.</b><br /> 
In the Qur'ān they asked Muhammad Sāhab, Whom should we bow after Allah?" So He said, "To Mother" -- "To the Mother." Then again they asked Him, He said: "Only the Mother." Again they asked Him, He said: "Only the Mother."<br />
I'm sure He must have said about the Divine Mother, because worldly mothers may not be complete mothers, perhaps. They are a[n] embodied, or, we can say, examples of Mother's Love, of the Divine Mother's Love, but they are human.<br />
So they can be conditioned, influenced or could be egoistical, especially if they are living in a particular country for a long time and have no idea of Divine Love.<br />
In Divine Love there is no expectations, it just flows, it doesn't think how to judge a person or what to do for a person, it just flows."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0513 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother's Day), Living Room, Palazzo Doria, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0026.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed"><b>Thank You</b> for descending from Your heavenly abode, Mātā Dvīpa, to bring light into the darkness of Kali Yuga.<br /> 
<b>Thank You</b>, Śhrī Mātājī, again and again.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for delivering Sahaja Yoga to a confused and self-destructive humanity.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing the meaning of creation and evolution to us.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing the actual existence of God to us.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for giving divine meaning to human existence.<br />
<b>Thank You</b> for revealing the reflection of the Viśhwarūpa within the human body to us.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b> The 108 Thank Yous offered to Śhrī Mātājī on 1996-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā in Cabella</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/wP_R9tpOVag">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today is ... I like the day when it is the Mother's, I should say, Mother's Day also. Because I think only a Mother can work it out that way. One has to have a lot of patience with people.<br />
......<br />
But mother's position is different. She'll go on struggling and fighting for her child. She'll fight it out to the last to see that the child gets all the benefits and this patience and this love and this forgiveness is innately built in in a mother, because her attitude is very different. Not any achievement, not any big name or what you call a sort of an award or anything. It is just she does it because she is a mother. And that is what is the sign of any mother, if she is a real mother, at least for her own children, she will go all out, she will work out everything for day in day out and to save the child from disaster. But Sahaja Yoga is a much bigger family and for that you really had to be worked out through the Mother's Principle. You cannot take any other principle.<br />
......<br />
So, in your own way, when you are doing Sahaja Yoga, there also you have to be a mother. <b>More mother's quality than the father's quality, that there's no ambition, there's no competition, there's no jealousies, nothing.</b> Just you want your children to come up and to grow into their spirituality. If that is the only attitude we have then you'll be amazed how satisfied you'll feel, because this is a very, very joy-giving thing, to see people growing in spirituality. Not only talking about it, not only reading about it, but actually happening, actualizing within yourself. So this quality is very helpful and that really helps every Sahaja Yogi to be patient, to be kind, to be humble."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Blessing of the Divine Pours Only if the Sahasrāra is Open (Meditation Is the Only Way You Can Enrich Yourself with the Beauty of Reality), Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0027.png" /></div>

<p style="color:MediumVioletRed; text-align:center;">
May I this day be what You'd have me be.<br />
May I this day say what You'd have me say.<br />
May I this day be part and parcel of the whole<br />
And may my thoughts be of a realized soul.<br />
May I this day have love for all mankind.<br />
Mother, be in my heart and in my mind.<br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now, [the] Principle of Mother is in every, every Scripture, has to be there. Now the Mother's character is that She is the One Who is the Womb, She is the One Who is the Mother Earth and She is the One Who nourishes you. She's ... She nourishes us, you know that. And this feminine thing in a one ma... in every human being resides as this Kuṇḍalinī, as you have seen. And when She rises, She gives you this new awareness which becomes compassion, which is flowing, which becomes soothing, nourishing Energy of Love. And that's what today people are saying feminist go this thing and all that. That's again a pendulum -- a man becoming a woman, woman becoming man -- all these problem you have had because of this. But when you move spirally upward, then where do you move? You move, become a personality full of compassion, of love, of universal understanding, through Collective Consciousness. And then you rise up to a position where you become universally conscious. So that is what should happen to you. And, if that happens, then we should say that your motherly qualities within you have risen. And that's what we have so far neglected. You do not become a woman but you become motherly. First the Father, then the Son, and now the Mother! All right?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1001 Interview with Barbara Schuler for the Program `Discovery' of Kazu Radio Station in Monterey, Seminar, Day 1, Session 3, Part 1, Kennolyn Campgrounds, 8400 Glen Haven Road, Soquel (10 kms ENE of Santa Cruz), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0028.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="MediumVioletRed">The Mother is everything — She is our consolation in sorrow, our hope in misery and our strength in weakness.<br />
She is the source of love, mercy, sympathy, and forgiveness. And this Earth is the Mother of the trees and flowers.<br />
It produces them, nurses them, and weans them.<br />
The trees and flowers become kind mothers of their great fruits and seeds.<br />
And the Mother, the prototype of all existence, is the Eternal<br />
Spirit, full of beauty and love. </font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>('Broken Wings' by Kahlil Gibran)</b></font>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0510 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Mother's Day), On Creativity, Entertainment Program, Living Room, Nirmala House, Sant'Angelo Romano (7 kms N of Guidonia), Lazio, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/127372212"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>She's Got the Whole World in Her Hands</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mother I Adore You</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/LsWaC7NktHA">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Isi Liye Mātājī Hamako</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Matajila</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/ybCnMcQi2ZQ">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namostute</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Mother&apos;s Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day: “Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth, all talk about Divinity was a myth.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/05" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Sahasrāra Day: “Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth, all talk about Divinity was a myth.”" /><published>2024-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/2024_05_05_Sahasrara_Puja</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/05/05"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So this Sahasrāra Day or, we can say, on the day the Sahasrāra was opened out, is a very important one, it's very subtle.</b> We just know about the Kuṇḍalinī, that She's coiled up in three and a half, and She's lying in the triangular bone known as sacrum. But we don't know what She works, how She works, what happens to us. She rises in six centers and breaks the seventh ... I should say She breaks the sixth center, because Gaṇeśha's center doesn't play any role. <b>So when She breaks the sixth center, which is the Sahasrāra, then She connects you to the All-pervading Power of Divine Love.</b><br />
<b>But what is this Divine Love? What does this do? It is the Energy of the Mother. We can say it is the Energy of Ādi Śhakti, which is all over, works through vibrations.</b> But what are these vibrations? It's a very subtle energy that starts flowing through your Sahasrāra. All the thousand petals of the Sahasrāra get slowly enlightened and it starts flowing throughout your body, throughout your hands, feet, throughout your body. And the more you are ... I mean your attention is, on the Sahasrāra, the more it works faster."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0506 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0021.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating the Sahasrāra Day.</b><br />
Perhaps we have not realized what a day it must have been. <b>Without opening the Sahasrāra, God Itself was a myth, religion itself was a myth, all talk about Divinity was a myth.</b> People believed in it but it was just a belief. And the science, as it was put forward, was about to obliterate all the value system, all the proof of God Almighty."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrar. Dwari<br />
Mukhi Nām. Gheta<br />
Nirmala Hi Tari <br />
Dhyan. Te Rangerle Sahasrār. Dwari </b></font><br />
O Mother we are enjoying our meditation in Sahasrāra<br />
Whenever we take Your name, You are always there to help us<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Charani Tujhya Baisat. Mate, Man. Te Nivale</b><br />
Sushumnachya Marge,<br />
Swarupachya Tiri</font><br />
When we are at Your Lotus Feet our attention is settled,<br />
we are in the path of Sushumna and very close to Your Divine form.<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U0w8QSa7zNY&amp;ab_channel=SahajBhajans">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today, <b>it's a great day for all of us, the seekers, that the last work of the Divine, of opening the last center in the Great Primordial Being, was done on the fifth of May nineteen seventy [1970].<br />
It is the greatest event of all the spiritual happenings of the Universe.</b> It was done with very great care and great adjustments.<br />
It is not in the limits of human understanding, how things are worked in the Heavens.<br />
It is your fortune and God's Love that has worked out this wondrous miracle.<br />
Without this happening, there could not have been a possibility to give [en] masse Realization to people. One could have done it for one or two persons here and there, but to give such a [en] masse awakening could not have been possible.<br />
As you know, in the Sahasrāra there are the Seats of the seven main chakras. There are one thousand nāḍīs or, as they call it, flames, and they all have each Sixteen Thousand Powers. Every nāḍī deals with a particular type of a person, and, with the permutations and combinations of all these nāḍīs, human beings are looked after.<br />
As soon as Sahasrāra was opened, the whole atmosphere was filled with tremendous Chaitanya."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Opening the Primordial Sahasrāra, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), Île-de-France, France</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0022.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Of course, Sahasrāra is a day which is very important, which makes a big history in the spirituality, uh and also in the evolutionary process."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0730 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Divine Laws, after the Evening Program, the day before Guru Pūjā, Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tu Ādi Śhakti, Sahasrar viraji </b><br />
You are Śhrī Ādi Śhakti seated on the Cosmic Sahasrāra<br />
<b>Chaitanya lutati, Saty.yuga jagati</b><br />
Showering Divine Vibrations and heralding the beginning of Satya Yuga<br />
<b>Viśhwa kī Janani, Tu Mahādevī</b><br />
You are the Mother of the universe and the Great Goddess<br />
<b>Tere Putra banne ki Patrata de Mā</b><br />
Mother please grant us all the qualities by which we can be Your children in reality.<br />
<b>He Nirmalā Mā, He Nirmalā Mā<br />
Tera pyar. moksha ka Anand. hai Mā</b><br />
O Divine Mother, Your unbounded love is the bliss of liberation</font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/v7T1xpKkYFU">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>When we enter into the Realm of Sahasrāra, then only we have [a] right to do the Sahasrāra Pūjā.</b> Before this nobody talked about Sahasrāra, nobody did any Pūjā to Sahasrār. This is your privilege that you are in the Realm of Sahasrāra and that you can do this Pūjā, perform it, is your right, you are chosen for this. It's a very privileged place for you to enter into the Sahasrāra of the Virāṭ, to reside in the brain as cells of that Sahasrāra.<br />
<b>Let us see what is the quality of the cells of Sahasrāra. These are specially created cells through the working of the Swādhiṣhṭhāna. Passing through all the chakras, when they arrive at Sahasrāra they are equipped to handle the brain's activity without getting involved into other elements in the body.<br />
In the same way, the Sahaja Yogis are not to be involved in the other cells, human beings, of the body of this Universe.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, State of Absolute (Nirānanda Absolute Joy, Absolute Love, Absolute Compassion, Absolute Power), Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"To keep the Sahasrāra open is, in a way, very easy, as well as difficult. As you have known in Devī Māhātmyam that ``at Sahasrārare Mahāmāyā comes." She's a Mahāmāyā: not easy to recognize Her, not easy to know Her. She lives just like you. She moves just like you. And you can never make out Her real nature. She is in the form of Mahāmāyā.<br />
......<br />
<b>So, in Sahasrāra Pūjā, actually, you have to recognize your own divinity, that you are divine, by experiencing your divinity. How do you experience your divinity? That you give Realization to others.</b><br /> 
It's a great experience to give Realization to others. Not only that you give Realization but you can tell about their chakras, you know what's wrong with them. You are quite confident."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Recognize the Mahāmāyā and Your Own Divinity through Your Heart, Sports Stadium, Island of Ischia (1 hour from Naples), Campania, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So My own effort was to take you into that beautiful arena of Sahaja, where you will be absolutely one with your Self, one with the nature, one with the ... all the people who are around you, with your own country and countries. Everywhere, in the whole atmosphere, as they say, the whole Brahmāṇḍa [universe] becomes part and parcel of you, and you are not separated from that.</b> Then, they ... we can say the echoes -- they call nināda -- the echoes of your being, of your life can be easily seen, not in material advancement or in any other kind of a thing, but in the spiritual area which is the highest. Or everywhere, in every country, there have been people of that quality, and, till today, they are all remembered. In the same way, <b>you all will be representing a very great knowledge about reality: in your life, in your creation or in your working. In every way you can do it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0507 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Sahaja Avasthā (Sahaja State), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0023.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Now, the Will of God, you are feeling it on your fingertips. After Realization, now, you have discovered the Absolute Science, which is the Will of God, which is an Absolute Science."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0510 Sahasrāra Pūjā, The Will of God, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Tuzhya Krupe Nid.Rit. Shakti Urdhvamukhe Yei</b></font><br />
The energy which is awakened with your blessings start to rise<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Sat. Chakre Tichya Sparshe Jagrut. Ti Hoi</b></font><br />
As it touches the seven chakras, they become enlightened<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Adnyasthani Yeta Mate</b></font><br />
When it reaches the Āgñyā chakra<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ka Ga Visawa<br />
Ughad. Sahastrār. Mate</b></font><br />
O Mother, please open the Sahasrara!<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> <font color="DarkRed"><b>Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks. Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
Nothing ever had a meaning nor a life, everyone so dry and so weak, then You came, O Mother, so caring, so sweet. You taught Your children even to walk and to speak. We thank You, O Mother, for bringing us up, opening the doors of Heaven for all of us.<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations to the Queen of the Seven Peaks. Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.<br />
We were the clay but You all the Supreme Creator.<br />
......<br />
Salutations to the Queen of Sahasrāra, salutations again and again to the Queen of the Seven Peaks. Today, on this great, great day, we see the Universe at Your Feet.</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0508 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Mahāmāyā Swarūpa, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>O Queen of universe</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/1Y2Z3tNAs0I">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahaja Yoga teaches how to love and adore the human body as the Temple of God Almighty.</b><br />
Sahaja Yoga is the working of the Unconscious and there are some very stupid people who think they can cheat God. In return they are cheated by Sahaja Yoga, and to their surprise, find themselves outwitted. The play of Sahaja Yoga can be very mischievous, and creates many miraculous happenings as well as a great deal of uproarious humor."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Adi Shakti, Chapter 8: Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Sahaja Yoga was known to Me all along.</b> It is a unique knowledge with which I was born. It was not so easy to reveal it and I wanted to find out how to reveal it.<br />
First of all I thought that the seventh chakra must be opened, which I did, on 05th May 1970. It is a secret in a way. Formerly, the Brahmachaitanya was avyakta. It was not manifested. It was not expressed by itself, and so the people who managed to reach Brahmachaitanya somehow, by attaining `realization', said -- ``it was nirākār kā guṇa" ``you are like a drop that gets dissolved in the ocean."<br />
No one could say, explain or tell people anything more about it. The Great Incarnations also who came out of this Great Ocean of Brahmachaitanya, tried their best to share it with the best available followers -- which were very few -- and introduce them to this Brahmachaitanya. But because the Brahmachaitanya was not in avyakta form, these Incarnations got dissolved in it.<br />
......<br />
<b>Now I have come as the Incarnation of the Brahmachaitanya as a whole.</b> The sea of the Nirākār has now become a big cloud [Sākār]. It has taken a form. Those who came before were all a part and parcel of it. Now the whole has come. This cloud has rain water. The rain water is nourishing the minds of the people. Gradually they are brought to a level were their Kuṇḍalinīs have risen. They have got their Realization and now gradually they are feeling everything on their senses, their fingertips. This is the reason why nobody has talked about vibrations so clearly. They managed to talk about Chaitanya Laharī. This was so because of its avyakta [unmanifest] form. It was only a state. A state to be enjoyed, only in that state with no manifestation in the gross."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0227 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi and Hindi), From Pieces of Conversation with Dr. Talwar and other Sahaja Yogis Leaders, after the Śhivarātri Pūjā, Juhu, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0024.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Amhi Matajinchya Char.nasi Alo</b></font><br />
As we have come to the Feet of Mother<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Chaitanya Sange Amrutat. Nhalo</b></font><br />
We have beenbathed in the Nectar of Chaitanya<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Janiv. Ti Jiva Kadhi Nahi Zhali</b></font><br />
Such recognition has never before happened to the Spirit<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shakti Kundalini Sharir. Vyapili</b></font><br />
And as we come to Your Feet the power of Kundalini drenches us completely<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Char.nasi Yeta Jagrutis. Alo</b></font><br />
By coming to Your Lotus Feet we got our realization.<br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"When your Mother is the Deity of Sahasrāra, the only way to be able to keep the Sahasrāra open has to be complete surrendering."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0504 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirvikalpa, the day before Sahasrāra Pūjā, Laxenburg Castle, Vienna, Austria</b></font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0505 Sahasrāra Pūjā, Recognize the Mahāmāyā and Your Own Divinity through Your Heart, Sports Stadium, Island of Ischia (1 hour from Naples), Campania, Italy</b></font>
<p><a href=""> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Namami Śhrī Gaṇarāj Dayal</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jago Savera Aya Hai, Mātā Ne Jagaya Ha</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/lUNkxcIAEs4">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tujhya Pūjāni</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b> Anyatha Sharnam Nāsti</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mā He Sahasrār Swāminī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/qWKprw2fe58">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Mavena Nayani Ananda</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vandan Karuya Matajila</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0025.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Ātā Viśhwātmakeṃ deveṃ yeṇe vāgyajñeṃ toṣhāveṃ. Toṣho..."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: Now it says that all of you, who are one in your Spirit -- this all description of Sahaja Yoga today, is the future, the present that you will get it, at this time what is going to happen. It is so beautifully shown, you'll be surprised, that you all will become one in the universe. The Spirit of the Universe will be satisfied with the Yagñyas they are going to do, with the fire ceremonies you are going to do. How it is appropriated! He said it three hundred years back.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Toṣhoniṃ maja jñāve pasāyadāna heṃ."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: And then you will, should give us the milk of your blessings by getting the complete satisfaction from us.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Jeṃ khaḷāṃchī vyaṃkaṭī sāṃḍo."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: That time all the horrible evil people will be ruined and their ... their plans will be spoiled.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Tayā satkarmī-ratī vāḍho."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: And people will take to righteousness. This is the description [unclear] Gupta</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Bhūtaṃ paraspare paḍo maitra jīvācheṃ."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: At that time there will be a tremendous friendship of the Spirit among people.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Duritāṃche timira jāvo."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: Those who are in ignorance will get light.</font><br />
<br />
<font size="+0"><b>Sahaja Yogi: "Viśhwa Swadharma Sūryeṃ pāho."</b></font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: The whole universe will see the light, the Sun of One Universal Religion.</font><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Pasāyadān</b></font><br />
<font size="+0">'O' God, The entire Cosmos Divine , Be pleased with this pious word offering of mine,<br />
Grant me in goodwill benign | Your Benevolent Grace Divine<br />
(Gyāneśhwarī is considered to be a masterpiece in Marathi literature. At the end of which Gyāneśhwar asks for the blessings of the Almighty through this Pasāyadān)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="orange @ Sahasrara Puja" /><category term="maroon @ Sahasrara Day" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Hanumān Jayanti: “We shall say that the right side is the source of power and the left of bhakti. Śhrī Hanumāna had in Him this harmony of bhakti and śhakti.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/22" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Hanumān Jayanti: “We shall say that the right side is the source of power and the left of bhakti. Śhrī Hanumāna had in Him this harmony of bhakti and śhakti.”" /><published>2024-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_22_Shri_Hanuman_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/22"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Today we have come here to do Hanumāna's Pūjā. 

Śhrī Hanumāna is a great character in our being and He runs all the way from Swādhiṣhṭhāna to your brain and He supplies all the necessary guidance we need in our futuristic planning or in our mental activities. He gives us guidance and protection.<br />
......<br />
It is very surprising how a Deity like Śhrī Hanumāna, who is an eternal child, because He was like a monkey. His head was that of a monkey, if not of an elephant.<br />
So He was an eternal child and He was the one who was used to run the right side of human beings. He was told that, ``You must control the Sun," to begin with He has to control the Sun, that the Sun in the people, if there is too much Sun then He must try to control it and make it cooler or smoother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā, Electromagnetic Force, Schloss Schwetzingen, Schloß Mittelbau, Schwetzingen, Baden-Württemberg, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0017.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"It is such a joy today, and the whole atmosphere seems to be bubbling with it, as if the angels are singing. And the speciality of Hanumāna was that He was an angel. Angels are born like angels. They are angels, and they are not human beings. They're born with the angelic qualities. But now, you all have become angels from the human beings. It's a very great achievement of Sahaja Yoga. The qualities that are born with the angels are seen from their very childhood."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Aarakta dekhile dola</b></font><br />
You saw with your eyes (the Sun) as red as blood,<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Grasile Surya-Mandala</b></font><br />
and You placed in your mouth the entire domain of the Sun<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Vadhata vadhata vadhe<br />
Bhedile shunya-mandala</b></font><br />
You who are forever increasing in size from the minutest dot;<br />
You can pierce even the domain of the absolute.<br />
<font size="-1"><b>Shri Māruti stotra<br />
(Verses in praise of Śhrī Hanumān by Rāmadāsa)</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are celebrating Hanumāna's Jayanti</b> [birthday].<br />
What to say about Hanumāna? The more powerful and wise, He was equally devoted and dedicated.<br />
Generally such a powerful person becomes right-sided and considers himself so high that he would not listen to anyone else.<br />
But <b>Hanumāna is a special Deity, a typical Deity full of qualities. There was a perfect balance between his devotion and power</b>. How could he achieve this balance is a thing to be understood. In Sahaja Yoga, when we are enlightened, we get many powers. Then we have to keep balance. We love others and with the power of the love, we keep on doing our duties.<br />
Śhrī Hanumāna was very powerful. He had many Divine Powers in Him Navadhā, that is Garima, Laghima, etc. He could be as big as he wanted to be and as small as an atom. He had achieved all these powers."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0018.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>So in the left side we have gaṇas, on the right side we have angels. And translated in Sanskrit language or in any Indian language as Devadūt -- means they are the Ambassadors of Gods.<br /> 
So now you are the same, you are all angels now.</b> Only thing you are not aware that you are angels while they were aware from their childhood. If you know that you are angels, all your qualities will start shining through, and you'll be amazed that the quality of standing by the Truth at any cost is so easily managed for you, because you have been given the right, you have been given the special blessings, the special protection from the Divine that if you stand for the right, and if you stand for the righteous, and if you stand for the Truth, all kinds of help to protect you will be given."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Devadūta sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b><br />
(The messenger of God, You are the archangel, Gabriel)</font><br />  
<font size="+0">Jay Hanumān!</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Even His sevaka [most obedient worshiper] Śhrī Hanumāna was an ideal disciple to be emulated by all the Sahaja Yogis. He was of Great Powers. He is an innocent personality of a very high order, always keen to perform the task set out for Him by Śhrī Rāma. Later on also He appeared during the Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and used to ride on the top of the chariot of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
<b>He is known as Chirañjīv, an eternal being, one of the seven eternal personalities. He also comes and helps and performs all the tasks assigned to Him. He is always present in all My Pūjās</b> and on one occasion He had been visible in vibratory form, in one of the Photographs taken in Bombay [Mumbai]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0405 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0019.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"We say that Sahaja Yoga is the work of Divine Love. It's right, whether we know it or not, Its power is innate. It is Divine Power. <b>When a human being bows before someone and regards him higher, it is the expression of that Divine Power.</b> But when a person is respectful to his guru then he gets blessed with the grace and power of the guru.<br /> 
So <b>the devotion and the power (bhakti aur śhakti) are not different things. It is one. We shall say that the right side is the source of power and the left of bhakti. Śhrī Hanumāna had in Him this harmony of bhakti and śhakti</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Ham Hanumate Rudr'atmakaya Hum Phat</b></font><br />
<b>Śhrī Hanumān, whose soul is Śhrī Śhiva Himself</b>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha and Śhrī Hanumāna are the Incarnations of this Divine Wisdom.</b> Śhrī Hanumāna was very powerful and fast and Śhrī Gaṇeśha is cool-natured. But when required, both are very big hitters. They remain with you every moment. Whenever anyone troubles you, your protectors are there. Often you see that security moves with the ministers and VIPs. The security of Sahaja Yogis also moves with them; that is, the security of gaṇas. Gaṇas have many things to do. Gaṇapati -- <b>Śhrī Gaṇeśha keeps them informed about you as to where is the problem, from where you are getting attacked and troubled. You do not know that if anybody wants to attack you secretly, even then these God's gaṇas stand by you. When Śhrī Gaṇapati informs about it, Śhrī Hanumāna sets them right</b>. So Sahaja Yogis have no need to be frightened. No need at all to be frightened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So that is very important, especially <b>in the West where it's being really dangerously destroyed, the idea of auspiciousness and of holiness. So that is the power of any angel and that has to be fully established within us, and then on that power will work out, which gives you discretion, which gives you egolessness.</b><br />
I hope today both these things will work out within us in such a manner that we really become absolutely self-confident realized Souls whom I call as angels of modern times."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0020.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"I hope today you have understood the subtle side of your being which is there, which is exhibiting, which I can see clearly and that you will, all of you will, <b>in your meditation become aware of what you have within yourself. That's the greatest thing that will please the Divine, and Divine will look after you fully. With the same confidence as the angels like Hanumāna you have to go further and work it out.<br />
May God bless you all.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), Kent, UK</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="blue"> You are always at the Feet of Śhrī Mātājī.<br /> 
You worship the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī.<br />
You perform miracles to convince the Sahaja yogis that Śhrī Mātājī made them all angels.<br />
You are the most effective instrument for Śhrī Ādi Śhakti because You are nothing but obedience, humility and dynamism.<br />
You make all the Sahaja Yogis join Your company to do our Holy Mother's work and transform the whole world. </font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (St. George's Day), You Are All Angels, Cliftonville, Margate (123 kms ESE of London), UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/65376957"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Hanumāna Chalisa</b> (1990-0831 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Hanumāna Chalisa translation in English</b> (1989-0423 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā)</font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Hanumān Stuti (Anjanichya Suta)</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Bhar de itni bhakti Ma</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Nām Gheta mukhi raghavache</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>He Mā de bhakti ka dān</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Hanumana Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Mahāvīr Jayanti: “In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/20" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Mahāvīr Jayanti: “In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George”" /><published>2024-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_20_Shri_Mahavira_Jayanti</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/20"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we are going to celebrate the birthday of Mahāvīra.<br />
Mahāvīra is the Incarnation of Bhairavanāth, or you call Him as Saint Michael.</b> Now these two Saints as you know one as the Gabriel, Hanumāna, and another is Saint Michael. One is placed on the Piṅgalā nāḍī and another one, Saint Michael, on the Iḍā nāḍī.<br />
So, Mahāvīra had to go through lots of search. Of course He was a[n] angel, but came as human being and He had to find out the thing of the left side, and how the left side acts. It's a very complicated thing, left side, is much more complicated than right side. On the left side we have also seven nāḍīs, and these seven nāḍīs are placed one after another. They are described in books and given different names to them. Now these seven nāḍīs that are on the left side, as you know, they cater to our past. Say for example, every moment becomes a past. Every present becomes a past. Then we have past of this lifetime, and also we have past of our previous lives. Then all the past is built in within us since our creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0014.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue">"Now, Mahāvīra also was one of Them, who ... who was born again and again, and He was Mārkaṇḍeya, and He was Kabīra.<br />
The way Kabīra lashes people, you can see that He is tremendous! <b>He is like Bhairava!</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The ascetic life of Mahāvīra was of a very, very extreme nature. He was the one who was born in a ... uh ... clan of warriors, Kṣhatriyas. And then He was also married, also He had a daughter. And then He decided, because He knew He had to do the work of the Divine, He decided to take a saṃnyāsa. So He took uh the permission of His brother because His parents were dead. He was a king, so He gave up all His uh material wealth, everything and He beg ... became a complete saṃnyāsī. And the He left His family, His left His ... house, everything behind and went alone with a little bowl for begging alms. And there people who joined Him were very few, and He asked them that, "You have to also become ascetics," Munis.<br />
He was a Reincarnation of Saint Michael and He resides on the left side, on the Iḍā nāḍī. And He looks after the whole of it, right from Mūlādhāra onwards up to the Sahasrāra. So Saint Michael was born as Mahāvīra, meaning The Greatest Warrior. But when He was born, the whole place got lot of uh prosperity, that's why <b>He was called as Vardhamān, to begin with.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>After they get their Realization, that He called as Kevalagyān: only the knowledge, only knowledge, means Pure Knowledge.</b> They will develop some Samyak Darśhan, means Integrated Personality and all the Collective Consciousness. He talked of all, all these things.<br /> 
But as He belonged to the left side, He has described Hell very clearly. Fundamentally, basically there are Fourteen Hells according to Him. And is horrible to read all that, what He has described about Hell. Because He wanted to tell people that, 'If you do all these wrong things, you'll go to Hell.'<br /> 
And He talked about, not about Form, Formly God, but Formless God, because He didn't want people to again start ritualism but get to right ... right to the position where they could get their Self-realization to cleanse themself.<br />
So you can imagine: how difficult, in those days at Mahāvīra, was even to be one of the candidates for Self-realization. It's frightening for you! <b>That's why I never had this uh Pūjā. Because to do all these things, first of all, and to become absolutely pure, then only He would give Realization.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0616 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Touch Your Depth and Complete Kevalagyān (There Is Hell and You Must Learn to Have Self-discipline), Ca'n Bosc (House of the Woods) (1 hour North of Barcelona), Spain</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0015.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Vardhamāna sākṣhāt<br />
Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namah!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily the one who makes us progress and evolve.<br /> 
Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That's why, <b>I think, this Mahāvīra Jayanti is a very great thing for us to observe.</b><br />
Now, why was He called Mahāvīra? Because only a person like Him -- Vir means a person who is brave, who is chivalrous -- because only He could do this, so only He could enter into the being fully and could kill or, you can say, destroy those horrible rākṣhasas, devils, all these negative things that come to us.<br />
Now, as you know, we use left side very much for so many negativity that is torturing us, but if there is no help, say, from Mahāvīra, we cannot do it. You call the name of Mahāvīra -- you could call Him Saint Michael, you can call Him by any name, but Mahāvīra because He was a human being. All this works out because of Him and He's such a great identity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Even though Saraswatī has created all the Swaras, so what! <b>But the emotions it contains, the bhakti it contains it is due to the blessings of Mahāvīr.</b> Mahāvīr has really worked hard for this because he scared people that if you go to the wrong way, you go to hell, and on taking this correct way you will be overwhelmed and you all are actually witnessing it. Like this <b>we all should increase our bhakti and growing bhakti in the work of Mahāvīr. I am happy that on this day of Mahāvīr Jayanti you all are doing Mahāvīr's work</b> ......<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we recognize Lord Mahāvīra as the Incarnation of Śhrī Bhairavnāth. He also incarnated as Imam Husayn. Saint Michael is the same who is also called Saint George [the Guardian angel of London]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0404 Śhrī Mahāvīra Jayanti Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0016.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="blue"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Mahāvīra sākṣhāt<br />
Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namah!</b><br />
O Divine Mother, You are verily Śhrī Mahāvīra! Salutations to You!</font><br />
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0328 Śhrī Mahāvīra Pūjā, Left Side and Soul, Gidgegannup, Darling Ranges (45 kms NE of Perth), WA, Australia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/76399695"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>21 names of Śhrī Bhairava recited during Mahāvīra Pūjā in Perth in 1991</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Tuz. Vina</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jarī Asel Anta</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Mahavira Jayanti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Śhrī Rāma Navamī: “God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal. We don’t leave our dharma, Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, even if we have lot of difficulties.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Śhrī Rāma Navamī: “God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal. We don’t leave our dharma, Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, even if we have lot of difficulties.”" /><published>2024-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_17_Day_9_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/17"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We have gathered here on the occasion of Rām Navamī.</b> Everybody has said, "Mother please tell us about Śhrī Rām."<br />
You know that Śhrī Rāma has a very important place on our chakra, He is situated on our right Heart. Śhrī Rāma has taken the place of father, hence if there is lack in the responsibility or love from father this chakra is caught.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we too understand that Śhrī Rāma and all other Deities have taken the form to fulfill Their divine work, in all Śhrī Rāma had a special task. As it was said by Socrates that the Benevolent King has to come the same way Śhrī Rāma had come on this Earth as benevolent king, He came in the form of human being, He even forgot that He was Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, forgot about Him but for all world He was Puruṣhottama Rāma.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga we need to know when we pray any Deity, we have imbibed the specialties and qualities of the particular Deity within us, Śhrī Rāma had many qualities.<br />
You all know his childhood life and you have already heard about his qualities, he was Puruṣhottama he had another quality that in his ruling, he did not care for his wife or children's in front of his subjects view."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0010.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo">"Śhrī Rāma was born at midnight so let's have Pūjā late. Śhrī Rāma Pūjā is not a specially long one. As He is in a human form He is humanity within us by which we understand our intellect and our thoughts get changed. Śhrī Rāma is that through Him we can change our thoughts. Our nature can change because He is our ideal.<br />
After achieving His ideals, we reach another because He was human ideal.<br />
<b>It is great that God came to this world in a human form to became our ideal. He has gone through all the hardships to show us strength to keep dharma. That is Viśhwa Dharma and the State of Yoga.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"Śhrī Rāma Himself was born on the right side. Great example for all of you is Śhrī Rām who was on the right side, who works the right side. When He was born and He was a child ... <b>He is a Sūryavaṃśhi, He is the son of Sūrya, I mean, Sūrya's everything comes from the Sun to Him.</b> When He was born and was a little child, He asked His mother that, ``I would like have uh like to have the Moon." The [He] started crying, and nobody knew how to satisfy. He said, ``I want to have the Moon." They gave Him any toys, He threw away. Said, ``What a child it is‽ Funny thing! He wants to have the Moon, now how to get Him the moon?" They did not know how to solve the problem. He said, ``Somehow you get Me the Moon. I don't want to eat or anything, I want to have the Moon." Here the Moon represents the Ātmā, the cooling [smiling:] capacity. He asked for the Moon.<br />
You are all on the right side, so ask for the Moon. Ask for the Spirit.<br />
And they didn't know how to satisfy this Śhrī Rāma, who was the [laughing:] Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, [laughing:] asking for the Moon of all the things, not for anything else. What's so important? So, the mother has always a[n] intuition. She brought a -- it's a, it's a māyā, it's a beautiful drama -- she brought a mirror and showed Him the Moon in the mirror. He [she] said, ``Now, you can get the Moon here." [Laughter, laughs.] So sweet! And He was satisfied! Even the reflection of that can satisfy.<br />
You are like the mirrors and I want to see the reflection of Moon [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] in you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0125 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Growth of the Being on the Subtler Plane (Count Your Blessings, Take Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga, Understand the Subtler Values of Everything, The Greatest Thing for a Sahaja Yogi Is the Living Energy, Be Sweet in Your Tongue, Just Open Your Heart, Great Power of Love, Take Up Love as Your Worshiping), Seminar, Day 3, Session 1 (morning), Lonavala (67 kms NNW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0011.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo">"Today I said that Śhrī Rāma was born at twelve o'clock hence the Pūjā should be at time as such it is not long Pūjā but we have to understand that the human form within us in form of humanity in which we understand and make changes in our mind, curiosity and thoughts.<br />
Through the medium of Śhrī Rāma can bring change in our thoughts, he can bring change in our behavior because he is ideal for us, reaching this ideal we can reach other ideals since he is ideal of human being.<br />
This is big thing that the God Himself came on this Earth and become ideal.<br />
<b>We don't leave our dharma, Vishwa Nirmala Dharma, even if we have lot of difficulties.</b><br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0325 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Hindi) (the day after Rāma Navamī Day), If You Believe in Śhrī Rāma Follow His Ideal (Our Nature Can Change because He Is Our Ideal and You All Become Ideals for this World), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Mātā Rāmo matpitā Rāma-chandrah Swāmī Rāmo matsakhā Rāma-chandrah</b><br />
Śhrī Rāma is my mother and my father; He is my lord and my friend,<br />
<b>sarvaswam me Rāma-chandro dayālur nānyam jāne n’aeva jāne na jāne</b><br />
 So also the ever-compassionate Śhrī Rāma is everything to me and I know nothing else at all</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>('Śhrī Rāma Kavach' in praise of Śhrī Rāma)</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Rāma was the Puruṣhottama, means-s-s: He was the best among all the human beings. That means: He incarnated as a human being, total human being, showing all the qualities of human beings is.</b><br />
Like He was, He married the Lakṣhmī Principle, that was Sītā, and then also He lived a normal married life, when He gave Her up, He lived like an ascetic, to show how a man should lead his life in a proper dharma, as a married man. And even when the Wife has gone away, how He was leading a life of complete chastity."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0814 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Secondary School, Saffron Walden, Essex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0012.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="Indigo">"<b>On the night of Full Moon, you should meditate on Śhrī Rāma and surrender yourself to Him for protection. The meaning of the word rāmachandra is `creativity'. You should completely dedicate your creative powers to Him.</b> Thus you have to take special care of yourself on these two days.<br />
However, <b>on the seventh (Saptamī) and ninth (Navamī) days of Lunar fortnights you have My special blessings. Remember that you are specially blessed by Me on these two days.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0529 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Dhyān Kaise Karein (How to Meditate), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, Indi</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Śhrī Rāma came on this Earth to establish the institution of benevolent king.</b> The political development and the political evolution started from this [right] side. <b>He is the one who gave leadership as a benevolent king, the one who represents God and who is a king. The idea of a king related to God came from Śhrī Rāma.</b><br /> 
But the modern kings are not like that, they have no relation with God. On the contrary, they are horrid people. Some of them are nothing but satanic people, absolutely Satan is there and you can see from the way they lead their lives, and they have led their life before. So the benevolence of Śhrī Rāma is here [shows the right Heart] to be followed by all the political leaders and all the people who are at the helm of affairs. He is the ideal that was created for human beings, to run their authority as the head, or the loving compassionate benevolent leader of the people, who has to govern them by making them respectful, by respect. And if human beings create such things who are not respectable, those who have no human values, those who have no moral courage, those who are selfish, those who are self-centered, then they have nothing to do to be there.<br />
<b>So this is the position of Rāma who is the Father. So the head of every state has to be the father of his subjects, that's what He has tried to show by His life. So much so that He had to sacrifice His beloved Wife, whom He loved so much.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Public Program (1st Day and 2nd Day of Navarātri), Self and Heart Chakra, Day 6, East West Center, 141 5th Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"That is a very beautiful song was written by him. But still, the description of a child, how when he runs when he runs, when he jumps, when he walks it's a beautiful songs about Śhrī Rāma. Ṭhumko atta hai who -- Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra, atta hai kya?<br />
[In Hindi:] <b>Do you know the song `Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra' ...?</b><br />
[In English:] Now these words are such that we cannot explain in English, but when they walk, you know, with -- started walking, so their body, you know, moves in a way that's called `ṭhumakanā' [toddle, waddle] in Hindi language. <b>So described by Tulasīdāsa, as Śhrī Rāma is walking in that way. `Ṭhumaka chalat Rām[a]chandra'. And His anklets are singing and then He's looking round and every pebble on which He's walking is reflecting Him, like the souls in which He's reflected.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0405 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Picnic, Lane Cove National Park, Lane Cone Valley Walk, West Pymble, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Thumak chalat raamachandra<br />
Thumak chalat raamachandra<br />
Baajat painjaniyaan</b><br />
(Baby) Śhrī Rām walks, swaying unsteadily<br />
(Baby) Śhrī Rām…. His anklets ring in tune with his steps<br />
<b>Kilaki kilaki uthat dhaay girat bhuumi latapataay<br />
Dhaay maat god let dasharath kī raniyaan</b><br />
Laughing joyously he stumbles around on the ground<br />
He is fondly picked into the laps of King Dasharath’s queens</font><br />
<b>Thumak Chalat</b><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0013.png" /></div>

<p style=" text-align:center;">
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau manasā smarāmi</b></font><br />
I worship the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra in my heart.<br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra charanau vachasā gṛunāmi</b></font><br />
Through my songs and prayers, I praise the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra.<br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra</b></font><br />
I bow at the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra.<br />
<font color="Blue"><b>Śhrī Rāmachandra</b></font><br />
I surrender at the feet of Śhrī Rāmachandra. <br />
<font color="red"><b>Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Rāmachandra sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ!</b></font><br />
<br />

</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0402 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī Day), Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
<p><a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1982-0402-shri-ramas-birthday-puja"> audio</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Vaishnav Jan To Tene Kahiye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kahe Samjhaye</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Mātājī singing the bhajan with Sahaja Yogis</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kavach Part 1 by Pt.B.Subramanian</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/jU0lTR3Rdg8">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Śhrī Rām Kavach Part 2 by Pt.B.Subramanian</b></font><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/VIexvFle7iQ">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Āratī and the Three Great Mantras</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="deeppink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><category term="green @ Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2024 Celebrating Gangaur Festival during Vasant Navarātri: “They have one festival called Gangaur that is a thing where they worship Gaurī.”</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/11" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2024 Celebrating Gangaur Festival during Vasant Navarātri: “They have one festival called Gangaur that is a thing where they worship Gaurī.”" /><published>2024-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/2024_04_11_Day_3_Vasant_Navaratri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/festivity/2024/04/11"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/image1.png" width="250" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have decided to have a Pūjā of Śhakti that is the Power, that is the Devī.</b> You know within us there are many Powers of Mahākālī, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahālakṣhmī, Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
All these Powers are there for us to ascent. If these Powers are properly used and understood, then your ascent can be permanent. Once you achieve your ascent and enter into the Kingdom of God, all these Powers get enlightened.<br />
And these Powers which are enlightened are absolutely filled with Love. Enlightenment, we have to understand that we get completely enlightened by Love. So after enlightenment, after Realization we use only one Power which is of Love."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Samara Oblast, Russia</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0006.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we'll worship the Śhakti</b> -- very much needed -- the Śhakti who destroyed all the devils, all the rākṣhasas. That is what you are going to worship today -- the Śhakti within you and without.<br />
<b>It's your desire which is going to work.</b><br />
So today we are going to worship the Śhakti Itself -- Mahākālī.<br />
May God bless you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1209 Śhrī Śhakti Mahākālī Pūjā, Auditorium, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>Today we have gathered here to do the Pūjā of the Śhakti.</b><br />
  Till today many Saints have written and spoken a lot about the Śhakti. Those who could not explain the Śhakti in their texts they did it in their poems. Additionally they learnt different meanings of the Śhakti.<br />
  But one thing probably we may not know is that inside every human beings these powers are present in a dormant state and all these powers human being can awaken within himself. All these powers which are present in the dormant state are endless, nor anybody can guess their limit because as an example there are 35 crores [350 million] Deities seated within you. Apart from that there are several powers that are running them, but at least we can understand that the Self-realization that we received today, certainly <b>some Śhaktis must have worked this out. Without this work you cannot get your Self-realization. When we are receiving our Self-realization we think that we got it very easily</b>."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1009 Śhrī Devī Pūjā (Hindi), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0007.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkRed"><b>"Kuṇḍalinī is Gaurī, today is Gaurī Pūjan, Gaurī Pūjan in the month of Chaitra is special. Means before installation of Gaṇapati we have installed Gaurī in the month of Chaitra. Gaurī who created Gaṇapati is the Gaurī from Chaitra and we all believe that."</b></font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0321 Birthday Pūjā (Marathi + English), Completely Surrender Our Lives to Sahaja Yoga and People Should See through You the Greatness of Sahaja Yoga (We Have Started Vishwa Nirmala Dharma and the Great Religion of Realized Souls), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti is the Power of Desire of Bhagavatī. She is easily awakened just by the Wish (Saṅkalpa) of Bhagavatī. A person of very high order has to put in great efforts for it.</b>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0000 Letter to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi) on Human Chitta from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 13 (January-February 1983), Pages 16 and 17</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>This Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti is your pure desire. It is the Desire of God Almighty.</b> When it is awakened in you, you get contented. You get satisfied and think that instead of material desire now I have entered into such a beautiful garden which is fragrant, full of joy, peace and love. When you achieve that state then you do not look back to material desires. To achieve this state in Sahaja Yoga is extremely beautiful. It happens very easily, you have to do nothing for it, give no money, do no rituals, no prayers, nothing. You should only have the pure desire to know the Spirit."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0326 Public Program (Hindi + English + Hindi) (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), Satya Ki Prāpti hī Sabase Baṛī Prāpti Hai (The Realization of Truth is the Greatest Achievement), Jawaharlal Nehru Stadium, Pragati Vihar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0008.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font size="+0">The Mahārāṇī adorned Śhrī Mātājī in a traditional Rajasthani ghagra (skirt) of vibrant colors. The Rajput women worshipped Her with flowers and Āratī.<br />
<b>From "The Tenth Incarnation", Volume 1 Chapter 40, Page 178, by Yogi Mahajan.</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkGreen">"<b>They have one festival called Gangaur: that is a thing where they uh uh worship Gaurī.</b> That's the biggest festival where the Queen ... Mahārāṇī has to worship the Gangaurī: is a statue, which goes round the whole of Jaipur state and everybody celebrates it. Is regarded as the biggest festival. So she, in the morning she came and touched My Feet. And she said, "Mother, can I'p worship You?" I said, "Why?" "Because You are my Gangaur, really. That's just a statue." She made Me stand the same way, she did everything, she made Me eat betel. Uh I don't eat all that, but he, she said, "You have to, You are Gangaur, so You have to eat it." [Smiles, laughter.] And she worshiped Me and all her whole rituals she did for about f... forty-five minutes, and the ... then she said, "Now I'll go and worship that statue." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0421 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Vertical Ascent, the day before Easter Pūjā, Before Dinner, The Burlington Hotel, Grand Parade, Eastbourne BN21 3YN, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"<b>We are the worshipers of Śhakti.</b> Here we are Śhakti Dharmī [religiously devoted to Śhakti] and many kings have been worshiping Ādi Śhakti.<br />
Everyone has different Deities and the names of each Deity is different. <b>The name of the Deity of this place is also different, it is Gangaur.</b><br />
But Ādi Śhakti was once born in Rajasthan state whose name was Satī Devī. It is Her Grace that we find our culture the dharma of wife, dharma of husband, dharma of ruling, etc. which are nourished by Her Śhakti.<br />
You all know the story of Satī Devī, I don't have to tell you in new way but She was Gangaur. She was married and while She was returning after marriage with Her husband some of the bad elements surrounded them and killed Her husband. She came out of the bride's carriage, took the Rudra Form and destroyed all of them who attacked Her husband and then She finished Herself also. We should see in this that since childhood till marriage She did not disclose that She was Mahāmāyā in any condition."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1211 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Mahāmāyā, Mahākālī, Śhāradā Devī, Mahālakṣhmī, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://pub-1e517d8c73a64c9c82977d676b1fff72.r2.dev/FT0009.png" /></div>

<p style="text-align:center;">
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Prabhavatı Prabha-rupa, Prasiddha Parameshvarı,<br /> 
Mula-prakritir-avyakta, Vyakt’avyakta-swarupinı. </b></font><br />
Full of light, as light is Your form, You are the Established, Supreme Ruler of the Universe;<br />
You are the Kundalini Shakti, imperceptible,<br />
both the manifest and the unmanifest are Your forms.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>(Śhrī Lalitā Sahasrānama, verse 86)</b></font><br />
<br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī tere Charano meaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<i>Ādi Śhakti Mātājī I have come to Your Lotus Feet</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Shyam Savere gun. Tere gaon, Tera hijaya hun mein,</b></font><br />
<i>Morning and evening I sing Your praise</i><br />
<font color="DarkGreen"><b>Śhrī Mā Tera hi jaya hu mein</b></font><br />
<i>Śhrī Mātājī I Have received Second Birth from You</i><br />
<a href="https://youtu.be/L1wSDCxZKS0?list=PLC8554007A2C98EA0">video</a>
</p>

<font size="+2"><b>Suggested Talk:</b></font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-0803 Śhrī Śhakti Pūjā, Power of Love, Camp, Shores of Volga, Togliatti, Samara Oblast, Russia</b></font>
<p><a href="https://vimeo.com/26181854"> video</a><br /></p>

<font size="+2"><b>Bhajans:</b></font>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Jay Durge Jay Ambā Bhavānī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a> 
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>Kuṇḍalinī Kuṇḍalinī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font color="green"><b>He Bhavānī Bhagavatī</b></font><br />
<a href="https://seven-teams.github.io/Videos_Links.html">video</a>
</p>

<p>
<font size="+0">Jai Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
On behalf of the festivity team!</font>
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="maroon @ Shri Gangaur Festival" /><category term="green @ Vasant Navaratri" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>