<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/photos.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-03-16T17:22:05-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/photos.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Photos</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 8: Second Annual Report</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2023/0312" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 8: Second Annual Report" /><published>2023-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2023/Photos_Post8_2023_Annual_Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2023/0312"><![CDATA[<p>
<br />
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
The website <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> <font color="DarkGreen"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font></a> has now 23,214 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī, including versions and details (an increment of 2,150 since the last annual report), and 7,207 photos Moments of Joy (an increment of 3,724 since the last annual report). There are 26 (named) Collections with 21,753 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī and 7,138 photos Moments of Joy.<br />
<br />
The XYZ Folder of the Collections shall be completed by May 5, 2023.<br />
<br />
So, there are more than 30.4K Photos and photos Moments of Joy uploaded to the website. When essentially completed, it is projected that the website will have between 60K and 5 million Photos and photos Moments of Joy, and each year we will reestimate these bounds.<br />
<br />
We will start having short posts announcing new events for which Photos have been just uploaded. They will be grouped under two numbered posts: one on early Photos (before 1976-0101) and one on special or less known events.<br />
<br />
Following in the footsteps of the Divine Cool Breeze website of Photographs, the download buttons for Photographs will be activated on May 5, 2023 (in the Chronology Folder to begin with). Accordingly, we will be using every opportunity to remind everyone about the delicate protocols that accompany the sharing of Photos. We really expect that all Photos downloaded from Eternal Moments will be exclusively used for worshiping and for the well-established Sahaja Yoga Projects, by which we mean projects which THROUGHOUT the history of Sahaja Yoga have been regarded as Sahaja Yoga Projects. Among these projects we explicitly mention the spreading of Sahaja Yoga via Public Programs or publications or dedicated, well-organized websites that have full self-control on their promotions. In particular, we do not regard websites or accounts that are either non-dedicated or are not well-organized or are promoted by third parties or mixed with other promotions as well-established Sahaja Yoga projects and as such our team would be very grateful to everyone if we could all refrain from downloading Photos and photos Moments of Joy and re-uploading them to such websites and accounts.<br />
<br />
We thank you in advance for your understanding, contributions, help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
The Photo Subteam<br />
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="orange @ Annual Reports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, The website Eternal Moments has now 23,214 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī, including versions and details (an increment of 2,150 since the last annual report), and 7,207 photos Moments of Joy (an increment of 3,724 since the last annual report). There are 26 (named) Collections with 21,753 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī and 7,138 photos Moments of Joy. The XYZ Folder of the Collections shall be completed by May 5, 2023. So, there are more than 30.4K Photos and photos Moments of Joy uploaded to the website. When essentially completed, it is projected that the website will have between 60K and 5 million Photos and photos Moments of Joy, and each year we will reestimate these bounds. We will start having short posts announcing new events for which Photos have been just uploaded. They will be grouped under two numbered posts: one on early Photos (before 1976-0101) and one on special or less known events. Following in the footsteps of the Divine Cool Breeze website of Photographs, the download buttons for Photographs will be activated on May 5, 2023 (in the Chronology Folder to begin with). Accordingly, we will be using every opportunity to remind everyone about the delicate protocols that accompany the sharing of Photos. We really expect that all Photos downloaded from Eternal Moments will be exclusively used for worshiping and for the well-established Sahaja Yoga Projects, by which we mean projects which THROUGHOUT the history of Sahaja Yoga have been regarded as Sahaja Yoga Projects. Among these projects we explicitly mention the spreading of Sahaja Yoga via Public Programs or publications or dedicated, well-organized websites that have full self-control on their promotions. In particular, we do not regard websites or accounts that are either non-dedicated or are not well-organized or are promoted by third parties or mixed with other promotions as well-established Sahaja Yoga projects and as such our team would be very grateful to everyone if we could all refrain from downloading Photos and photos Moments of Joy and re-uploading them to such websites and accounts. We thank you in advance for your understanding, contributions, help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com Jay Śhrī Mātājī! The Photo Subteam]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 7: Nonempty Chronology Galleries</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2023/0115" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 7: Nonempty Chronology Galleries" /><published>2023-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2023/Photos_Post7_Nonempty_Chronology_Galleries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2023/0115"><![CDATA[<p>
<br />
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
We are pleased to mention that all galleries of the Chronology Folder of the <font color="DarkGreen"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font> website of Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī are nonempty.<br />
The direct link to the Chronology Folder is:<a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/Chronology"> Chronology</a><br />
Among the 47 years before the start of Sahaja Yoga (i.e., 1923 to 1969), the Chronology Folder has 10 nonempty galleries, and we hope and pray that one day it will have 47 nonempty galleries.<br />
We will gradually upload many more dated Photos from the early years of Sahaja Yoga.<br />
We would be most happy to receive, enjoy, study, and share more Photos of our Divine Mother. We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />

<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
The Photo Subteam (of the Comprehensive Compilations Team)
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="green @ Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, Jay Śhrī Mātājī! We are pleased to mention that all galleries of the Chronology Folder of the Eternal Moments website of Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī are nonempty. The direct link to the Chronology Folder is: Chronology Among the 47 years before the start of Sahaja Yoga (i.e., 1923 to 1969), the Chronology Folder has 10 nonempty galleries, and we hope and pray that one day it will have 47 nonempty galleries. We will gradually upload many more dated Photos from the early years of Sahaja Yoga. We would be most happy to receive, enjoy, study, and share more Photos of our Divine Mother. We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 6: Handwritings Galleries</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/0724" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 6: Handwritings Galleries" /><published>2022-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/Photos_Post6_Handwritings_Galleries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/0724"><![CDATA[<p>
<br />
Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
The photos of handwritings are very special photos Moments of Joy that are very relevant to multiple projects, searches, and studies. As such, we are pleased to make an offering at the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī and to let you know that Handwritings Galleries have been singled out from the Moments of Joy Galleries. They will be showing up in both the Collections Folders as well as altogether in the Moments of Joy Folder of the <font color="DarkGreen"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font> website of Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī.<br />
</p>

<p>The link to the website is:<a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> website</a></p>

<p>The direct link to the altogether Handwritings Gallery is: <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/Moments-of-Joy/Handwritings/"> link</a></p>

<p>
Currently this gallery contains 108 handwritings (as photos) but we will gradually add more.<br />
<br />
We would be most happy to receive, enjoy, study, and share more handwritings of our Divine Mother. We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com<br />
<br />
Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br />
<br />
The Photo Subteam (of the Comprehensive Compilations Team)
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="green @ Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs, Jay Śhrī Mātājī! The photos of handwritings are very special photos Moments of Joy that are very relevant to multiple projects, searches, and studies. As such, we are pleased to make an offering at the Lotus Feet of Śhrī Mātājī and to let you know that Handwritings Galleries have been singled out from the Moments of Joy Galleries. They will be showing up in both the Collections Folders as well as altogether in the Moments of Joy Folder of the Eternal Moments website of Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 5: Search Feature</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/0505" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 5: Search Feature" /><published>2022-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/Photos_Post5_Search_Feature</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/0505"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>As part of the celebration of the 52nd anniversary of the <font color="DeepPink"><b>Sahasrāra Day</b></font>, we are pleased to offer at the Lotus Feet of our Divine Mother and to bring to your attention the search feature added to the navigation menu of the <font color="blue"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font> website of Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī.</p>

<p>The link to the website is: <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> link</a></p>

<p><b>The search feature serves at least four purposes as follows:</b><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li>One can build its own gallery for the enjoyment of vibrations and blessings.<br /></li>
  <li>To help in identifying untitled (undated or unplaced or unspecified) Photos and photos Moments of Joy.<br /></li>
  <li>To help in identifying unedited or original Photos or photos Moments of Joy so that all edited Photos and photos that are inappropriately circulating on facebook, etc., could be identified, avoided, and hopefully eliminated.<br /></li>
  <li>To help all Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs involved in different projects to identify faster the Photos and photos Moments of Joy that would enhance their projects.
The searchable Keywords fall in two categories.<br />
a. coming automatically from the title of the Photos and photos Moments of Joy (such as Evening Program, Public Program, Pūjā, Talk, etc.); 
b. manually added.</li>
</ol>

<p><b>WARNING:</b> 
For a: ONLY Photos uploaded or re-uploaded after November 25, 2021 have the keywords automatically created from the titles (they are in thousands).<br />
For b: We are still working to manually add keywords to the Photos from 255 months of the years 1981 to 2010 and for photos Moments of Joy from the years 1983 to 2011.</p>

<p><b>Very important:</b> none of these keywords, that are automatic or manually added, are on the Photos or photos Moments of Joy (i.e., later on when the download button will be added, via download only the original keywords will be there.</p>

<p>We are constantly working on re-uploading and manually adding keywords, and as such it was felt that it is the right time to start the search feature.</p>

<p><b>Two ways to use the search feature:</b><br />
<i>A (a priori set up search):</i> i. clicking on SEARCH; ii. below the elongated horizontal box choosing the right category (basically Photos or Galleries, in most cases being actually Photos); iii. typing in the elongated horizontal box the keywords that would delimit the search most, the words ought to be separated by space (say, typing: public India)<br />
<i>B (inspired search or seeking to set up a search):</i> i. clicking on any Photo or photo Moments of Joy; ii. clicking on the top left little icon that is an i-circled (Photo Details); iii. From the details lists, click on anyone of the KEYWORDS of that Photo or photo Moments of Joy</p>

<p><b>SUGGESTED KEYWORDS FOR TYPING VIA COPY AND PASTE (to be enlarged):</b><br />
<i>I. Categories:</i> advices, art, comments, conversations, Havan, interview, press, conferences, letter, faxe, marriages, meetings, personality, public, address, talk, Public Program, workshop, Pūjā, quote, message, prayer, story, writing, guideline.<br />
<i>Pūjā Types:</i> Ādi Śhakti, Āhlāda, Akṣhaya Tṛitīya, Athena, Begum, Bestowing, Bhairavanāth, Bhavasāgara, Bhūmī, Birthday, Boons, Buddha, Chakra, Chandramā, Christmas, Chitta, Dāyinī, Devī, Diwālī, Durgā, Easter, Ekādaśha, Fāṭimah, Gaṇeśha, Gaurī, Gṛuhalakṣhmī, Guḍhī, Guru, Haṃsa, Hanumāna, Holī, House, Jesus, Kārttikeya, Kṛiṣhṇa, Kubera, Kuṇḍalinī, Lakṣhmī, Lalitā, Local, Mahādevī, Mahāgaṇeśha, Mahākālī, Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāmāyā, Mahāsaraswatī, Mahāvīra, Mahiṣhāsuramardinī, Makar, Mary, Nāṇaka, Nava, Navarātri, New Year, Nirmalā, Pāḍavā, Pallas, Paramachaitanya, Pasha, Rājalakṣhmī, Rājarājeśhwarī, Rāma, Rakṣhābandhan, Rudra, Sahasrāra, Saṅkrānti, Saraswatī, Sea, Śhivarātri, Small, Śhailaputrī, Śhakti, Sūrya, Swāminī, Unspecified, Vāstuśhānti, Varṣha, Virāṭa, Viṣhṇu, Viṣhṇumāyā, Warming, Yogeśhwara.<br />
<i>III. Countries:</i> Andorra, Argentina, Australia, Austria, Belgium, Brazil, Bulgaria, Canada, China, Colombia, Czech Republic, Denmark, Egypt, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, India, Italy, Japan, Malaysia, Nepal, Nether- lands, New Zealand, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Russia, Singapore, Spain, Switzerland, TBD, Taiwan, Thailand, Tunisia, Turkey, Ukraine, U.A.E., UK, U.S.A.<br />
<i>IV. Other words:</i> Āratī, baby, blessing, book, building, BW, candle, cake, chappal, child, closed eyes, crown, curtain, darśhan, face, family, fan, furniture, garden, garland, glasses, hand, laugh, Lotus Feet, meal, mike, miracle, namaskār, nature, night, nose ring, ocean, painting, Photo, prasād, procession, scarf, purse, sandal, sea, shoe, seeker, shawl, Śhrī, smile, sweater, walk, wall, Sahaja Yogi.<br />
<i>V. Collections:</i> Alessandra, Anant, Asha, Balwant, Băjescu, Brenner, Brownscombe, Bruno, Burd, Călin, CCT, Chavhāṇ, Chiroiu, Colin, Cooper, Daulat, Deity, Descaves, Durand, Harris, Heinsen, Jatobá, Karan, Khurana, Kolkata, Kumbhojkar, Louis, Mahajan, Marian, Marie, Mark, Markl, Matthew, Michael, Pallini, Paul, Pavan, Peter, Prabhakar, Radu, Ray, Taylor, Vasiliu, Willi, XYZ, Yogi.<br />
<i>VI. Colors:</i> essentially all.<br />
<i>VII. Cities:</i> essentially all, the ones with IAST will be gradually added here as well so that they can be copied and pasted [the issue is an incompatibility between different devices, like ā will work in a search, but ā will not, though they look the same].</p>

<p>All these suggested words are also listed on the main page of the website.</p>

<p>We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="green @ Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 4: First Annual Report</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/0312" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 4: First Annual Report" /><published>2022-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/Photos_Post4_2022_Annual_Report</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2022/0312"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The website <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> <font color="blue"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font></a> has now 21,064 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī, including versions and details (an increment of 3,492 since Post 3), and 3,483 photos Moments of Joy (an increment of 2,845 since Post 3). 
There are 21 Collections with 19,954 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī and 3,444 photos Moments of Joy.</p>

<p>Gradually, the Photographs and the photos Moments of Joy that are not part of the Collections will be also made available in the XYZ Folder of the Collections.</p>

<p>We have started a complete round of re-uploading everything so that all the words in the title are available as Keywords and as such searchable. In the process, we are checking and rechecking each and everything.</p>

<p>In just a few days, Search will be added to the Navigation Menu.</p>

<p>Besides the Keywords that are automatically coming from the titles, we are manually adding a large list of Keywords. The list will considerably grow as we re-upload more and more Photographs and photos Moments of Joy. Currently, besides the colors, it consists of the following words:</p>

<p><i>BW, candle, child, closed eyes, crown, curtain, darśhan, face, family, fan, furniture, garden, garland, glasses, hand, laugh, Lotus Feet, mike, miracle, namaskār, nature, night, nose ring, painting, Photo, scarf, purse, sea, seeker, shawl, smile, walk, wall, Yogi</i></p>

<p>Please kindly suggest carefully chosen extra Keywords. Also, please kindly enjoy and share.</p>

<p>We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="orange @ Annual Reports" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 3: Updates</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/1127" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 3: Updates" /><published>2021-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/Photos_Post3_Updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/1127"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The website <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> <font color="blue"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font></a> has now 17,572 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī, including versions and details (an increment of 4,646 since Post 2), and 638 photos Moments of Joy (an increment of 124 since Post 2). Also, it now has a navigation menu accessible on every page.</p>

<p>Please enjoy and share.</p>

<p>We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="green @ Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 2: Updates</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/0926" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 2: Updates" /><published>2021-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/Photos_Post2_Updates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/0926"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The website <a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> <font color="blue"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font></a> has now 12,926 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī, including versions and details (an increment of 6,547 since Post 1). Also, 514 photographs Moments of Joy have been uploaded.</p>

<p>Please enjoy and share.</p>

<p>We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="green @ Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Photos Post 1: Website</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/0502" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photos Post 1: Website" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/Photos_Post1_Website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/photos/2021/0502"><![CDATA[<p>Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>As part of the celebration of the 51st anniversary of the <font color="DeepPink"><b>Sahasrāra Day</b></font>, we are pleased to offer at the Lotus Feet of our Divine Mother and to bring to your attention the <font color="blue"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font> website of Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī that was started in 2018.</p>

<p><i>The website treasures the eternal moments with Śhrī Mātājī by organizing some of Her Photographs within collections as well as chronologically.</i>
The link to the website is:
<a href="https://eternalmoments.smugmug.com/"> link</a></p>

<p>The website has currently 6,379 Photographs of Śhrī Mātājī, including versions. More than half of the Photographs come from 9 collections. Among the 9 collections, 7 of them were shared with us (first to work on them by titling them and eventually to upload them to the website). The eighth collection is the one of Ray Harris that has been around for many years but only partially dated. A ninth collection was added as the titles for the 1982 to 1984 period Photographs help the database.</p>

<p>We hope very much that you will enjoy the <font color="blue"><b>Eternal Moments</b></font> website.</p>

<p>At this moment we are seeking your feedback on the website and we are considering enlarging the team.</p>

<p>The Photographs of the website can be currently extracted in many ways, say by copying. Until the download buttons are activated, the extracted Photographs will not come up with their displayed titles. But the extraction part suffices for most projects. We aim to activate the download buttons in the next couple of months, once the links to Galleries are better set up.</p>

<p>We thank you in advance for any help, support, and feedback. Please write to us at sahajayoga.compilations@gmail.com</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Comprehensive Compilations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Photographs of Shri Mataji" /><category term="green @ Updates" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dear Sahaja Yogis and Sahaja Yoginīs,]]></summary></entry></feed>