<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-07-03T19:06:43-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Quotes</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ RUKMINĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0625" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ RUKMINĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri_Rukmini</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0625"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"His Power Rādhā was then divided into two, that is, Rukmiṇī in Dvārika and Rādhā in Vṛindāvan. It is very humanly."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The place of Nagpur is very high, in My point of view Nagpur is Nābhī of the whole world. So you understand it that how much carefully and how properly Nagpurians have to live and should behave and how wisely they should think! Whereas whole world is afraid of Nagpurians!<br />
Once I went to Lata Mangeshkar and asked her to come to a program. She replied, "No question of me, I will not allow even anybody else to go there. Once I went there, they threw shoes at me."<br /> 
Another person also had same experience.<br />
I said, "I am going to My parent's place."<br /> 
<font color="red">They got Me down halfway in Badnera [Kuṇḍina], where Rukmiṇī Haraṇ took place and they brought Me here stealthily in the same way [Rukmiṇī Haraṇ] saying that, "Don't go there otherwise people will throw stones at you." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1219 Public Program (Hindi), Nagpur, Maharashtra, India (other date 1222)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">Right Viśhuddhi mantra is Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Viṭṭhala Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī] sākṣhāt ...</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Viṭṭhala?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">Viṭṭhala Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī]!</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Viṭṭhala Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī].<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Ha-ha!<br />
<b>All Sahaja Yogis:</b> Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Viṭṭhala Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī] sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ. Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Viṭṭhala Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī] sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ. Auṃ Twameva sākṣhāt Śhrī Viṭṭhala Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī] sākṣhāt Śhrī Ādi Śhakti sākṣhāt Śhrī Bhagavatī sākṣhāt Śhrī Mātājī Śhrī Nirmalā Devī namo namaḥ.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Mhh! Good? [Laughs.]<br />
Just see: if the Mantras are awakened, how powerful they can be!<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1008 Public Program, Maintaining Purity of Sahaja Yoga, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Viśhuddhi chakra has two other points, which are very important, within us.<br /> 
I take this up because you people are suffer[ing] from left Viśhuddhi.<br />
Left Viśhuddhi is on the left-hand side, and right [is] on the right-hand side.<br /> 
<font color="red">Right-hand side Viśhuddhi is the Viśhuddhi when ... when He was the king and called as Viṭṭhala and His wife Rukmiṇī</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0401 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 5, Viśhuddhi and Āgñyā Chakras, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Like Kṛiṣhṇa's case, you see, Kṛiṣhṇa had it Sixteen Thousand Powers and He got them, they were born in India as women. Ah but He couldn't keep it them in the house because everybody would say that, `They ... they are His keeps,' you see. So He made one king uh-uh ...<br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> You come [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> ... to capture them, all these sixteen thousands, and keep them in the house, you see, in his arrest. So, Kṛiṣhṇa defeated him and got all of them, and married them! [Drinks tea during translation.]<br />
<font color="red">And He had five, five elements also which He kuh tried to incarnate, and then He married too as five, His wives, His queens.</font><br />
And He was called as Yogeśhwara.<br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> Mother, sorry I am not sure: did You say that He married the five elements?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font><font color="red"> Five elements: they were called His five wives, they were five elements.</font><br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> Who were they, Mother?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red"> You see, there were five of them Kālī and all that. There are five of them: Rukmiṇī, and all these five of them. [Smiles.] He had five queens!</font><br /> 
But after all He was, you have Virāṭa, you see. [Laughing:] Imagine, He has to have all these powers."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0503 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before and during Breakfast, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"On the right side of the Viśhuddhi resides Kṛiṣhṇa, who in Maharashtra is known as Viṭṭhala and who ruled over Dvārika, which is in your city. When He is in the center, He is in the form of Gopi-Gopika, when He was ruling Dvārika He was on the right side, and on the left His Power is that of a woman who was His sister. <font color="red">Rādhā was His Power in the center, and Rukmiṇī, His wife, was His power on the right side."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0219 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Session 1 (evening), A Sahaja Yogi Will Reflect on the Outside His Inner Quality, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">So, for the right Viśhuddhi we use the mantra of Viṭṭhala and Rakhumāī [Rukmiṇī], these two persons.</font><br />
You see, it is very significant that also.<br />
Because they say that there was a Puṇḍarīkākṣh, one boy, who was serving his parents. "<font color="red">And his parents were sleeping, he was pressing their feet, when Viṭṭhala and His Power Rakhumāī ... Rukmiṇī, They appeared uh in the door. But he said, ``Now keep quiet. My parents are sleeping, so You stay there!" So he had one brick near him which he threw, and asked Them, ``You stay on that." So They kept quiet. They kept quiet because they are sleeping."</font><br /> 
Now, this is the thing is: on the right side, if you are talking loudly, if you talk too much, uh-uh-uh-uh if you uh intimidate people with your talking, then you catch on right Viśhuddhi.<br />
So for that, best is to take some rest, and give some rest to your right Viśhuddhi, by stopping your talk. `Go into mauna,' they say: just don't talk. For some time if you don't taulk [talk], you'll see that your Viśhuddhi will be improved, your problems will be improved."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0814 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Secondary School, Saffron Walden, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"During the Dwāpara Yuga at the time of Lord Kṛiṣhṇa, Ādi Śhakti again incarnated as three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">2. Rukmiṇī (Mahāsaraswatī) as Kṛiṣhṇa's Queen"</font><br />
......<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Page 20</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Ādi Viṣhṇu's eighth form was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa during the Dwāpara Yuga, and again Ādi Śhakti took three forms. Mahākālī lived for a very short time as Viṣhṇumāyā, the infant sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She was actually born as the daughter of Yeśhodā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's foster mother, and was killed by the demon Kaṃsa. She later took birth as Draupadī, wife of the Pāṇḍavas. Yeśhodā was Herself an Incarnation of Mahāsaraswatī. <font color="red">As Mahālakṣhmī She took two forms, Rādhā and Rukmiṇī.</font> '<i>Rā</i>' means power or energy and '<i>dhā</i>' means sustenance, so the name 'Rādhā' means the one who sustains the power. <font color="red">As Rukmiṇī She became Queen to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the King in Dvārakā.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 34</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Rukmini" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahasaraswati" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ DATTĀTREYA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0623" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ DATTĀTREYA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri%20Dattatreya</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0623"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"To make the people cross the Void (Bhavasāgara) He has to make some arrangement. So the Great Power like Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha was created and they were placed in the Area of Dharma.<br />
Dattātreya and Ādi Gurus incarnated in this world many a times. He incarnated as King Janaka who was like the father of Ādi Śhakti. After that He incarnated in Iran as Zoroaster, then as Macchindranāth, then as Muhammad Sāheb and Nāṇak Sāheb.</font><br />
No one fought with each other. See what type of darkness you are in?<br />
Fāṭimah, the daughter of Muhammad Sāheb was the same who became daughter of King Janaka.<br />
Whom are you fighting? Think over it.<br />
The Nāṇakī of Guru Janaka was none else but Jānakī.<br />
<font color="red">Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth was also an Ādi Guru.<br /> 
They are the Masters of all.</font><br />
<font color="red">Also, They are My Gurus. These Ādi Gurus taught Me all this Knowledge. In different Incarnations They kept Me teaching.<br /> 
Ultimately I had to come and do His work. They could not do it and now They are placing Me as a Guru so that I take up the job of a Guru.<br />
There was an age when no one was willing to accept a woman as a Guru but in Kali Yuga only Mother could do His work: it is beyond the power of men.</font><br />
This work could not be done by force, only the love of a Mother could do it because already there is so much pressure, tension in this world. The day it is forced upon the human being they will break down. So, love is the only way out.<br />
So this Gurudom was given to Me. Everything is acceptable to Me.<br />
But I didn't know the qualities of a Guru.<br />
Gurus maintain distance but mother does not keep distance with the children. Children sit on her head.<br />
So, you people also could take liberty with Me and enjoy. Be with Me with full freedom, you will neither be afraid nor be embarrassed. There is no problem, you could come and talk to Me boldly about your problems. You could complain to Me as you do to your mother. I am freely available to you.<br />
Freedom was needed, religion was required to be discussed openly, there is no secret, no secret about it. Ultimately everything has to be explained very clearly. All the secrets are to be told about, everything could not be said everywhere."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But before reaching the Heart chakra, the gap I showed you, is all the Bhavasāgara. In the center is the seat of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, and on it Śhrī Brahmadeva creates the whole universe. He made this Bhavasāgara.<br />
After creating the Bhavasāgara, the question was, 'How to cross it over? The human being was created, but how to make him realize it? How to make human beings recognize it? In him, how to activate the Brahma Tattwa?' Meaning, 'How to get the Union of Śhiva and Śhakti within him? How would the connection be established?'<br />
<font color="red">For this, a special personality was created in this world. This was created by the combined essence of Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, and Maheśh, who we acknowledge as Śhrī Dattātreya. Śhrī Dattātreya is none other than Ādi Guru.<br />
He is My Guru. He has mentored Me all His past lives.<br />
If you hear about His birth and all His previous lives you would be amazed. We have forgotten such a great thing.<br />
Śhrī Dattātreya's Incarnations are numerous. Firstly He came as King Janaka. Śhrī Sītājī was His daughter, who was the embodiment of Śhakti Herself. Then He came as Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, and Muhammad Sāhab, who were a completely different type of human being.<br />
They trialed out lots of different things.<br /> 
Śhrī Datta, the Primordial Masters firstly in this world educated us about the symbolic forms within us. And then also said that, "You people got entangled in symbolism, in idol worshiping." Their meaning was to go beyond and recognize the Śhakti within these idols. That's why They talked about the idols.</font><br />
<font color="red">For example, there is a flower, and to describe the honey within the flower, They talked about the flower first, from which the people would taste the honey. But people got stuck to flower. So Then they took Incarnations and talked about the honey.<br />
In that, They talked about God in the abstract. They deliberately didn't talk about the reincarnation of life.</font><br />
Because as soon as you talk about past lives, people ask Me, "Mātājī, tell me about my past lives." The life that has passed, why do you want to know that? Whether you were a king or a pauper, what difference it will make?<br />
<font color="red">That's why They did not discuss past lives.<br />
Muhammad Sāhab was the same, Dattātreya's Incarnation, and the same Incarnation was King Janaka. The same Incarnation was Nāṇaka,</font> whose sister Nāṇakī, was the same Ādi Śhakti. She was Sītājī.<br />
......<br />
I always say, "If a Muslim gets obstructed from getting his Realization, you take the name of Dattātreya." And if [a] Hindu gets obstructed, I say, 'You take Muhammad Sāhab's name.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The same Śhrī Dattā incarnated many a times on the Earth.<br />
As I told you yesterday, King Janaka was one of them. King Janaka was the father of Jānakī [Śhrī Sītā]. He was none other than the Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya.<br />
Thereafter, Macchindranāth, most have you must have heard His name, was also His Incarnation.<br />
After that Zoroaster who came three times on the Earth, He was also His Incarnation.<br />
After that Muhammad Sāhab, who was His Incarnation.<br />
And when He was asked that, "Bhāī [Brother] there must have been others also before you," then He replied, "Yes, there [was] a Muhammad." Then again He was asked who was before him. He replied, "There was one Muhammad."</font><br />
Muhammad means Praise, the One who is praised, the One who deserves to be praised and is the One who is Redeemer of the world.<br /> 
<font color="red">They were all Muhammads, they were all Dattātreyas, who came on Earth regularly.<br />
After that [was] Nāṇaka, Guru Nāṇaka. If you ever read His teachings, if you read His talks then you will be surprised that He has always talked in a Sahaja. He has said, "Sahaja Samādhi lago." He has said, "Kāhe re ban khojan jāe, Sarab nivāsī sadā alepā tohī saṃg[a] samāī, Puṣhpamadhya jo bāsa basata hai mukara māhī jaise chhāī, Taise hī harī base niraṃtara ghaṭa hī khojo bhāī." "Why to go to forest to find Him, He is always there with you just like there is a fragrance in a flower and just as the reflection is there in a mirror, in the same way God is residing in you eternally seek Him within. He is just inside, achieve Him just inside. We are just singing poem, singing songs, we are just cramming His prescription."<br />
The talk of seeking this Absolute Principle, residing just inside the heart, has been made since ancient times by these Ādi Gurus, who are incarnated on this Earth again and again.</font><br />
......<br /> 
<font color="red">After Nāṇak Sāhab, around fifty, sixty years ago in our Maharashtra Dattātreya incarnated as Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī.</font> If you want proof of it, then you get your Realization and after that if you put your hand on anyone, then you will get vibration of same kind: from just vibration only you can know about all.<br />
As you must have eyes to see any shape, its color, in the same way you are required to feel vibrations so that you may know all the gurus of the world and will be able to know as who is a true guru and who is a liar, who is equal to that Incarnation of Ādi Guru Dattātreya, for mere saying there are thousands of guru in modern times. No one become guru just by saying of another. And by believing in him also, he does not become a guru."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"When someone gets cancer, he can be cured by either Nāṇak Sāhib or Muhammad Sāhib, no one else. Because what we call Void, is known to doctors, we call it Bhavasāgar, Dattātreya, who is Ādi Guru, who helps us in crossing Bhavasāgar, where all Gurus are present, unless you take the name of one of Them, you are not going to be free from problems of Bhavasāgar, which manifests as cancer.</font> You can recognize cancer from the throb here. You cannot be cured."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0326 Public Program (Hindi+English), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But in some people that stability has to be brought about. No problem. You have obtained that thing, you recognized it, you reached there and there is a complete arrangement for bringing stability.<br />
<font color="red">As soon as that stability is achieved, in Absolute Peace and Joy, you achieve that Witness State described by Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, by Jesus, by all the Scriptures whether by Zoroaster, Socrates, Confucius or any of Dattātreya's Incarnations."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then comes the most important part of our body, is the stomach. It represents the Bhavasāgara. Is the māyā, in which we are placed.<br />
We are born in this Bhavasāgara, when Śhrī Vriṣhṇu [Viṣhṇu] Himself incarnates again and again -- you have seen as Matsya Avatāra, Kūrma Avatāra -- and He Himself leads the human beings in their evolutionary path.<br />
<font color="red">He is helped by another, another Deity, whom we call as Primordial Guru: the Ādi Guru Dattātreya.</font><br />
Śhrī Viṣhṇu rises from Bhavasāgara, and gives you the leadership to rise within yourself. He builds up your awareness, step by step, and today you are as ... as a human being.<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">Now the ... these three aspects, the essence of these aspects, or we can say the innocence of these three aspects, is combined in the Primord[i]al Guru, or the Ādi Guru Dattātreya, who resides in the Bhavasāgara and helps Śhrī Viṣhṇu for your evolution.<br />
Now He has taken many Incarnations, mainly Ten Incarnations. And these are very important, and we have to understand Them in Their full entirety.<br />
If you accept Him as Dattātreya, you have to also accept Him as Rāja Janaka.<br />
It's easy for a Hindu mind to accept Rāja Janaka, but they cannot accept Muhammad Sāhab, who was same as Rāja Janaka. It is a fact which can ... we can prove it on your Kuṇḍalinī.</font><br />
A person who is suffering from cancer of the stomach -- now this is the thing, when I say that Sahaja Yoga can cure your cancer, you have to give up certain notions that we have in our hear... head.<br />
<font color="red">A person, eh supposing he's a Hindu, and he's suffering from the stomach cancer, I have to ask him to take the name of Muhammad Sāhab. If I fail to ask him or if I convince ... do not him ... convince Him, I cannot cure his can't ... cancer. I'm sorry, I tell him, 'I just cannot do it.' But if he is a Muslim, I have to tell him: 'You have to take the name of Dattātreya.'</font><br />
Human beings, like fools, have taken away the living flowers of one tree, and now are fighting on something that is dead.<br />
<font color="red">He was Dattātreya. There is no doubt about it.</font><br />
And His daughter Fāṭimah was nobody else but Sītā Jānakī Herself.<br />
And Her two sons, Hasan and Husayn, were nobody else but Lava and Kuśha. They were born again and again: They were born as Mahāvīra and Buddha, and then They were born as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
It is only possible through Sahaja Yoga to realize that this is the Truth, this is the fact.<br />
<font color="red">He was born as Nāṇaka.</font> And Nāṇakī was nobody else but Jānakī.<br />
<font color="red">In Nāṇaka's life He has expressed it. Of course I don't know how many people have read about Nāṇak.<br />
Nāṇaka one day was sleeping, and His Feet were towards Kaaba. And people were getting vibrations from that side, so they said: "What are You doing your? Your Feet are towards Kaaba!" So He said, "All right, I'll turn My Feet's on the other side." And they started getting vibrations from the other side. They said, "What? Kaaba has moved or what?"<br />
He has, in a way, showed.<br />
'But how dare They say many things?' When They said very few thing[s], they have killed all these people and tortured Them.<br />
If you read Muhammad Sāhab['s] life, you will feel, 'What foolish people we have been, the way we have tortured [Him]!'<br />
For fanaticism the way He was killed!<br />
Actually was poisoned. He had no place where to hide His head the way people were after Him, because He was telling the Truth.<br />
And fanaticism is one thing He fought.</font><br />
So, Guru Tattwa is killed as soon as you become a fanatic person. Your Guru Tattwa is immediately finished, as soon as you take to fanaticism of any kind!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Another thing is, here in Bhavasāgar, all Three, Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśhwar, combined to make a child, who is called Ādi Guru, is known as Dattātreya. There were many Incarnations of Him. And His Child Tattwa also took Incarnations. First was Dattātreya, then came Rāja Janak. Like this, many Incarnations came, Rāja Janak, Nāṇak, Zarathusrta, Muhammad Sāhab, Sāi Nāth of Śhirḍī.<br />
They are all one. Are They or not? You can witness it after Self-realization. If you believe in one Guru, like Nāṇak, then you have no right not to accept Muhammad Sāhab. If you get Muhammad Sāhab and not Nāṇak, then you have no authority as well."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-032x Public Program (Hindi), Day y, Advertised as 'Kuṇḍalinī Awakening', New Delhi, India (date to be confirmed)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And with Paraśhurāma, Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya had also many Incarnations. But due to Śhrī Dattātreya's collaboration in Śhrī Paraśhurāma's Incarnation, one in karoṛs or lākhs used to get his Realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0527 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Sahaja Yoga Baddal Sarvānna Sangaychee Hi Sahajayogyānchi Jababdari Āhe (Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Before some years back we had Great Guru of Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. No doubt about it, He was an Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya. There is no doubt about His Incarnation. He was a Muslim. You recognized Him, that is important."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0531 Public Program (Marathi), Sahajyog Sgalyāṃnā Samagra Karto (Sahaja Yoga Makes Everyone Holistic), Matunga, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">They are the same people! There are Ten of Them born like that. They are the same people born again and again. And They are the people, if you accept Them, in only one Incarnation, They are not going to accept it. You have to accept Them in all Their Incarnations!</font><br />
I give an example. There was a doctor who was suffering from the cancer of stomach, Muslim. He met Me in London. <font color="red">And when I told him, that, "You have to worship Dattātreya," he got a shock of his life! He said, "You mean to say I must give up my religion?" I said, "Your religion is in ... in imbalance. He was the same as Muhammad Sāhab. Actually Dattātreya incarnated as Muhammad Sāhib." He said, "I cannot do that! I only believe in Muhammad Sāhab!"</font> I said, "All right, I cannot cure your [] ... cancer because cancer is because of imbalance. Is too much activity on one side."<br />
Overactivity of the sympathetic nervous system causes cancer. You write it down today and you can verify it. And that's why when people say I've cured cancer, I have! No doubt! Not only Me, but even this doctor who is here he has cured cancer.<br />
Cancer is only curable through the balance of Sahaja Yoga. Otherwise is not possible! Take it from Me!<br />
So the imbalance of this man, he would not listen but cancer is a vague thing that way.<br />
<font color="red">He had to come back. "All right Mother, I accept You." I said, "All right. Now will you place to ... pray to ... pray to Dattātreya?"</font><br />
A Muslim has to become a Hindu, and a Hindu has to become a Muslim. A Sikh has to become a Muslim, and a Muslim has to become a Sikh."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I wish all of you a very-very happy New Year today because it is Navroz, and Navroz is the day when Zartosht [Zoroaster in Urdu] started His work on this world. He was a great Sahaja Yogi. He was an Incarnation of Dattātreya Himself.<br />
Vaidya Sāhab has told you about Muhammad Sāhab, I have to tell you that He was My Father. And He was the Incarnation of Dattātreya Himself. He was not an ordinary person. Though the people tortured His life. Every moment that He lived, they tortured Him."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>[<font color="orange">WARNING: Quotes after 1977-0321 to follow.</font>]</p>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"For Cancer best treatment is of water i.e. putting feet in the river, sea or in the water at home with the photograph. <font color="red">Water has the religion (Dharma) of cleansing and hence Shri VISHNU and DATTATREYA responsible for the religion (Dharma) of human beings are to be worshiped. They help you to cure and also the local Deity of the Chakra that is attacked.</font> Put the patient before the photograph with the candle and his feet being in the water, bring down your hands across the sympathetic nervous system towards the water. The patient will cool down gradually. If he gets realization, then he is cured."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0000 Letter to Dr. Raul from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 8 (March-April 1982), Page 24</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So the dharma that has been established in us by God Almighty because if we want to go to the Kingdom of God, then in our freedom we must desire to get to God. If someone tries to pressurize us and says, `You must ask for God,' then it is of no use, it is not an evaluation. That is why to reach in this state, a person has to seek the God as per his own independent sweet will and not due to any pressure, or any disease or any hardships or any sorrow, but only because of the fact and realizing that, `It is the only motive of our life to seek God.'<br />
<font color="red">That is why, when we desire for this Divine Gift, then the doors of God Almighty's Divine Blessings open for you, and around the center is a place of Ten Primordial Gurus. These are the Main Gurus which are the Incarnation[s] of Śhri Dattātreya. They are: Socrates, Moses, Muhammad Sāhab, Guru Nāṇak, Śhirḍī Sāi Nāth, and Zoroaster. They are all Incarnation[s] of one Incarnation.</font>"<br />
There is no difference between Muhammad Sāhab and Guru Nāṇak. When Muhammad Sahab saw that people are taking wrong interpretation of His Dharma and doing everything against the dharma, then He was born again as Guru Nāṇak to correct it. Because He wanted to bring unity among people but you know what happened during Their lives.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"If they would have recognized that Sāi Nāth is an Incarnation of Datta, this is very recent, that in your land of Maharashtra He did not even have food to eat. You are such great followers of Datta. Did you recognize Datta?<br />
Now after He is gone, they are worshipping Him. But you have given immense respect to rogues when they were alive."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0115 Public Program (Marathi), Akurdi, Piṃparī Chiṃchavaḍa (18 kms NNW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Dattatreya" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Adi Guru" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ MĀRKAṆḌEYA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0610" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ MĀRKAṆḌEYA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri%20Markandeya</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0610"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"References to Kuṇḍalinī awakening abound in many of the Indian Scriptures. Some of these are Vāsiṣhṭha Yoga, Ṛigveda, Puruṣha Sūkta, Upaniṣhads of Atharvaveda, Yogopanishad, Yogaśhikhā Upaniṣhad, Kaṭhopaniṣhad and Yoga Kuṇḍalinī Upaniṣhad. <font color="red">In the Purāṇas are Devī Bhāgavat[am] Purāṇa, Mārkaṇḍeya Purāṇa, Śhrī Bhāgavat[a] Purāṇa, etc.</font> In Sanhitas: Haṭh[a] Yoga Sanhita, Laya Yoga Sanhita, Rāj Yoga Sanhita, Śhiv Sanhita. In the Yoga tests: Haṭha Yoga Pradīpikā, Saundaryalaharī, Śhubhodayam, Lalitā Sahasrānam, and by Saints such as Bhakt Kabīr, Nāṇak, Gyāneśhwar, etc."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote from the book Divine Knowledge through Vibrations (1992) by P.T. Rajasekharan and R. Venkatesan, Pages 73 and 74</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"You have read Devī Māhātmyam. Not one word is wrong in it. Mārkaṇḍeya Swāmī was a great Seer. Not a word by Him is untrue. Not a word is distorted.<br />
I am sometimes surprised, how far did humans have seen these things so minutely.<br />
......<br />
But have anyone heard Mārkaṇḍeya Swāmī's name? He, in Saptaśhatī, described Śhrī Durgā."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Those people who are very big paṇḍits, if they want they should read Kabīr Dās, Nāṇakjī and if possible also read Śhaṅkarāchārya, He is the best. If you read Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya then you can understand what is this Chaitanya Laharī [Wave of Vibrations], I am talking about.<br />
I have not yet met anyone who has systematically said or explained about Kuṇḍalinī.<br /> 
You know that little knowledge is a dangerous thing. The same can be said about Kuṇḍalinī, otherwise how they could have written this kind of strange things, I do not know on what basis.<br />
<font color="red">But still the Witness State of human being is so high, so high that if you read Devī Bhāgavat[am], Saptaśhatī of Mārkaṇḍeya Swāmī, then you will be surprised how deeply, in small detail,They have understood this thing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"If you read Devī Mahātmyam, a simple book written by Mārkaṇḍeya Swāmī, you will know that all these things given in that: like how to make out a person, who is an Incarnation, who is not an Incarnation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0219 Public Program, Day 3, Gita Mandir Hall, Bhara-tiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0218)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I feel that Ānand (Sadhana's son) is incarnation of Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya. <font color="red">Śhrī Mārkaṇḍeya Swāmī Himself took incarnation as Śhaṅkarāchārya.</font> Kalpana soon will give birth to [a] second gem."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1117 Letter to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar Raul (Marathi), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But you have to be very careful with those horrible destructive forces that have come in so many ways. I can tell you that there are sixteen rākṣhasas whom I know have been taken birth. Mahiṣhāsur is there, Narakāsur is there, Vṛutrāsur is there. There there are six rākṣhasinis who have taken birth. And you have no idea to what they are doing. They'll do all kinds of tricks to convince you that they are godly people.<br />
<font color="red">But you must only ask for the Supreme, for the Last, which is being described by so many Sages like Mārkaṇḍeya, like Śhaṅkarāchārya.<br />
We are so lucky that we have had such great people, who have elaborately said, who have clearly said, that, "This is what is the supreme, ask for the reality. And do not ask for something cheapish.</font>"<br />
You cannot cheapen God. You do not try to mold Him [laughing:] in your own small cups.<br />
......<br />
Above this chakra is the Āgñyā chakra, which is a very, very important chakra, which is the Door, which is the Door of the Sahasrāra. At the Āgñyā chakra resides Mahāviṣhṇu.<br />
<font color="red">Those who have read about Mahāviṣhṇu, in the Mārkaṇḍeya Purāṇa or in the Devī Bhāgavat[am], you will know what I am talking about. But you will not know when He incarnated and who He was.</font><br />
He was nobody else but Jesus Christ."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"This chakra, called Āgñyā chakra, is situated in the middle center where optic nerves cross, called optic thalamus. Śhrī Mahāviṣhṇu is placed in the Āgñyā chakra.<br />
<font color="red">You can read the description of Mahāviṣhṇu in Saptaśhatī, Mārkaṇḍeya, Bhāgavat, or Devī Purāṇa.<br />
But these days you don't read such books and spend time reading Rajneesh.<br />
If you read Devī Bhāgavat, there is a perfect description of Mahāviṣhṇu.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-032x Public Program (Hindi), Day y, Advertised as 'Kuṇḍalinī Awakening', New Delhi, India (date to be confirmed)}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Mārkaṇḍeya discovered all these things through meditation.</font><br />
Now I can tell you these things, it is up to you to verify it.<br />
<font color="red">I asked him: "Why do You want to write?" He told Me, "I must write otherwise they may not recognize You."</font><br />
Today, all the Gods you may recognize in Me whom you call as Nirmalā. It's a very mild Form. But all the Powers are inside and may be used. They have become subtler, simpler. This finger may look dainty to you but it has a very powerful weapon which has killed many rākṣhasas."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1000 Pūjā, Śhrī Mātājī's House, 2, Parklands, Ice House Wood, Hurst Green, Oxted, Surrey, UK (month not sure; also listed as 1974 or 1975)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You can have free cabaret, and you can have free discourses on all the nonsensical things debasing God Himself! All these things are so interesting to human being! Are they really seeking the Truth? Are they really asking the reality?<br />
They will never read Śhaṅkarāchārya!
<font color="red">Yesterday I told you: 'They will never go and find out what Mārkaṇḍeya had written!</font> They have time to find out what Jesus has to say about it. They don't know what Muhammad Sāhab has said.'<br /> 
Nāṇak Sāhab said so many things, Kabīra has said so many things. 'They are all fools!'<br />
These 'wise' have come from somewhere to teach us about all these satanic methods that they want to employ on us. So be ware! Be careful! This is a ghor Kali Yuga. All these satanic forces are acting!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1222 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (English+Hindi), Spirits of the Dead, Sweet Home, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Thirdly we have Swāmī Mārkaṇḍeya and Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya.</font> We call ourselves Hindu, this and that but no one reads Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya's work. Even after reading it no one could understand Him well.<br />
He was such a big devotee of Mother that He won't do anything other than offering prayers to Mother. All the time He kept praying to Mother Bhagavatī and He knew nothing else. He would suggest only to pray to the Mother and anything shall be done. And this is absolutely correct. He said, "Whatever Yoga, etc. you do, will not help you find Divine. You can find [the Divine] only when Mother endows Her blessings, otherwise you just can't find Him. He mentioned this very clearly."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi+English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So that center which is here placed at the crossing point of the optic nerves is known as the Āgñyā chakra. And the Deity placed there is Mahāviṣhṇu.<br />
<font color="red">I don't know how far people have read about Devī or Devī Māhātmyam or Mārkaṇḍeya or even Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya.<br />
Now Mahāviṣhṇu is a creation of Rādhājī, is the Son of Rādhā. He [She] had created Him out of Śhrī Gaṇeśha's essence, and in a special way. And this Child was created in the Vaikuṇṭha Stage, in the Heaven we can say,</font> and He incarnated on this Earth as Jesus Christ."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Christ is Brahm, the Form of Brahm. That's why His physical form is also that of Brahm. You can say a special being was created.<br />
<font color="red">If you read the Devī Bhāgavat[am] although you do not read such things, if you read Mārkaṇḍeya Purāṇ, all such things are mentioned in it. His name was Mahāviṣhṇu. His Father was none other than Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the Virāṭ. The person He keeps talking about, His Father, is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0201 Public Program (Hindi), Brahma kā Gyān (Knowledge of Brahma) or Mūlādhāra to Viśhuddhi, Āgñyā, and Sahasrāra, 9 Raisina Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[<b>Version 1:</b>]<br />
Now this Kuṇḍalinī, Dñyāneśhwar has also talked a lot about It. <font color="red">Mārkaṇḍeya has done the most amount of work on it, so has Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya. They have described and explained it so beautifully.</font><br />
But I am surprised that no one reads the work of Śhaṅkarāchārya. He was a resident of Kerala and He had spent His entire lifetime over there. So it was even more surprising when I came to know that the people from His place didn't even know who He was.<br />
So much ignorance has come into people over there. They think, just because they have been educated in English they are someone special."<br />
[<b>Version 2:</b>]<br />
Now this Kuṇḍalinī is right here, Dñyāneśhwara has also talked a lot about It. <font color="red">Similarly, Mārkaṇḍeya Swāmī and Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya have done the maximum amount of work on It. They have made It lucid and explained It all so beautifully.</font><br />
But I am surprised that no one reads the work of Śhaṅkarāchārya. Not only this but I had been to Kovalam and He belongs to Kerala, He spent his life in Kālaṭi village there, and I was surprised when people over there told Me, "We do not know who this Śhaṅkarāchārya, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya was, whom are you speaking about."<br />
So much ignorance has come into people due to English education.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now I will tell you about Kuṇḍalinī and I will describe one or two experiences about It. You can see with your eyes the pulsation of Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
<font color="red">That is My identity. Mārkaṇḍeya has professed about Me, that, "The Kuṇḍalinī will pulsate at Her Feet." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0227 Public Program (Marathi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Kuṇḍalinī knowledge is very much known to us.<br />
Actually we are so much anglicized, thanks to Lord [Thomas Babington] Macaulay, that a very few people who even know the word Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
If you read Kabīr, the whole thing, Kabīr is nothing but Sahaja Yoga.<br />
How many of you read Kabīr? For fashion sake even if they read they don't know what He is talking about.<br />
Nāṇak has talked about it, Gyāneśhwara has talked about it.<br />
Christ has talked about it that, "I will appear before you like tongues of flames." What is the meaning? Christians do not know about it.<br />
So it is being promised.<br />
Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, of course, the greatest son of our country has described it so elaborately, but those who call themselves also Hindus, do they know the word Kuṇḍalinī? <font color="red">While throughout in the Mārkaṇḍeya Purāṇ, such a Great Sage, the one who has not read the Mārkaṇḍeya, I would not call him an Indian at all.<br />
One of the greatest Sages of this country is Mārkaṇḍeya who has written a complete knowledge about the Devī to such a little extent, to such a small detail that you will be so surprised, 'How He could see all these things? Did He enter into the body of Devī to find out these small small minute things?'</font><br />
But all this we have done in this country much more than any other country."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0328 Public Address, Inauguration of The Advent (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 5--12</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Take the case of our Buddha. Now, Buddha was the ... one of the very Great Incarnations in the sense that He was the son, one of the sons of Rāma, who incarnated on this Earth, Buddha, to occupy the highest life on this Earth. So He had to take saṃnyāsa. Because without that He could not show that.<br />
But there was no need for anybody else to take saṃnyāsa.<br />
But in His case mistakes, uh-uh-uh I mean why there were some mistakes about things were, because when He tried all these tricks of saṃnyāsa, going here and there, He never realized that this is all not needed.<br />
He was so tired and fagged out, that suddenly, spontaneous, the Primordial Mother Herself gave Him the Realization. Because He was so tired.<br />
Now, supposing this is Caxton Hall. To come here, you go to, say, uh-uh-uh-uh Reading, then you go to-oo, in the north, to Leeds, then you go this side and uh-uh-uh then you go to Brighton and come back here. And you tell everybody, "If you have to go to Caxton Hall, you better do all that." It is just like that! It is just like that, very misleading!<br />
Because when He found it out, as you have found out too, you do not realize how you have found it. You do not know how you have done it. If I do not tell you that it is God who has done it, how are you going to believe it? You'll think, 'I have done Self-realization, all right, I am a self-realized person.'<br />
Self is most important.<br />
That's why He believed this a ... anīśhwaratv, means atheism. He said, "There's no God. Only thing, the Self is to be achieved."<br />
Naturally. Because there was nobody to tell Him that, 'You have achieved through the Grace of the Primordial Mother.'<br />
So He was to be born again as one of the sons of Fāṭimah Bi, who was the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab. <font color="red">Then again He was to be born as Mārkaṇḍeya, and again as Śhaṅkarāchārya: just to neutralize what He has been preaching.</font><br />
So you will see that in the sixth century Śhaṅkarāchārya is the one who put end to Buddhism, the nonsense of Buddhism in India. Because, apart from what Buddha's understanding of the whole thing is, the His disciples made it so perverse, that somebody had to come down to tell: that, 'The marriage system has to be re-established.'<br />
And this is how this right side was controlled through various Incarnations coming down."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0611 Public Program, How Aspects of God Are Expressed within Us, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Is a technique which is written in all the Scriptures. Kabīra has described it. If Nāṇaka has described it. All the other Scriptures of Śhaṅkarāchārya has described it. <font color="red">If you read Mārkaṇḍeya, He has described it.</font> Nothing new about it.<br />
But because you do not know it, you are naive about it, that's why you don't understand. But nothing is going to harm you."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0806 Public Program, Self-realization and Fulfillment, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[<b> Version 1:</b>]<br />
"Now, this Gaṇeśha Principle becomes Jesus Christ when He arrived in this world at Āgñyā chakra.<br /> 
<font color="red">Do read Devī Māhātmyam or Devī Bhāgavat[am]. Go through the description of Śhrī Mahāviṣhṇu in it. It is described that Śhrī Rādhājī prepared Her son similarly as Śhrī Pārvatī did it but the main principle in this is Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle and the son prepared as Śhrī Gaṇeśha came in the world as Jesus Christ."</font><br />
[<b> Version 2:</b>]<br />
This Gaṇeśh Tattwa, when It comes on the Āgñyā chakra, It took the form of Christ when It came in this world.<br />
<font color="red">You would have read in Devī Māhātmya[m], the [Devī] Bhāgavat[am] written by Śhrī Mārkaṇḍeya.<br />
You could say Mārkaṇḍeya is My most beloved son.<br /> 
Nowadays nobody reads Mārkaṇḍeya, but if you can get it, read the description of Śhrī Mahāviṣhṇu. He has mentioned that Rādhā had created Her own Son by Herself. Means just as Pārvatī created Her Son, She too had created [Hers].</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0922 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī and Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Navarātri Celebrations (1st Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Two Great Powers are combined in Jesus Christ. The first Power is that of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, who is recognized as His Original Power, and the other is that of Śhrī Kārttikeya.<br />
Because of this, the Incarnation of Jesus Christ is of complete Brahman Tattwa or Oṃkār.<br />
Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, He being the Father of Jesus Christ, bestowed a number of boons on Jesus Christ prior to His birth.<br />
<font color="red">One of these boons was that, "You would dwell on a plane higher than that of mine."</font><br />
This could be explained to mean, that while the plane of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is the Viśhuddhi chakra, located at the base of our neck, the plane of Jesus is Āgñyā chakra, which is located at the junction of the optic thalamus.<br />
<font color="red">The second boon granted by Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was that, "You would be the support of the whole universe."<br />
The third boon was, that, "You would be the first to receive one-sixteenth part of all the offerings made to Me in Pūjā."<br />
In this way, after bestowing a number of boons, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa permitted Śhrī Jesus Christ to incarnate on the Earth.<br />
You would understand these things better, if you read Mārkaṇḍeya Purāṇa. Śhrī Mārkaṇḍeya, the author of the Purāṇa has beautifully explained a number of such subtler points.<br />
In the same Purāṇa, there is a graphic description of Śhrī Mahāviṣhṇu. If you would listen to this description while in meditation, you would notice that the description is of Jesus Christ only.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0927 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Kuṇḍalinī and Lord Jesus Christ, Navarātri Celebrations (6th Day), Hinduja Auditorium, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So all these experimentations are of no use.<br />
As a Mother I'm telling you, 'Please stop it.' Awaken your Lord Gaṇeśha within you, by respecting your chastity!<br />
Our Indian men think that, 'Chastity has no nuh-neah ... no meaning for them. Only the women have to be chaste, and men are not supposed to be chaste at all'! Is more surprising.<br />
Chastity is the most important thing for human beings, to be in the center, because it is Śhrī Gaṇeśha's blessings one gets, then only the Kuṇḍalinī is going to rise.<br />
Now, Śhrī Gaṇeśha has incarnated in this Earth ... on this Earth Himself as Lord Jesus Christ. He came on this Earth as Lord Jesus Christ on this center, what you call the Āgñyā chakra, where I am putting this red thing.<br />
But He has evolved a lot. There are Eleven Rudras, as we call them Ekādeśha [Ekādaśha] Rudras, which are His Powers.<br />
<font color="red">All this is described in the Devī Māhātmyam, Devī Bhāgavat[am]. His name is Mahāviṣhṇu. He is called as the Support of the Universe.<br />
But who reads Devī Bhāgavat[am]? Or who reads Mārkaṇḍeya's books or Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya's books?<br />
They will uh say that, 'We are great Hindus,' and they have not even heard the name of Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya!</font><br />
I went to Kerala and these newspaper people told Me that, "We have never read Him."<br />
In Kerala, such a great man was born, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, I mean they have not read about Him!<br />
He never preached any Hinduism, it's a wrong idea! He said, "Na Yogen na Sāṅkhyen" [part of line 1 of Vivekachūḍāmaṇi 56]. He said, "Not by these philosophies you are gore ... you are going to gain [get] to God. But through Mother's Grace only you will gain that position."<br />
He's clearly said it. He never believed in any such secular uh-uh-uh sort of ideas or any such ideas which meant that, 'This religion is different.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0128 Public Program, Seminar, Day 1, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"One has to know that the powers are tremendous. <font color="red">You cannot conceive it, as it is said by Mārkaṇḍeya. You cannot conceive it.</font> Is beyond your conception. Outwardly, you cannot understand. You just cannot understand.<br />
Under such circumstances, the best thing is: to surrender yourself.&gt;br&gt;
Now, in surrendering, what do you surrender? What do you surrender? Is your ego and your superego."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1019 Havan, Navarātri Celebrations (Dussehra Day), To Solve All Your Problems Is to Surrender, Temple of All Faiths, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, this is the message we have talked today. And, in the same way, we must understand that all the religions have predicted about Christ, and supported Him.<br />
<font color="red">As you know in Mārkaṇḍeya's book, He is described as Mahāviṣhṇu.</font><br />
And they all have talked about Him and He's come on this Earth.<br />
In Hindi to support, the ādhār, is to hold Him. Because He is from the very beginning. As Gaṇeśha is Ādhā-rā and as Christ also is Ādhār.<br />
But what you have done of Him, His spirit, His intellect. So give anything to human beings, and they'll make up with a laugh of it. Just think: the brain is like that. I don't know how you can do that to Him. It's another crucifixion, every moment I feel, the way people have done it."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1020 Public Program, The Way of Kuṇḍalinī, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You'll be amazed, none of the books which have been written so far have been able to tell you about the spiritual be-ing that is within you as you have come to know through Sahaj Yog. One has to accept it. It is so. Any one of them, whosoever has written any books, even, I would say, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, He could not explain so many things which you know.<br />
<font color="red">But the quality of Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya is very great, or people of His type, Mārkaṇḍeya or Buddha, the quality is very high, because They are extremely pure people -- purity. They have achieved individual salvation of a very high degree while you have achieved your collective salvation better. But individually, they are of a very-very high quality. I mean, They had no doubts about Divine Power, They had no doubts about God. They never had any doubts. And They were very dignified. And They never bothered as to Their petty problems of life. For Them, this was too petty to think about. 
"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1201 Public Program, You Are Part of the Divine Being, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Mentions that Her forefathers ruled in Rāhurī and that the Nāth Pānthis worked there.]<br />
<b>Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ:</b> [Asks who were the Nāth Pānthis.]<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> I have so far told you how the evolution was led by Viṣhṇu and His Incarnations on the Earth.<br />
Apart from this there was a unique Incarnation of the Primordial Master, Ādi Guru, in the Void or Bhavasāgara. He incarnated many a times to guide humanity to cross the Void.<br />
These Masters evolved new personalities endowed with the Principles of Disciples or Śhiṣhya Tattwa, who manifested as Great Disciples of this Ādi Guru. The disciples created by Ādi Guru were human beings but they achieved salvation with the help of their Gurus or their own efforts. They were not Divine Incarnations and are known as Avadhūts.<br />
<font color="red">They incarnated on this Earth as other personalities: Solomon, David, Guru Vasiṣhṭha, John the Baptist, second and third Zoroaster, Mārkaṇḍeya, Gaganagaḍ Mahārāj and the Nine Nāths.</font><br />
The Nav Nāths knew that Kuṇḍalinī awakening is the only way you can get your Self-realization. Their attention was enlightened, and they could just put it on matter or anything and it would work.<br />
For instance, Chāṅgadev would put his attention on heat and cook on it!<br />
They had the True Knowledge of the Kuṇḍalinī and went as far as Bolivia and Ukraine to bestow Kuṇḍalinī awakening.<br />
<b>Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ:</b> Are they to be worshiped?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Only Deities are to be worshiped.<br />
<b>Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ:</b> Are there any Avadhūts born in India?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Now Sahaja Yoga has created the environment for many great Souls to take their birth.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1229 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>[<font color="orange">WARNING: Quotes for the period 1981-02 to 2000-04 will follow in due time.</font>]</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"About Kuṇḍalinī, many people knew It long time back.<br />
<font color="red">I must say, there was Mārkaṇḍeya, who was thirteen thousand years back, He has talked about Kuṇḍalinī.</font><br />
Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has talked about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
And later, am I ...  I must say, they were at least sixteen to seventeen Great Saints, seventeen, who have talked about Kuṇḍalinī in the twelve ... in the sixteenth century.<br />
One of them was Guru Nāṇak, who has clearly said: that, "You have to seek it within."<br />
And Kabīr, who is also included in the Grantha Sāhab, has said, [laughing:] that: "It is the Kuṇḍalinī that can give it."<br />
All of Them have said the same thing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0926 Public Program, Day 1, Royal Albert Hall, Kensington Gore, London SW7, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">According to Mārkaṇḍeya, an ancient spiritual giant and author of an important <i>Purāṇa</i>, these demonic forces [tāntrikas] are destroyed many times in physical form, and are sent to hell to suffer untold punishment.</font> In spite of all the punishment they go through there, they never cease in their search to find more subtle and cunning methods of wrecking the morality of human beings who genuinely sought God. Like prisoners released from jail, they return to Earth again and again to wreak their evil against this morality which builds up the sense of religion in man (<i>dharma</i>)."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 6: Tantrism</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">We had a Saint called Mārkaṇḍeya, who they say lived fourteen thousand years ago. He has written about this fourth dimension and has described it as the blessing of the Primordial Mother.</font> The second person who was very well equipped with this knowledge, was Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya who has written many books. The first book he wrote was Vivekachūḍāmaṇi, in which he describes this fourth dimension and explains why we should try to attain this fourth dimension. An intellectual, one Mister Sharma, challenged him and told him that he could not do anything as an ascetic and win over my intellect. Thus he felt that for the common people all this discussion might just seem to be mental acrobatics. So he decided to write books just praising the Primordial Mother, especially in Saundaryalaharī, where he described all the Divine Vibrations as the vibrations of the loving beauty of the Primordial Mother. At that time all this was written in the Sanskrit language but the common people did not understand this language, except for a very few learned people, who also did not want to go into the details of this exposition."&lt;/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 9: Evolution</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Markandeya" /><category term="hotpink @ Disciple Principle" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ PARAŚHURĀMA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0603" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ PARAŚHURĀMA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri_Parashurama</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0603"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"It is very surprising that till today My experience with Haṭha Yogis -- there are many Haṭha Yogis in America also -- has been that all of them have heart troubles. It is very surprising. Haṭha Yogis are especially great worshipers of Śhivjī.<br />
<font color="red">The reason is that Haṭha Yoga is not for people leading a worldly life but for those living in the jungles, like Paraśhurām.</font> It is another thing to do a little within balance, but Haṭha Yoga is not meant for you people. If you do it in extreme, then your heart will suffer from problems."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And after many Incarnations on this Earth, They gave Realization to some people, but very few. And then these people later on started giving Realization to others.<br />
<font color="red">We can say that this all started with Paraśhurāma. When Paraśhurāma was incarnated it was the beginning of individual spirituality. People started learning spirituality by going individually to the forest. But Paraśhurāma was [an] Incarnation.<br />
And with Paraśhurāma, Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya had also many Incarnations. But due to Śhrī Dattātreya's collaboration in Śhrī Paraśhurāma's Incarnation, one in karoṛs or lākhs used to get his Realization.</font><br />
And after this, He also used to sit in the forest. He was next to the Incarnation. People used to get cured by going to Him in case of need. They thought, 'He is a Saint, we should pay our respects to Him.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0527 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Sahaja Yoga Baddal Sarvānna Sangaychee Hi Sahajayogyānchi Jababdari Āhe (Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, they are feelings and also they are uh these uh rajoguṇī expressions, which you can see with your eye, you see the Creation itself.<br />
But they are also feelings.<br />
So, those who can see feelings more, a person who has been very loving and who has dealt uh in this side of life, in ... who has been a bhakti man, you can say a dedicated man, who has been praying to God and crying for Him and asking for His help and weeping before Him with all his heart, such a man uh will uh feel a person more.<br />
And a person who is a ... more dedicated, say, to forms and things, he will see him ... uh see them in a different way as forms.<br />
So, then they see them in colors because they are also colors.<br />
They are also colors and they are also sounds. So the sound is also one of the elements, so they can see a sound.<br />
And they also see them when their Kuṇḍalinī moves. You see, they see the sound moving. And they also saw.<br />
<font color="red">Most of the people who have seen this have been the people who have been uh meditating through this, you can say, the Patañjalā [Patañjali] style of meditation where they were single people, Paraśhurāma style [austere], you see.</font> And they saw these uh forms and they saw the movement of the Kuṇḍalinī through the chakras, when It passes, It creates a sound, a word.<br />
And so, they studied every sound: how which sound was created, what sound was created, what color was there.<br />
And so it is the one-sided knowledge of the right-hand side, of the people who went to the right-hand side that they say, that, 'This thing was created,' 'That thing was created,' and then, 'This sound was created.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0126 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (28th Republic Day), Day 1, Questions on Chakras, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"We had Vāman Avatār, then Paraśhurāmjī incarnated it, then Śhrī Rām incarnated."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You cannot have any rapport with the Divine unless and until you are realized, unless and until you know you are [the] Ātman, your Ātmā. Before that whatever you may try may create a depth in you, a serenity in you, a character in you but still you cannot have a direct rapport. You are to be connected. Now somebody has to do this job. That is why many Incarnations came on this Earth.<br />
You cannot have any rapport with the Divine unless and until you are realized, unless and until you know you are [the] Ātman, your Ātmā. Before that, whatever you may try may create a depth in you, a serenity in you, a character in you but still you cannot have a direct rapport. You are to be connected.<br />
Now somebody has to do this job. That is why many Incarnations came on this Earth.<br />
But somehow human beings do not like Them. They have never liked Them.<br />
The reason is man does not like himself. He cannot believe that in his lifetime an Incarnation can come. If he knew how great he is what a great wondrous thing God has created in him, if he knew what a great mechanism is built within himself, he would not have resisted against Incarnations.<br />
At the time of Rāma He decided, it was decided, that He should not also remember that He is an Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu because even that memory may spoil the game.<br />
<font color="red">But you know Paraśhurāma recognized Him.<br />
There was a trick in that. Paraśhurāma is also an Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu and Śhrī Rām is also an Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu.<br />
Why these two Incarnations came together? Because when Paraśhurāma came, He was a strong man, very strong, fiery, extremely fiery, and in those days people only cared for very strong people. He had captured the hearts of people through His fierce nature.</font><br />
In human beings there are of different levels at different times.<br />
<font color="red">Then when Rāma came and when Paraśhurāma recognized Him, then people had to recognize Rāma."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0328 Public Address, Inauguration of The Advent (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 5--12</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="Peru"><b>Gentleman:</b></font> If ... if there is no karma, does that mean there is no reincarnation?<br /> 
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Well, how can you say that? '[If] there is no karma, there is no rea ... reincarnation,' all these are their ideas, nonsense, they talk like that.<br />
Then why did Kṛiṣhṇa Himself reincarnated so many times on this Earth? Did He have any karmas? He was Yogeśhwara Himself! You should ask them!<br />
<font color="Peru"><b>Lady:</b></font> Who?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Why did He incarnate?<br />
Did He not? <font color="red">He came as a fish, then He came as this and that and that, and then He came as Rāma, Paraśhurāma, and then He came as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.</font><br />
Why? How? Because He at least was beyond karmas."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0616 Public Program, This Is Not the Work of Mediocres, House of Dr. Johnson, Birmingham, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">When Śhrī Rām came, people said that they accepted Paraśhurām,</font> when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came they said, they accepted Śhrī Rām, and at the time of Śhrī Nāṇaka, they accepted Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. When Christ was here they accepted Abraham.<br />
All of Them had taken human form. But it is all the play of buddhi: how interesting it is!<br />
Now, I have come and people are accepting Śhrī Sāī Nāth.<br />
But when He lived here, He did not even get anything to eat. Why was it so? He was also a human being. As long as He was alive, He too was considered useless and tortured. But when He died, He was regarded as Bhagavān.<br />
What is the reason of this all? Why has man been like this?<br />
You will have water of the Ganges, where She flows. If She is flowing here, will you say, 'We do not accept Her as the Ganges!'? There may be nothing at the place where She was flowing earlier, or maybe only a nullah [ravine] at present. If you want to take it as the Ganges, you go your way. If the Ganges is flowing at this place, why not accept it?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0818 Public Program (Hindi), Ātmā and Paramātma, Saradār Patel Vidyalaya (School), Lodi Estate, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"This area, according to Indian mythology, is governed by a Power called Lakṣhmī, which on one side gives us our sustainance [sustenance] and on the other side guides it [us] how to behave.<br />
And from the same Power, the Male Form of that Power incarnates, again and again, to guide the people, in human form.<br />
This Incarnation in the beginning was a fish, when we were fishes. When we were tortoises, It was a tortoise, when we were reptiles It was a tortoise. Then we were quadrupeds, we ... It was a boar. Then later on It became half man and half uh half lion. Then It became a small man, short man. <font color="red">Then It became the very strong man, Paraśhurāma.</font> Then He came as Śhrī Rāma. At His completion, He came as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0419 Public Program, Day 4, Spiritual Evolution of Man, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Only twelve people somehow, you see, managed to be there, somehow. They would not accept Him either. Till He was resurrected, then they accepted Him, in a way.<br />
And then what are you going to do but to create a myth around it‽ And to say that, 'Of course, we believed in Christ.'<br />
Now what, which Christ did you believe in? Because that Christ, whom you had to face, you did not face. And now you live in imaginary world! You have your own paradise about it.<br />
Where does He live within us? Has He created any position within us? Is there any meaning to His life, which has left a permanent mark within us? Was He even [one] of the milestones within us? If so, where does He reside within us? How can we be connected to Him?<br />
Nobody made any exploration about it. Again the comfortable shell started.<br />
It has happened not once, thousands of years it has been happening: whenever an Incarnation came on this Earth that's how they behaved.<br />
<font color="red">When Rāma came they said, "We believe in Paraśhurāma."</font> [Laughing:] Then Kṛiṣhṇa came they said, "We believe in Rām."<br />
Same thing with Christ, with everyone.<br />
But you better now recognize and know your Self, and face it once for all, the time has come. How long are you going to live with your myths? The time has come."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0421 Public Program, What Is Second Birth, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">But the controversy, why one starts, is this way: that, when Rāma came, people said, "We don't believe in You. We believe in one Paraśhurāma!"</font> Because Paraśhurāma was dead by then! Very good idea! Never face the reality when it comes to you! Then came Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, six thousand years back, so when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa started talking about Reality, they said, "You see, You don't tell us. We only believe in Rāma!" When Rāma lived, they put Him out for fourteen years in the forest, very nicely! <font color="red">They never believed in Him: they only believed in Paraśhurāma.</font> Now, when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came, they said, "You see, we believed only in Śhrī Rām, and not in You. Śhrī Rāma was our thing."<br />
So, Kṛiṣhṇa did not tell anything about Reality, only told one disciple, that's Arjuna, that, too, was not realized."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0720 Public Program, The Force that Lies Within, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then the sustainance [sustenance] start[s] growing, till you become a human being, as shown [points to the Chakra Chart:] here.<br />
[Circling:] In this Void, [points to Mūlādhāra chakra:] here as carbon, [pointing to the Nābhī chakra:] then you move into the Void. And here, you go through all the evolution, starting from a fish up to the human level, where you become a small man.<br />
Once you become the small man, Vāmana is called that. First the man who came on the Earth was a small statured man.<br />
<font color="red">Then a man came who was Paraśhurāma, a very, very ... Poseidon, a very large man, huge man.<br />
Two extremes.</font><br />
And then came the man who was in the center."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Public Program (1st Day and 2nd Day of Navarātri), Self and Heart Chakra, Day 6, East West Center, 141 5th Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, this movement was on the right-hand side.<br />
Right-hand side was the Vedas where they tried to discover the Deities that are ruling the sun, the ruling the moon, the ruling the uh, say, uh-uh ... the sea. The sea is ruled by Neptune, and it's called as Passidon [Poseidon] in this Greek way.<br />
<font color="red">And also they knew about Paraśhurāma. See as He, Paraśhurāma, who came before Rāma. And He's one of the persons who is an Eternal Being, He moves in every way. He is but the one who is respected as Zeus. But people are quite confused, because the Greeks brought all the Gods to their level.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1013 Public Program, Day 2, John Muir Elementary School, 1721 Ocean Park Boulevard, Santa Monica (23 kms W of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now the light which is past, gone, cannot enlighten you. That's finished. That is there, that is there to help you, but it cannot enlighten you, cannot give you Realization.<br />
You have to have some living light which is just now burning before you, to enlighten you.<br />
So when They came you said, "No, no, no, no, no, not this, not this, not this." "We believe."<br />
<font color="red">Say like when Rāma came they said, "We believe in Paraśhurāma."</font> When Kṛiṣhṇa came, they said, "We believe in Rāma." When Buddha came they said, "We believe in Kṛiṣhṇa."<br />
Very good. Not to believe in the person who has come now, but to believe in something that was there. Why? Because it 'helps' you a lot.<br />
Actually it does not.<br />
But you can use that Guru as you like. About Kṛiṣhṇa you can say what you like. About Rāma what, you say what you like. About Nāṇaka you say what you like. About everybody you can say what you like. That, 'He said so,' 'He said so,' they all feel they have become themselves the gurus. Because you can use them also very well.<br />
But they cannot give you Realization, that's a fact."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0223 Public Program (English+Hindi), Day 6, The Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple (Āśhram), Deities that Adorn the Centers, and After Self-realization, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India (place not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"His brother knew about it.<br />
Now He had two brothers, very interesting. I mean he had other brothers also, but Bharat and another was Lakṣhmaṇa. These were two brothers were with Him.<br />
Now they show the two sides of a human being.<br />
One was Lakṣhmaṇa, and he was that fiery type, you see. He couldn't bear anybody misbehaving towards Rāma. He couldn't bear anybody talking in a very mundane type to Śhrī Rāma. And he used to get so angry with all these people, that he would just come out like a big thunderbolt on anybody who tried to say anything about Śhrī Rām.<br />
<font color="red">Even Paraśhurāma who was, there, a contemporary Incarnation of Śhrī Rāma Himself was Paraśhurāma. Is a very interesting story about that.<br />
But, he could not bare Paraśhurāma in any way</font> [<font color="Orange">gap</font>]<br />
...... He is the Śheṣha as they call it: the ... the serpent which sleeps in the Bhavasāgara, on which Śhrī Viṣhṇu rests. The same Śheṣha had taken birth as Śhrī Lakṣhmaṇa."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0402 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā, Rāma Navamī, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The original sin is the big problem. The biggest problem was that.<br />
Now to solve it up, one had to do all these things.<br />
So first the Vāmana Avatāra came.<br />
<font color="red">After the Vāmana Avatāra came the Incarnation of a very tall and a hefty man. That was Paraśhurāma. That I don't know, in the Greek philosophy, if Zeus was Paraśhurāma, because it sounds like Zeus. Because Paraśhurāma is contemporary of Rāma Himself. Because somebody had to announce. You see, it is necessary that somebody must announce the Advent, at that time it was necessary. So Paraśhurāma came. The tall and a hefty man, who came on this Earth, maybe Zeus is called. I mean they are so confused that, you see, to ... to relate this to that, is another confusion. I don't know how. But looks like Zeus.<br />
But He is the Incarnation of ... o[f] this sustainance [sustenance] force within us, sustainance [sustenance] force: the one that gives us religion, the one [that] gives us ascent.<br />
So He came on this Earth, you can say, at the same time as Rāma came. And then He appeared on the scene at a point where Rāma tried to break the bow which was given by Paraśhurāma. And Paraśhurāma wanted to find out the Incarnation. So He gave this bow to a King, whose wife ... whose daughter was Sītā.</font><br />
She was this central path of Mahālakṣhmī. She came on this Earth as the Central Power of Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
Later on She incarnated as the Mother of Christ."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1029 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Creation, Original Sin, and Incarnations, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"This is a kind of emotional thing that, 'I am a sad person.'<br />
The second emotional feeling is that, 'I have a lot of faith in God.'<br />
<font color="red">When Śhrī Rām came on this Earth people said, "We do not believe in Rām. We believe in Paraśhurām." When Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came people started to say, "We believe in Śhrī Rām."</font><br />
Now, if someone else incarnates, people will say, "We believe in Lord Kṛiṣhṇa." Is Kṛiṣhṇa standing in front of you today? You should think about who is standing in front of you.<br />
We have no tendency to live in the present. People prefer staying in the past and become passionate about these feelings.<br />
Then we notice that both kinds of people, intellectuals and emotional people, become fanatics.<br />
This fanaticism gets stuck to one emotion. This emotion then gets stronger and stronger, but it's a blind faith. It's a blind faith that the pure desire of these human being gets destroyed, exactly like a river flowing through, that enters a pile of sand and gets finished there.<br />
Similarly, our pure desire to attain Union with God gets disturbed and vanishes here and there."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-1204 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Hindus are the same it, extremely fanatical.<br />
They have a funny custom of having caste system, which was never, never preached before.<br />
Actually the one who wrote Gītā, was Vyāsa, who was the illegitimate child of a fisherwoman.<br />
So how could you say that you are born as a Brahmin?<br />
Vālmīki who wrote Rāmāyaṇa was a man who was a thief, and also a fisherman, and he became such a Great Saint.<br />
<font color="red">None of the Incarnations took birth in the Brahmin family except for Paraśhurāma's.</font><br /> 
So the so-called Brahmins today who say that they are the ones who are the fundamental Hindus, should know that they are not."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0315 Public Program, Day 2, Where Are Religions Leading, Royal Exhibition Building, Carlton Gardens, 9 Nicholson Street, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">They say that, "Paraśhurām was attracted to[wards] women." How is this possible? Are bāpū! He was so harsh, how could He be attracted to[wards] women? Viṣhṇu was depicted in another dirty form.</font><br />
Like this they defamed all God and Goddesses."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0325 Chaitra Navarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Sahajyogiyo Keliye Bhartiya Sanskṛiti ka Mahatva (Importance of Indian Culture for Sahaja Yogis), Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But main thing one should understand that, 'If you have to grow, we have to be without any thought. And whatever we were doing, before coming to Sahaja Yoga, gives us a thought.'<br />
Like if they are Christians, they'll talk about Christ, all the time. Bābā, just now forget Christ, I'm sitting before you. Now where is Christ? I'm sitting [before] you. Where is Rāma? Where is Kṛiṣhṇa?<br />
Like Venugopalan said, "You see I don't know anyone. I only know my Mother. She's given me Realization. Now, if you want to talk about Others, I'll believe it because Mother says, 'They are true.' But otherwise I don't know Them. Now I know only my Mother. She's given me Realization."<br />
But this is the trouble to stand in the present.<br />
<font color="red">Always we did that. When Rāma was here, we used to talk about somebody else, Paraśhurāma. Then when Kṛiṣhṇa came, they used to talk about Rāma.</font><br />
Now when I have come, you are talking about Kṛiṣhṇa. Where is He?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0129 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Proper Understanding of Sahaja Yoga, before the Carnatic Vocal Concert by Tv. Gopala Kṛiṣhṇana, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Why, whas [what's] the matter with you? Why? What is it? You come and sit here, this side. Come along, Tina! Come and sit on the other side! Why do you talk to her? Go and sit at the back! Go.<br />
She's already given Me a very bad time in Poona [Pune]. And now, here she is.<br />
While I'm talking, please don't talk to each other! This is the least you can do to Me. Have you seen any Indians behaving like this?<br />
[After 12 seconds:] Is very disturbing!<br />
I'm concentrating on you, while you are not concentrating on Me.<br />
It's all right: when there's a joke, something you laugh, bu[t] whas [what's] the need to talk to each other? I can't understand!<br />
All right.<br />
Sorry, I had to say that, you see, at the time when I'm discussing Śhrī Rāma. Śhrī Rāma would not have said that. [Smiles, some laughter.]<br />
But in Sahaja Yoga [raises Her shoulders], you can't carry on like Śhrī Rāma. <font color="red">Sometimes you have to be like Paraśhurāma also, otherwise things don't work out.</font><br />
......<br />
[After the crown is removed, before Āratī with the garland on, refers to the second bow:] [Laughs.] Is kamāl hai [is (a) feat]! Is a real professional one!<br />
<font color="red">So, one belongs to Paraśhurāma and one belongs to Rāma!</font>" [Laughter.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1004 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Maryādā Puruṣhottama and Message of Sītā's Life (Very Great Achievement Within Ourselves), Centre International, Les Avants, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Not only it has happening within us in our everyday life, but also in religious life I have seen it happens.<br />
<font color="red">When Śhrī Rāma came on this Earth, they said, "We believe only in Paraśhurāma," because He's dead now, finished. If He is dead is better to believe in a person who is dead.</font> Then Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came, they said, "We don't believe in You: we believe in Śhrī Rāma." Because He's dead!<br />
They never want to believe in something that is living today, from where you can gain. But they want to believe in something that is dead and finished. Because you can keep such a person in the pocket. Nobody is going to ask you. If Christ is not living, He's not going to say, 'Why did you do this wrong?'<br />
So, people don't want to take anything in the present, but present is the truth."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1013 Public Program, Day 2, Auditorium Maximum, University, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The Devaloka was formed here, and Devas were here, they ruled here, no doubt, but in the human awareness they were brought down to the human level.<br />
<font color="red">Like Zeus was Paraśhurāma. Paraśhurāma: the One who was an Incarnation to announce the Advent of Śhrī Rāma. And He came before Śhrī Rām, eah ... died also very much before Śhrī Rām. But they painted Zeus as a man who, who was a womanizer.</font><br />
So, all Gods were brought to the level of human beings, with ... 'bestowed' with all the weaknesses, you see. Actually 'decorated' with all the weaknesses. [Laughing:] Like that."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0524 Śhrī Pallas Athena Pūjā, The Origins and Role of Greece, House of Stamatis Boudouris, Athens, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> What is it?<br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> This is ...<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> This is Zeus, yeah?<br />
<b>Same Sahaja Yogi:</b> ... Zeus.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Zeus, Zeus.<br />
<b>Same Sahaja Yogi:</b> Yes. [].<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So is very good today because of Lakṣhmī. After all, Lakṣhmī is a ...<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> With Zeus.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b>: Zeus is the Paraśhurāma Avatār.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0624 Śhrī Lakṣhmī Pūjā, Summer House of Stamatis Boudouris, Island of Hydra, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But as human beings have evolved, even the Deities have evolved Themselves accordingly. <font color="red">So it was a fish, and then, then a tortoise, and like that, it went on, till we come to the stage of Vāmana Avatāra where it was a small man, then a big man, a tall, big man, a Greek, who we call as Zeus, is Paraśhurāma.</font> And then came Śhrī Rā... Śhrī Rām."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0817 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before the Evening Program, the Friday before Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And He used their powers, you see. For what? For creating so many things.<br />
Like, if Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had not come we would not have known really the significance of spiritual life. He was the first who talked of spiritual life.<br />
Rāma did not talk of spiritual life, though there was an undercurrent in India. People knew there is spiritual life because there were Saints, there were uh-uh lots of uh-uh-uh, what you call the, uh-uh-uh Seers, all of them were talking about it. But no Incarnation talked about spiritual life.<br />
<font color="red">We had Vāmana Avatāra, then we had Paraśhurāma, we had so many of these people, never, never They talked of spiritual life, never.</font><br />
It was Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa only who first started talking about spiritual life, and only to Arjuna He talked. Because, you see, what was the condition: people were not prepared. So those people, Sahaja Yogis, who feel frustrated today, because there are not many Sahaja Yogis or the there's a[n] obstruction, there are certain problems, must know that at the time of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, He could dare speak about spirituality only to one person, and that one was Arjuna.<br />
So, I mean, we are much better off, you see? [As laughter starts:] Aren't we?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0819 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"His channel is the evolutionary path, and His Ten Incarnations of the Virāṭa have helped mankind to evolve:<br />
......<br />
<font color="red"><i>vi. Strong Man</i> ............................................................... Paraśhurāma Avatāra</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Page 14</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">His sixth form was as the Strong Man (Paraśhurāma). He brought forth the powers achieved by self-control (<i>tapobala</i>).</font> When they were fully evolved human beings developed their 'I'-ness and felt a need to seek the unknown within themselves. They began to think about God, and became aware of the strengths of spiritual life, and started a new search of the inner life. The search was an individual one, and the seeker absolutely secluded himself from society. Many renounced the world and went into complete retreat in the forests and jungles in search of the Ultimate Reality, often pursuing their quest day and night for years on end, and often for life after life. <font color="red">Paraśhurāma was the founder of Haṭha and Rāja Yoga which were practiced all alone under the guidance of a guru.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 32</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Ādi Śhakti incarnated as Durgā a thousand times to protect such Saints, and apart from these full Incarnations She also manifested Her Powers through many chaste women of India in a partial form (<i>Aṃśhāvatāra</i>). <font color="red">The Incarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu as Paraśhurāma. (the Strong Man) created an awareness of the techniques of physical and mental powers. Seekers discovered many new methods of meditation through such discoveries.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7: Haṭha Yoga and Rāja Yoga, Page 105</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><a href="http://bit.ly/3x3O6L7">Download pdf here</a></p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Parashurama" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Vishnu" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quotes on Śhrī Reṇukā, Version 4</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0522" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quotes on Śhrī Reṇukā, Version 4" /><published>2022-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/Shri_Renuka_Devi_V4</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0522"><![CDATA[<p>Please find attached the pdf file <font color="blue">Shri_Renuka_Devi_V3.pdf</font> obtained by searching for Śhrī <font color="red">Reṇukā</font>.</p>

<p>This version has a quote from 1 extra talk. We would like to thank Anne-Marie Ene for pointing out this quote.</p>

<p>If by chance extra quotes on <font color="blue">Śhrī Reṇukā</font> are found out, please kindly share them with all of us.</p>

<p>Please share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/Shri_Renuka_Devi_V4.pdf">Download pdf here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Renuka" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahasaraswati" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please find attached the pdf file Shri_Renuka_Devi_V3.pdf obtained by searching for Śhrī Reṇukā.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quotes on Śhrī Anasūyā, Version 2</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0521" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quotes on Śhrī Anasūyā, Version 2" /><published>2022-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/Shri_Anasuya_V2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0521"><![CDATA[<p>Please find attached the pdf file <font color="blue">Shri_Anasuya_V2.pdf</font> obtained by searching for Śhrī <font color="red">Anasūyā</font> or Śhrī <font color="red">Anusūyā</font>.</p>

<p>This version has quotes from 3 extra talks and is 3 pages longer.</p>

<p>If by chance extra quotes on <font color="red">Śhrī Anasūyā</font> are found out, please kindly share them with all of us.</p>

<p>Please share the files with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/Shri_Anasuya_V2.pdf">Download pdf here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Anasuya" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahasaraswati" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please find attached the pdf file Shri_Anasuya_V2.pdf obtained by searching for Śhrī Anasūyā or Śhrī Anusūyā.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quotes on Śhrī Narasiṃha Avatāra, Version 2</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0515" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quotes on Śhrī Narasiṃha Avatāra, Version 2" /><published>2022-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/Shri_Narasimha_Avatara_V2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0515"><![CDATA[<p>Please find attached the pdf file <font color="blue">Shri_Narasimha_Avatara_V2.pdf</font> obtained by searching for Śhrī <font color="red">Narasiṃh</font>.</p>

<p>This version has quotes from 8 extra talks and 1 book and is 13 pages longer.</p>

<p>If by chance extra quotes on <font color="red">Śhrī Narasiṃha</font> are found out, please kindly share them with all of us.</p>

<p>Please share the files with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/Shri_Narasimha_Avatara_V2.pdf">Download pdf here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Narasimha" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Vishnu" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please find attached the pdf file Shri_Narasimha_Avatara_V2.pdf obtained by searching for Śhrī Narasiṃh.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quotes on Śhrī Mandodarī, Version 3</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0510" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quotes on Śhrī Mandodarī, Version 3" /><published>2022-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/Shri_Mandodari_V3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0510"><![CDATA[<p>Please find attached the pdf file <font color="blue">Shri_Mandodari_Version_3.pdf</font> obtained by searching for Śhrī <font color="red">Mandodarī</font> and for the demon <font color="red">Rāvaṇa</font>.</p>

<p>This version has a quote from 1 extra talk. We would like to thank Anne-Marie Ene for pointing out this quote.</p>

<p>If by chance extra quotes on <font color="blue">Śhrī Mandodarī</font> are found out, please kindly share them with all of us.</p>

<p>Please share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/Shri_Manadodari_Version_3.pdf">Download pdf here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Mandodari" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahakali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please find attached the pdf file Shri_Mandodari_Version_3.pdf obtained by searching for Śhrī Mandodarī and for the demon Rāvaṇa.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quotes on Śhrī Reṇukā, Version 3</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0504" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quotes on Śhrī Reṇukā, Version 3" /><published>2022-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/Shri_Renuka_Devi_V3</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0504"><![CDATA[<p>Please find attached the pdf file <font color="blue">Shri_Renuka_Devi_V3.pdf</font> obtained by searching for Śhrī <font color="red">Reṇukā</font>.</p>

<p>This version has 1 quote from an extra talk and 2 extra versions of prior quotes, while everything has been updated.</p>

<p>If by chance extra quotes on <font color="blue">Śhrī Reṇukā</font> are found out, please kindly share them with all of us.</p>

<p>Please share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/Shri_Renuka_Devi_V3.pdf">Download pdf here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Renuka" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahasaraswati" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please find attached the pdf file Shri_Renuka_Devi_V3.pdf obtained by searching for Śhrī Reṇukā.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quotes on Śhrī Mandodarī, Version 2</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0427" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quotes on Śhrī Mandodarī, Version 2" /><published>2022-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/Shri_Mandodari_V2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0427"><![CDATA[<p>Please find attached the pdf file <font color="blue">Shri_Mandodari_Version_2.pdf</font> obtained by searching for Śhrī <font color="red">Mandodarī</font> and for the demon <font color="red">Rāvaṇa</font>.</p>

<p>This updated version also has quotes from 2 extra talks.</p>

<p>If by chance extra quotes on <font color="blue">Śhrī Mandodarī</font> are found out, please kindly share them with all of us.</p>

<p>Please share the file with all our brothers and sisters.</p>

<p>Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>The Quotes on Incarnations Team</p>

<p><a href="http://seven-teams.github.io/files/Shri_Manadodari_Version_2.pdf">Download pdf here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Mandodari" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahakali" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Please find attached the pdf file Shri_Mandodari_Version_2.pdf obtained by searching for Śhrī Mandodarī and for the demon Rāvaṇa.]]></summary></entry></feed>