<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-08-08T18:13:47-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Quotes</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ JESUS CHRIST in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0808" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ JESUS CHRIST in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Jesus_Christ</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0808"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Christ was concerned all the time with the benevolence of the world. Christ was knowledge. He knew His goal. He spoke the Truth with complete courage, intensity and dedication."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Śhrī Jesus Christ from Akashwani, Volume I, Issue IV (May 2000), Page 3</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Mary was in Her own right a Divine Being. She was venerated as such by Christ and some of the suppressed Scriptures describe Her as the Holy Spirit incarnate[d]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Śhrī Mary from Akashwani, Volume I, Issue XII (December 2000), Page 3</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"It was the power of Christ's discretion that made others discrete."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Discretion from the book Insights, Inspirations and Eternal Moments, Chapter 44, Page 140 by Yogi Mahajan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"According to me, Hazrate [Hazarat] Muhammad was one of the greatest incarnations because he was even greater than a Prophet. He announced some prophecies which none of the incarnations, such as Jesus, had described. The first thing he said was that we must have Meerraj [Mirāj], meaning the ascent through different levels. And at the third level he described how he met with all the previous Prophets such as Ibrahim, and he described the ascent on the white horse which is actually the power of Kundalini [Kuṇḍalinī]. Secondly, he said that when you receive your realization you have to fully surrender, meaning ``Islam", and then your hands will speak. He did not condemn any previous religion or incarnation. For example, the Kabe Makeshwara [Kaaba Makkeśhwara] is also described in the Indian Koran [Qur'ān]. And thirdly, he described the next advent that is going to come. He never said that he was the last one. What shows that he never said he was the last is that he said that I am the seal, meaning that he was the stamp of the Prophets. He described the work of the advent of Mandi [Mahdī]. The word of Mandi [Mahdī] actually means the incarnation of the great primordial Mother -- Ma + Adi [Ādi]. No one has prophesised [prophesized] so clearly about Sahaja Yoga except for Hazrate [Hazarat] Muhammad who has described Sahaja Yoga in his great book of Koran [Qur'ān]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-0000 Letter Published in the Turkish Newspaper Bursa</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"In the life of Jesus Christ (incarnation of Maha Vishnu) the highest expression of the essence of spiritual innocence came on this earth. Human beings witnessed the sacrifice of the dearest and only son of the Father (Virata) for the sake of humanity. This allowed a deeper human perception for God's great love for humanity. The crucifixion of Christ happened at a time when people knew about Go almighty the Father but did not know how to crucify their human self to make the spiritual self express itself; tis is the meaning of the Resurrection of Christ by which man could be the physical witness of the immortality of the spirit which does not suffer or perish. The human awareness first time registered the truth of immortality of spirit which Krishna preached in his lifetime."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Vision of the Virāṭa related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"At the Agnya chakra She resides as Mary (Mahalaxmi) mother of Jesus Christ [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Residing on Chakras</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Shri Krishna and His power Radha beget a son called as MahaVISHNU who is created as a saviour with the esence of Shri Ganesha[.] Ganeshas [Ganesha's] brother become [becomes] the body of MahaVISHNU. This powerful essence of Godliness is born in this world as Jesus Christ. As He is placed on the crossing of two channels in the Primordial being[,] He controls the ego and super ego of man and is the dor to enter into the last chakra of Sahastrara."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Evolution Led by Viṣhṇu and His Incarnations</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"How much did we pay to Christ? How much did we pay to Mother Earth for these flowers? "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1904-0000 Public Program, Ocean of Joy, U.S.A. (likely 1993 + in)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"You killed Christ! You all killed Him!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1904-0000 Public Program, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Christ has said a parable, and this is the parable: "Again I tell you, the seeds which have sprouted have to grow into trees." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1904-0000 Public Program</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"For example, if you say that, `Christ was resurrected in person?' `Yes, that's true.' You'll get more vibration[s]. But if you see now, that if you say, `Is it Mātājī the Mother of Christ?' If you do not accept it, you will not get it on the Sahasrāra. It should be the S......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1904-0000 Public Program, UK (likely)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"She ... She ... She .... uh awakens Christ over here, inside you, and sucks these two in, ego and superego, and then creates a space here. And these two just go down."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1904-0000 Public Program, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Beware, dear aspirants.<br />
There is a Judas within us. Be careful. He walks with us, works with us. Sings the praises of the Divine Mother, but he is an ugly serpent, the representative of the Satan, who is in disguise. He helped to crucify Christ in a sly manner. He may be a woman like Pūtanā, who came to poison the child Kṛiṣhṇa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1905-0000 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Beware, Dear Aspirants from The Life Eternal, 1980 Issue, Page 25</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1905-0000 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, On the Essences of Elements</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I have read a book about Jesus coming to India in Kashmir and meeting one of the Kings of Śhālivāhana. The meeting is quoted from an ancient book of Purāṇas, in Sanskrit, which perhaps, the writer doesn't know. It is written that Śhālivāhana King asked Jesus his name, and he said his name was Īsā Masīh and he asked him: ``Why are you here in this country?" He said: ``I have come from a country where people are `Mlecchas'. Mlecchas are the people who have a desire to be only filthy or to be vulgar and immoral." In those days, foreigners were all called ``Mlecchas" in India because Indians believed that they had no idea of purification or transformation. Whatever may be the case, this was the conversion between Śhālivāhana and Lord Jesus Christ. So Śhālivāhana asked him: ``Why you do not go back and cleanse these people and teach them about Nirmal Tattwa?" (means the Principle of Cleansing). Thus, I think Christ went back and was crucified within three and a half years by the Romans who were not keen about their salvation. Now the way the Church of England is trying to support illegal marriages, etc., taking the support of the gene's theory shows how the Indians were right calling the Westerners ``Mlecchas." I have dealt with this gene's theory in the chapter of Metascience.<br />
......<br />
Christ has said that you have to cleanse yourself, you have to control your attention and you have to see, through your introspection, what is wrong with you, and try to cleanse yourself. Otherwise, he said (in the chapter written by Matthew, in the Bible) ``that if your one eye does the sin, (even if you look at a woman twice) you better take out your eyes. If your hand does anything wrong, anything sinful, cut out your hand." He said: if somebody slaps you on one cheek, to turn the other cheek to that person. Imagine Christians tolerating even one slap on the face?<br />
When you see the Christian people in the Christian nations, the way they killed people all over the world, one wonders, by what yard-stick they call themselves Christians. One can very well understand that these are all absolutely impossible rules and regulations for the advanced modern persons to follow. These hard rules may not have been propagated by Christ, but may have been introduced by Paul who was a squatter in the Bible and who edited it. He was epileptic according to the Principles of Sahaja Yoga. He was possessed and wrote all kinds of lies through Peter who was the weakest disciple of Christ. How could Christ give him the keys to build a church on seven hills? On the contrary, He said: ``The Satan will take you over". Who is this Satan? The anti-Christ.<br />
It's not possible for anybody to be worthy of the Christian religion because they have to be extremely sensitive to sinful actions like Saints or angels. I haven't seen anybody with a cut hand or with eyes missing in the whole of the Christian kingdom. This proves that their belief in Christ is followed only up to the point of going to the church, listening to the sermons preached by a person who is not even a realized Soul, and who has not had his Divine Baptism.<br />
It is very surprising, because our mayor in Italy asked me: ``How is it there are so many people attending your program for hours together. They never get bored. While when we are in the church, after fifteen minutes, we start looking at our watches, and after half an hour, we just run out of the church. It is just a social event but it so very boring that after the lecture we feel like going to the pub, otherwise we start fighting with each other." After the blessing of the Trinity, why should they be so anxious to drink and get lost?<br />
Thus, we find that, in the Christian countries, people are behaving in an absolutely opposite manner to what Christ had asked them to do. He had gone into a very subtle side of purity that says, ``Thou shall not have adulterous eyes" while in the Ten Commandments, it was only said: ``Thou shall not commit adultery". If you are observant, you will be shocked to see that it is very hard to find any man or woman in the Western countries who does not have adulterous eyes. Of course it is different, if they are blind, or too old to flirt with their eyes. They are always moving their eyes from one person to another person with lust or greed. It's impossible to understand how they can move their attention so fast from one person to another, unless some screws are loose in their brains, like a doll, which has screws that control the eye balls. The eyes start moving very fast like flirts. They might become mad or get possessed by one thing or another. In fruitless pursuit, how can the human attention be so mobile?<br />
After Christ came Muhammad Sāhib, and perhaps He felt that if all these rules and regulations were written down they were only for men. But what about the women? So He said something should be done about the women. If they follow an absolutely moral path, then men will be also automatically moral. He respected holy women. He had great respect for Christ's Mother and also for women as a whole. In the Bible She is called as an ordinary woman. The idea of Madonna came from the Pagan religion which existed before Christ. But Muhammad Sāhib, who was the Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Prophet), knew who was the Mother of Christ. In Sahaja Yoga She is worshiped as Mahālakṣhmī. He did not want many women to be immoral and take to prostitution. For a married woman, there are very strict punishments. It is said that in the Qur'ān He said: ``Any woman, who is immoral, must be buried in the sand halfway and should be stoned," (sometimes, she could be dead.) I wonder if He said such a thing, or if it was Muʿāwiyah [ibn Abī Sufyān] who edited the Qur'ān. But the way they follow it in the Islamic countries is really sinful to give this kind of punishment to all those who are considered immoral women. Whatever it is, it is very difficult, in these modern times, to find very moral people after the pattern that Muhammad Sāhib thought.<br />
He accepted many marriages because He didn't want women to have relationship without marriage. In those days, there were many women who survived after the death of their husbands, in the wars they had among the tribes. There were many young girls who had no chance of marriage, as many young people were killed in the wars they had in the different tribes against Muhammad Sāhib. Whatever He did at that time (samayāchār), was very essential to create a new generation of very pure and compassionate people. Both Jesus Christ and Muhammad Sāhib were not only divine but they were Incarnations who had a Special Mission to come on this Earth.
......<br />
Now, in Islamic fundamentalism, the main problem Is that they say they are fighting the Western culture. Firstly, we must understand that Western culture, which today is nowhere near what Christ has talked about. Immorality has become the lifestyle of human beings in the West, but what about the immorality the Muslims are indulging in secretly whenever they get the chance? They can be worse than Christians.<br />
......<br />
In these nations, in their private life, or in society can one find that they try to imbibe the great qualities that our Lord Jesus Christ has taught? Only in name are they followers of Christ; for political control, they use religions without any substance of these great religions. All of them are making money and are not willing to accept the universal pure innate religion, which is the fountain-head of all these religions. Their own standard of understanding moral life is really very shocking. For example, they believe in heavy drinking, because they say that in the Christian religion, drinking is allowed as Christ went to a wedding and there he made wine out of water. The word ``wine" is used in the Hebrew language, even for grape juice, and also for grape wine.<br />
How did they interpret that he made Benedictine, French wine or Scotch Whisky. It is very simple to understand the logic that you cannot create alcoholic wine in a short time spontaneously. It has to ferment, and then it becomes a very good, expensive alcoholic wine that can cause intoxication. If it is a very, very old smelly, rotten wine, one can sell it for a very high price. This is not the same wine that was created by Christ at all. It is very easy to understand that he was constantly preaching for a higher awareness. Therefore how could he try to subscribe something like alcoholic intoxicating wine, which is anti-spiritual in nature and which reduces awareness.<br />
In Canada, I met a scholar who had a doctorate from some English university. To my surprise, he had written a thesis on how alcohol creates more awareness for Divinity. Moreover, many people in Europe believe that by taking drugs they can get a very high awareness to achieve their divine ascent. It is all absurdity to the last limit, but who can tell them. They can't talk to you after six o'clock anyway, especially in France, as they all start drinking quite early. It is impossible to understand why all these people have taken to drinking in the name of religion and even when they give the communion to God, which they call in their language, Holy Communion (it is given with wine and some sort of rotten bread). How can any one believe that this wine and alcohol, which makes a person so sick and causes so many diseases and which is so dangerous for children to consume, has something to do with the divine ascent, because it is the blood of Christ, our Lord. What an insult to the great life of Jesus, who was a pure Incarnation for innocence, Logos or Auṃ.<br />
......<br />
On the whole, if you see, Western culture denies Christ who sacrificed his life for the sins of the people. Those who call themselves Christians indulge in all kinds of activities which are anti-Christ. When Christ came into this world in the Realm of Divinity, one had to go through penance (tapasyā). Buddha and Mahāvīra had to do the same at that time. Christians do not know what is penance and they cannot sacrifice even a pin for others. They are very good at lip service. Big conferences are held in the developing nations for monetary help, who pay for these conferences and the outcome is that nothing can be done for the poor countries while Westerners spend their superfluous money on all kinds of waste.<br />
......<br />
Ego is against Christ. As they don't respect themselves they also do not respect others. Thus, the people in the West are extremely egoistical and arrogant. They feel that if somebody is humble, he is a weak person, while Christ has said: ``The meek will inherit the Earth." They advertise openly about their ego and what things can please their ego. I have seen advertisements about smoking stating that it makes you look egoistical. The training of children in the West is to develop the ego and also, very surprisingly, children are told to grab things from others rather than to share with others. I am talking about democratic countries where there is no understanding of compassion and humility, although they are Christians they do not practice Christianity.<br />
So the fundamentalists of the Christian religion have now become a new type, those who believe in a new culture of people. They go to church with their skin heads and on their return they kill Hindu ladies who wear kumkum (mask of marriage). They worship Christ and call themselves ``dot-busters" and look like lousy vagabonds. They never wear any suits anymore, neither do they have any proper dresses. They wear the same clothes for the whole year and hold very high positions in the media or in other organizations. People laugh at a person who is not in this kind of lousy, shabby, repulsive attire. One has to appear rustic and innocent like a primitive villager, while the brain is ultramodern. Islamic fundamentalists are fighting these Western modern fundamentalists who believe in all kinds of absurd modernism.<br />
Even in art, in writing and also in expression in different types of literature, you find that books which are popular are usually very grotesque.<br />
France is full of these ideas and perhaps all these ideas really come from France, where the politicians, at a very high position, have keeps. There is no ideal for the people to follow. Idealism ended with Marie Antoinette, who was killed by the public, who themselves, had become bourgeois. All their lives have changed and they have taken to all the mannerisms of the bourgeois which they condemned and therefore hanged their king and queen. Thus, we have a society of very licentious and vulgar people. The qualities that were very important in the West were given by Christ, but nobody cared for them.<br />
......<br />
Actually Hazarat Muhammad never made Islam an exclusive religion in the Qur'ān. He very respectfully talked about Moses, Abraham, Christ and His Mother, one after another. Even so Muslims believe they are exclusive. Jews and Christians also believe theirs are exclusive religions. There is another problem -- they believe that Muhammad was the exclusive messenger of God and Christians believe that Christ is the last word, while Jews believe that their Savior has yet to come. If these Incarnations were the last ones why did Muhammad say, ``I will send you the Twelfth Mahdī?" Also why did Christ say that He would send the Holy Ghost? We cannot say how long the Jews are going to wait for their Savior to come. They are wailing and crying before the wailing wall wearing the Torah in small amulets, but actually the most important thing for them is to collect the money that they have lent and buy diamonds at any cost.<br />
......<br />
The Christians are converted in India. They usually come from very poor back grounds. They believe that Christ was an Englishman born in Buckingham Palace. There is a joke about a villager near Allahabad. He was converted and given the name Sikander (Alexander), so he became Alexander Bhura. Bhura was his own name meaning Blondy. Every time he came to Allahabad, he would go for a dip in the Holy River, the Ganges. The missionaries who converted him said that now that had become a Christian he could not worship the River Ganges. He was amazed at this absurd proposal and said in his village language: "I have become sāhib, but how can I leave my religion (dharma)?"<br />
......<br />
Now we find statues of nude Mahāvīra everywhere, with his private parts shown meticulously, as if Mahāvīra was nothing but his private parts. This really irritates any sensitive person. Why should they insult Lord Mahāvīra like this? If you notice the work of Michelangelo who has done the Sistine Chapel so well, he did not show Christ or Mother Mary or the Father, God without clothes. He showed other people, but never them. So it is very insulting to see a Great Incarnation like Lord Mahāvīra exhibited in the nude all over in India."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I have met many people who cannot accept the Truth because of their ego. Once a very rude and arrogant interviewer from the television came to interview me. Of course, most of them are brought up that way so one should criticize their stupidity. Now this one was very special. He asked me what was I doing in London or England. He said I should help my own poor, India. I told him: ``I am not here of my choice but as my husband has been elected to a UN post with headquarters in London, I have to be with him. But I am in India every year at least for half a year". Very humbly I asked him: ``Who is responsible for India's poverty? If a country has ``guests" for three hundred years without any visa or immigration, how can you expect such a country to be rich? While all the wealth is sucked out of India without any consideration, who do you think will become poor and who will become rich?" He felt quite upset with this answer from an ordinary Indian housewife. Then he asked another question: ``Why do you have such a large population in India?" I said very calmly: ``Sir, I may say that for this overpopulation also perhaps you are responsible." The ego explosion of this English interviewer was really worth viewing in silence. He jumped with temper: ``How do you put the blame on us for your mad population?" To this I answered with great peace. I said: ``Sir, I read in the newspaper that in England, sorry, in London itself, two legal children are killed by their parents every week. So sir, please tell me which sane child would like to be born in a country where there is not an atmosphere of love for the children. Even the neighbors do not like children. If one has children one may not get a flat on rent. Perhaps children are very happy to be born in India to loving and caring parents. Children do not want to know what bank account one has. They want love which is the most valuable thing". All this answering made him mad with fury. So he attacked me: ``I am told you do not take any money for Self-realization work. This no Anglo-Saxon brain can understand." I answered him very politely: ``Sir, how much can you pay for Divine Love? How much did you pay to Christ? By the way can I now ask you a question?" He said: ``Yes, go ahead". I asked: ``Will you tell me which God has made this special Anglo-Saxon brain?" That settled him. He walked out with his gear and cameraman who never took any photographs. Later on people told me about him, and that he is called a Bulldog, even in the media.<br />
......<br />
For example, the war in Bosnia is the misidentification of Croats, Muslims and Serbs. They follow the Christian and Muslim religions. The Croats are Catholic Christians but do they follow Christ? What about Muslims who believe in the Formless God and despite this fight for land? Actually, Muhammad never talked of an exclusive religion. He talked about Abraham, Moses and Christ in a series and the fourth was Himself. Even Christ talked about Abraham and Moses. Why do people who follow Moses, Christ or Muhammad fight? They have the same roots. At least these three religions should produce people who understand the oneness of their religions. Of course, the Hindu religion is not exclusive. It accepts all the religions but even Hindus in charge of religious affairs have made different laws for different religions. They are taking advantage of the minorities for votes in the Democracy."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 7: Peace</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"For example, some of them project a kind of missionary in a developing country who collects money by showing off Christ's compassion, etc. all the time. Substantial donations are collected and these are perhaps shared with the media. Altogether, this seems to be a profitable business. The media can build up even a Nobel Prize-winning image. No one knows where all this money is going and what is happening. There are no properly audited accounts. People who are sensitive, especially those in the West get very impressed by such persons. Once a missionary came to a conference and started saying: ``You must think about the poorest of poor, you must take something out of your lunch for the poorest of poor" and so on and so forth. All the Western people in the audience heard these three or four sentences and, to our amazement, they started crying. They donated so much money to that missionary, and it is said that this missionary collects people from the streets, baptizes them, and converts them into Christians. Those who fall sick and die are buried or cremated unceremoniously. The media are promoting the images of such missionaries practically in every developing country.<br />
......<br />
Muhammad Sāhib has talked about Abraham, Moses, Christ in a series as They came one after the other. He has talked about the Mother of Christ especially with great respect. In the Bible She is not given so much respect because of Paul who edited the Bible. She is just called ``the woman". But Prophet Muhammad says that anyone who talks against this Holy Lady will be punished, or something to that effect. So one can see that Muhammad Sāhib never talked of an exclusive religion called ``Islam" (i.e., I surrender to God Almighty). But so many followers of Islam are fighting the followers of other religions and even amongst themselves.<br />
......<br />
"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 8: World Peace</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Gaṇeśha establishes within you the higher self. The baser self which enjoys all baser things of lives are If you see Mona Lisa, I don't know, she cannot be an actress, she cannot be in any beauty contest. Her face is very serene, very motherly, very pure, her eyes, and that's why it is that she is eternally so much appreciated? The reason is, there is Gaṇeśha Principle in her. She's a mother. The story about that one is that this lady had lost her child and she would never smile, she would never cry and one little child was brought to her. She saw the child, and then the smile that came on her face of that love for the child is being depicted by this great artist, that's why people are appreciating it. You have seen in the West though the people don't show much interest in the mother-child relationships, anywhere you go, the mother and child theme is the best. They will show you a photograph, this is Mother and Child. This is Christ's Mother and Child. When Christ was brought down, the Mother is there. They have to have Mother and the Child Principle acting otherwise that picture is not regarded as something great. Or you have to have actually Christ who is a Gaṇeśha Principle Himself, to be shown. I haven't seen any picture as such of those days where these principles are not there. Even Picasso has used it. Even people who have been quite modern had to use this principle to popularize. But some people had used to popularize not the Gaṇeśha Principle, just anti-Gaṇeśha principles. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Education Enlightened A Guide For Schools, Chapter 1: Establishing the Principle of Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Then the third one (Incarnation of Mahālakṣhmī) came as the Mother of Christ. She gave Her child to be crucified. Would we just introspect ourselves? How much we are attached like hawks to our children? If anybody says anything to the children, people don't like i. While we are so much attached to our children. What are we teaching them? Are we teaching them any sacrifices? Are we teaching them any sharing? Are we teaching them any tolerance? Are we teaching them forgiveness? Leave alone crucifixion, leave alone even little punishment, the child has now become the biggest ordeal for Sahaja Yogis. Everybody gets children. What's so great about it? The greatness is what kind of children you are. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Education Enlightened A Guide For Schools, Chapter 13: Light Burns For Others, Not For Itself</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Jesus Chris" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Ganesha" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahaganesha" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ SĪTĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0807" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ SĪTĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Sita</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0807"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The Raja Yoga is a derivation of Hathayoga. In this style the of practices the Gurus led a life like kings. They wore clothes like royal personalities and ruled the people. Raja Janaka an incarnation of Primordial Guru was the father of Seeta. In their inner life they were yogis but they led royal life without any attachment. They did not practice Asanas or Pranayamas but they worshiped God by different styles of bowing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Haṭha Yoga related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"On the right side on the right channel of Adi Pingla [Piṅgalā], a part of the cardia[c] center extends in this part resides the deity of Rama + Seeta who are the evolved forms of Shri Vishnu."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Incarnations of Viṣhṇu and Higher Chakras</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"$\bullet$ New Moon pray to Śhrī Śhiva, Full Moon pray to Śhrī Sītā Rāma."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advices Given to Dr. Madhur Rai, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1972-0409 Public Program (Marathi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"For example, if Rāvaṇa was to be born in this country, he can very well settle down here. And [he] call him... himself a God and preach such horrible things to destroy all the Sītās of this country.<br />
Is quite possible in the jet age: everybody has freedom to do whatever he likes.<br />
......<br />
The fear about Kuṇḍalinī must be given up. It's like fearing your own mother. If you know what is a Mother, and the purity of Hers. And if you remember how Sītā, the Mother, Her purity could not be spoiled by Rāvaṇa.<br />
......<br />
Rāvaṇa was a very powerful preacher and had a very big library of his own. And with his speech he used to mesmerize the people such a lot that they used to go into horrible states. He had that power within.<br />
And when Sītā would not allow him to come close to Her, he could not because of Her holiness and chastity, and Her Divine Powers. He used to threaten Her that, "In my next life I will come and destroy the chastity of every woman of Your country." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0324 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Jet Age, Seminar, Day 2, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0828 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Most Dynamic Power of Love, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"So, Śhrī Rādhā incarnated after Śhrī Sītājī. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Dattātreya's Incarnations are numerous. Firstly He came as King Janaka. Śhrī Sītājī was His daughter, who was the embodiment of Śhakti Herself. Then He came as Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, and Muhammad Sāhab, who were a completely different type of human being.<br />
......<br />
Muhammad Sāhab was the same, Dattātreya's Incarnation, and the same Incarnation was King Janaka. The same Incarnation was Nāṇaka, whose sister Nāṇakī, was the same Ādi Śhakti. She was Sītājī.<br />
......<br />
Sītājī was Śhrī Rāma's wife. Was married. The injustice that was done to Her by the society, made Her leave the house, by accusing Her falsely, disgraced Her. Why back then these great people had a blindfold on? Why didn't they said, that, `She is our Mother? You are asking Her to leave the house?' She already had passed the test, bypassing the fire, why were they dumbfounded then? What happened to their vigor [light] back then? All were so-called very great then. Nobody raised any point on that."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As I told you yesterday, King Janaka was one of Them. King Janaka was the father of Jānakī [Śhrī Sītā]. He was none other than the Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya.<br />
......<br />
Shia word has been derived from Siyā. The word which come from Siyā became Shia -- Siyā means Sītājī. If you go to UP [Uttar Pradesh, India] then nobody says Sītājī, they say Siyājī, 'Siyā var Rām[a]chandra ki jay.' Everyone takes the name Siyā. She was Sītājī, Ādi Śhakti Herself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Like Sītājī: how Rāvaṇa took Her away, poor Sītājī, who was Ādi Śhakti incarnate, could not come to sense that this Rāvaṇa has taken Her away."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1219 Public Program (Hindi), Nagpur, Maharashtra, India (other date 1222)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Sītājī was driven out of Her house, no Saint bothered about it. When She died, they built thousands of temples for Her.<br />
......<br />
If Sītā was caught in the guile of Rāvaṇa, it was a display of Her innocence. He had no stature to hold Her hand or misbehave with Her. Where is the glory of innocence and where is the cunningness of Rāvaṇa? No one can aggress an ordinary woman.<br />
But till such time he carried Sītā on his head, he remembered his own mother. All his greatness was reduced to the size of a small child."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0325 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Param Tattwa and Chetna Tattwa, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Who was Sītājī? Who was Rādhājī? And who was Mary? Are these ladies knowledgeable?<br />
To recognize Them, you should have a love for yourself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0326 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Tomorrow you come to My house. The kumkum that I['ll] give, with that draw a line outside the door of your māmā's house; this will be like Lakṣhmaṇ Rekhā. [Line meant to Śhrī Sītā and protect drawn by Śhrī Lakṣhmaṇa around the dwelling He shares with Śhrī Rāma and Śhrī Sītā at Panchavati in the forest of Dandakaranya, now part of Nasik.] As a result of that your māmī will not be able to throw your māmā out of the house. Otherwise, your māmī will kill your māmā, she is a rākṣhasī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0000 Conversation with Venu Narayan Phaḍake and His Māmā (Marathi), House of Śhrī Mātājī, Gurudev Cooperative Housing Society, Prabhadevi Sea Face, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This same power also is Durgājī, Pārvatījī, Sītājī and when It raises further the same power is also Rādhājī who is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Power and on Āgñyā chakra She is Mother Mary, Īsā Masīh's Mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0331 Public Program (Hindi), Gita Mandir Hall, Bhara-tiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now, what will be your condition when you go to Hell? I am discussing all this, on this day of Diwālī because Diwālī was celebrated on the occasion of Sītājī's reunion with Rāma. We can no more be slaves once we embrace chastity. We are our own slaves and not the slaves of others. We shall not lie for any reason whatsoever. I have lived in Delhi for a long time and am quite surprised at how much they lie. They are not afraid of lying at all. By telling lies openly they might benefit here, they might earn more money, but it is not known that they will not go to Heaven. I want the Sahaja Yogis to promise that neither will they lie nor will they support the people who lie.<br />......<br />
Today is an auspicious day, because many things took place on this day. Sītājī returned during the period of Rām[a]chandrajī, whatever great deeds were done during the period of `Kṛiṣhṇajī' were done by people who were realized Souls. So the first thing that you decide for sure is that we won't do any dishonest deed at the same time if any one else does then we will get him exposed. But I am seeing in this country that the Whites are fighting the Blacks, someone is fighting with someone else. They want the country of India to be separated which is not going to be beneficial at all. How can it be beneficial when you are honest and when you have a good character!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1110 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Diwālī Pāḍavā Day), Honesty and Patriotism, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"During the Tretā Yuga, at the time of Śhrī Rāma, Ādi Śhakti incarnated in three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
&emsp;1. <i>Sītā [Jānakī] (Mahālakṣhmī) as the daughter of Rāja Janaka<br />
&emsp;&emsp;This was the first absolute human form ({\it Laukik})"&lt;/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play</b></font>
&lt;/p&gt;

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Maheśha (Śhiva), Viṣhṇu and Brahmadeva form the Trinity which incarnated as one teacher God, the Primordial Master, Dattātreya. He came onto this Earth to teach people the secrets of the Divine, to reveal God, and to help them cross the Ocean of Illusion themselves within their own identity. Evolution could not go further in the hands of human beings who were in the bondage of ignorance, so they were given guidance through this Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) again and again in different lives. He was created as the three-headed child, Dattātreya, by Ādi Śhakti who appeared on Earth during the Tretā Yuga as Satī Anasūyā, wife of the Sage Atreya. He was born as Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara] who founded Jainism -- one of the oldest religions. Then he was born as Rāja Janaka, father of Jānakī also called Sītā, Rāma's wife. She was an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis. Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya.<br />
It is very important to understand that until the animal stage there was no need for animals to solve the problem of life, as animals were under the complete command of God. At the human stage, however, as we learn from the history of Adam and Eve, they were given the choice and freedom to solve the problem of life. That was how evolution was to go a step further. Without such freedom human beings were not equipped to learn the secrets of Divine Power.<br />
Ādi Viṣhṇu Himself took His seventh Incarnation during the Tretā Yuga as Lord Rāma, a human being who crossed the Ocean of Illusion and touched a new dimension of awareness. As Śhrī Rāma, Ādi Viṣhṇu came to enlighten human social and political consciousness as the true model of what Plato, thousand of years later, would call `the philosopher king'. He settled for human beings the rules of socio-political correct action ({\it samāj tatha rājkaraṇ dharma}). He also expressed God's aspect of majesty and order within kingship and institutions, and led a life of an ideal human being ({\it Maryādā Puruṣhottama}). This was witnessed by multitudes, resulting in a mass awareness for the first time among human beings. Śhrī Rāma was the ideal King for all kings, and {\it Rām Rājya}, His kingdom, was the ideal kingdom.<br />
He reached a point in the Primordial Heart Chakra (Ādi Anāhata Chakra) crossing the Void along the central path (Ādi Suṣhumṇā Nāḍī). His wife Sītā was an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. The {\it Rāmāyaṇa}, the epic about Lord Rāma's exploits written by Vālmīki, tells how Lord Rāma was made to forget that He was the Reincarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu for some time, because it was desired that He should act absolutely like a human being, to make them feel absolutely free with him. He gave them a human leadership. Later on, when Sītā disappeared back into the Mother Earth, Lord Rāma remembered His divinity.<br />
At the time of Rāma's Incarnation Ādi Śhakti existed in three persons: Mahālakṣhmī, as Sītā, His wife; Mahāsaraswatī, as Satī Anasūyā who gave birth to Dattātreya, the Primordial Master; and Mahākālī as Mandodarī, the wife of the demon Rāvaṇa.<br />
......<br />
The Incarnations of Rādhā show how the ideas of human beings gradually changed. The life as Rādhā was definitely a peg above in social advancement in the dogmatic thinking of society, compared to the time of Sītā. She was not married to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa in a formal human way ({\it laukika}). Their wedding was divine ({\it alaukika}), and was performed spiritually and socially in the presence of many people by Brahmadeva. Earlier, as Sītā, although formally married to Rāma in a wedding ceremony that was collectively sanctioned, She was still condemned by society. Kṛiṣhṇa's love and adoration of Rādhā brought Her glory without marriage, while Sītā was denied that public acceptance even though She was the legal wife of Rāma.<br />
Princess Sītā was married to King Rāma in a very traditional way. When He went into exile, Rāvaṇa the rākṣhasa, Satan disguised as an ascetic, appeared before Her and took Her away to the capital of his kingdom in Lanka. Rāma fought a war with Rāvaṇa to rescue His wife, who was secluded by Rāvaṇa in the core of his island kingdom. Rāma defeated His enemy and brought Sītā back to His kingdom, Ayodhyā. Although She was the purest of the pure, and the holiest of the holy, She was treated with suspicion by the citizens of Ayodhyā, Rāma's capital city. They would not accept Her as queen, blaming Her for having been abducted by force by Rāvaṇa. The suspicious citizens questioned Her chastity, and committed collective sin by rejecting Her. Although She was pregnant Rāma was forced to forsake Her. She lived with the Saint Vālmīki in the jungles of Bihar State where She gave birth to twin boys, Lava and Kuśha. They were absolutely human personalities but of very great spiritual heritage from previous births. Sītā taught them the divine way of life. They were later born again in Bihar as Gautama, known as Lord Buddha, and as Śhrī Mahāvīra, the leader of the great religion, Jainism. This all happened 500 years before the birth of Christ. Internally they reached a very great height through these births. They preached the doctrine of nonviolence ({\it ahiṃsā}) which was later developed into an extreme form of vegetarianism. They took birth in the warrior caste ({\it Kṣhatriya}) rather than as fanatical Brahmins in order to keep away from the extremes of vegetarian abstinences, and to stay more balanced. Still their disciples carried their teachings to the extreme of abstinence and vegetarianism. They confused inner asceticism ({\it saṃnyāsa}) with organized institutions of asceticism, and nonviolence with vegetarianism. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was later very much criticized by the so-called vegetarian followers of Buddha and Mahāvīra.<br />
Later They were born in Arabia as Hasan and Husayn, the two sons of Fāṭimah, daughter of Muhammad Sāhib. They were murdered in a very violent war at Karbalāʾ. Their death signifies a great sacrifice in the name of religion. It is an indication how people who are extreme in nature take to fanaticism and, in their blindness, kill the very essence of religion that is born in flesh and blood as an Incarnation. This awakening gave a rude shock to the mass of religious human beings of the land, and there ensued a phenomenon of mass repentance. In this way people were made to realize that there can be no attachment to war for a realized Soul. Violence and nonviolence are attributes of mind but awareness is beyond these extremes. In defense of righteousness one has to go to war, but when one becomes the witness one only sees the play of war without taking any credit or discredit for it, or being disturbed by its aggression.<br />
After Fāṭimah, the Reincarnation of Sītā, died, sectarian war broke out among the Muslims. One side, the Shiya sect, was founded by Her; in Indian dialect Sītā is pronounced `Shiya'. They are known today as Shiites. Shiya women are regarded as fair, innocent and beautiful because of their motherly expressions; in the same way the women of Janakapur, Sītā's birthplace in India, are similarly blessed by Mahālakṣhmī.<br />
After Her Incarnation as Sītā She was born and lived in China as Kuan Yin [Guānyīn], the Mother of Mercy, as a virgin. Ādi Śhakti took Her first Incarnation in Nepal where still today the Goddess is the presiding national Deity. Most of Her births were on the Himalayas near Nepal where people have mixed Indian and Chinese features. The women of Nepal are mostly fair and soft skinned, and are known to be very serene and beautiful. Because of their high cheek bones they look very young all the time. Ādi Śhakti's facial expression is very much in this mold; to be precise She looks Nepali.<br />
......<br />
When one takes the name of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa one has to take the name of Rādhā first, so a seeker recites the mantra to the Virāṭa as `Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa'. Similarly Sītā's name has to be taken before Rāma's for the mantra `Sītā-Rāma'. Even the Virgin Mary ({\it Kanyā}) who was so quiet and potential at the time of Christ, was recognized later on by His disciples as the Power behind Him. She was worshiped for many years after Her death by early Christians. In modern times human beings who are satanic personalities are challenging the validity of the Primordial Mother's virginity and the Virgin Birth in particular. Mary has clearly shown the power of virginity that can raise a mother to such an exalted powerful position that she can conceive a child by desire alone. She had reached that high stage of evolution when by Her Divine Will, She could immaculately conceive. There are other such instances in Hindu purāṇik literature when Kuntī, by the wish of the Mantra, gave birth to the Pāṇḍavas and to Karṇa immaculately."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"<br />
......<br />
The other Deities remain on their different centers:<br />
&emsp;1. <i>Sahasrāra chakra</i> &#8211; Ādi Śhakti Herself<br />
&emsp;2. <i>Āgñyā chakra</i> &#8211; Jesus Christ + His Mother Mary<br />
&emsp;3. <i>Viśhuddhi chakra</i> &#8211; Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa + Śhrī Rādhā<br />
&emsp;4. <i>Anāhat chakra</i> &#8211; Śhrī Rāma + Śhrī Sītā (right side) Śhrī Śhiva + Śhrī Pārvatī (left side), Śhrī Jagadambā (Durgā) in the center<br />
......<br />
The dangling chakra moves in a circle around the Nābhī chakra, creating an area called the Ocean of Illusion (Bhavasāgara) or the Void. Lord Viṣhṇu, through His ten Incarnations which represent the ten stages of the evolution of the Primordial Being (Virāṭa), crosses this Void. His seventh Incarnation was as Śhrī Rāma who resides on the right side of the Heart chakra with His Power, Śhrī Sītā. Rāma incarnated as the representation of a personality who was the perfect male human being ({\it Maryādā Puruṣhottama}). Lord Viṣhṇu's eighth Incarnation was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who, with His Power Rādhā, resides on the Viśhuddhi chakra. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was the ultimate expression of the Primordial Being (Virāṭa) in human form, and taught us to regard the Creation as a play ({\it Līlā}) of the Divine Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The Heart Center has three parts:<br />
<br />
&emsp;1. On the left side of the Chakra, Pārvatī resides with Her husband, Lord Śhiva. He governs the left side channel of Iḍā nāḍī.<br />
&emsp;2. On the right side of the Chakra is the seat of Lord Rāma, an Incarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu, and His wife, Sītā, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
&emsp;3. Pārvatī enters alone into the central part of the Chakra as Durgā or Jagadambā, Mother of the World. When Ādi Viṣhṇu incarnated as Lord Rāma, this central part was vacated by Durgā who, in Her role as wife, rejoined Lord Śhiva in the left chamber whilst Lord Rāma with Sītā occupied the central chamber.<br />
......<br />
<b>The fourth center of Anāhat</b><br />
<br />
Is governed by Ādi Śhakti (the Goddess) as Durgā or Jagadambā whose sustenance is Universal Motherly Love. The left part of this Chakra governed by Śhiva and Pārvatī has the sustenance of existence, of innocence, simplicity and steadfastness. The right part of the Chakra is governed by Śhrī Rāma and His dedicated wife, Sītā, and has the sustenance of majesty, and His perfect political leadership. This couple symbolizes the steadfast love between husband and wife."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 10: The Central Path of Sustenance</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Those people who do not respect their parents and their elders always have a weak Mūlādhāra chakra when they come to Sahaja Yoga. They also have a very weak right Heart center (Anāhata chakra) where Śhrī Rāma resides with His wife, Sītā. If they are particularly unkind to their mothers, then the center and right Heart gets very weak. We must therefore understand just how important our parents are, and how the spiritual link is held in the inner being of personality. Our parents have their roots in the Primordial Parents, and marriage has its roots in their primordial and eternal loving relationship. Those who do not respect their marriage, or enjoy the glory of their chastity, also suffer from a very weak Heart center and Mūlādhāra chakra. In such shameless, sex-obsessed people the Kuṇḍalinī just does not rise."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Later on Śhrī Rāma who was one of the Incarnations on this Earth, showed in his own life that he respected people for their aptitude. For example when Śhrī Rāma was exiled and went to a forest, he met there a poor old woman called Śhabarī who was of tribal caste. She offered some berries to Śhrī Rāma with great affection and devotion. She said: ``Please eat them because they are not at all sour. I have already tasted them." The food or fruits tasted by somebody else are not to be eaten (uttiṣhṭa). If someone has bitten off even a part of a fruit, that fruit is no longer pure and cannot be offered to another person, certainly not to an Incarnation. But Śhrī Rāma was greatly moved by the love of the old lady. He accepted the berries with much joy and ate them. He praised their taste and gave some to his wife, Sītā. His brother Lakṣhmaṇ, felt rather jealous and asked for some berries for himself. There are many incidents where Śhrī Rām gets very friendly with people who were not of very high castes. Also his own Rāmāyaṇa, his life story, was written by a fisherman who was a dacoit. This fisherman was transformed into a Saint by another heavenly minstrel called Nārada. Of course an ordinary fisherman who was also a dacoit had such respect for Śhrī Rāma that he wrote this beautiful epic, the Rāmāyaṇa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>


<br />
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>
</i></font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Sita" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahalakshmi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ RĀDHĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0806" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ RĀDHĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Radha</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0806"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"At the Vishuddhi chakra she resides as Radha [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], as the power of shri Krishna."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Residing on Chakras</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Shri Krishna and His power Radha beget a son called as MahaVISHNU who is created as a saviour with the esence of Shri Ganesha[.] Ganeshas [Ganesha's] brother become [becomes] the body of MahaVISHNU. This powerful essence of Godliness is born in this world as Jesus Christ. As He is placed on the crossing of two channels in the Primordial being[,] He controls the ego and super ego of man and is the dor to enter into the last chakra of Sahastrara."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Evolution Led by Viṣhṇu and His Incarnations</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0828 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Most Dynamic Power of Love, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"There is a saying in Hindi, "Na nau mana tela hogā, na Rādhā nāchegī," meaning, "Neither there will be nine liters of oil, nor will Rādhā dance." That's it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0910 Public Program (Hindi), Bholāpan (Innocence), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (place not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"In this case there is a beautiful example of Rādhājī.<br />
There are many worshiper of Rādhājī that is why I am willing to talk of Rādhājī.<br />
Once, Rādhājī got jealous of flute. She asked Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, "What is so special about this flute that you always keep this flute near your mouth?" Then He replied that, "You better ask this question to flute itself." She went to ask flute that, "What is your speciality that you are always attached to His mouth?" Then the flute replied, "Oh, mad, you do not even know that I have nothing special, that's what is my speciality. I have become totally hollow. That is why He made me play. If ever I stand then his whole melody will go in waste. I have become completely hollow." Then Rādhājī asked Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa that, "You make Me Your flute in My next birth." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1117 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"They call It, the Saivite [Śhaivite] call it as the Śhiva and the Śhakti. Vaiṣhṇavite call It as a Viṣhṇu, Kṛiṣhṇa and Rādhā. Whatever you call It, is not the point. Actually, we human beings only call Them by names and separate Them.<br />
......<br />
But sometimes, She comes as a wife, and sometimes as a mother, then She is dormant. She acts, but She is not felt. Like Rādhā of Kṛiṣhṇa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1124 Public Program, Day 6, 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"So, Śhrī Rādhā incarnated after Śhrī Sītājī. She was placed on the fifth chakra, that is Viśhuddhi. She is very humane and She sang the song of love. It is said that at the time of killing the Kaṃsa, the māmā of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, Śhrī Rādhā was called, Rādhā &#8211; 'rā' means energy and 'dhā' means the sustainer.<br />
The stream of Śhrī Rādhā starts flowing in you. Śhaivite people are the followers of Lord Śhiva. They do not believe in Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. There is no difference between Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and Lord Śhiva. Śhiva is placed in your heart as Spirit and Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is on the Viśhuddhi.<br />
Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa has sixteen powers (kalās). Similarly you have got sixteen plexuses. It is surprising that Lord Kṛiṣhṇa is the Deity of Viśhuddhi chakra which has sixteen petals.<br />
His Power Rādhā was then divided into two, that is, Rukmiṇī in Dvārika and Rādhā in Vṛindāvan. It is very humanly."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I am talking about Jesus Christ first because on Viśhuddhi chakra is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. But Jesus Christ's Mother was Rādhā herself. That's why I am discussing His Form first. This is on the Āgñyā chakra on number two.<br />
Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and His wife Rādhā: Rā means energy, dhā means the one who sustains it. Rādhā works on Viśhuddhi chakra.<br />
Now over here, if you ask the doctors, are sixteen sub-plexuses on the cervical plexus, have Her sixteen attributes. They are complete.<br />
But even being complete, He could not finish the work He came for because all His life finished fighting the evil people. He came at a very evil era and got all wasted.<br />
Although the description of [His] Līlā is all Sahaj. This is Sahaja Yoga. You would be surprised, Him breaking the earthen pots, tying the people around in a group, breaking Rādhājī's earthen pots, was all Sahaja Yoga. Because She used to carry the vibrated water from the River Yamunā, that water would get spilled on the lanes and the road was the reason He would [spill over] Her pot.<br />
You think, 'Rādhā didn't know about that,' of course She fully knew it. But back then you could not get the people together in a hall like today and say, "You people go into meditation." Then people would have said, "Have You gone insane? We are householders, how could we get into meditation?"
......<br />
The Redeemer was necessary, that's why Christ was established here, who was Rādhā's Son.<br />
You would be surprised that Mary Herself was Rādhā. There is a reason for this, a great reason.<br />
Sītājī was Śhrī Rāma's wife. Was married. The injustice that was done to Her by the society, made Her leave the house, by accusing Her falsely, disgraced Her. Why back then these great people had a blindfold on? Why didn't they said, that, 'She is our Mother? You are asking Her to leave the house?' She already had passed the test, bypassing the fire, why were they dumbfounded then? What happened to their vigor [light] back then? All were so-called very great then. Nobody raised any point on that.<br />
To teach them a lesson Rādhājī did not marry Kṛiṣhṇa under the societal norms. But still, the whole world knows Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa as Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa. But for Him, the formal marriage is important, that's why there was no child."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Who was Sītājī? Who was Rādhājī? And who was Mary? Are these ladies knowledgeable?<br />
To recognize Them, you should have a love for yourself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0326 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Rādhājī going into River Yamunā and filling water, it meant that the water of Yamunā river gets vibrated, and when She carries a pitcher on Her head and when Kṛiṣhṇajī makes a hole in it by throwing a stone at it, the water will again trickle into the river and the river water gets doubly vibrated, and when going through Her Kuṇḍalinī, the entire earth gets vibrated. So much calculation, planning was done. Only Rādhājī could do it, no one else was capable of doing it.<br />
Gopikās [wives of cowherds] going to the panghaṭ [waterway] has a lot of significance for that in our place. In the incarnation of Kṛiṣhṇa, they used to do many chores, but getting water from panghaṭ [waterway] was considered important. Its pratīk [symbol] is that Rādhājī has to sit with Her legs in the river. With that water used to get vibrated and gopikās [wives of cowherds] filled their pitchers with this water and took it home and this cleared their Nābhī chakras, etc.<br />
......<br />
Like reciting mantras. Reciting mantras harms Vaikharī, because the voice comes out of here. When we take the mantras in a very mechanical way, this power becomes weak and you will be surprised that at this place of Kṛiṣhṇa, at the Viśhuddhi chakra, for those who chant the names of Rādhā-&#8211;Kṛiṣhṇa day and night, their chakra becomes weak. It is very surprising that you take the name of Rādhā&#8211;Kṛiṣhṇa and your Viśhuddhi chakra gets damaged!"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0213 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Seminar, Second Floor Hall, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now also you are common [normal] people who will recognize Me first. And those who have become great Sādhus and Saints and Bābājī[s] and sitting, they will not recognize Me. They had not recognized Christ nor Rādhā and have not recognized Me. And now also they will not recognize Me. Even now they are sitting as bābājī[s] with their ego."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0329 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Vigyān Manuṣhya kī Rachanā Nahīṃ Khoja Hai (Science Is Human's Discovery, Not Creation), Sweet Home, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This same power also is Durgājī, Pārvatījī, Sītājī and when It raises further the same power is also Rādhājī who is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Power and on Āgñyā chakra She is Mother Mary, Īsā Masīh's Mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0331 Public Program (Hindi), Gita Mandir Hall, Bhara-tiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I felt very happy reading about Miss Anjali. Ramesh exhausted himself a lot, he worked day and night. This time I will take care of you all and massage your feet and wash them. Jesus Christ had washed the feet of His disciples. Kṛiṣhṇa had massaged the Feet of Rādhā."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0508 Letter to Nirmalā (sister of Rājabhāī Modi) (Marathi), 2, Parklands, Ice House Wood, Hurst Green, Oxted, Surrey, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Look, they even don't know how to pronounce the mantras, they can't even say Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa' with lot of difficulty they are able to pronounce 'Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa'. For you it is so easy ... that you can cleanse your Viśhuddhi. You just say 'Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa' and it's cured ... Now, they can't pronounce clearly 'Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa', so Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa gets little angry on it. Their pronunciation is also not all right, but, with you it's easy and you can awaken him easily. They don't know how to put kumkum. They don't know what is kumkum for. They don't know how to offer flowers, they don't know how to make Śhrī Gaṇeśha, they don't know how to make Swastika, every time they make it reverse. They never knew all these things."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1221 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Apanī aur Dṛuṣhṭi Rakhe (Keep the Attention on Yourself), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"You will be surprised that in this throat resides Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. When anyone faces a problem in the throat or in the cervical plexus then the name of Rādhā Kṛiṣhṇa has to be taken in the science of Kuṇḍalinī. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"......<br />
......<br />
......<br />"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0000 Public Program, India (year not sure) from the book Eternally Inspired Recollections of Our Divine Mother, Volume 7, Page 71</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0000 Chaitanya Nidhi (Hindi) Written by Mr. S. C. Rai and Mr. Mishra with Handwritten Corrections by Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"During the Dwāpara Yuga at the time of Lord Kṛiṣhṇa, Ādi Śhakti again incarnated as three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
&emsp;1. Rādhā (Mahālakṣhmī) as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's first and eternal love"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Ādi Viṣhṇu's eighth form was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa during the Dwāpara Yuga, and again Ādi Śhakti took three forms. Mahākālī lived for a very short time as Viṣhṇumāyā, the infant sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She was actually born as the daughter of Yeśhodā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's foster mother, and was killed by the demon Kaṃsa. She later took birth as Draupadī, wife of the Pāṇḍavas. Yeśhodā was Herself an Incarnation of Mahāsaraswatī. As Mahālakṣhmī She took two forms, Rādhā and Rukmiṇī. '<i>Rā</i> means power or energy and '<i>dhā</i>' means sustenance, so the name `Rādhā' means the one who sustains the power. As Rukmiṇī She became Queen to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the King in Dvārakā.<br />
......<br />
In their early days, Rādhā and Kṛiṣhṇa played a game of <i>Rāsa</i> (<i>rā</i> + <i>sa</i> &#8211; meaning 'with energy'). Rāsa is the play which manifests identification with the Power of God. It was the play of Sahaja Yoga, of the Divine Circuit of Vibrations. All Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's playmates were innocent, simple cow herders (<i>gopīs</i> and <i>gopas</i>). They did not know that he was trying to manifest the working of Sahaja Yoga (spontaneous growth of the inner self) through the play (<i>Līlā</i>) of Rāsa. It was a very simple game similar to 'Ring-A-Ring-A-Roses'.<br />
When Rādhā filled pitchers of water from the Yamunā River She automatically vibrated that water with Praṇava, as She was Ādi Śhakti and was carrying the water on Her head. When Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa broke the hers the vibrated water was meant to fall on the soil of Vṛindāvan where Kṛiṣhṇa and Rādhā lived, vibrating it. Similarly when Rādhā placed Her Feet in the Yamunā River, the waters of the river became vibrated. Se when the gopīs and their husbands, the simple folk of Vṛindāvan, carried water from the river in earthenware pitchers, Kṛiṣhṇa broke the pitchers so that the vibrated water would fall from their heads onto their spinal cord. Their Kuṇḍalinī would thus be awakened and raised, and they would get their Self-realization through the spontaneous awakening of Sahaja Yoga. It was sportive and playful baptism, but all these tricks or designs of Kṛiṣhṇa do not completely and immediately work out the whole manifestation of Sahaja Yoga. He could only sow the seed of Sahaja Yoga, His name meaning 'the One who sows' (<i>Kṛiṣhi</i>). The gopīs and gopas did get Kuṇḍalinī awakening which was a great achievement. The awakened state of their Kuṇḍalinī made the finite nature of human beings enlightened and enlarged their consciousness, but they still could not pierce into the infinite. That was left to be done after Kṛiṣhṇa's time, and thus awakened, their Kuṇḍalinīs needed many years of effort or many lives' experience to become receptive to Sahaja Yoga.<br />
The Incarnations of Rādhā show how the ideas of human beings gradually changed. The life as Rādhā was definitely a peg above in social advancement in the dogmatic thinking of society, compared to the time of Sītā. She was not married to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa in a formal human way (<i>laukika</i>). Their wedding was divine (<i>alaukika</i>), and was performed spiritually and socially in the presence of many people by Brahmadeva. Earlier, as Sītā, although formally married to Rāma in a wedding ceremony that was collectively sanctioned, She was still condemned by society. Kṛiṣhṇa's love and adoration of Rādhā brought Her glory without marriage, while Sītā was denied that public acceptance even though She was the legal wife of Rāma.<br />
......<br />
not live like Rādhā who did not bring forth Her only Son, Mahāviṣhṇu, on this Earth though She had created Him in the Body of the Virāṭa in the Vaikuṇṭha Stage. It was as a virgin that Mary conceived Jesus Christ, the ninth Incarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu.<br />
The greatness of this Incarnation cannot be adequately described in words but in the <i>Devī Bhāgavatam</i> there is a passage about Christ. It tells how He was born in Heaven to Rādhā as Mahāviṣhṇu, the only Son of the Virāṭa. He is none other than Śhrī Gaṇeśha, the symbol of eternal childhood. His body was constructed from the body of Śhrī Kārttikeya who was Brahma Himself, the only brother of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, and was conceived by one-sixteenth part of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the Virāṭa, who was His Father. As Mahāviṣhṇu He is the sustainer (<i>āśhraya</i>) of the whole world. A father always wants his son to be greater than himself, so Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa gave His Son a boon making Mahāviṣhṇu a million times greater than Himself and promising to place Him even higher than Himself. His Being would contain unlimited Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva), and from His forehead Eleven Rudras would be created when the last day of destruction will come.<br />
Rādhā in Mary's Incarnation wanted to give Her Son the name of Her Lord, Kṛiṣhṇa. Kṛiṣhṇa comes from '<i>kṛiṣhi</i>' + '<i>ṇa</i>'. '<i>Kṛiṣhi</i>' means farming, '<i>ṇa</i>' means the one who carries. So the name 'Christ' came from the 'kṛiṣhi' in Kṛiṣhṇa. The name Jesus was derived from Jasodā, a form of Yeśhodā, the foster mother of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. Rādhā also wanted to give Yeśhodā's name to Her Son because of Yeśhodā's devotion and worship of Her in Vṛindāvan and Gokul. The abbreviation of Yeśhodā was 'Jesu' or 'Yesu', so Rādhā/Mary named Her Son Jesus Christ.<br />
In the life of Jesus Christ, the highest expression of the essence of spiritual innocence came onto Earth as God the Son. Human beings witnessed the sacrifice of the dearest and Only Son of the Father (Virāṭa) for humanity's sake. This allowed a deeper human perception of God's great love for the human race. The crucifixion of Christ happened at a time when people knew about God the Father, but did not know how to crucify their human self to allow the spiritual Self to express itself. This is the real meaning of the Resurrection of Christ: that man could be the physical witness of the immortality of the Spirit which does not suffer and never perishes. For the first time, human awareness registered the Truth of the immortality of Spirit which Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had preached in His lifetime, which is recorded in the <i>Bhagavad Gītā</i> written by the poet Vyāsa.<br />
When one takes the name of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa one has to take the name of Rādhā first, so a seeker recites the mantra to the Virāṭa as 'Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa'. Similarly Sītā's name has to be taken before Rāma's for the mantra 'Sītā-Rāma'. Even the Virgin Mary (<i>Kanyā</i>) who was so quiet and potential at the time of Christ, was recognized later on by His disciples as the Power behind Him. She was worshiped for many years after Her death by early Christians. In modern times human beings who are satanic personalities are challenging the validity of the Primordial Mother's virginity and the Virgin Birth in particular. Mary has clearly shown the power of virginity that can raise a mother to such an exalted powerful position that she can conceive a child by desire alone. She had reached that high stage of evolution when by Her Divine Will, She could immaculately conceive. There are other such instances in Hindu purāṇik literature when Kuntī, by the wish of the Mantra, gave birth to the Pāṇḍavas and to Karṇa immaculately.<br />
Rādhā had created Her Only Son, Mahāviṣhṇu, in the Vaikuṇṭha Stage but as Rādhā She could not conceive a child because She was unmarried. As Mary, though, She conceived Her child outside marriage in complete virginity. This is an expression of the power of virginity, the sinless Immaculate Conception. In Mary's life the greatest advancement in social consciousness regarding the power of chastity came about, and society went through yet another evolution. Though a virgin She was raised to such an exalted position by the birth of Christ that She was acceptable to public opinion as the Mother of God, not just then but still today."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations &#8211; Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"$\bullet$ They fabricated many salacious stories about Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, Śhrī Rādhā and the gopīs. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 6: Tantrism</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"These Deities also manifest Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa with His Power Rādhā, and the Lord Jesus Christ, whose Power is His Mother Mary (Mahālakṣhmī Herself). These two Deities are the evolved human Incarnations of Śhrī Viṣhṇu and Śhrī Gaṇeśha respectively.<br />
......<br />
The other Deities remain on their different centers:<br />
&emsp;1. <i>Sahasrāra chakra</i> &#8211; Ādi Śhakti Herself<br />
&emsp;2. <i>Āgñyā chakra</i> &#8211; Jesus Christ + His Mother Mary<br />
&emsp;3. <i>Viśhuddhi chakra</i> &#8211; Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa + Śhrī Rādhā<br />
......<br />
Lord Viṣhṇu's eighth Incarnation was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who, with His Power Rādhā, resides on the Viśhuddhi chakra. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was the ultimate expression of the Primordial Being (Virāṭa) in human form, and taught us to regard the Creation as a play (<i>Līlā</i>) of the Divine Power.<br />
In the brain above the Viśhuddhi, where the optic nerves cross each other, is the Āgñyā chakra, where Lord Jesus Christ resides in every human being. He is the complete manifestation of the Son God Principle. His body was formed from Śhrī Kārttikeya, the only brother of Śhrī Gaṇeśha and a Divine Personality. Although He came as a human being His Resurrection was made possible by the divine substance of His human body. In the Vaikuṇṭha Stage He was created as Mahāviṣhṇu, the only Son of Kṛiṣhṇa and Rādhā. As the ninth Incarnation of Viṣhṇu He was called Buddha or 'the mild Incarnation'. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Above the Ādi Anāhat Chakra lies the sixteen-petalled Ādi Viśhuddhi Chakra which controls the cervical plexus. Ādi Viṣhṇu incarnated the Virāṭa as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, whose Power is Rādhā."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 10: The Central Path of Sustenance</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The River Ganges which runs with Divine Water, and is the expression of the love between Rādhā and Kṛiṣhṇa, has such Divine Vibrations. If you put water from the Ganges in a bottle and leave it there for months, you will be surprised to note that there is no formation of any living organisms in it as would happen with any other water. The water remains as crystal clean as ever."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 14: The Powers of Ādi Śhakti and the Three Guṇas</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Radha" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahalakshmi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ HANUMĀNA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0805" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ HANUMĀNA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Hanumana</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0805"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[The name Gabriela was not recommended because Gabriel, Śhrī Hanumān, did not marry.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Names from the book Eternally Inspired Recollections of Our Divine Mother, Volume 7, Page 93</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"$\bullet$ Monkeys evolved as integrated animals. The monkey raised the head and stood up. That created a new dimension in animal evolution. The missing links half oman [man] and half monkey existed on this earth. They evolved and became angelic identities like Hanumana [Hanumāna] and Bhairava."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Creation of Matter related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 3</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Sometimes Hanumāna and Bhairava want to be with Me. Those two disks which you observed [revolving around for almost 30-45 minutes] were Them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1970-0700 Meeting with (Visiting) Gaganagirī Mahārāj, Day 2, Āśhram Gaganabāvaḍā (near Khopolī, 70 kms SE of Mumbai), Maharashtra, India (month not sure; before 1973-1209)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I have told you many a times and today he also remarked: that you should know you are never alone when you are realized. There have been many people who have been realized, before even you were born, who exist, who are anxious to help you at every moment. In our Śhāstras [Scriptures] we call them Chirañjīvas [eternal beings], you know them. They are people who are Nirañjanas. As he said about Bhairava and Hanumāna. All these people exist, and they are waiting just for a call from you.<br />
Once we went to the market, and there was a problem about something. And I had somebody with Me, a disciple, who was also with Me. I just wanted to see what will be his reaction. He tried to argue out with a person to tell him about something. So he told Me, "Mātājī, let us go now!" When a we came out the shop, I said, "What are you going to about it?" He said, "I have already told Hanumān to look after that part."<br />
And the work was done! It is gross, but it happened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0828 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Most Dynamic Power of Love, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Take up any work in Sahaja and sākṣhāt Hanumān is standing and he tells Me, 'Mother, with whom should I stand?' Hanumānjī is doing all your work.<br />
Take up any work in the name of your Mother, even of work of the world. For Sahaja Yoga the Five Immortals (Chirañjīvas) are standing there for you.<br />
All these Deities are ready with Their Śhaktis standing in the background for you. And what do They see? That, 'The actor who has come is in very bad shape. He is looking here and there.'<br />
How will the drama go on? This half-baked attitude won't do."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0125 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Har Śhwās Me Sahaja Yoga Ko Prasthāpit Karanā Hogā (Sahaja Yoga Must Be Established in Every Breath or Must Listen Every Day and Imbibe Sahaja Yoga), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"But I see that without properly inviting Deities chakras never work. And these Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, and Maheśh[,] They never listen to [if not properly invited]. Even until you all human beings accept Me [as Śhrī Ādi Śhakti], Śhrī Gaṇeśha, Christ, Hanumāna or Bhairavnāth, no one gets awakened, too. Then every time I have to request Them all [to get awakened]. And here [in overseas countries] these big People [all Deities and gaṇas] they take their attention back. [In] addition to that, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa [is] playing his diplomacy all the time. So unnecessarily you all call Me Mahāmāyā. In reality, all credit goes to you [Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar] and all these Kings [Deities]. I am just witnessing. Now I do not know how to explain all these to these English people."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0914 Letter to Mrs. Rāja Kuṃwar Raul (Marathi), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"It is working and is activated all the time all around enveloping ... what we call as Unconscious! What is called as Praṇav [Divine Breath] to what I call as 'Divine Love' is all around ... for helping you, circling around you. Bhairavnāth is sitting here, Hanumānajī is sitting here ... there are thousands of them with you, working hard on you, for you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1221 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Apanī aur Dṛuṣhṭi Rakhe (Keep the Attention on Yourself), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Whatever Justice Vaidya has said he is an extremely learned man. I have not read anything in the form of books in My life. Despite reading everything and searching through all books, his vision has a devotion like that of Hanumān that, "It is not there in this too," 'It is not there in these words,' 'This has only signs,' 'I have not got that thing yet,' and as soon as he got it, he recognized it. This is a special kind of devotion.<br />
......<br />
With regards to diseases you know that many have been cured by the disciples themselves, many mental diseases of people have also been cured. This is not something special. This has to happen.<br />
The Temple of God is being cleaned by everyone from Bhairava to Hanumānjī. Whether They exist or not is to be seen by coming into this Kingdom."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"......<br />
In English, Hanumānjī is called Gabriel, which means in Christianity, Saint Gabriel, and Bhairavnath is called Saint Michael. It's the same. Absolutely the same. There is no difference. The names are different, all are Hanumānjī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0117 Public Program (Hindi), Day 4, Chakroṃ para Upasthita Devatā (Deities on All Chakras), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"So in our country, I have also seen that people put Gaṇapatijī's picture, Saraswatījī's picture, and all sorts of images and do namaskāra to them, not knowing who they are, what they are. They go to Hanumānjī's Temple every Tuesday, but who is He, what is His work, if He is awakened within us or not, no one thinks about that.<br />
But when I try to say, then people bring in science and say, "Mātājī, this is unscientific."<br />
Here people talk about the sympathetic system, and there they talk about Gaṇeśhjī. Both are the same, which means that Hanumānjī is taking care of our preconsciousness. He is the ruler of our preconsciousness.<br />
The mind that is before awareness that moves here and there. The awareness or the conscious, which is in the middle before that, is preconscious, which you can call mind. This mind moves here and there, going towards ego and superego, towards the brain, and from the brain goes towards ego and superego. This restless mind is taken care of by Hanumānjī.<br />
You have to proceed carefully with Hanumānjī's Power. He does the planning, and He tells us about the future, and He is the guru of it.<br />
[Whether] He is present or not, you will find out today. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-032x Public Program (Hindi), Day y, Advertised as 'Kuṇḍalinī Awakening', New Delhi, India (date to be confirmed)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0324 Public Program (Hindi + English), Love Is the Potential Power within Us, Rāmlīlā Maidān, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Before man came into being he existed at the monkey stage. Monkeys had also been struggling in their evolutionary process. To help them, the Primordial Preconscious Mind of the Virāṭa Itself took Incarnation as Hanumāna, the Monkey God, the devotee of Śhrī Viṣhṇu. Hanumāna led the monkeys who were half human &#8211; 'the missing link' as Darwin called it in human evolution. The monkeys were helped to evolve into human beings."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations &#8211; Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"$\bullet$ Monkeys evolved as integrated animals. The monkey raised the head and stood up. That created a new dimension in animal evolution. The missing links, half man and half monkey, existed on this Earth. They evolved and became angelic identities like Hanumāna and Bhairava. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 3: Evolution</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"It is said that God made the creation in seven days. Monday is the day of Ādi Śhakti, and also of Lord Śhiva. Tuesday is the day realized Souls (Sahaja Yogis) should worship Śhrī Gaṇeśha in the Mūlādhāra chakra. Hanumāna, who controls the preconscious mind (<i>chetan mana</i>), should also be worshiped on Tuesday.<br />
......<br />
Śhrī Gaṇeśha surrounds the left half circle of the Void, while His brother Kārttikeya surrounds the right half of the circle. They reunite below the Heart chakra. From this point, the Monkey God Hanumāna, who is created to be the guiding angel of the Preconscious Mind of the Virāṭa, sits on the right-hand channel of Piṅgalā, which manifests as the right sympathetic nervous system. This Deity takes the form of Saint Gabriel above the Viśhuddhi chakra following Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Incarnation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This is the expression of the activating mood of Ādi Śhakti, the rajoguṇa in Her aspect as Mahāsaraswatī. She acts through the Ādi Piṅgalā Nāḍī, whose Presiding Deity is Brahmadeva. This channel originates on the left side of the brain of the Primordial Being (<i>Virāṭa Śharīra</i>), and passes through the Ādi Āgñyā Chakra towards the right side of the Great Being's Body. In the Primordial Brain it forms the Universal Mind that thinks, organizes and creates the material side of creation. Hanumāna, the Monkey Deity, moves on this channel and represents the Preconscious Mind of the Virāṭa. <br />
......<br />
Realized Souls who have reached the stage of God-realization, and on whom Brahmadeva bestows His Powers are very rare and never show off their tricks or <i>siddhis</i>, because these powers are not very important to them. This includes Deities and Incarnations like Hanumāna and Jesus Christ. These powers come to them as a part of their nature, and through them they can control the Sun, and the rain and other elements by the Grace of Brahmadeva.<br />
Powers like flying through the air, floating on water, being buried underground, stopping the sunrise or drinking up the oceans can also be performed with the help of disembodied spirits. It is easy to distinguish real Siddhas from impostors. Siddhas never use their powers for their betterment or fame or material well-being. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 14: The Powers of Ādi Śhakti and the Three Guṇas</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Hanumana" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ MARY MAHĀLAKṢHMĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0804" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ MARY MAHĀLAKṢHMĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Mary_Mahalakshmi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0804"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[<b>Page 251 footnote:</b>] <font color="red">"After His assumption, Christ descended on this Earth in a hidden place while the Holy Spirit [Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī] stayed back to inspire the faith of the early Christians. After Her assumption She joined Her Son and They lived together for many years in Kashmir. They are buried there."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quotes from the book The Advent (2002 edition) by Grégoire de Kalbermatten</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Mary was in Her own right a Divine Being. She was venerated as such by Christ and some of the suppressed Scriptures describe Her as the Holy Spirit incarnate[d]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Śhrī Mary from Akashwani, Volume I, Issue XII (December 2000), Page 3</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"At the Agnya chakra She resides as Mary (Mahalaxmi) mother of Jesus Christ [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Residing on Chakras</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As She has come, you know, as Nava Durgā She has come, as Mother Mary She has come, as Quan Yin She has come. She has come in many forms in many parts of the world. She came as Muhammad's daughter, She came as Nāṇaka's sister, She came as Janaka's daughter. Only one person, all the time, coming in this world in different forms.<br />
When She comes only as a Mother, She is very effective, and She is very dynamic. But sometimes, She comes as a wife, and sometimes as a mother, then She is dormant."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1124 Public Program, Day 6, 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had only one Son who was Praṇava incarnate. Think of it, He was Auṃ incarnate. He incarnated on this Earth. His name was Jesus Christ. Mary was His Mother. He was placed on the Āgñyā chakra.<br />
......<br />
Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī, whose praise we sing so frequently, no one has described Her. Where is She placed? She is Mary Herself. Whenever She incarnates with Her child and husband, She is very peaceful. But when She comes alone, then She is tremendous."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The Redeemer was necessary, that's why Christ was established here, who was Rādhā's Son.<br />
You would be surprised that Mary Herself was Rādhā. There is a reason for this, a great reason.<br />
Sītājī was Śhrī Rāma's wife. Was married. The injustice that was done to Her by the society, made Her leave the house, by accusing Her falsely, disgraced Her. Why back then these great people had a blindfold on? Why didn't they said, that, 'She is our Mother? You are asking Her to leave the house?' She already had passed the test, bypassing the fire, why were they dumbfounded then? What happened to their vigor [light] back then? All were so-called very great then. Nobody raised any point on that.<br />
To teach them a lesson Rādhājī did not marry Kṛiṣhṇa under the societal norms. But still, the whole world knows Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa as Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa. But for Him, the formal marriage is important, that's why there was no child.<br />
But in the next life, She came as Mary and Her Child glorified Her, who was a Virgin.<br />
Not a difficult thing to have a child as a virgin. If you are a realized Soul, then you are at that state, as these days I give birth to thousands from My Sahasrāra. Not a difficult thing. But She did it. Not difficult if someone wants to birth a child from Her womb. She did it without any difficulty.<br />
Even though in the world's eyes, in society's norm it is not OK, but now the world recognizes Mary as a great woman. People call Her Divine Mother. This is Her Child's doing."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And what scientific proof do you want? For the blind, no scientific proof is enough.<br />
For them, it looks strange that, 'A woman, a housewife, how does She know all this?'<br />
Who was Sītājī? Who was Rādhājī? And who was Mary? Are these ladies knowledgeable?<br />
To recognize Them, you should have a love for yourself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0326 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This same power also is Durgājī, Pārvatījī, Sītājī and when It raises further the same power is also Rādhājī who is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Power and on Āgñyā chakra She is Mother Mary, Īsā Masīh's Mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0331 Public Program (Hindi), Gita Mandir Hall, Bhara-tiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1225 Christmas Pūjā, Introspection Is Very Helpful for You to Overcome These Two Hurdles (conditioning and ego) of Your Āgñyā Chakra, We Should Not React, Just Know You Are a Sahaja Yogi and a Sahaja Yoginī (The Greatest Achievement Is to Respect Your Innocence and Try to Be Simple, Innocent, Not Reacting and Keep Quiet and Peaceful), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[The Pūjā was held in Centra, in the outskirts of Lisbon where the apparition of Virgin Mary took place. Śhrī Mātājī mentions it is a very special place for Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā as Sintra refers to the central channel of Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Power.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1100 Quote on the Meaning of Sintra, Sintra (29 kms NW of Lisbon), Portugal</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2002-0421 Easter Pūjā, Pandal, Kilya Resort Hotel on the Black See Shore, Kilyos (35 kms N suburb of Istanbul), Turkey</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0000 Chaitanya Nidhi (Hindi) Written by Mr. S. C. Rai and Mr. Mishra with Handwritten Corrections by Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The fourth human birth of Ādi Śhakti was as the Virgin Mary, Mother of Christ. She incarnated in the Middle Eastern Kingdom of Judea. In that life She did not marry and did not live like Rādhā who did not bring forth Her only Son, Mahāviṣhṇu, on this Earth though She had created Him in the Body of the Virāṭa in the Vaikuṇṭha Stage. It was as a virgin that Mary conceived Jesus Christ, the ninth Incarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu.<br />
The greatness of this Incarnation cannot be adequately described in words but in the <i>Devī Bhāgavatam</i> there is a passage about Christ. It tells how He was born in Heaven to Rādhā as Mahāviṣhṇu, the only Son of the Virāṭa. He is none other than Śhrī Gaṇeśha, the symbol of eternal childhood. His body was constructed from the body of Śhrī Kārttikeya who was Brahma Himself, the only brother of Śhrī Gaṇeśha, and was conceived by one-sixteenth part of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the Virāṭa, who was His Father. As Mahāviṣhṇu He is the sustainer (<i>āśhraya</i>) of the whole world. A father always wants his son to be greater than himself, so Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa gave His Son a boon making Mahāviṣhṇu a million times greater than Himself and promising to place Him even higher than Himself. His Being would contain unlimited Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva), and from His forehead Eleven Rudras would be created when the last day of destruction will come.<br />
Rādhā in Mary's Incarnation wanted to give Her Son the name of Her Lord, Kṛiṣhṇa. Kṛiṣhṇa comes from '<i>kṛiṣhi</i>' + '<i>ṇa</i>'. '<i>Kṛiṣhi</i>' means farming, '<i>ṇa</i>' means the one who carries. So the name 'Christ' came from the 'kṛiṣhi' in Kṛiṣhṇa. The name Jesus was derived from Jasodā, a form of Yeśhodā, the foster mother of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. Rādhā also wanted to give Yeśhodā's name to Her Son because of Yeśhodā's devotion and worship of Her in Vṛindāvan and Gokul. The abbreviation of Yeśhodā was 'Jesu' or 'Yesu', so Rādhā/Mary named Her Son Jesus Christ.<br />
In the life of Jesus Christ, the highest expression of the essence of spiritual innocence came onto Earth as God the Son. Human beings witnessed the sacrifice of the dearest and Only Son of the Father (Virāṭa) for humanity's sake. This allowed a deeper human perception of God's great love for the human race. The crucifixion of Christ happened at a time when people knew about God the Father, but did not know how to crucify their human self to allow the spiritual Self to express itself. This is the real meaning of the Resurrection of Christ: that man could be the physical witness of the immortality of the Spirit which does not suffer and never perishes. For the first time, human awareness registered the Truth of the immortality of Spirit which Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had preached in His lifetime, which is recorded in the <i>Bhagavad Gītā</i> written by the poet Vyāsa.<br />
When one takes the name of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa one has to take the name of Rādhā first, so a seeker recites the mantra to the Virāṭa as 'Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa'. Similarly Sītā's name has to be taken before Rāma's for the mantra 'Sītā-Rāma'. Even the Virgin Mary (<i>Kanyā</i>) who was so quiet and potential at the time of Christ, was recognized later on by His disciples as the Power behind Him. She was worshiped for many years after Her death by early Christians. In modern times human beings who are satanic personalities are challenging the validity of the Primordial Mother's virginity and the Virgin Birth in particular. Mary has clearly shown the power of virginity that can raise a mother to such an exalted powerful position that she can conceive a child by desire alone. She had reached that high stage of evolution when by Her Divine Will, She could immaculately conceive. There are other such instances in Hindu purāṇik literature when Kuntī, by the wish of the Mantra, gave birth to the Pāṇḍavas and to Karṇa immaculately.<br />
Rādhā had created Her Only Son, Mahāviṣhṇu, in the Vaikuṇṭha Stage but as Rādhā She could not conceive a child because She was unmarried. As Mary, though, She conceived Her child outside marriage in complete virginity. This is an expression of the power of virginity, the sinless Immaculate Conception. In Mary's life the greatest advancement in social consciousness regarding the power of chastity came about, and society went through yet another evolution. Though a virgin She was raised to such an exalted position by the birth of Christ that She was acceptable to public opinion as the Mother of God, not just then but still today.<br />
Through a deeper understanding of Sahaja Yoga the reader will grasp the simplicity of the Immaculate Conception. Mary proved She was the Primordial Mother by conceiving the child in Her Sacred Heart (Primordial Heart Chakra). The Sacred Heart is the place where the Mother of the Universe (Jagadambā) exists. In the same way that She conceived the universe She also conceived Jesus Christ, and moved it through the Ādi Suṣhumṇā Nāḍī into the Ādi Swādhiṣhṭhān Chakra which controls the Primordial Uterus (<i>Kumbha</i>) to give Him human birth as a baby. In that divine heaven of creativity the Immaculate Conception took the form of a zygote egg (<i>Aṇḍam</i>). It remained in that state for many ages (<i>Kalpas</i>) until Ādi Śhakti took birth as Mary. She then manifested it as Jesus Christ. It was not difficult for Ādi Śhakti to do that. Unfortunately the greatness of Her Powers was only recognized after She departed from the Earth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations &#8211; Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Their entry occurs through the Āgñyā chakra, known as the 'third eye'. This is the center Indian ladies traditionally cover by a vermilion <i>tilak</i>, or <i>bindi</i>. Many English people laugh at this mark, some even foolishly make fun of Indians who wear it. This mark keeps the entry of spirits away, and is the mark of the Primordial Mother. It is the mark of the Virgin Mary who sacrificed Her blood, Her only child, to save humanity. She wore the mark of the Precious Blood running in the body of Her Son, Jesus Christ. It is He who guards the subtle center of Āgñyā, and protects from spirits entering there."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 5: The Subconscious and the Collective Subconscious</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Ancient Sages, who meditated and achieved great heights of awareness, have written a lot about Kuṇḍalinī. Living away from the public in forest dwellings they saw the working of Kuṇḍalinī within themselves during meditation. Apart from descriptions in ancient Indian Scriptures, Kuṇḍalinī has also been described in religious books like the Torah, the Bible and the Qur'ān as 'the fire tree'. In those books there are many references couched in secretive language which few would have understood. The Bible tells of the first meeting of all the disciples with the Virgin Mary after the Crucifixion. The closed room they met in 'was filled with a great wind, and there appeared above their heads, as it were, separate tongues of fire, and they were filled with the Holy Ghost.' This is a description of a vision of Kuṇḍalinī. Various Chinese philosophers have also described the Kuṇḍalinī in their writings, and Greek mythology cataloged the same Gods and Goddesses I have written about in the chapter on Creation. The Zen Buddhist religion teaches very clearly that the basis of Buddhist meditation is the science of Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
......<br />
These Deities also manifest Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa with His Power Rādhā, and the Lord Jesus Christ, whose Power is His Mother Mary (Mahālakṣhmī Herself).<br />
......<br />
The other Deities remain on their different centers:<br />
&emsp;1. <i>Sahasrāra chakra</i> &#8211; Ādi Śhakti Herself<br />
&emsp;2. <i>Āgñyā chakra</i> &#8211; Jesus Christ + His Mother Mary<br />
......"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This Mūlādhāra chakra is made from the first syllable 'A' of the tripartite sacred syllable, 'Auṃ'. Each syllable is a mantra. The mantra 'A' represents the Mahākālī Power of Ādi Śhakti, and the Mūlādhāra chakra was created by Mahākālī as Gaurī, who is Śhrī Gaṇeśha's Mother. Later on She hands over Her only child to Mahālakṣhmī, who as the Virgin Mary gives birth to Him as Jesus Christ."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now we find statues of nude Mahāvīra everywhere, with his private parts shown meticulously, as if Mahāvīra was nothing but his private parts. This really irritates any sensitive person. Why should they insult Lord Mahāvīra like this? If you notice the work of Michelangelo who has done the Sistine Chapel so well, he did not show Christ or Mother Mary or the Father, God without clothes. He showed other people, but never them. So it is very insulting to see a Great Incarnation like Lord Mahāvīra exhibited in the nude all over in India."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Muhammad Sāhib has talked about Abraham, Moses, Christ in a series as They came one after the other. He has talked about the Mother of Christ especially with great respect. In the Bible She is not given so much respect because of Paul who edited the Bible. She is just called ``the woman". But Prophet Muhammad says that anyone who talks against this Holy Lady will be punished, or something to that effect. So one can see that Muhammad Sāhib never talked of an exclusive religion called ``Islam" (i.e., I surrender to God Almighty). But so many followers of Islam are fighting the followers of other religions and even amongst themselves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 8: World Peace</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Gaṇeśha establishes within you the higher self. The baser self which enjoys all baser things of lives are If you see Mona Lisa, I don't know, she cannot be an actress, she cannot be in any beauty contest. Her face is very serene, very motherly, very pure, her eyes, and that's why it is that she is eternally so much appreciated? The reason is, there is Gaṇeśha Principle in her. She's a mother. The story about that one is that this lady had lost her child and she would never smile, she would never cry and one little child was brought to her. She saw the child, and then the smile that came on her face of that love for the child is being depicted by this great artist, that's why people are appreciating it. You have seen in the West though the people don't show much interest in the mother-child relationships, anywhere you go, the mother and child theme is the best. They will show you a photograph, this is Mother and Child. This is Christ's Mother and Child. When Christ was brought down, the Mother is there. They have to have Mother and the Child Principle acting otherwise that picture is not regarded as something great. Or you have to have actually Christ who is a Gaṇeśha Principle Himself, to be shown. I haven't seen any picture as such of those days where these principles are not there. Even Picasso has used it. Even people who have been quite modern had to use this principle to popularize. But some people had used to popularize not the Gaṇeśha Principle, just anti-Gaṇeśha principles. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Education Enlightened A Guide For Schools, Chapter 1: Establishing the Principle of Śhrī Gaṇeśha</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Then the third one (Incarnation of Mahālakṣhmī) came as the Mother of Christ. She gave Her child to be crucified. Would we just introspect ourselves? How much we are attached like hawks to our children? If anybody says anything to the children, people don't like i. While we are so much attached to our children. What are we teaching them? Are we teaching them any sacrifices? Are we teaching them any sharing? Are we teaching them any tolerance? Are we teaching them forgiveness? Leave alone crucifixion, leave alone even little punishment, the child has now become the biggest ordeal for Sahaja Yogis. Everybody gets children. What's so great about it? The greatness is what kind of children you are. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Education Enlightened A Guide For Schools, Chapter 13: Light Burns For Others, Not For Itself</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Abraham" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahalakshmi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ WILLIAM BLAKE in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0803" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ WILLIAM BLAKE in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_William_Blake</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0803"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="red">"Many Seers had announced about this era [time]. Recently, saw William Blake's book called Milton. He was very philosophical and in His prediction He mentioned the place where Sahaja Yoga started (Surrey Hills) and the place where the foundation of the first center was established (Lambeth Vale), writing about both places is very surprising. It is also written that a common person will be becoming a Preṣhit (Prophet), who will be bestowed with special power. With this amazing power he will create many more Preṣhit [Prophets]. After reading this so deep and so correct information about Sahaja Yoga in His poem felt tremendous joy. If our country's Sahaja Yogis' also be aware of this knowledge[,] then recognizing the greatness and accepting the depth of this greatness will be their great responsibility."</font><br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
<font color="red">"This yuga was predicted by many great people. Recently, I saw the book Milton written by William Blake. He was a great philosopher and it's so surprising how he predicted the foundations of Sahaja Yoga (Surrey Hills) and the first Sahaja centre (Lambeth Vale). He also wrote that with a special power, ordinary people will become a Preṣhit (Prophet), who will be bestowed with special power. With this amazing power he will create many more Preṣhit [Prophets]. And with this wonderful power they will liberate many others. I enjoyed very much his poem that had such depth and such clear knowledge. If only the Sahaja Yogis of our country could become aware and alert towards this kind of knowledge, then they will aim at achieving the greatness and the depth of Sahaja Yoga."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1901-0000 Letter (Message) (Hindi) from Nirmala Yoga, Issue 1 (January-February 1981), Pages 2 and 3</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1002 Public Program (1st Day of Navarātri), Knots on the Three Channels, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1113 Public Program, Evolution beyond Organized Religion, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0616 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Bala Kanayson's House, Rosemary Road, Tamworth (31 kms NE of Birmingham), Staffordshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0715 Public Program, What We Are Wanting Is the Reality, Cambridge, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0721 Public Program, Auspiciousness, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0809 Public Program, What Are We Inside, Carrs Lane Church Center, Birmingham, West Midlands, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0907 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, How to Know where You Are, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0922 Public Program, Day 2, Hotel Aston La Scala, Nice, Provence-Alpes-Côte d'Azur, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1005 Public Program, Lausanne, Vaud, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1012 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (4th Day of Navarātri), Winterthurerstraße, Zürich, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1019 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Dussehra Day), How to Spread Sahaja Yoga in Europe, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"There's one more thing: I was happy to learn that the great poet of this country, Blake, had prophesied about Me.<br />
And it is so beautifully done, that He said that: "England is going to be the Jerusalem." We, this is going to be the pilgrimage. The venue has shifted.<br />
And then He has very beautifully &#8211; have you got the thing to read? No. You haven't brought [it].<br />
But what reading! That: He has said that first thing furnace will be burning in Surrey Hills, where I came first, and then He has mentioned Lambeth Vale, where we have got our Āśhram. Where the foundations will be laid, we have laid the foundations.<br />
And that Jerusalem is going to be in England, not in India. And you are the people responsible for this Jerusalem."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1019 Havan, Navarātri Celebrations (Dussehra Day), To Solve All Your Problems Is to Surrender, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1023 Public Program, Why We Are Seeking Our Spirit, Friends Meeting House, 120 Heath Street, Hampstead, London NW3 1DR, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1027 Public Program, Be Absolutely Absorbed into Your Being (How Necessary It Is to Develop Your Inner Being and The Innermost Core of Every Center is the Spiritual), Outside Qualities Are so Joy-giving to the Spirit (You Have to Enrich Your Outside to Bear that Inside Beauty and Physical Stability, Principle of Well-being, Esthetics of Generosity, and Emotional Life), and Divinity Is Universal (It Embraces Every Thing), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1031 Public Program, You Are to Be Resurrected, Newbury, Berkshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1103 Public Program, We Are All One, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1123 Śhrī Guru Nāṇaka Jayanti Pūjā, You Are to Become Prophets, Temple of All Faiths (now demolished, 11c Pond St), Belsize Park, Hampstead, London, UK (perhaps Caxton Hall)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1124 Public Program, Are You Seekers, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0205 Public Program, Day 1, Introduction to Mūlādhāra Chakra, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1212 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, House, 48 Brompton Square, Knightsbridge, London, UK (date not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1231 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, New Year's Eve, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2001-0716 Public Program, Day 2, Hall, Holland Park School, Airlie Gardens, Campden Hill Rd, London W8 7AF, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Also the leader can read books which are written by some enlightened people to show where they have gone wrong. They should not say that "I say so" but they can use some other book like Khalil Gibran or William Blake or someone like that to show how things were said absolutely in a wrong manner by some of the people who managed to enter into the Scriptures and master them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0700 Book 'Sahaja Yoga', Chapter 5: The Leader in Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This process has now started on an en masse scale and is the fulfillment of William Blake's most heartfelt desire: "would that all God's people were Prophets". In this age of Kṛita Yuga, through the compassion of the Paramachaitanya (or Divine Love), the Kuṇḍalinī is being raised in countless human beings, so that it is actually happening: God's people have become Prophets and, what is more, they have powers to make others Prophets too.<br />
......<br />
Most of the seekers that I met during that time told me that, although they knew they were looking for something, they were completely ignorant of what it was and had been mesmerized by these negative and false teachers. I have to say that it is truly lamentable the way earnest seekers have been exploited by these horrible so-called gurus from India. For seekers are a special category of people and, as such, they are very precious. William Blake describes them as "men of God". They are the ones who have been seeking in many lifetimes to find the Divine and have often become lost in the web of words of false ideas ("śhabda jālam" in Sanskrit, as described by Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya).<br />
......<br />
On the firm foundation of Absolute Truth only, can one have complete confidence and an absolutely peaceful, nonviolent stand in the face of the relative world of uncertainty, contradiction and confusion. Such a person, like William Blake, for example, is truly what is meant by the word Saint &#8211; a person who states the truth simply as he sees it with his higher vision, and does not react vehemently or violently to contradiction and scorn, but pities his or her aggressors as blind and ignorant.<br />
......<br />
Of course, modern art can also have a very evolved manifestation if it is emitted from the formless Spirit. It breaks the lines and forms of conventional art to create a formless substance which is full of light and transparent meaning. But to achieve this potential, one has to be a realized Soul, who can paint his formless joy in such a way as to represent and emit that abstract spontaneous enjoyment of the Spirit by the Spirit. Such art requires no commentary and no discussion. Only a poet can describe it. A poet like William Blake, who was a great evolved Soul and Seer, could also draw and paint the visions He describes in His poetry. The imagination of such poets touches all the beautiful heights that only an enlightened Soul can appreciate and enjoy. All those evolved souls, whether they are sitting in a simple village weaving a shawl for the Goddess, or singing the praise of the Eternal and Everlasting in divine poetry, or playing the divine music, are all the Creator's own Divine Ripples. They may sometimes not be understood, they may be criticized by ignorant, blind people, but they work and sing and play for themselves and for those who have Divine Knowledge and who can understand the world they portray."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 1: Modernism and Rationality</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"These are the seekers all over the world. What they are seeking is the peace of their own mind. It is a good news for such people that a unique discovery has been found out by which one can achieve the peace within. One has to go beyond the mind. This was very old knowledge in the East, especially in India, and there were Seers in the West who also knew about this knowledge by which one can achieve that state of Self-realization. In England William Blake, Molière in France, de Maupassant in France, and many other poets like C.S. Lewis, and certain persons in America, have been endowed with this future vision of divine life entering into human beings."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 11: The Subtle System</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Do the Āratī with the children, have lots of music to develop their sense of rhythm and how to sing. It is important to sing in tune. No dreamy airy-fairy world. Don't let them float about. Give them reality. They can be poets, but use real images like Blake did."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>Education Enlightened A Guide For Schools, Chapter 18: In the Classroom</b></font>
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri William Blake" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ MAHĀVĪRA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0722" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ MAHĀVĪRA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Mahavira</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0722"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Sahaja Yoga is very difficult for the Jains. If the Jains come into Sahaja Yoga they are very difficult people. Because their traditions are very shallow. The people of Ārya Samāj are very shallow people.<br />
Similarly the Buddhists: they believe in the formless but not as far as God is concerned.<br />
<font color="red">Look at this, 'We do not know Buddha. We do not know Muhammad. We have not seen Them. We do not know Mahāvīra. We do not know anyone [of Them]. Who gave us Self-realization? Śhrī Mātājī. That we were able to know because of Śhrī Mātājī.'</font><br />
So, whomever we believe in Them, we will have to believe Them in Śhrī Mātājī itself. Not in Sahaja Yoga."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote, Navarātri Pūjā, from the book Sahaja Yoga, An Experiential Treatise (Sahaja Yoga Anubhavāche Bola) by Venu Narayan Phaḍake, Chapter 19, Pages 248 and 249</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Lot of work was done to cross the Void, some success was achieved. And if you people could get it, They are helpful today. They become eternal. The founder of Jaina Dharma, Śhrī Mahāvīra and Śhrī Buddha are amongst Them. They were born of the same Mother, born of the womb of Ādi Śhakti. Try to know Their first relation that where were They born. But it was experimental for all of Them. All of Them made experiments so that human beings could cross the Void. Very few, however, could cross the Void."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, what can I say, you would be surprised, that the Shia sect that started after Muhammad Sāhab, His daughter was Fāṭimah, She was also Ādi Śhakti.<br />
<font color="red">And Her two children were, Hasan and Husayn, back then, when They saw even after the annihilation of the world, the human beings did not understand, then They were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra and They brought the non-violence as religion, and attempted that, 'Maybe with the establishment of non-violence people will achieve Self-realization.' But couldn't do it.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And His daughter Fāṭimah was nobody else but Sītā Jānakī Herself.<br />
<font color="red">And Her two sons, Hasan and Husayn, were nobody else but Lava and Kuśha. They were born again and again: They were born as Mahāvīra and Buddha, and then They were born as Hasan and Husayn.</font><br />
It is only possible through Sahaja Yoga to realize that this is the Truth, this is the fact."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Such born realized people: this is a very, very far-fe... fetched stuff. They are very few!<br />
<font color="red">I would say, perhaps, you can Buddha and Mahāvīra are the only two, two human beings in who have gone through many lives. From one extreme to another They went. And ultimately, They found out: that going to the extremes is not proper. Still, They have not reached the complete height of an Incarnation.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0126 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (28th Republic Day), Day 1, Questions on Chakras, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now beyond that is God's Realization.<br />
There are three stages to that also, but just now I have told this: the Sat-chit-ānand State.<br />
<font color="red">The God's Realization is the state in which Gautama Buddha and Mahāvīra only rose, and They are settled down here in our brains, both of Them are here, Christ is here.<br />
And these two were not Incarnations. They were born as human beings. They were born to Sītā, as Lav and Kuśh. Then they were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra and Ādi Śhakti was their mother again. Then they were born to Fāṭimah Bi as Hasan and Husayn. They are both placed here in your head and They are the two milestones you have got by which you can know what a human being can rise up to.<br />
Now today they are like Incarnations. Incarnations are beyond but maybe the gap can be bridged.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0216 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Śhivajī Ke Ūpara Sārā Saṃsāra Nirbhara Hai (The Whole World Is Dependent on Śhivajī), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"All the Scriptures, whether it is Bible, Qur'ān, or any Indian Scripture, even Lao Tze, or if we go to Zen or Buddha, Mahāvīra, all of them have said that: "You are to be reborn." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0823 Public Program, Day 1, Temple de la Fusterie (Fusterie Temple), Place de la Fusterie, Geneva, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And that's what one has to do: is to place yourself in such a way, 'Let us see.' Keep your minds open to see: what is the Truth about yourself.<br />
Now this Truth has been told by many Great Sages, by Prophets and many Incarnations who came on Earth. <font color="red">As we know Christ has said about it, Nāṇaka has said about it, Kabīra has said, Lao Tze has said, Buddha has said, everyone has said one thing, which is ... people ... which I should say people neglect and are not bothered about it.</font> And the simple thing is, that: 'You have to have your Second Birth. You have to know your Self. you have to have Self-realization.' This every one of them have said it."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1007 Public Program, Truth Is to Be Achieved, Guild Hall (now Bedford Guild House), 56 Harpur Street, Bedford, Bedfordshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Everyone has said it: Christ has said it, Muhammad has said it, Buddha has said it, Mahāvīra has said it.</font> Everyone has said the same thing! Like Lao Tze, you can say Zen system, everything has said that, ``You are to be born-again," there has to be some transformation within you. They didn't tell us lies!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0308 Press Conference, The Hotel Windsor, 111 Spring Street, Melbourne, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, what people are enamored is that, if they see some people dancing madly, they feel enamored. Is a sign that you have not been able to understand.<br />
<font color="red">We have seen Christ, we have seen Buddha, Mahāvīra, Kabīra, Nāṇaka, we had Lao Tze and so many others. Did They behave like this? Did They become mad?</font> We have got Moses, did He become mad anytime? Was He mad anytime, behaving like a mad person?<br />
All these new theories have started, I think, fifty years back, or about sixty years back, that people believe in these new theories and they have forgotten all the kn... traditional things that have come to us, our heritage. And we depend more on these nonsensical things, which has no moorings at all! Because the people who are supposed to be the founders of all the religions, have never behave like this, and why this new type of things that has started? That people are behaving in this manner, and accepting it to be a very normal thing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0315 Public Program, Day 1, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"All the Incarnations who came on this Earth were a milestone on the ladder of our evolution. But They all had one type of work to do.<br />
Like the Goddess had to kill the rākṣhasas and save the devotees.<br />
That is why Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa arranged this play. This was all a play. There is no need to be so serious about it. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa won everyone with His sweetness. He explained all our faults in a sweet and roundabout way. It was a very beautiful Incarnation of His.<br />
<font color="red">After Him came Mahāvīra and Buddha, who took an Incarnation of Seriousness. In this seriousness, They spoke of Oneness of the Spirit and the knowledge of the Whole.<br />
Then seriousness developed and the people became serious-minded, and made their daily lives very difficult. In fact neither Buddha nor Mahāvīra had said so.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0409 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Ramadas Swami" /><category term="hotpink @ Angels" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ BUDDHA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0714" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ BUDDHA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Buddha</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0714"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This is the experience Buddha received under the boddhi tree but you are not the Buddha."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Śhrī Buddha from the book The Third Advent by Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Page 98</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Look at this, 'We do not know Buddha. We do not know Muhammad. We have not seen Them. We do not know Mahāvīra. We do not know anyone [of Them]. Who gave us Self-realization? Śhrī Mātājī. That we were able to know because of Śhrī Mātājī.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Progress and Global Task from the book Sahaja Yoga, An Experiential Treatise (Sahaja Yoga Anubhavāche Bola) by Venu Narayan Phaḍake, Chapter 13, Page 169</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[Śhrī Vishnu incarnated in several forms from that of a fish to the state of Buddha Avatār and uplifted that form and this led to the human being.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 The Story of Creation (Marathi), House of Śhrī Mātājī, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"It is true that the field of human thought and action before realisation is a field of force, of tension which is generated by the bipolarity of the sun and the moon line. But, within this field of contradiction, the balanced people always look for the synthesis which will bring them closer to the Central path. <font color="red">This [is] the eight fold path described by Lord Buddha.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note Eight Fold Path related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 10</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In the process of bettering his reflectors, he created the human being. And man alone in the entire known creation was gifted with a free moral will and a sense of discretion. Perhaps that the only way, after the ape stage, he could go further with the progress of evolution. It is thus that the human beings constitute the best reflectors of the Creator. <font color="red">Some of them as sages, like Lord Buddha, Jesus Christ, Lord Mahavir, mark the destination of human progress,</font> others as scientist discover the mighty forces of creation which are being constantly harnessed in the service of man. Similarly, some others gifted with extraordinary faculties of perception and understanding play the role of "Artists". They have not only an extra-ordinary "eye" but also an ability to communicate with others through the medium of art. They have an extremely sensitive heart and an equally eloquent medium by which they can touch the hearts of their fellowmen. This factor assumes a social importance and thus an artist plays a vital role, as member of a society."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1961-1000 Article 'Art Culture and Artist' published in the souvenir 'Dignity of Art' brought out to commemorate the Inauguration of the 'Youth Society For Films' by the Union Home Minister Lal Bahadur Shastri on 1961-1008, the function presided over by the Chief Minister of Maharashtra Y. B. Chevam, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Even [a] person like Buddha, He went round the whole world, did all sorts of renunciations and all that, ultimately He got tired. And when He was lying at the feet of a tree, in that relaxed condition, the All-pervading Mother, Holy Mother, just poured Her blessings on Him and He got Realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0324 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Jet Age, Seminar, Day 2, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The essence of whatever has been described in all the religion is only one and is 'to know thyself' and to know this there is only one way that is Sahaja Yoga which may be called as spontaneous growth what happen spontaneously.<br />
<font color="red">Buddha only got it from Sahaja Yoga. He was wandering thousands of places here and there and one day while he was laying, getting tired, His Kuṇḍalinī said that, 'My son is too much tired, somehow to give Him Realization.' That very moment the rays came down to His head and stopped and from below the Kuṇḍalinī strike down His Sahasrāra and got His Realization.</font><br />
Nobody has ever got Realization without Sahaja Yoga."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1117 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Lot of work was done to cross the Void, some success was achieved. And if you people could get it, They are helpful today. They become eternal. The founder of Jaina Dharma, Śhrī Mahāvīra and Śhrī Buddha are amongst Them. They were born of the same Mother, born of the womb of Ādi Śhakti. Try to know Their first relation that where were They born. But it was experimental for all of Them. All of Them made experiments so that human beings could cross the Void. Very few, however, could cross the Void."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, what can I say, you would be surprised, that the Shia sect that started after Muhammad Sāhab, His daughter was Fāṭimah, She was also Ādi Śhakti.<br />
<font color="red">And Her two children were, Hasan and Husayn, back then, when They saw even after the annihilation of the world, the human beings did not understand, then They were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra and They brought the non-violence as religion, and attempted that, 'Maybe with the establishment of non-violence people will achieve Self-realization.' But couldn't do it.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Shia word has been derived from Siyā. The word which come from Siyā became Shia &#8211; Siyā means Sītājī. If you go to UP [Uttar Pradesh, India] then nobody says Sītājī, they say Siyājī, 'Siyā var Rām[a]chandra ki jay.' Everyone takes the name Siyā. She was Sītājī, Ādi Śhakti Herself.<br />
<font color="red">And Her two sons, who were Hasan and Husayn, destroyed many evils. When They ultimately died after getting tried, then in the next birth they thought of establishment of nonviolence, violence led them nowhere.<br />
They were [re]born as Mahāvīr and Buddha to make a new experiment. Experiments do happen.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You seek: first you seek in money, then in power. If in this birth any person has abundant money, then in next birth he will say, 'I do not want money, make me a minister somewhere.' Then he will seek in power. If he has not found it in power then he will seek in religion. But all of his seeking is done from outside.<br />
<font color="red">The moment he is tired of all his seeking, like Buddha also, who was tired from all corners and He laid down getting exhausted [and thought], 'No, I am not going to find it in this way. I did not get it in what I was seeking.' The moment He got tired, the very moment He was blessed and He ultimately found it. He too got it from Sahaja Yoga itself and all the Big Gurus of this world too have got it from Sahaja Yoga, everyone had achieved it through Sahaja Yoga.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1219 Public Program (Hindi), Nagpur, Maharashtra, India (other date 1222)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And His daughter Fāṭimah was nobody else but Sītā Jānakī Herself.<br />
<font color="red">And Her two sons, Hasan and Husayn, were nobody else but Lava and Kuśha. They were born again and again: They were born as Mahāvīra and Buddha, and then They were born as Hasan and Husayn.</font><br />
It is only possible through Sahaja Yoga to realize that this is the Truth, this is the fact."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Those who go to the extremes of things are also no good for Sahaja Yoga.<br />
<font color="red">Extreme takes you away from reality which was said by Gautam Buddha. He said, "Take to the mid... middle path. Keep to d... to the middle path." But His disciples have gone to the extreme path, of foolishness. He said, "Don't worship any Gods or Goddesses," at that time, because He was in Sahaja. So, His disciples started worshipping His tooth, nail, everything.</font><br />
Of course, that too has a meaning. But not for people who are not realized."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0319 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, It Is a Spontaneous Growth of Your Being into that Infinite Realm of God's Grace and The Articulation of Your Personality, Seminar, Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Rd, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So what must we do?<br />
<font color="red">The human beings have to come to the state of Gautama who became the Buddha. He searched in all earnestness and honesty. He gave up first all fake worldly preoccupations. This is not required but when he gave up all hopes of searching, (the occupation of the mind), he accepted his defeat. He felt tired and fell at the feet of the Holy Ghost.<br />
Buddha had dharma. His body was clean, His mind, the attention, did not find any joy in the worldly greed or desire. His cup was ready and it emptied when he was tired and surrendered and that was the moment: like torrential rain, the "Shakti" filled His cup and made Him the "Shakta", the Enlightened One.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-1012 Letter to Grégoire de Kalbermatten about Dharma (also Pyramids and Tāj Mahal), London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Such born realized people: this is a very, very far-fetched stuff; they are very few.<br />
I would say perhaps Buddha and Mahāvīra are the only two human beings who have gone through many lives. From one extreme to another They went and ultimately They found out that going to the extremes is not proper. Still They have not reached the complete height of an Incarnation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0126 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (28th Republic Day), Day 1, Questions on Chakras, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now beyond that is God's Realization.<br />
There are three stages to that also, but just now I have told this: the Sat-chit-ānand State.<br />
<font color="red">The God's Realization is the state in which Gautama Buddha and Mahāvīra only rose, and They are settled down here in our brains, both of Them are here, Christ is here.<br />
And these two were not Incarnations. They were born as human beings. They were born to Sītā, as Lav and Kuśh. Then they were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra and Ādi Śhakti was their mother again. Then they were born to Fāṭimah Bi as Hasan and Husayn. They are both placed here in your head and They are the two milestones you have got by which you can know what a human being can rise up to.<br />
Now today they are like Incarnations. Incarnations are beyond but maybe the gap can be bridged.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"All the Scriptures, whether it is Bible, Qur'ān, or any Indian Scripture, even Lao Tze, or if we go to Zen or Buddha, Mahāvīra, all of them have said that: "You are to be reborn." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0823 Public Program, Day 1, Temple de la Fusterie (Fusterie Temple), Place de la Fusterie, Geneva, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And that's what one has to do: is to place yourself in such a way, 'Let us see.' Keep your minds open to see: what is the Truth about yourself.<br />
Now this Truth has been told by many Great Sages, by Prophets and many Incarnations who came on Earth. <font color="red">As we know Christ has said about it, Nāṇaka has said about it, Kabīra has said, Lao Tze has said, Buddha has said, everyone has said one thing, which is ... people ... which I should say people neglect and are not bothered about it.</font> And the simple thing is, that: 'You have to have your Second Birth. You have to know your Self. you have to have Self-realization.' This every one of them have said it."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1007 Public Program, Truth Is to Be Achieved, Guild Hall (now Bedford Guild House), 56 Harpur Street, Bedford, Bedfordshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, what people are enamored is that, if they see some people dancing madly, they feel enamored. Is a sign that you have not been able to understand.<br />
<font color="red">We have seen Christ, we have seen Buddha, Mahāvīra, Kabīra, Nāṇaka, we had Lao Tze and so many others. Did They behave like this? Did They become mad?</font> We have got Moses, did He become mad anytime? Was He mad anytime, behaving like a mad person?<br />
All these new theories have started, I think, fifty years back, or about sixty years back, that people believe in these new theories and they have forgotten all the kn... traditional things that have come to us, our heritage. And we depend more on these nonsensical things, which has no moorings at all! Because the people who are supposed to be the founders of all the religions, have never behave like this, and why this new type of things that has started? That people are behaving in this manner, and accepting it to be a very normal thing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0315 Public Program, Day 1, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Everyone has said it: Christ has said it, Muhammad has said it, Buddha has said it, Mahāvīra has said it.</font> Everyone has said the same thing! Like Lao Tze, you can say Zen system, everything has said that, ``You are to be born-again," there has to be some transformation within you. They didn't tell us lies!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0308 Press Conference, The Hotel Windsor, 111 Spring Street, Melbourne, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"......<br />
So, all the saṃnyāsa and all these ideas came gradually: everyone who came on this Earth, people have really made a mess out of them.<br />
<font color="red">And Buddha's mess has gone to such an extent, that, if you see that you'll be shocked. It went into many formations.</font><br />
But I heard from My son-in-law that he went and visited some of the caves where the very early Buddhist lived, very early Buddhist lived. In the caves because they were not supported by kings or anything so, they had a very bad time. And they used to live in the caves. And what My son-in-law told Me that in the caves there are writings: in Sanskrit, in Pali, and in Indian script, say-ing that, "It is the spontaneous happening that can bring forth the Self-realization." He's got that photographed.<br />
So, it's coming forward.<br />
You see, so they knew about it, the Sahaja Yoga. They knew about it.<br />
But then as every religion has gone into a mess and lot of funny sort of uh-uh-uh, we can say the uh-uh-uh, funny sort of uh expressions, also, Buddhism has gone, it became Mahāyān, Hīnayān, all sorts of thing.<br />
But one of them was called as Viditama, who ran away from India, settled down in Japan and he started the Zen system of religion, which he kept to the spontaneous happening. That's one was preserved.<br />
Another was the Lao Tze style who did not talk of God and of Buddha, but of Ta-o Itself: the Energy or we can say about the Ādi Śhakti.<br />
<font color="red">So these two good things came out of Him [Lord Buddha].</font><br />
......"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0526 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Brighton Center, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"We have heard about the All-pervading Divine Power. <font color="red">Right from Lao Tze to Christ, to Buddha, all of Them have talked about it.</font><br />
We did not know about ether before, but we have heard about the Divine Power which is all-pervading.<br />
Once you are united with it, connected with it, then only you realize that you are a part and parcel of the whole. But before that, it's only talk. Talk of religion, talk about all philosophies, is just a talk.<br />
Without any experience of this Divine Power, if we are going to believe into these talks and these dogmas, also these mental projections, we'll reach a state where we will say: 'We don't believe in it.' But this is not the way to know the Divine."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0917 Public Program, Collège Saint-Michel, Boulevard Saint-Michel 24, Etterbeek, Brussels-Capital Region, Belgium</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"All the Incarnations who came on this Earth were a milestone on the ladder of our evolution. But They all had one type of work to do.<br />
Like the Goddess had to kill the rākṣhasas and save the devotees.<br />
That is why Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa arranged this play. This was all a play. There is no need to be so serious about it. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa won everyone with His sweetness. He explained all our faults in a sweet and roundabout way. It was a very beautiful Incarnation of His.<br />
<font color="red">After Him came Mahāvīra and Buddha, who took an Incarnation of Seriousness. In this seriousness, They spoke of Oneness of the Spirit and the knowledge of the Whole.<br />
Then seriousness developed and the people became serious-minded, and made their daily lives very difficult. In fact neither Buddha nor Mahāvīra had said so.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0409 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā (Hindi), Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Buddha said the same, Mahāvīra said the same, Christ said the same, Kṛiṣhṇa said the same, Rāma said the same, Lao Tze, you find everyone, the Zen, everybody said the same thing that we have to achieve that world, that we have to enter into the Kingdom of God."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0321 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Birthday Felicitations, before Birthday Pūjā, Kalā Mandir Hall, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And you know everything! All the subtle knowledge which was not known to you.<br />
<font color="red">Then you can understand uh-uh-uh Tao of Lao Tze, you can ... you can understand uh Buddha, Zen, Viditama, Christ, and all other Incarnations. You get connected to them. And that is how you achieve this power.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0420 Public Program, Taipei City, Taiwan}\label{1994-0420 Public Program, Taipei City, Taiwan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"How do you know your Self? When this Kuṇḍalinī rises, She passes through six centers. She passes through six centers, and pierces through the, we call it seventh one, through the bra... fontanel-bone area, which is actualization. You can feel It on top of your head.<br />
I mean, every Saint, every Sufi has talked about it, if you have read them. Lao Tze has talked about it. <font color="red">Everyone, Buddha has talked about it, that you have to have your Self-realization.</font> Self-realization means knowing about your Self. All of them have said this!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0616 Public Program, Town Hall, 123 West and 43rd Street, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 10: The Central Path of Sustenance</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"omehow when it comes to religion, they will only follow Christ, or only follow Muhammad Sāhib or only follow Buddha. In Sahaja Yoga we have all of Them, absolutely activating your Kuṇḍalinī. Everybody in Sahaja Yoga knows so much about Them, and the most important thing is that They are all with us, They are part and parcel of us and They are not separated by anything. They were working the same process in history, and now we are working it out in the present with all of Them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0700 Book 'Sahaja Yoga', Chapter 2: Vishwa Nirmala Dharma</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"All the religions from ancient times have said that a man or a woman has to cleanse their mind through religious activity, with righteous thinking. The aim of every religion was to establish balance in every way to make way for the ascent of the seeker. <font color="red">The Second Birth, Walīhood, Selfhood, Buddha's State, Jaini State, Gnostic, or Ātma-sākṣhātkār, are all names for Self-realization.</font> It was all right in the olden days, where people wanted to be good and to ascend. They obeyed and tried to do whatever was asked for by the Saints, Prophets or Incarnations.<br />
......<br />
On the whole, if you see, Western culture denies Christ who sacrificed his life for the sins of the people. Those who call themselves Christians indulge in all kinds of activities which are anti-Christ. When Christ came into this world in the Realm of Divinity, one had to go through penance (tapasyā). <font color="red">Buddha and Mahāvīra had to do the same at that time.</font> Christians do not know what is penance and they cannot sacrifice even a pin for others. They are very good at lip service. Big conferences are held in the developing nations for monetary help, who pay for these conferences and the outcome is that nothing can be done for the poor countries while Westerners spend their superfluous money on all kinds of waste.<br />
......<br />
Now, a few words about Buddhism. <font color="red">Lord Buddha talked about compassion, compassion and compassion. He bore all the troubles of those days and at the end of his life he was in a very bad financial condition and ultimately he died in a very remote corner of India. Lord Buddha's life has been really ideal but people believe that you cannot attain spiritual ascent unless and until you suffer like Him and give up everything the way He had given it up.</font> The ascetic concept is that one has to give up the family, one has to give up money, property, all possessions, one has to give up the normal life that one leads and has to be an absolute celibate in order to move on the spiritual path. But there are Buddhists and Buddhists. Most of their different forms are lost in ritualism or mental meditation. The Japanese follow the Zen system without understanding anything about it. <font color="red">They have built a beautiful temple of Buddha in Bodhi Gayā where Buddha got his Nirvāṇa.</font> When Genghis Khān invaded Behar, the Buddhist monks did not resort to violence and died. Another style of Buddhism is that of the Japanese who had to learn a lesson through the extreme suffering of Hiroshima.<br />
The Dalai Lamas preach nonviolence, but they have been very money or gold-oriented people. In Beijing, one can see thousands of gold plates and gold beer mugs with Pali inscriptions in the secret vaults. It is said they were rescued from a river by the Chinese soldiers who went after Mister [Dalai] Lama and his followers who were running away to India and who dumped part of the gold they were carrying in the river. This was rescued and put in the museum. They wear saffron clothes to show that they are saṃnyāsīs but live like lords in Dharmaśhālā. I met such a Canadian saṃnyāsī in Canada and he told me that he had no other clothes but these. He said he lost all his property to Dalai Lama who begs all over the world. In Dharmaśhālā, there was a great protest against these very aggressive Dalai Lama's people, but many Governments have sympathy for this money-oriented (gold-oriented), spiritual head, so to pacify these ignorant Governments, who do not discriminate between truth and hypocrisy, the protesters had to ask for forgiveness.<br />
As it is, India has a large load of refugees and they cannot afford to have these gold-oriented saṃnyāsīs which have created a diplomatic rift between China and India. There are Buddhists in Nepal who believe in black magic. Many seekers go to Nepal and get lost. Buddhist Lamas are of many kinds. Some of them have monasteries where to raise the Kuṇḍalinī the seekers are beaten on the spinal cord till their backs are broken. In China they also worship Mother Mercy, Kuan Yin [Guānyīn], who was a Chinese Incarnation. <font color="red">Lord Buddha has given three mantras to chant: to surrender to Lord Buddha or a realized Soul; surrender to dharma (morality); surrender to collectivity.</font> They use a noisy wail to chant mantras. <font color="red">Like all other religious Incarnations he has talked of "Maitreya", is a future Buddha who will give liberation. "Maitreya" means that three Mothers together will incarnate to give Nirvāṇa.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
In Japan we had another great Master whose name was Viditama. <font color="red">"He was the disciple of Lord Buddha and he went to Japan and started the Zen system.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 8: World Peace</b></font>
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Buddha" /><category term="hotpink @ Disciple Principle" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ YEŚHODĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0707" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ YEŚHODĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Yeshoda</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0707"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, Jesus Christ thing.<br />
<font color="red">Jesus, Jesu or Yeśhu, this is the name of Yeśhodā, was given by Rādhā to Her Son. We say Yesu or Jesu.</font> And Krist is His surname."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0222 Public Program, Day 1, About Different Chakras and Their Deities, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now just put attention on the word Christ. The name comes from Krist. And Krist comes from Kṛiṣhṇa. Because He was Kṛiṣhṇa's Son, so the name of Father was continuing so His name was Krist. But His name was Jesus also, that is because He was also the Son of Rādhā. <font color="red">Rādhā thought that, 'Till today nowhere the name of Jaśhodā was mentioned.' That's why Ya-śho-dā means Jesus. Like we say Yasodā, we say Jesu. If someone's name is Jasoda, he will be known as Jesu, and Jasoda will be known as Jesu.<br />
Many people like in Maharashtra know him as Yeśhu and Jasoda as Jesu.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0201 Public Program (Hindi), Brahma kā Gyān (Knowledge of Brahma) or Mūlādhāra to Viśhuddhi, Āgñyā, and Sahasrāra, 9 Raisina Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Kṛiṣhṇa was His father and therefore He was called Christ. <font color="red">And Rādhājī called Him Yeśhu after Yaśhodā.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0304 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Session 2 (evening), Town Hall, Dehradun, Uttarakhand, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Christ is none other, He is the incarnation of Śhrī Gaṇeśh.<br />
How He was made? If you read Devī Bhāgavat[am] by Mārkaṇḍeya, you will understand. He was made as Mahāviṣhṇu first and was described as how He is the basis of this Universe and how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who is the father of Christ, that is why He is called Christ. They call Him Christ, like it is the surname. <font color="red">And Yaśhodājī's name is used and He is also called as Yeśhu. That is how Rādhāji Herself kept His name, and Rādhāji is His mother.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0311 Public Program (English + Hindi), Day 2, Session 2 (evening), On Gāndhī and Collective Consciousness, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"His name was Jesus because you know that in UP [Uttar Pradesh] Yaśhodā is called as Jasodā. It is Jasodā's name Rādhājī wanted to give Him and that's why [She] called Him Jesu or Yeśhu."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0328 Public Address, Inauguration of The Advent (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 5&#8211;12</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />  
"Do read Devī Māhātmyam or Devī Bhāgavat[am]. Go through the description of Śhrī Mahāviṣhṇu in it. It is described that Śhrī Rādhājī prepared Her Son similarly as Śhrī Pārvatī did it but the main principle in this is Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle and the Son prepared as Śhrī Gaṇeśha came in the world as Jesus Christ.<br />
<font color="red">Because Christ was prepared by Rādhājī so He got the name Christ in the name of Kṛiṣhṇa and Yeśhu in the name of Yaśhodā.</font> In this way, She manifested the Gaṇeśha Principle in the form of Śhrī Christ."<br />
<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
Nowadays nobody reads Mārkaṇḍeya, but if you can get it, read the description of Śhrī Mahāviṣhṇu.<br />
He has mentioned that Rādhā had created Her own Son by Herself. Means just as Pārvatī created Her Son, She too had created [Hers].<br />
But Gaṇeśh Tattwa is the base for it. And based on Gaṇeśh Tattwa, the Son She had created, He came in this world as Christ.<br />
<font color="red">Now Christ. As Rādhā had created Him, He is called Christ in the name of Kṛiṣhṇa and as Yaśhodā is there, hence Yeśhu.</font><br />
In this way She has positioned the Gaṇeśh Tattwa in the form of Christ.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0922 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī and Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Navarātri Celebrations (1st Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, if you study the etymology of the word Christ, you would know that the word has originated from a corrupted form of word Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
As a matter of fact, the Father of Jesus Christ is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. That is why He is called Christ.<br />
The manner in which His name Jesus originated is also very interesting. <font color="red">The mother of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, Śhrī Yaśhodā Mātā, was addressed as Yesu. Even today, we notice that in northern Indian somebody named Yeśhu is not addressed as such but as Jesu. It is therefore clear, that from Yaśhodā came the word Yeśhu and then further became the word Jesu, and finally the name Jesus Christ.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0927 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Kuṇḍalinī and Lord Jesus Christ, Navarātri Celebrations (6th Day), Hinduja Auditorium, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0401 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 5, Viśhuddhi and Āgñyā Chakras, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1006 Public Program (8th Day of Navarātri), Day 3, The New Age Has Started (From Kṛiṣhṇa to Christ), Venue 2, Unity (Church of Christianity), 2929 Unity Drive, Houston, TX, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1018 Public Program, Day 2, Session 2 (evening), Heartwood Community Center, 200 7th Avenue, Santa Cruz, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">And She [Śhrī Rādhā] is the one who called Him Jesus. Actually, in the Hebrew it is Yesu. And also in the &#8211; thank God, I read the Bible in Marathi, which was directly translated from Hebrew &#8211; Yesu is the name. Yesu is the name of the Mother of Christ, now, Mo... Mother of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. Yesu, means, as we call Her, Jesu or Yesu from Jesodā or Yeśhodā. From that She called Him.</font> And Christ word comes from Kṛiṣhṇa. <font color="red">So She called Him Krista and Yesu or Jesus.</font><br />
<font color="red">We, too, call Yeśhodā sometimes Jesu or Yesu.</font><br />
<font color="red">So She called Him by that name. And that is how She put the link for us to understand how close He was to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1225 Christmas Pūjā, Rationality Can Never Make You Understand Divinity, Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0820 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, In Every Walk of Life You Should Have a Very Spontaneous Decision and You Have to Create (fun and joy, maybe art, maybe music, maybe poetry, maybe literature) and Above All You Have to Create Sahaja Yogi (Personality Which Only Lives for Others Not for Oneself and Which Really Reflects God's Love and Becoming a Mahāyogi by Which Your Spirit Gives Joy, Peace and Blessings to Everyone), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Ādi Viṣhṇu's eighth form was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa during the Dwāpara Yuga, and again Ādi Śhakti took three forms. Mahākālī lived for a very short time as Viṣhṇumāyā, the infant sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. <font color="red">She was actually born as the daughter of Yeśhodā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's foster mother, and was killed by the demon Kaṃsa.</font> She later took birth as Draupadī, wife of the Pāṇḍavas. <font color="red">Yeśhodā was Herself an Incarnation of Mahāsaraswatī.</font> As Mahālakṣhmī She took two forms, Rādhā and Rukmiṇī. '<i>Rā</i>' means power or energy and '<i>dhā</i>' means sustenance, so the name 'Rādhā' means the one who sustains the power. As Rukmiṇī She became Queen to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the King in Dvārakā.<br />
......<br />
Rādhā in Mary's Incarnation wanted to give Her Son the name of Her Lord, Kṛiṣhṇa. Kṛiṣhṇa comes from '<i>kṛiṣhi</i>' + '<i>\it ṇa</i>'. '<i>Kṛiṣhi</i>' means farming, '<i>ṇa</i>' means the one who carries. So the name 'Christ' came from the 'kṛiṣhi' in Kṛiṣhṇa. <font color="red">The name Jesus was derived from Jasodā, a form of Yeśhodā, the foster mother of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. Rādhā also wanted to give Yeśhodā's name to Her Son because of Yeśhodā's devotion and worship of Her in Vṛindāvan and Gokul. The abbreviation of Yeśhodā was 'Jesu' or 'Yesu', so Rādhā/Mary named Her Son Jesus Christ.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations &#8211; Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Yeshoda" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Yashoda" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Yasoda" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Jashoda" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Jasoda" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Jeshoda" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Jesoda" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahasaraswati" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ MACCHINDRANĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0630" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ MACCHINDRANĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Macchindranath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0630"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Macchinder Nath an incarnation of Primordial Guru started Nath Pantha.</font> Even after some decades these were very few real Gurus (Avadhuta[s)] left in this cult. The deterioration started. Tankrikas [tantrikas] who imposed themselves as Gurus took charge of the cult in Many places."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Haṭha Yoga related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now about this power ... in our country many people knew about this for ages and they were called true Masters (Sadguru). These people had attained this knowledge through very hard penance.<br />
A power named as Kuṇḍalinī resides in our triangular bone. And we call it Kuṇḍalinī because it's [it] sits in the shape of three and a half coil. It is very surprising that even Greeks knew about this. Because the triangular bone where Kuṇḍalinī resides, they call it sacrum bone. It means there is this sacred bone within us. Not sure, if many of these things they adopted from us or they attained this knowledge themselves in sahaja way.<br />
<font color="red">In our country, experimentations to achieve Self-realization have been going on for ages. In Maharashtra [India] there have been people belonging to Nāth sect like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, etc., these people were all into this.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1907-0000 Interview (Hindi) with a Lady for a TV Program Directed by Ashok Agarwal, Ardhamātrā Volume 2, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To make the people cross the Void (Bhavasāgara) He has to make some arrangement. So the Great Power like Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha was created and They were placed in the Area of Dharma.<br />
Dattātreya and Ādi Gurus incarnated in this world many a times. He incarnated as King Janaka who was like the father of Ādi Śhakti. <font color="red">After that He incarnated in Iran as Zoroaster, then as Macchindranāth, then as Muhammad Sāheb and Nāṇak Sāheb.</font><br />
No one fought with each other. See what type of darkness you are in?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Śhrī Dattātreya's Incarnations are numerous. Firstly He came as King Janaka. Śhrī Sītājī was His daughter, who was the embodiment of Śhakti Herself. <font color="red">Then He came as Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, and Muhammad Sāhab, who were a completely different type of human being.</font><br />
They trialed out lots of different things.<br />
Śhrī Datta, the Primordial Masters firstly in this world educated us about the symbolic forms within us. And then also said that, "You people got entangled in symbolism, in idol worshiping." Their meaning was to go beyond and recognize the Śhakti within these idols. That's why They talked about the idols."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The same Śhrī Dattā incarnated many a times on the Earth.<br />
As I told you yesterday, King Janaka was one of Them. King Janaka was the father of Jānakī [Śhrī Sītā]. He was none other than the Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya.<br />
<font color="red">Thereafter, Macchindranāth, most have you must have heard His name, was also His Incarnation.</font><br />
After that Zoroaster who came three times on the Earth, He was also His Incarnation.<br />
After that Muhammad Sāhab, who was His Incarnation.<br />
And when He was asked that, "Bhāī [Brother], there must have been others also before You," then He replied, "Yes, there [was] a Muhammad." Then again He was asked who was before Him. He replied, "There was one Muhammad."<br />
Muhammad means Praise, the One who is praised, the One who deserves to be praised and is the One who is Redeemer of the world.<br />
They were all Muhammads, They were all Dattātreyas, who came on Earth regularly.<br />
After that [was] Nāṇaka, Guru Nāṇaka. If you ever read His teachings, if you read His talks then you will be surprised that He has always talked in a Sahaja. He has said, "Sahaja Samādhi lago." He has said, "Kāhe re ban khojan jāe, Sarab nivāsī sadā alepā tohī saṃg[a] samāī, Puṣhpamadhya jo bāsa basata hai mukara māhī jaise chhāī, Taise hī harī base niraṃtara ghaṭa hī khojo bhāī." ["Why to go to forest to find Him, He is always there with you just like there is a fragrance in a flower and just as the reflection is there in a mirror, in the same way God is residing in you eternally, seek Him within."] He is just inside, achieve Him just inside. We are just singing poem, singing songs, we are just cramming His prescription.<br />
The talk of seeking this Absolute Principle, residing just inside the heart, has been made since ancient times by these Ādi Gurus, who are incarnated on this Earth again and again.<br />
......<br />
Now just look at Gaganagaḍ Mahārāj, it is true that he cured many people, but the problem is that his fingers moved inside like a telescope and those of feet also. The poor man lives on a tree or moves on a lion. Apart from this he cannot move anywhere. But when I reached to him, these people were with Me, he quickly recognized Me. There is no doubt about it. He has not yet seen Me in this lifetime. But from many years he knew about Me. He is elder to Me. He began to say, "Mother, I have been waiting for you for many years. Today I am so fortunate that you have come here." <font color="red">He is a Nāth Pānthi, so he is just like Macchindranāth and a very great person.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, we have had great Saints in our country, no doubt.<br />
Even a person like Gyāneśhwara, was a great Saint we have [had]. <font color="red">And He was in the same line as Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, then Gyānināth, and then His father [brother] there was Nivṛuttināth, and He initiated Him. And we had a Great Guru paramparā, Guru tradition in a ... that Nāth Pānthis.</font><br />
Even He, Gyāneśhwara, who was a realized Soul, no doubt, and His brother was really a very great Saint. Even He, when He writes about [the] Kuṇḍalinī awakening, He doesn't do the way you Sahaja Yogis [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
That I wish you could read Marathi, I could make you understand now.<br />
And how He has raised the Kuṇḍalinī, what happens: He could give Realization to two people in His lifetime. See?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0527 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, TM, False Gurus, Industrial Revolution, Christ, Go Slowly with New People, Seminar, Day 1, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Dattātreya is the innocence of all these Three Powers.<br />
And this Guru uh was the One whose ... who then had a big tradition of Gurus.<br />
In the same tradition, we had many Gurus in our country. And, specially, in the area near Bombay [Mumbai], which is called as Maharashtra, they came as Nāth. They are, they were called as Nāth.<br />
<font color="red">So the first one was Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], then ahh Dattātreya, then Macchindranāth, then Gorakhnāth, like that a tradition of these Gurus came.</font><br />
But all Their knowledge was kept as a guarded secret. It was a Gupta Vidyā. Is absolutely guarded secret: secret knowledge about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
They never talked about it, they never told about it. Because they thought: that, 'Just now, let us experiment with it fully, and then we will give some idea about it to people.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0107 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), Jñāneśhvarasāgar (Mulā Dharaṇa or Mula Dam), Bārāgāva Nāṃdūra (near Rāhurī), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0106 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), Ascent Is the Main Attention, Sangli, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0125 Pūjā, Why We Have Failed in Our Pursuit of God (The Whole System Has to Be Changed), Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1221 Pūjā (Marathi + English + Marathi + English), Become Beautiful Vessels of Vibrations and Attention on Quality, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[We had many Yogis who started work on the middle path of human ascent like Gorakhnāth, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], Macchindranāth. They worked on the problem of human beings and how to make this ascent possible. They discovered in human beings in the triangular bone sacrum a residual power.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1018 Public Talk, 1st World Conference on Yoga Organized by the Soviet Ministry of Health, Moscow University, Moscow, Russia (other date 1019)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0212 Public Program, Day 1, Chowdia Memorial Hall, Town Hall, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, the tradition is, that: we had a group, we should say, we called them as Nāth Pānthis, in India, who were working on the central path, which is called as Suṣhumṇā. But the tradition was that only one guru c[o]uld have only one disciple. That was the tradition, for ages together.<br />
<font color="red">And the we had this-s Gorakhnāth, and you must have heard about the Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], all these people.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0413 Public Program, National Press Club, Canberra, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />  
"In early tradition, it was accustomed to have one guru per student.<br />
<font color="red">It was like this in Nāth Pānthi. One path was devotion (Bhakti Mārg) and the other path was to read about lok [mankind, world] or ved [knowledge]. But as far as Self-realization was concerned, Nāth Pānthi introduced [it] in Maharashtra, like Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth. At that time also there was a custom to have one guru per student.</font>"
<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />  
"Earlier, it was a custom that one guru should have only one disciple only.<br />
<font color="red">This was the custom in Nāth Pānthi also. On one side, they were very ignorant, and on the other side, people were reading Vedas, etc. But when it was the question of Self-realization, it was Nāth Pānthis who said it was in Maharashtra. Like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth. At that time, it was a custom that one master should have only one disciple.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1216 Public Program (Hindi + Marathi), Day 1, Kuṇḍalinī Eka Mahāna Śhakti (Kuṇḍalinī Is a Great Power), Grounds, New English School, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And that is why, in this country, people knew about Kuṇḍalinī since long.<br />
I don't know if you have read about Mārkaṇḍeya, who is, see, was about fourteen thousand years back in history. And He has talked about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
<font color="red">Then we have Nāth Pānthis who were, like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, ancient! They have talked of Kuṇḍalinī. They where the ones who really used a separate or different type of a method, which they called as Sahaj the Way.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0115 Public Program, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[Today's Sahaj Yoga is only one advancement.]<br />
[If you read Mārkaṇḍeya, who was thirteen thousand years ago, he was only sixteen years old when He wrote about the Kuṇḍalinī.]<br />
<font color="red">[Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth and Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya have described it.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0118 Public Program, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1008 Śhrī Śhakti Devī Pūjā, We Have to Understand Our Own Responsibility (Sense of Responsibility and the Main Quality of Viśhuddhi Chakra is Responsibility) and The Greatest Problem of America is Mister Ego (Surrender your ego and Ego Must Be Controlled), Camp Vacamas, 256 Macopin Road, West Milford, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1028 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi + Hindi + English), after Concert, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi) (5th day after Diwālī Day), Nargol, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1030 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + English) (6th day after Diwālī Day), Sahajyog Ke Suruvat (How Sahaja Yoga Started), Nargol, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0219 Public Address to Doctors, Inauguration, International Sahaja Yoga Research and Health Center, Plot No. 1, Sector 8, H.H. Śhrī Nirmalā Devī Mārg, C.B.D. Belapur, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0721 Public Program, CSCA Stadium, Povitroflots'kyi prospect 2, Kiev, Ukraine</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0919 Public Program, Convocation Hall, University of Toronto, 31 King's College Circle, Toronto, ON, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But I was surprised that in Kiev, which is the capital of Ukraine, I went to see the museum: is full of paintings of Kuṇḍalinī and of the chakras, different chakras. I was amazed: 'How could it be?'<br />
<font color="red">And then they said that, "Two thousand before Christ [2000 B.C.], two S-Saints came from India," and they told Me the name and I was a... amazed how they knew the names of those people: Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth.</font><br />
That time I think America didn't exist, otherwise they would have come here also. [Laughter.]<br />
<font color="red">And these two people went there. And they taught them all about Kuṇḍalinī, but they said, "We didn't know how to raise, we didn't know how to achieve it. So, we just knew it, but we didn't know how to do it.</font>"<br />
Same in India: Gyāneśhwara has written about it.<br />
But much before that, thirteen thousand years back, another Saint, Mārkaṇḍeya, has written about it.<br />
Then in the sixth century, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has written about it.<br />
And it has been written by many people. In the sixteenth century, so many Saints have written about.<br />
In the Bible also it is there, that, "I'll appear before you like tongues of flames," and these are the chakras that you see."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0924 Public Program, The Olympic Collection, Grand Ballroom, 3rd Floor, 11301 W. Olympic Boulevard, 204, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0927 Public Program, Auditorium, New York Society for Ethical Culture, 2 West 64th Street, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0406 Public Talk to Doctors, Conference "The Art of Healing and 'Sahaja Yoga' &#8211; A Special Session on Alternative Medicine", Indian Medical Association, FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0622 Public Program, Convocation Hall, University of Toronto, 31 King's College Circle, Toronto, ON, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Those who went into the research of this in India were called as Nāth Pānthis. Nāth means master and paṇṭh[an] means way, that is, way or road of mastery. Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth were two of these Saints thousands of years ago. These two and others traveled extensively. They had visited the land which is now Ukraine because in the museum you can find ancient pottery with paintings of these chakras."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0827 Written (Presented) Talk, Russian Folk Medicine Conference, Russia (other date 0901)}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">I am very surprised that from India people like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, who used to talk about Kuṇḍalinī, traveled to places like Bolivia, several thousand years back, which is a very difficult place for us to reach. They went to Ukraine and also to some parts of Russia. And after going there they explained to people that, 'This Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti is inside you and all the chakras are present inside your system.'</font><br />
And we people who are their progeny do not know anything about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
The natives of Bolivia know everything about Kuṇḍalinī but they say that they do not know how to awaken the Kuṇḍalinī, though they are aware of the existence of Kuṇḍalinī. I went to Bolivia only once, and many thousands of people got Self-realization instantly.<br />
But we people do not have any knowledge of this, and no one tells us about it, nor it is mentioned in any of our books. It is as if we have been completely severed from that great culture and the great knowledge, and we ourselves do not know what kind of peculiar human beings we have become. We are neither Indians nor English. We do not know to which country we belong to. People also do not know the meaning of Kuṇḍalinī. Just imagine, people do not know what is this Kuṇḍalinī which has an ocean-like knowledge inside it."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-1218 Public Program (Hindi), Naitikatā aura Deśhabhakti (Ethics and Patriotism), Rāmlīlā Maidān, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, Friday before Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0305 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English + Hindi + Marathi), Stadium, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Many Saints from our country went to other countries. <font color="red">I think Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth also went to many countries.</font><br />
Bolivian people know about them. They know the names of the chakras and also they know about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
I have seen, in the ancient paintings of the Russia, they have painted plexuses. If you travel a little in this country [Russia], then you will be surprised that how and from where have they known about it! Decidedly some of our Saints might have gone there and told about every thing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0325 Public Program (Hindi), Hamārī Ātmā Kyā Chīja Hai (What Is Our Spirit), Rāmlīlā Maidān, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0408 Public Address to I.A.S. Officers' Wives Association, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Africa, I was surprised: that they have talked about Kuṇḍalinī. They have! And I have seen some of the maps, old maps, of Africa, they have made the picture of Kuṇḍalinī also, all over.<br />
Even in a place like Bolivia, which is so far away, and the somebody went to Bolivia, from Italy, and he said, "Mother they know everything about Kuṇḍalinī!" I said, "Really?" "Yes, they know, but they don't know how to awaken It."<br />
And sprea... Sahaja Yoga has spread so much in Bolivia: the Minister from there came to see Me.<br />
And who told them? I said, "Who told them?" They said, "There were two Saints who came from India."<br />
Even in Ukraine, I was surprised, they said, "There were two Saints who came here from India, they told us about Kuṇḍalinī."<br />
Chinese people, they believe that there is a treasure of spirituality in India, but they don't know what it is, you see.<br />
<font color="red">But these two, I don't know, there were two Saints known as Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth who have been traveling all over the world. But I don't know if they went all the way [smiling:] over there.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0927 Public Program, Day 2, Hall, Holland Park School, Airlie Gardens, Campden Hill Rd, London W8 7AF, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis.</font> Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations &#8211; Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Macchindranāth, an Incarnation of Dattātreya, the Primordial Master, started {\it Nāth Pāntha}.</font> There were some very feared gurus ({\it Avadhūtas}) of this cult even decades later. Its deterioration started, though, when tāntrikas imposed themselves as gurus, and took over the cult in many places. These fake gurus were criticized by the great Saint Kabīr Dās in His poems."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7: Haṭha Yoga and Rāja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In this Void is placed the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) formed from Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva). This Primordial Master is also known as Dattātreya. <font color="red">He has taken many human births as a Prophet and teacher, such as Rāja Janaka, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, Guru Nāṇaka, and Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.</font> This Deity helps human beings to seek their salvation by crossing the Void or Ocean of Illusion within themselves."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Ramadas Swami" /><category term="hotpink @ Angels" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>