<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-12T19:48:06-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Quotes</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ DRAUPADĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1112" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ DRAUPADĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Draupadi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1112"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Second gentleman started telling Me that, "I make woman nude because Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa also used to do the same."<br />
Just tell Me what kind of nonsense is this? Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was a child of five years old! It was His childlike activities. How can a five-year-old child make women nude? He was very deep and used to do the activities of Sahaja Yoga. For a five-year-old boy, who is elder and who is younger? Could He understand all these things at that age? He was not even five years old, less than that.<br />
<font color="red">Then I asked him, "If this was the case, then while living in Dvārika why did He run on occasion of Draupadī chīr haraṇ [tearing of clothes] taking with Him Śhaṅkh, Chakra, Gadā, Padam [Padma], and Garuḍ? Why did He run? If He had no sense of chastity of a woman, then why did He run?"</font> On this issue that 'Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa', [he] became silent."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
My complete blessings are with you. My heart, mind, body be always engaged in your service. I am not away from you even for a moment. Whenever you will remember Me anywhere by just closing your eyes, at that moment I shall come to you with all My Powers, "Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari" [<font color="red">just as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came riding on His Garuḍa condor from Dvārika, with all His Divine Weapons -- Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma -- when Śhrī Draupadī called Him</font>].
Even for a moment I shall not be late but you will have to be Mine. This is very important. If you are Mine then I shall not be late even for a moment. I shall be before you. [<b>Variant:</b> It'll not take even a moment, but you will have to be Mine. This is very important. If you are Mine, then it'll not take even a moment to be with you.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0529 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Dhyān Kaise Karein (How to Meditate), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And that's how they fought the war.<br />
So because Pāṇḍavas were blessed by Kṛiṣhṇa they had all the supraconscious powers with them and that's how they knew all the Chakra [[<font color="orange">unclear</font> Bhīma].<br />
Abhimanyu, you see, was a great general expert on Chakra Bhīmas and he heard his father telling Draupadī about the Chakra Bhīma, you see, when She was pregnant. And he heard that time and remembered, but ultimately it, the end of it. So he failed and he died somehow [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
Young son. Now this Abhimanyu was the son of Arjuna, you see.<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">"If you ... if you read the Mahābhārata, how these people created -- specially Draupadī ...</font>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0528 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Christ the Gate and Śhrī Mātājī the Destination, Seminar, Day 2, Session 1 (morning), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">But when He was the king in Dvārika," I asked this nonsensical fellow who says he is a Bhagavān and the Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, I said, "When He was a grown-up man and a king in Dvārika," which is at least two thousand miles away from Hastināpur, Delhi, and the lady called Draupadī, who called Him as a brother, was troubled because She was pond [pounded] and all that, a big story of Mahābhārata, you might be knowing Draupadī, and the devil of a man called Duryodhana, said that, "I'll make you nude," tried to pull Her sāṛī. It's [a] beautiful description of the whole thing. He, She was worried that She will lose Her chastity by removing Her -- [holding the corner of Her āṛī:] this is called as añchal. So She put it in Her mouth, [putting Hers:] like this. And She was to call Kṛiṣhṇa, She says, "Kṛi-" [taking Hers out:] and She was holding because '-ṣhṇa' means it falls down. And as soon as She found that, 'Now the sāṛī is going,' you see, She said, "-ṣhṇa." And the description is so great: "Dvārika meṃ śhor bhayo, śhor bhayo bharī ... Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." When She did that the, "-ṣhṇa," it echoed in Dvārika where He was ruling. He was the king there. And with [counting on the fingers of the raised left palm:] Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, these are His four weapons. One [laughing:] better that the other. One is sufficient, the chakra, I told you. All of them together, on the Garuḍa, on the condor He arrived there to save the chastity of His sister. "If He was fond of removing the clothes of women, why did He all the way come to save that?" And this fellow didn't know how to answer Me." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1006 Public Program (8th Day of Navarātri), Day 3, The New Age Has Started (From Kṛiṣhṇa to Christ), Venue 2, Unity (Church of Christianity), 2929 Unity Drive, Houston, TX, U.S.A. (Unity to be confirmed)]</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">But when Kṛiṣhṇa became the king of Dvārika, that time there's a story of Draupadī, His sister, who was tortured by a man called Duryodhana. And who wanted to make Her nude and he wanted to take out the sāṛī, from Her shoulder. And when he pulled Her sāṛī, She was holding on to it like this [puts Hers between Her teeth], it's [a] very beautiful description. Like this, K... [holding Hers with the teeth:] "Kṛi." [As it drops doen:] She would not say '...ṣhṇa', because 'ṣhṇa' it would fall off. [A lady laughs.] It said that, but when She thought that is pulled, now, sāṛī, so She said, "...ṣhṇa." There's a very beautiful poem on that kī [of] ... when that word went. Then what happened: "Dvārika meṃ śhor bhayo, śhor bhayo bharī Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." It is said that: 'When these things happened the great sound came in Dvārika where He was ruling.' And there was a tremendous sound. And He came on His Garuḍa: with [counts on Her fingers:] Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma to save the chastity of His sister!</font><br />
Chastity of a woman is her power, even of men. Men don't believe, in these Western countries, that their chastity is important. But that's your power. That's really your power! If you have no chastity, sense of chastity, you are a powerless person: anybody can attack you."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1018 Public Program, Day 2, Session 2 (evening), Heartwood Community Center, 200 7th Avenue, Santa Cruz, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Now, eh this sister of His was born later on as Draupadī. And that to very near the place we have been to Vani, you know, where we saw.</font>
Guh ... Gavin do you remember when we were going to Nagpur?<br />
<font color="red">Near Vani She was born, that place, and there's a very big temple of that. She was called as Draupadī. And you know how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa tried to save Her chastity.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (5th day after Diwālī Day), The Mahālakṣhmī Powers and the Powers of Water, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Another work He does as a Lilādhār is that He sucks both our ego and superego that makes us submissive to others. He can absorb both of them.<br />
<font color="red">If you see any egoistical person, for example, Duryodhan had big ego and He fixed him: Draupadī's sāṛī was never ending so much that he got exhausted, his ego got tired.</font><br />
If His mace is lifted on whoever is an egoistical person, He makes him dance to an extent that that person gets defeated unaware.<br />
Similarly, if there's a subservient person, who has been made submissive by the society, who is in poverty like Sudāmā, giving respect to such a person, uplifting his friendship to such an extent and giving everything to him night and day, this work is also of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0316 Public Program (Hindi), Day 4, Heart and Viśhuddhi Chakras, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So coming to the relationship of Viṣhṇumāyā, is that Viṣhṇumāyā is the One who is the sister, sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She's the One who announced the coming of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She's the One who sacrificed Her life to save Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's life. Viṣhṇumāyā is the One which surrounds Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
<font color="red">And She was born as Draupadī who, you know, was later on humiliated by Duryodhana, and it was Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who came and helped Her.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0811 Havan (Rakṣhābandhan Day), Maryādās, Āśhram, Hounslow (Outer London), Middlesex, UK]</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But how much joy is to give to these Sahaja Yoginīs. And when I go, they come to receive Me in those sāṛīs, is beautiful!<br />
<font color="red">And I thought of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa that, when Draupadī, you must have heard that story, that Draupadī was His sister, Pāṇḍavas's wife, and She was sold out to these rākṣhasas, Duryodhana. And he wanted to insult Her by taking out Her sāṛī, in the presence of many. And when he put his hand to Her sāṛī, is a wit ... beautiful thing about it, that She thought of Her brother that, 'He's the only One who will save My chastity now!' So She put Her sāṛī to Her mouth, and were [was] held it, that She might be able to huh hold it, you see. So She says: "Kṛi!" Kṛi She could say, but it [if] She said, '-ṣhṇa', it falls down. So She was holding on with "Kṛi," you see. As soon as She said, "-ṣhṇa," is a beautiful thing written by Tulasīdāsa: "Dvārika meṃ śhor bhayo, śhor bhayo bharī, Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." When it happened whence it ish [She said], "-ṣhṇa," the whole thing resounded in Dvārika where He was. And with Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, all His four things, on a Garuḍa He came down, and started supplying.</font><br />
And today I felt on a Janmāṣhṭamī to buy sāṛīs. This, I'm doing Kṛiṣhṇa's job to you even today. [Some laughter.] What a pleasure it was!<br />
And always I take from America the sāṛīs, you will be amazed! All the sāṛīs I take from America because it is Kṛiṣhṇa's country and I have to give them sāṛīs for their chastity. [Some laughter.]<br />
That's the beauty of this country. And you have to rise up to that. You have to become those gopīs and go... gop[a]s who gave joy to others and happiness to other[s], with grace and not leftovers!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0818 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā (the day before Janmāṣhṭamī Day), Tent, Backyard, House of Judy Gaddy, 442 Liberty Road, Englewood, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You see, now, the times change, then this samayāchār has to be changed accordingly. For that you require wisdom.<br />
Śhivajī, who is known for his chastity, had to marry four times, because of certain lays of work he had to do.<br />
<font color="red">And the Draupadī had to marry fer ... five husbands, you see, [laughing:] because of [a Sahaja Yogi laughs] certain uh promise they gave to their mother.</font><br />
And Kṛiṣhṇa had to marry sixteen thousand women who were His Powers! Because He had no Sahaja Yoginī, you see."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0906 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Because in [Bhagavad] Gītā, when they said, "The Kṛiṣhṇa has taught ahiṃsā," I'm surprised. He taught hiṃsā! You know Karṇa, when his foot was caught up in the wheel, so uh Karṇa uh uh Arjuna, you see, raised his gāṇḍiva [bow] on him. So, Karṇa said, "See, you are a vīra, I am a vīra, and how can you kill a niḥśhastra [without any arms, unarmed] vīra?" You see? <font color="red">So then Kṛiṣhṇa pointed His finger like this, and He said, "When, where was your vīratā [heroism, manliness], where was your bravery when Draupadī's lajj[ā] was taken?"</font> He said, "You kill him, now!" Where did He teach ahiṃsā? I don't know! Stupidity to think that He preached ahiṃsā. He preached that, "Who is so ever is duṣhṭa, who is wrong should be killed by God. And by the people who are following God." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0125 Pūjā, Why We Have Failed in Our Pursuit of God (The Whole System Has to Be Changed), Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"At times, situations arose where violence had to be used, such as when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa told Arjuna during the war, "Kill all these people, because they are already dead." 

He did not teach Arjuna today's nonviolence that also protects all kinds of insects. Am I going to give Kuṇḍalinī awakening to these insects that you are protecting? 

At that time, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa said, "Kill all these people, and kill your guru also." 

You should understand the religion completely. You know the story of Karṇa when his foot got stuck in the wheels of the chariot. At that time, Arjuna lifted his bow at Karṇa. Then Karṇa said, "You are a warrior, and I am also a warrior. According to the rules, you cannot attack a weapon-less person." <font color="red">At that time Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa raised His finger towards Karṇa and said, "Where was your chivalry when Draupadī's modesty was under attack?"</font> So he killed him."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0219 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Session 1 (evening), A Sahaja Yogi Will Reflect on the Outside His Inner Quality, Jaipur, Rajasthan, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"One of the examples is that at the time of war, Karṇa, the great generous man, very well-known for his great virtues, was caught up by a wheel of his chariot. And he could not take out his leg out of that chariot. When Arjuna faced him, and raised his own gāṇḍiva [bow], and Karṇa challenged him saying that, "I am a vīra," a chi... chivalrous person, a person who is fighting, "and you are another warrior, and in dharma, when I have no weapons on Me, you cannot kill Me, with your weapons." <font color="red">That time Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa pointed at him like this, and He said, "Kill him! Where was his warrior virtues when Draupadī was insulted? Draupadī's insult was the greatest sin that was committed and what was he doing at that time‽"</font> And Arjuna killed Karṇa.<br />
This is dharma!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0220 Public Program (English + Hindi), Day 1, The Essence of Gītā, Sir Shankarlal Concert Hall, Modern School, Bara Khamba Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The beautiful narration regarding wealth, as made by Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, as per My thinking, could not have been made by anybody else, because He was a great and intelligent diplomat.<br />
As regards Karṇa's life history, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa said that he was a greatly religious and a charitable person. He was always immersed in worship and charitable deeds. He was the eldest brother of Pāṇḍavas. He was always engaged in pūjā rituals. He was a brave Kṣhatriya. But during war, when his chakra got stuck, at the same time Arjun lifted his gāṇḍīva to strike him and challenged him to face it, Karṇa said, "Arjun, we both are Kṣhatriyas and we are bold. It is not ethical to lift a weapon on an unarmed soldier." <font color="red">At that time, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa never talked of right and wrong, but lifted His finger and asked Arjun to strike Karṇa. He asked, "Where was he and his valor when Draupadī was being subjected to embarrassment?"</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0331 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Sahajyog ke Anubhav (Experience of Sahaja Yoga), Ghanaśhyām das Birla Sabhaghar, 29 Ashutosh Choudhry Avenue, Near Birla Mandir, Ballygunge, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [After meditating for 9 seconds:] <font color="red">We'll call her Draupadī. Draupadī. I haven't given this name to anybody so far, ...</font><br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> No.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">... Draupadī.</font><br />
No, no, no. Sorry sorry sorry. Oh, oh, oh. [Laughter.]<br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> Is as good as being the King of the Gods. [Laughing:] I think she would be assured.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> That's your sister? [Saying mutedly, 'Yes.']<br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> The name of the baby is uh Draupadī.<br />
......<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> That's a boy.<br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> Dro ... Draupadī was the wife of the Pāṇḍavas and She was the one whom was the Power behind that ...<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].
<font color="red">She was Viṣhṇumāyā, reborn.</font><br />
<b>Grégoire de Kalbermatten:</b> She ... She was an Incarnation of Viṣhṇumāyā.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="red">Born again, as that.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0921 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Śhrī Jaldevatā, Oude Stadsfeestzaal, Mechelen (27 kms S of Antwerp), Belgium</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
Kṛiṣhṇa, who was a Divine Diplomat, has depicted dharma very beautifully.<br />
Karṇa who was a very charitable person and did pūjās, who was a great warrior and a brother of Pāṇḍavas, when the wheel of his chariot got stuck in the earth and Arjuna raised his bow, Karṇa said to Arjuna to stop and reminded him that he is a brave warrior and, "I am as well. It is not righteous to kill a warrior when he is in trouble and not ready." It wasn't a sign of bravery. At that moment Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa pointed His finger towards Karṇa and said to Arjuna to kill him and did not talk of non-violence. <font color="red">"Kṛiṣhṇa said to [about] Karṇa, "Where was his sense of dharma and bravery when Draupadī was molested in the court openly? Where was he?"</font><br />
Your sense of dharma, charity and bravery might have importance but the dignity of a woman is extremely important. It is a big thing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
"You might know that Kṛiṣhṇa built a house of gold for Sudāmā in Dvārika, <font color="red">you might be knowing how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa protected the modesty of Draupadī when Her dress was being pulled off</font>.<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
You must be aware that Narsinh Bhagat's bill of exchange was redeemed. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa constructed Sudāmā's house in the gold at Dvārakā, you must be knowing it. <font color="red">You also know that Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa protected Draupadī's chastity when She was being disrobed.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1101 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + Marathi) (Diwālī Day), Puṣhpa Maṅgal Karyalaya, Mote Mangal Karyalay Road, Sheth Narayan Das Dugad Chowk, Bibwewadi, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
Today is Tṛitīya the third day of Hindu calendar. Today is the day of worshiping Virgin. Virgin is pure power. She goes to the Viśhuddhi chakra and becomes lightening, that is, Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā. This pure power can be offered only at the Lotus Feet of Guru. When She goes to Guru, She accompanies Him in the pure bondage (pavitra bandhan) of being his daughter or sister. Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā was Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's sister. <font color="red">Śhrī Draupadī who incarnated after Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā was also Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's sister.</font><br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
Today is Tṛitīya, when the kanyā [virgin] is worshiped. 

Kanyā is the pure power, absolute power, who, after reaching the Viśhuddhi chakra, becomes lightening, the Viṣhṇumāyā. Only the pure power like Her could be offered at the Feet of the Guru, and when She goes to the Guru, She stays as His sister or His daughter. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Viṣhṇumāyā was also His sister, Draupadi. <font color="red">Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's sister, Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā, came on this Earth after that.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0103 Śhrī Nirmalā Devī Pūjā (English + Marathi), Purity is to be worshiped out and out (Complete Purity and Virginity, In Sahaja Yoga You Come Here to Dissolve All Your Powers, and The Meaning Has to Come from the Practices Not from the Precepts), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So one must understand how to handle a sister.<br />
<font color="red">In this case, we have to know that the same [Viṣhṇumāyā] was born, again, at the time of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa as Draupadī. She took Her birth as Draupadī. And when Draupadī was attacked by the Kauravas, they wanted to remove Her sāṛī. So remove the sāṛī itself is a symbol that they challenged Her chastity.<br />
Now if you see in the Māyā Nagarī, women have no sense at all that they should cover this part of their body. In this Māyā Nagarī, the other way round. When I heard a very responsible person saying, that, "In our culture, women must expose their body." What is this culture? Is antic ... anti-Kṛiṣhṇa, completely anti-Viṣhṇumāyā.<br />
......<br />
So how the brother's love can compel even Ādi Śhakti to do things that She would not normally do.<br />
<font color="red">In the same way, when Draupadī was challenged, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was not in Hastināpur where it had happened. He was thousand, at least, more than thousand miles, away from that place. But is said that, "Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." He came on His condor with all His weapons: Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma. All these He brought to save the chastity of His sister.</font>:<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0809 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Y.M.C.A. Holiday Hills Conference Center, 2 Lakeside Drive, Pawling, NY, U.S.A</b></font>
&lt;/p&gt;

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Uh as I told you that, I have already talked to you how the-ee war between Alexander and Puru's was finished because of a sister's intervention.<br />
<font color="red">And, also, how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, whose sister was Draupadī, Viṣhṇumāyā was born as Draupadī, and how He came to save Her chastity, by rushing all the way from Dvārika.</font><br />
So, we can see that when we ascend in the Collective Consciousness and we have collective living, collective meeting, at the Viśhuddhi chakra, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa establish[ed] this, or He manifested uh this pure relationship of a sister."&lt;/font&gt;<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0807 Rakṣhābandhan Pūjā, Room, House of Dr. Vinod Worlikar, 17301 Maria Avenue, Cerritos (32 kms SE of Los Angeles), CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But ... the Power of Saraswatī becomes Mahāsaraswatī when It is manifested by the Mahābrahmadeva, which is called as Hiraṇyagarbha. For that She has to cross through the Haṃsa. She crosses through Haṃsa and becomes the Viṣhṇumāyā Śhakti. I mean, She ... She is the Viṣhṇumāyā Śhakti. So Saraswatī becomes the Viṣhṇumāyā. She crosses at two points: one at Haṃsa and another at Viśhuddhi.<br />
So, She is the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
So Saraswatī was born as the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
And when Kṛiṣhṇa's māmā, his name was, uncle was Kaṃsa, he came to kill Her, She just rose into the sky and became the lightning. And She declared the coming of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, that He is already there existing.<br />
So the relationship between Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and Viṣhṇumāyā is that of a brother and a sister.<br />
And surprisingly, the other day [on 1990-0807] we celebrated the Rākhī Bandhan, the Rakṣhābandhan, which is the same thing as the brothers-sisters relationship.<br />
So now here we are celebrating actually the Deity which is the Sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
<font color="red">Later on She was born as Draupadī. And that's why Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa went to save Her chastity, because is the brother only who is concerned about the chastity and the name of the sister.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0811 Śhrī Saraswatī Pūjā, Inform People like the Viṣhṇumāyā Does what Sahaja Yoga Is with Your Fiery Talks (Go All Out and Become Fiery), Tent, Grounds, Āśhram, Lyons Bay (near Vancouver), BC, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Like when Draupadī was in trouble -- Draupadī was actually Viṣhṇumāyā, His sister -- She thought of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She will [was] ... holding on to Her sāṛī, when it's, was pulled out by Duryodhana. And She was holding it [holding a border of Her sāṛī with Her teeth:] like this, "Kṛi." She wanted to say Kṛiṣhṇa but She said, "If I say '-ṣhṇa', it will fall down." So She was holding on. As soon as She dropped, "-ṣhṇa," sāṛī dropped out [of Her mouth]. Then he described, about Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is: "Dvārika me śhora bhayo ... Dvārika me śhora bhayo śhora bhayo bhare. Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." That sound went into Dvārika. Now where is D[v]ārika and where is Hastināpur? At least distance of at least two thousands miles. But the sound, you see, went through Chaitanya and made a big sound there [in Dvārika]. And, "Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma." Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma are the weapons [of Viṣhṇu] as you know. All of them He took and came on His Garuḍa to save the chastity of His sister. Immediately, spontaneously, that moment! He could have said, 'All right, let it be. Let one sāṛī come out, two, then I'll go later on.'"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0901 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Īśhwara of Yoga (Master of the Play, Master of All the Arts of This Yoga, Master of Yoga, Master of Masters) and Subtler and Subtler Yuktis of Sahaja Yoga (In Yoga Everything that You Do Should Be just a Play, Mādhurya, Complete Humility When You Talk to Another Person, Equanimity, No Temper, Master the Temper of Others, Transfer Your Jobs to a More Capable Person, One Should Not Try to Do Impossible Tasks in Sahaja Yoga, Expert of Drama), Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Then again She took Her birth at the time of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa when He was ... He was uh-uh-uh the King of Dvārika, and She married, uh-uh-ah I should say, these five Pāṇḍavas. Because She was Draupadī. There's a significance in that. That, this is the One which joins five elements. And these five Pāṇḍavas represented five elements, and so She joined them as one wife. Because She's the One who joins all the five elements that have created this material universe.<br />
Thus, we have a eh-eh-eh relationship established with Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. And Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa as you know that, treated Her as a sister.<br />
Now once, when you know that they tried to insult Draupadī by pulling out Her sāṛīs, it was Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who helped Her because She was His sister and such a powerful lady.<br />
She's also responsible for the Mahābhārata. She's the one who brought forth, She's the one, who told that, "You have to fight," these Pāṇḍavas. She absolutely told them very clearly that, "You have to fight the Kauravas and in such a way that they should be defeated, not only, but they should be destroyed."</font><br />
Because the chastity of [a] woman is very important.<br />
And, in India, anybody who tries to molest the chastity of woman is to be cursed, is to be destroyed.<br />
<font color="red">And this was a very great message of Mahābhārata, that only because She was insulted so much, all the war took place and all of them were destroyed.</font><br />
......<br />
But now, don't try to destroy yourself by feeling guilty.<br />
That's why we have to redoing the Pūjā of Viṣhṇumāyā. <font color="red">She is Kālī, who is the sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and who was Draupadī, who is the One who is all the time for our protection and for telling us that we should not feel guilty at all, and enjoy life.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0704 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Viṣhṇumāyā's Powers, Āśhram, Everbeek, Belgium</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"At the time of Mahābhārata, She was born as Draupadī. And this Draupadī was the sister of Śhrī Rāma [Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa]. And when, as you know in Mahābhārata, all of you know the story of Mahābhārata, I need not tell that, Duryodhana tried to take out Her clothes, then She called for Kṛiṣhṇa. First She said, "Kṛi," [putting the border of Her sāṛī in the mouth:] She had put Her teeth like this. Till She had said, [putting it again:] "Kṛiṣhṇ," it was there. Because She was thinking if is said '-iṣhṇa', the thing will fall down, and She will become exposed. As soon as She said, "Kṛiṣhṇa," the thing fell down. Snd that's the time Śhrī Rāma came all the ... Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came all the way from Dvārika. In that, Tulasīdās really described it very well in Hindi language: "Dvārika meṃ śhor bhayo." "In Dvārika, there was a big" -- 'śhor' -- big noise you can call it or what I don't know, "śhor bhayo." "Śhor bhayo bharī": tremendous-ss uh-uh, what you call the, thunder you can call it, because She was the One who's responsible for thunder. "Śhor bhayo bharī. Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." "With the Śhaṅkha, the Chakra, with Garuḍa, with Padma, all of them, He came on the Garuḍa." With all His weapons, He came on a Garuḍa to help Her. He started supplying the sāṛīs to Her and this Duryodhana got absolutely, Duḥśhāsana did that, got absolutely tired and he fell on the ground.<br />
So now here Viṣhṇumāyā is the One who is the virgin. Not only that She is a virgin, but She exist[s] in all the five elements, as shown that She [Śhrī Draupadī] married five Pāṇḍavas. And that, this power of virginity in Her, used to expose people to the dangers of these horrible Kauravas who were going to rule and destroy the dharma. See, so She stood back. And She is the one who said that, "You have to fight. You have to fight for dharma, whatever may happen."<br />
And Kṛiṣhṇa always supported Her. So, as a brother, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa supported Her."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0919 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Stop Feeling Guilty or She Exists in All the Five Elements, The Shawnee Inn, 100 Shawnee Inn Drive, Shawnee on Delaware, Smithfield Township, PA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now there's another thing where, how He was connected with the Pāṇḍavas, Draupadī was also His sister. So Viṣhṇumāyā was born as Draupadī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1211 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Yamunānagar, Haryana, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">But His real sense of morality is seen in the case of Draupadī. You know the story of Mahābhārata, when She was brought in the court, in Duryodhana, asked Duḥśhāsana to take out Her sāṛīs is.<br />
At that time, Tulasīdās has written what happened. She's to ... She was holding Her sāṛī by Her teeth. She called, Kṛiṣhṇa," She could only say Kṛi-": '-ṣhṇa' means it fells down ... falls down. She was holding on with only, "Kṛi-," and She wouldn't say, '-ṣhṇa'. But as soon as He says [She said], Kṛiṣhṇa," the sāṛī fell down. Then He describes: "Dvārika meṃ śhor bhayo, śhor bhayo bharī, Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma, Garuḍa layi sidhari." What did He do? When She just said, "Kṛiṣhṇa," there was a big uh-uh-uh sound in Dvārika -- He was in Dvārika. Immediately, with Śhaṅkha, Chakra, Gadā, Padma," these are His four ... four weapons, He came on the Garuḍa."</font><br />
The way it is said is tremendous. I mean, I feel really it's ... fulfills your heart with such understanding of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
<font color="red">For His own sister He came all the way to save Her chastity. To Him, the chastity of His sister was of the greatest importance. He could have said, 'No, no, no, I have My ... I am a king, I have to look after this, I have to do that, I have to,' nothing. If Her chastity is in danger, He came flying on the Garuḍa, and supplied that.<br />
And this fellow got tired pulling out Her sāṛīs.</font><br />
I think, he must have borrowed sāṛīs from Me because I have too many sāṛīs. [Laughter, laughs.]<br />
<font color="red">One after the other, one after the other, he made a pile of sāṛīs, they got tired. He could not make Her nude!<br />
The chastity of Draupadī was of such a height. And how Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa tried to save it is remarkable!</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1002 Śhrī Yogeśhwara Pūjā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and the Enlightenment of the Brain, Donald Jonas Gymnasium and Leonard Franklin Theatre, Camp Vacamas, 256 Macopin Road, West Milford, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
<font color="red">And now you have given Me so many sāṛīs, that I keep thinking that, 'Only if one more Vastra Haraṇ [disrobing of Draupadī] happens then only these sāṛīs will be of use.'</font> Otherwise they are just piling up in heaps and heaps. Where will I wear all these sāṛīs? But no one is willing to listen. I keep saying, "Please don't give Me any presents. I do not require anything." So they say, "Then You should not give us." But let Me give. I am a Mother. Are you a Mother? And they say that, "Only this gives us joy."<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">Otherwise there will have to be a Vastra Haraṇ. There will have to be another Mahābhārat. Then Draupadī will have to appear. Then She should leave Her hair loose, and then the Vastra Haraṇ. Then I can give these sāṛīs to Kṛiṣhṇa, and He will use them to supply Her.</font>"<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
"<font color="red">Now you people have given Me so many sāṛīs that I think, 'If once again there is a Draupadī Vastra Haraṇ [disrobing of Draupadī] then only these sāṛīs will come in use.'</font> Otherwise they are collecting in heaps and heaps and where am I going wear them? But no one listens. I say that please do not give Me any presents, I don't want anything. They say, "You don't give us any presents." But I say, "Let Me give because I am a Mother." But they don't listen. They say, "We feel joyful in giving presents to You." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1204 Śhrī Rājalakṣhmī Pūjā (English + Hindi), Bharat Scouts Ground and Guides Marg, Nizamuddin, National Zoological Park, Sundar Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Another very great miracle I must say, I was to go to Russia, but felt sick and I had to take rest, couldn't go to Russia. And the Russians had prepared for the marriages, you see. So then they thought, 'We could have marriages in Cabella.' I said, "That's absurd, because we can have an English marriage, but not possible to have an Indian marriage in Cabella. Will be very difficult."<br />
But a thing happened, you see, to convince Me. I said, "The biggest problem will be about sāṛīs for the brides." Because nobody can select. I have to go and select, and how will it happen? And suddenly somebody told Me, "Mother, we have some very nice sāṛīs." "Very nice sāṛīs? Bring them along." I was amazed: there were seventy-two sāṛīs, very beautiful with very good zari work, just for the bride, in red color. Can you imagine? <font color="red">I said, "This is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, who has sent the sāṛīs, as He had supplied it at the time when Draupadī asked for sāṛīs," you see.</font><br />
......<br />
So, this Paramachaitanya is working, but this time specially, supplying sāṛī is the job of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, you know, and He's done His job very well."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0822 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, We Must have the Weddings, before Departure after the Evening Program, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"During the Dwāpara Yuga at the time of Lord Kṛiṣhṇa, Ādi Śhakti again incarnated as three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">3. Viṣhṇumāyā (Mahākālī) as sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She lived but for a short time. She later took birth as Draupadī, wife of the Pāṇḍavas."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Page 20</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Ādi Viṣhṇu's eighth form was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa during the Dwāpara Yuga, and again Ādi Śhakti took three forms. <font color="red">Mahākālī lived for a very short time as Viṣhṇumāyā, the infant sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She was actually born as the daughter of Yeśhodā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's foster mother, and was killed by the demon Kaṃsa. She later took birth as Draupadī, wife of the Pāṇḍavas.</font> Yeśhodā was Herself an Incarnation of Mahāsaraswatī. As Mahālakṣhmī She took two forms, Rādhā and Rukmiṇī. '<i>Rā</i>' means power or energy and '<i>dhā</i>' means sustenance, so the name 'Rādhā' means the one who sustains the power. As Rukmiṇī She became Queen to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, the King in Dvārakā."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 34</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Even more cunningly competent people overturned all the age-old cultural barriers. They flouted all ideas of a sense of chastity, and claimed they were all Incarnations of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who Himself had tried to strip the gopīs naked. Actually Lord Kṛiṣhṇa at the innocent age of five began teasing the gopīs. As a child He had no awareness of sex. <font color="red">When Duryodhana later tried to molest the chastity of Draupadī, Kṛiṣhṇa, then King of Dvārakā, was the first to rush to Hastināpur (near Delhi) to defend Her honor.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 6: Tantrism, Page 96</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>
</font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Draupadi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ ANASŪYĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1111" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ ANASŪYĀ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Anasuya</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1111"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">She [Śhrī Ādi Śhakti] was incarnated in the form of Satī Anusūyā. This is the only such a Satī in the whole world who has thought of emancipation of the human beings. This is a very great thing.<br />
These Three Children [Śhrī Brahmā, Śhrī Viṣhṇu and Śhrī Maheśhwar] came to Anusūyā.<br />
The meaning of Anusūyā is the One who is void of envy, She does not envy anyone, who is the Universal Love.<br />
In such a person there is no place for insignificant, petty thoughts such as jealousy, anger, etc. The one who does not have any asūyā, she is Anusūyā.<br />
It is said that these Three went to Her door to examine Her. And that moment She used Her Tej Bal.</font><br />
What was this Tej Bal? This was the Love of Mother, very much divine, Love of a powerful Mother.<br />
This Tej Bal fell on Them and They became small children.<br />
Their complete unified form is Śhrī Dattā Mahārāj.<br />
He is a strange Majesty, whatsoever description is made of Him but will fall short. And even if this is made to be explained, it will be beyond explanation.<br />
This is Śhrī Dattā Mahārāj who is full of triguṇa.<br />
He came in the world in form of Ādi Guru many times to teach how to cross the Bhavasāgara [Void]."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Nobody can con an innocent man. This is true. Even if someone tries to con, there will be such a drama, the person himself will be conned.<br />
If Sītā was caught in the guile of Rāvaṇa, it was a display of Her innocence. He had no stature to hold Her hand or misbehave with Her. Where is the glory of innocence and where is the cunningness of Rāvaṇa? No one can aggress an ordinary woman.<br />
But till such time he carried Sītā on his head, he remembered his own mother. All his greatness was reduced to the size of a small child.<br />
<font color="red">You have heard the story of Satī Anasūyā, is it not?</font><br />
The condition of Rāvaṇa was also similar. She has made Her innocence dance. She got into Sahaja Yoga in Her innocence.<br />
That will give you motherhood."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1974-0325 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Param Tattwa and Chetna Tattwa, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, this Guru was created when the world was created itself. Because we ... one had to create a Guru before the world was created in then Vaikuṇṭha Stage only.<br />
But then He reincarnated many a times.<br />
<font color="red">At the time of Rāma, very early, even before Rāma came into this world, much earlier than that, He was created by Satī Anusūyā. She was Herself a part of the Ādi Śhakti, who created Him out of the essences, the innocence of Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśh.<br />
There's a legend about it which I will tell you sometime.<br />
And She created Him. Actually, She created Him, so She's the Mother.</font><br />
But then, She becomes the Guru.<br />
When She is born as Sītā, He becomes the father. So, She ... father is Her Guru.<br />
Then, when Rāja Janaka is born as Muhammad Sāhab, then She becomes again the daughter.<br />
But when He is born as Nāṇaka, then He becomes the ... She becomes His sister.<br />
So the relationship exists and whenever He is born, She is born, in a way, that, you see, that relationship is kept a sublime relationship. I mean to say: that they are never born as husband and wife."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0701 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day) (first more formal Pūjā in the West), Self-realization, Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Like there was uh-uh-uh another one, Anasūyā: was another very great uh woman in India, Anasūyā. She was so great! She changed, I mean She ... She made the sun wane, She made the river change its course, She did all kinds of things for Her husband who was a horrid fellow. [Some laughter.] He was absolutely the dirtiest possible fellow with all these diseases because of dirty things he did all his life, you see. And he would ill-treat Her and every... Then he ... She ... he got horrible diseases because, you see, all his life he was so [<font color="orange">unclear</font> frustrated]. Then he got leprosy, he got this. She took him from one place to another to all the temples and everything, and She defied all the nature, everything. This Satī Anusūyā, you see. Such a powerful woman: She cured Her husband, She got everything done. You see, is very powerful woman.</font><br />
And uh then Nirm... Narmadā, the river, see, that we have, She Herself was the Deity. And now She is the uh She ... She ... She was actually, uh She never married. But She loved somebody and wanted to marry some[one], you see, so She dedicated Herself fully to that love. Then She became this river, you see. And it's a Virgin River.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says something:] So, in India, you see, people do not take out water from that River Narmadā. They just say: 'All right. This is the river we are not going to touch, we are not going to take out the uh water out of this river.'<br />
I mean, it was so deep into us, you see, we had known all these things and everything.<br />
So, the Satī used to be feared very much, you see.<br />
I'm also a little afraid of them, [laughing:] the way they [as some Sahaja Yogis laugh:] are, you see. Oh-oh, and if someone has a husband, you know, who is uh-uh-uh wanting a divorce from a Satī, I think: 'I'm out of it! I'm not [as some Sahaja Yogis laugh:] for it, you see. Keep Me out! I'm not.'<br />
See, they are not to be disturbed. And they have ..."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0528 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Christ the Gate and Śhrī Mātājī the Destination, Seminar, Day 2, Session 1 (morning), Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, these Gurus first started under the Primordial Master Himself, He was called as Dattātreya.<br />
And this G... Dattātreya is the One who is comprising all these forces: say, the existence force and the evolutionary force and the creative force, all of them, in Its innocence.<br />
I don't know if you understand it, but there is a story about Them is, that there are Three Deities, which belong to these Three Forces: the left one is Śhiva's Force, then the right one is Brahmadeva's Force, and the center one is Viṣhṇu's Force. <font color="red">So they say that all these Three Gods felt that the wife of Dattātreya [Sage Atreya] was a great, uh devoted woman. And She would, with Her powers, can curse anyone She feels like. So They wanted to take a ... take Her test and wanted to find out: how far She was a devoted wife.<br />
So They went to Her. And the They told Her that, "We want some alms."</font><br />
And in ... in India, it is regarded as a great honor to be able to give somebody alms who come to your house.<br />
<font color="red">And Three Saints, they were dressed up like Saints, They came on the door, so, when They asked for alms, She said, "All right, uh I will get you some alms." They said, "No! We'll come inside the house, and uh You have to become completely naked, and then give Us the alms."</font><br />
Because to become naked before a man, you lose all your powers as a uh-uh-uh devoted wife, as a Satī.<br />
<font color="red">She said, "All right. If you say so, I will do it." And She started taking out Her clothes. As soon as She touched Her clothes, you see, They became small children, absolutely small children. [Laughing:] And She took out Her clothes, and gave Them the alms.</font><br />
So, these three small children, put together, made the Dattātreya, is the Guru, is the One who is innocent like a child. Innocent like a child, who has no sense of sex.<br />
So, we come to conclusion: a guru who has interest in women, a guru who has interest in sex, is not a guru but is anti-Guru.<br />
Dattātreya is the innocence of all these Three Powers."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">The story is about the Advent of the Primordial Master, you see. That Three Deities, of Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha, you know who They are, uh-uh-uh .. They've ... Their wives, see Their Powers, felt, they say were jealous of a Lady who was very pure, actually Anasūyā.<br />
She is the Power of the Primordial ... She's the Mother. I mean She was the Primordial Mother. She's the Mother of all the Gurus, you see.<br />
And the ... They [the wives] ... They said that, "She ... She is, this Lady is such a chaste lady, and You must go and the ... make Her fall from Her chastity. You test Her fully." And She was actually the Primordial Mother, you see. So they went into Her house, you see. She was the wife of a very big Saint. And the -- he was out -- and They said, "We want uh-uh-uh ..."</font><br />
You see, a guest who comes to your house can demand anything, according to Indian dharma.<br />
<font color="red">So They came in and They'll said that, "We want You to serve our food naked. Take out all Your clothes and You must[<font color="orange">unclear</font>]."</font><br />
Now, you can't say no to your guests. Because that is your dharma.<br />
"It's all right, I will do it."<br />
<font color="red">And She said ... as soon as She started, both of Them -- undressing -- both of Them became small, little children. Three of Them. [As a Sahaja Yogi laughs:] Little, little babies, you see, She undressed Herself. And the little baby doesn't understand anything, and She nursed Them together. And She ... then She said, "Now!" She combined Them together, and that's how Dattātreya [has] three faces. Innocence of these people, She brought Them to Their innocences -- was created. This is the innocence of all these Three Deities was [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].</font><br />
Because Christ is the innocence[<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
These three form this innocence part to balance you.<br />
And [moving twice the right index finger along the top part of the forehead, from left to right:] at this stage They come, here, as [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-092x Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Three Hours Sightseeing Tour on a Boat of 'Circle Line', Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">This one, is today's Pūjā, it has a special meaning because yesterday was Dattā Jayanti: means the uh birth of Dattātreya. And you know the story of Dattātreya, most of you know the story of Dattātreya, that Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha tried to uh take a test of a uh-uh-uh Ādi Śhakti, called Anasūyā. They came to Her place and asked Her uh for alms.</font><br />
And is supposed to be a great privilege in India to give alms to others, to -- I mean, it's a great privilege to attend to guests, it's a great privilege to be generous, it's [laughing:] great privilege to distribute things to others. It's a great privilege."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1227 Śhrī Devī Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), Knowledge of the Roots, Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Last time you had asked Me for Guru Pada. And you should know that the essence of Guru is Śhrī Gaṇeśha, the innocence.<br />
<font color="red">You must be knowing the story of a very devoted wife, faithful wife, of a Satī, Her name was Anasūyā, and She was so religious and so dedicated that they say that the wives of all the Gods, Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha, got very jealous of Her. So, They told Their husbands that, "You must go and test Her, if She is really a woman with chastity or not."<br />
So all of Them came down as Sādhus, dressed up like saṃnyāsīs. And She said it, She wanted to serve Them, give Them something. They said, "No, We want to have food." She said, "All right, come and sit down." She cooked food for them. So They said, "No, We will not have the food unless and until You take out all Your clothes. We will only ha... have the food unless and until You take out all Your clothes. We'll only have the food if You take out all your clothes." She said, "Is it so?" She [They] said, "Yes." So She made Them into little, little children, three little children. [Laughing:] And then She became nude, because innocent doesn't understand anything about [it]. And then is She joined Them together, Their three innocence was joined together, and They got Their Guru Pada.</font><br />
That's how the Ādi Guru was created."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0830 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, Understand the Essential Fundamental Principles of Śhrī Gaṇeśha and If You Want Your Guru Pad You Have to Be Innocent (First is Wisdom or Genetic of Wisdom), Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">During the Tretā Yuga, at the time of Śhrī Rāma, Ādi Śhakti incarnated in three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
&emsp;1. Sītā [Jānakī] (Mahālakṣhmī) as the daughter of Rāja Janaka</font><br />
&emsp;&emsp;This was the first absolute human form (<i>Laukik</i>)"<br />
&emsp;<font color="red">2. Satī Anasūyā (Mahāsaraswatī) as the wife of a Great Saint</font><br />
&emsp;3. Mandodarī (Mahākālī) as the wife of the demon Rāvaṇa<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Page 20</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Maheśha (Śhiva), Viṣhṇu and Brahmadeva form the Trinity which incarnated as one teacher God, the Primordial Master, Dattātreya. He came onto this Earth to teach people the secrets of the Divine, to reveal God, and to help them cross the Ocean of Illusion themselves within their own identity. Evolution could not go further in the hands of human beings who were in the bondage of ignorance, so they were given guidance through this Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) again and again in different lives. <font color="red">He was created as the three-headed child, Dattātreya, by Ādi Śhakti who appeared on Earth during the Tretā Yuga as Satī Anasūyā, wife of the Sage Atreya.</font><br />
......<br />
At the time of Rāma's Incarnation Ādi Śhakti existed in three persons: Mahālakṣhmī, as Sītā, His wife; <font color="red">Mahāsaraswatī, as Satī Anasūyā who gave birth to Dattātreya, the Primordial Master</font>; and Mahākālī as Mandodarī, the wife of the demon Rāvaṇa."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 32 to 34</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Anasuya" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ VĀMANA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1110" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ VĀMANA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Vamana</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1110"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">As you must have heard of Rāja Balī [Mahābalī or Māveli] when Vāmana Avatār occurred. Rāja Balī was said to be religious person.</font> [<b>Variant:</b> <font color="red">You must have heard about king Bali when Vāmana Incarnation took place. Rāja Balī was a religious person.</font>] But he did Yagñya.<br />
For getting creative powers people do Yagñya.<br />
......<br />
If we acquire it without the shadow of dharma, then it can also have a negative impact as in Rāja Balī.<br />
When Viśhwāmitra asked Rāja Balī to do tapa, he asked Brahmadev to grant a wish that he can destroy all the Devas.<br />
<font color="red">After that, you know Vāmana Incarnation took place. About Vāmana Incarnation we know that our powers in the middle, which we call Sattvaguṇa Powers, which are Powers of Lord Viṣhṇu, the powers because of which we became humans from amoeba, that power took Incarnation to restore the balance.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="red">In the old time when the torture of Balī increased, Vāmana Avatar came to kill him.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-1200 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Just as fish still exist today, elephants too, some evolution continues slowly. We can say that up to seven evolutions [it continues].<br />
The first evolution was when the Supreme Being had to be in human form, which was the Vāmana Avatār, a small man. He first showed that humans can conquer all [the] three realms. It means that humans can conquer the five elements. This is the Vāmana Avatār."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0117 Public Program (Hindi), Day 4, Chakroṃ para Upasthita Devatā (Deities on All Chakras), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Bhavasāgar is all around Nābhī. Humans have evolved from here. Animals could not come out of present, they have a word from here.<br />
<font color="red">We had Vāman Avatār, then Paraśhurāmjī incarnated it, then Śhrī Rām incarnated.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Afterwards, we can say, that the Incarnation of the center, this green color center, which we cap ... call as the Nābhī chakra, the Incarnations started on this point, one after another, taking different forms of living animals in the evolution. Like first the fish: It came as a fish. They say, when Noah was having a bad time with the deluge, this fish helped him. They came as an Incarnation, that aspect of God which we call as evolutionary. That came as a fish on this Earth, and then, then It came as a quadruped. Then It came as a short man. That It came as a strong man. And on and on and on like that till we reached a stage where the top one, you can see, or here. This is the stage where Śhrī Rām, who came eight thousand years back. This was established within us like a milestone. They were the leaders of our evolution. They led us into evolution as well as They left a mark for us there, and They exist within us in that path."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But there is another guidance which has come to us from God. This is very much believed into in India. Even in the Western world, if they follow Christianity or Judaism, they believe in it. It is believed that [pointing to the Chakra Chart:] at that spot is, resides the Power of God which evolves.<br />
<font color="red">This area, according to Indian mythology, is governed by a Power called Lakṣhmī, which on one side gives us our sustainance [sustenance] and on the other side guides it [us] how to behave.<br />
And from the same Power, the Male Form of that Power incarnates, again and again, to guide the people, in human form.<br />
This Incarnation in the beginning was a fish, when we were fishes. When we were tortoises, It was a tortoise, when we were reptiles It was a tortoise. Then we were quadrupeds, we ... It was a boar. Then later on It became half man and half uh half lion. Then It became a small man, short man. Then It became the very strong man, Paraśhurāma. Then He came as Śhrī Rāma. At His completion, He came as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0419 Public Program, Day 4, Spiritual Evolution of Man, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa incarnated as one of the Incarnations of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, who is responsible for our evolutionary process.<br />
It is only through Śhrī Viṣhṇu that we evolve. He is the aspect which gives us dharma: dharma is our sustainance [sustenance]. Through changing our sustainances [sustenances] or our capacities we have evolved.<br />
<font color="red">Like, I can say, carbon was at Mūlādhāra chakra. And this carbon achieved matter got Prāṇa into it, by which it started moving as a living thing. This living thing then grew into higher and higher awareness, till it reached a ... reached a stage where you were an animal and then you had to become a human being. The first human beings were short people. That Incarnation of ... Incarnation of the short people is called as Vāmana.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0401 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 5, Viśhuddhi and Āgñyā Chakras, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then the sustainance [sustenance] start[s] growing till you become a human being as shown [points to the Chakra Chart:] here. In this Void, [points to Mūlādhāra chakra:] here as carbon, then you move into the Void. <font color="red">And here you go through all the evolution starting from a fish up to the human level where you become a small man. Once you become the small man, Vāmana is called that. First the man who came on the Earth was a small statured man. Then a man came who was Paraśhurāma, a very, very ... Poseidon, a very large man, huge man. Two extremes. And then came the man who was in the center.</font><br />
......<br />
In this Void, [points to Mūlādhāra chakra:] here as carbon, [pointing to the Nābhī chakra:] then you move into the Void. And here, you go through all the evolution, starting from a fish up to the human level, where you become a small man.<br />
<font color="red">Once you become the small man, Vāmana is called that. First the man who came on the Earth was a small statured man.</font><br />
Then a man came who was Paraśhurāma, a very, very ... Poseidon, a very large man, huge man.<br />
Two extremes.<br />
And then came the man who was in the center."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0929 Public Program (1st Day and 2nd Day of Navarātri), Self and Heart Chakra, Day 6, East West Center, 141 5th Avenue, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So this center, we come to, of our evolution, is presided by the Preserver, the aspect of preservation: He's the Father who looks after us, He's the One who gives us our well-being. He comes on this Earth again and again, in different forms. According to Indian Purāṇas, the Ark of Noah was saved by a fish, which was a dolphin. And this dolphin fish was this aspect which incarnated. Then the second aspect came as the tortoise. Then the third as a quadruped.<br />
Like that they have described the evolution, how these Incarnations had to come to break the barriers of the evolutionary ignorance. These are the people who came for the breakthrough. <font color="red">Ultimately, a short man was created called as Vāmana</font>, then a very fiery, big man, He's called as Passidon [Poseidon], or in Greek language."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-1005 Public Program (7th Day of Navarātri), Day 2, The Beauty that You Are, Venue 1, Unity (Church of Christianity), 2929 Unity Drive, Houston, TX, U.S.A. (Unity to be confirmed)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[As the names of Śhrī Viṣhṇu are read:] <font color="red">"Vāmanaya."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1009 Bestowing of Boons Pūjā, House of Maria Laventzi, Irchester (near Wellingborough), Northamptonshire, UK]</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, at the time, first time the Incarnation as a human being came on this Earth, as we say of this sustainance [sustenance], was of Śhrī Rāma.<br />
<font color="red">But before that was uh-uh Vāmana Avatāra, which is the short man, a very short [man]. I mean, first the man was created as a short man. He is the first one as Vāmana Avatāra. And that One came as a leader, the first one was Vāmana Avatāra, and He was given the power ... He was given the blessings that He can spread into three worlds: so, into, into the higher worlds, into the lower worlds, and into the central world.<br />
That's how human beings uh got distributed into these three worlds. And a big, you see, problem started.<br />
Like the house that moves wild, you know. Then it goes amok. Then you have to get all the things collected, put them right.<br />
The original sin is the big problem. The biggest problem was that.<br />
Now to solve it up, one had to do all these things.<br />
So first the Vāmana Avatāra came.</font><br />
<font color="red">After the Vāmana Avatāra came the Incarnation of a very tall and a hefty man. That was Paraśhurāma.</font> That I don't know, in the Greek philosophy, if Zeus was Paraśhurāma, because it sounds like Zeus. Because Paraśhurāma is contemporary of Rāma Himself. Because somebody had to announce. You see, it is necessary that somebody must announce the Advent, at that time it was necessary. So Paraśhurāma came. The tall and a hefty man, who came on this Earth, maybe Zeus is called. I mean they are so confused that, you see, to ... to relate this to that, is another confusion. I don't know how. But looks like Zeus."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1029 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Creation, Original Sin, and Incarnations, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"In evolutionary process is described, in the Daśhāvatārs, in the Ten Incarnations, which is exactly the same as has happened: first is the fish and then is the tortoise -- I know Indian names so I -- uh then is the quadruped, like that it moves from one to another, then a small man, and then a large man, and then Śhrī Rāma.<br />
Śhrī Rāma resides on the right side, as the Father [Principle], right side of the Heart."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0317 Public Program, Day 3, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Another one is Hariśhchandra, who had a guest who came as Vāmana, It's means Śhrī Viṣhṇu to take his test. And the, He asked for all his kingdom. So, Hariśhchandra gave Him all his kingdom and went into the forest with his wife and suffered a lot. But in that sufferings, he got his Mokṣha. And he got again complete reward of his kingdom and everything, is very much purified.<br />
And also there is a case of uh this coming to a king uh Śhrī Viṣhṇu as Vāmana. And the He asked that, ``You have to give Me land which is uh ... which could be measured by My three steps." Bali was his name. He said: ``All right. Whatever You say." So with one foot He touched the sky, with another foot He touched the Mother Earth. With the third foot, He put Bali's head and put him in the Pātāla, in the uh lower [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], lower world. And that's how Vāmana Avatāra came soon."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0624 Śhrī Lakṣhmī Pūjā, Summer House of Stamatis Boudouris, Island of Hydra, Greece</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"But as human beings have evolved, even the Deities have evolved Themselves accordingly. So it was a fish, and then, then a tortoise, and like that, it went on, till we come to the stage of Vāmana Avatāra where it was a small man, then a big man, a tall, big man, a Greek, who we call as Zeus, is Paraśhurāma. And then came Śhrī Rā... Śhrī Rām."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0817 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before the Evening Program, the Friday before Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, Essex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Like, if Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa had not come we would not have known really the significance of spiritual life. He was the first who talked of spiritual life.<br />
Rāma did not talk of spiritual life, though there was an undercurrent in India. People knew there is spiritual life because there were Saints, there were uh-uh lots of uh-uh-uh, what you call the, uh-uh-uh Seers, all of them were talking about it. But no Incarnation talked about spiritual life.<br />
<font color="red">We had Vāmana Avatāra, then we had Paraśhurāma, we had so many of these people, never, never They talked of spiritual life, never.</font><br />
It was Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa only who first started talking about spiritual life, and only to Arjuna He talked. Because, you see, what was the condition: people were not prepared."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0819 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, Essex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Today we are going to worship Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa as Yogeśhwara.<br />
<font color="red">As it is, you know that Viṣhṇu's first Incarnation as a human being was Vāmana Avatār.</font> And then went till He came as Śhrī Rām. So, the past of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was Śhrī Rām."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1002 Śhrī Yogeśhwara Pūjā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa and the Enlightenment of the Brain, Donald Jonas Gymnasium and Leonard Franklin Theatre, Camp Vacamas, 256 Macopin Road, West Milford, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"His channel is the evolutionary path, and His Ten Incarnations of the Virāṭa have helped mankind to evolve:</font><br />
......<br />
&emsp;<font color="red"><i>v. Short Man ...... Vāmana Avatāra</i>"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Page 14</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">In His fifth Incarnation Śhrī Viṣhṇu appeared for the first time as a human being. He took the form of the Short Man (Vāmana Avatāra) who came on this Earth to give leadership to people seeking God. Vāmana was enlightened with the idea that He could capture the three worlds (<i>Triloka</i>): Earth (<i>Pṛithvī</i>), Heaven (<i>Ākāśha</i>) and Hell (<i>Pātāla</i>, the subconscious). So in corollary, this Incarnation brought forth the idea in the human mind that man can overpower all three worlds.</font> It should be understood that Ādi Viṣhṇu's Incarnations, the line of evolution, lead the way towards higher, deeper and wider spiritual awareness which is the true index by which the development of the Creation can be measured. First the individual evolution is achieved and then the collective assimilation by the masses was experienced."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 32</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Vamana" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ MANDODARĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1109" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ MANDODARĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Mandodari</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1109"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"On the right-hand side also, was another one, where the wives, you see, the dedicated wives, devotees, uh devoted wives, you see, as called as Satī.<br />
Now, one are known as Yatis, another are Satīs. So, the ones who tried to find out about uh-uh-uh element-ts, and overpower the elements and all those things, they ... they were Yatis, and the ones who tried to find out about uh ... sorts of mast... have a mastery with their willpower, you see, were the devoted women. They too master the elements very much.<br />
Though the devoted women are regarded even higher than uh Yatis. You know, Satīs are higher than Satīs [Yatis] ... uh-uhh uh Satīs are called as the-ee ... uh the ... Sanskrit it's a ucchatar [higher]: they are much higher than the Yatis. So their achievements were uh-uh-uh much more in dimension. Because what they had ... had used their bhakti also, because they were dedicated to their husbands.<br />
<font color="red">One of them you can say was Rāvaṇa's wife, to take it foy ... for example, was Rāvaṇa's wife. She was so powerful! Such a powerful woman She was. Of course, She was Mahākālī Herself. So, that you give ... you can imagine: She was the Mahākālī Force Herself. But She was a Satī as She came. So She had a Sahaja Samādhi. She had the Sahaja uh Power.</font><br />
But there are many Satīs who achieves [achieve] Satī Power.<br />
<font color="red">But I'll describe this Lady, you see, this Satī, Mandodarī She was, Rāvaṇa's wife.</font><br />
<font color="red">Now, when She married him -- She had to marry though She was Mahākālī, there's also a big story. Uh-uh-uh, if I go through that story also is very interesting. Can tell you later on about it.<br />
So She was married to him.<br />
And when Rāvaṇa, you see, uh-uh-uh s... was fighting Rāma, She was the Satī and She ... She was a de... devotee of Śhrī Viṣhṇu. And She always used to worship Śhrī Viṣhṇu.<br />
So She threw Her kaṅkaṇ</font> [bracelet of thread used in Pūjās] -- this is the kaṅkaṇ. It's call as kaṅkaṇ, you see. See this one?<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says something:] [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. See now.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says something:] Very interesting, very interesting.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh-hm,":] Kaṅkaṇ.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh,":] You see, not easy to make.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Yeah.":] [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
[After two Sahaja Yogis say something:] You see.<br />
Be careful, [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
[<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says something:] You see? You see, she came out.<br />
<font color="red">So, all these ... uh ... this kaṅkaṇ, you know, She threw it in the air. And Rāma's ... ah-ah-uh arrows were coming, and they would return back to Rāma.</font><br /> 
Because Rāma cannot cross beyond the Powers of a Satī also. He has to respect her [a Satī in general].<br />
<font color="red">Because She was the devotee of Rāma, first of all, and of which, you know, that Kālī is the sister of a ... Umā is the sister of ...</font><br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Viṣhṇu,":] <font color="red">... Viṣhṇu. So, you see, how can He kill the whuh ... husband of ...</font><br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi interrupts, "Sister":] <font color="red">... the sister?</font><br />
You see, all of these points are there.<br />
<font color="red">And the kaṅkaṇa was in the air, is projective. Everything failed. You see, nothing would go, even Sudarśhan Chakra wouldn't go that side.</font><br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh,":] So, Lakṣhmaṇa said, "What are you doing‽ What is it? You are getting back your, all your arrows! Why don't you control your arrows? You see what to do. See there, what is there." <font color="red">He saw this kaṅkaṇa was moving there.</font> He said, "Oh, God! Now, you have it. If this is the thing to work out, then am I useless?" Poor Lakṣhmaṇa was sitting very much in frustration.<br />
Then Yama, the God of Death, he thought: "The time is coming and what is this kaṅkaṇ doing here? You see, so must try to solve this problem." [Sahaja Yogi laughs.]<br />
So, He is the clever one.<br />
<font color="red">He ... he went into the heart of ... uh-uh-uh or He went into the mind of Rāvaṇa, and told him: "Oh, you are not uh the one who is winning the war, it is your wife's anger."</font> And, oh, his ego was challenged. [During laughter:] [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], <font color="red">"Kaṅkaṇ</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] <font color="red">you see in the air, you see that</font> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] <font color="red">is there. That is the one that is protecting you." Very angry: "What does She mean by challenging my manliness?"</font><br />
See, so he went down to his palace.<br />
<font color="red">And he saw She ... She was sitting there smiling. She said: "I know you will come back." He said: "What do You mean? I cannot fight the war? You think I live by Your powers? Will You please get ... get back your kaṅkaṇa? It's my order!"</font><br />
So, as a Satī you have to obey the orders of your husband, you see.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh,":]  <font color="red">She said, "All right. I will take it back." She took [it] back, you see.</font><br />
So, [as the Sahaja Yogi laughs:] but you can find out loopholes, you see. That is, that's the [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. [Everyone laughs.]<br /> 
<font color="red">So, She said, "Now, I've taken back My kaṅkaṇ." All right. Then She sat before Viṣhṇu. She said, "How dare You kill My husband? I will not eat food till he comes back here alive, I will not eat."</font><br />
Now, Viṣhṇu had a problem. Now what to do? He cannot kill, Rāma being Viṣhṇu, you see. [Another Sahaja Yogi laughs.] He cannot kill Rāvaṇa. Now He said, "What to do?" So He told Lakṣhmaṇa: "It's a big problem!"<br />
<font color="red">So Lakṣhmaṇa informed Yama: "Again the problem has come</font> [same Sahaja Yogi laughs]<font color="red">: She won't eat food till [he laughs again] ... Rā-ah ... Her husband goes back, you know."</font> <font color="red">So Yama said, "I know it's very dangerous, but I have to try this trick otherwise I'm in for trouble. This man has to die, for the time has come." So, Yama said, "It's a very big risk of ... to say this to Satī."</font><br />
<font color="red">You see: one woman fighting all this [he laughs again], with Her will Power.</font><br />
"It's all right." He says, "All right. I will manage it."<br />
He took the form of a ... of Rāvaṇa himself. He became, took, started looking like Rāvaṇa.<br />
<font color="red">And He went there, and He stood up in the door. And he said: "Now, see, I have come now." [She] said: "Did you win the war?" She [he] said, "Yes!" She said, "All right." "Now, will You eat Your food?" And the food was lying before Her. And She made a mistake there: She ate the food.</font><br />
Before your husband has taken the food you are not supposed to eat your food. You see, that's why Indian women will never eat it. [Sahaja Yogi laughs.] Because this gives them power, you see. To be [a] dedicated wife means power.<br />
So, they do not mind, even if their husbands are bad, even if they are rākṣhasas, they are anything: they will be dedicated to their husbands. They'll love them. So that they keep their own powers, and by that they save their husbands' also.<br />
<font color="red">So he stood up there, and [<font color="orange">unclear</font>], "You eat Your food."<br />
As soon as She ate the food, you see, uh not even She ate the first morsel, Rāvaṇa's head was cut. And the head fell at the feet of a ...</font><br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh-hm,":] <font color="red">... Mandodarī.<br />
And then, you know, he, Yama came in his own form. And She cursed him that, "You will be a dog in the next life." And He became a dog, in the next life. He has to become that.</font><br />
So they are so powerful.<br />
<font color="red">But this I'm telling you about someone who was uh uh sort of a Sahaja Sāmarthya [Spontaneous Power], [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].</font><br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi interrupts, "Which dog was this, Mother?":] Hah?<br />
[After the Sahaja Yogi says, "Which dog? This wasn't the dog which accompanied Yudhiṣhṭhira,":] Of course!<br />
[Overlapping with a Sahaja Yogis]: Who else?<br />
Yes!<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi laughs and says, "That's the Yudhiṣhṭhira who released Yama from this,":] You see, actually, it is uh, Rāv... after Rāma, you see, whatever curses and everything went carried on during the time of Kṛiṣhṇa.<br /> 
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Acchā,":] So he is the same dog!<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh,":]  The one who followed Yudhiṣhṭhira, you see.<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi says, "Mh-hm,":] Near ... Dharmarāja means ...<br />
<font color="red">So, this uh ... this story, She ... tells you about Mandodarī, who was of's Kālī, Umā, She was Pārvatī Śhakti, so is different.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0528 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Seminar, Day 2, Session 2, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There are many stories like this.<br />
<font color="red">Even the wife of Rāvaṇa [Mandodarī], who was killed by Rāma, was like that, which I will tell you later on sometimes.</font><br />
There are stories and stories may interest you."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0330 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 4, Anāhata, Śhrī Lalitā, Śhrī Chakra, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And if you get the Powers like Me, then what to say? Then you all will sit and obtain everything [<b>Variant:</b> And if you get the Powers like Me, then what is there to say? Just sitting you will do everything.]<br />
Meaning, if I don't like something, I will not fight for it but make arrangements that such a thing does not occur only [laughter], by itself.<br />
So either you all should obtain such Śhaktis, but stay in pure Śhakti, not that for some time you become a man or for some time become a woman, it cannot happen then. [Laughter.]<br />
Women should live with their feminine power, like here we believe in Satī's power. Then you can see that just sitting in one place you can make people run around. You have to be in its glory.<br />
We used to consider Satī's power greater than Yati's. Even Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Mūrti was considered less than of a Satī.<br />
She [Gāṃdhārī, the mother of the 100 Kauravas killed during the Mahābhārata War] told [after the War] when He was cursed, "You will die, the entire Yaduvaṃśh will die," He completely honored the curse because it was from a Satī.<br />
<font color="red">In front of a</font> [pointing with Her left index finger to the right bracelet:] <font color="red">kaṅkaṇ from Mandodarī, even the arrow of Śhrī Rāma would return.<br />
That is the power of the woman!</font><br />
Like Dharā, Earth, She is a woman. She has the power to take away all the sins of the world in Her and from Her you get all fruits, flowers. This Ṛitaṃbharā Prāgñyā comes from Earth."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0216 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Learn to Love Yourself, Universal Sahaja Yoga Temple, Āśhram, 78 Kṛiṣhṇa Nagar, Safdarjung Enclave, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Formerly everybody used to put in India but now they have become very modern so they don't put anything.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> But I think, Mother, ...<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Mother, [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> ... widows don't use the kumkum.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Huh?<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> The widows, they don't use their kumkum.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> No, ah, in Sahaja Yoga we do. We don't accept widowhood in Sahaj Yog. Nobody is a widow, in Sahaj Yog. Neither men nor women.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> [Laughing:] [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> This is all just to suppress women, they started widowhood.<br />
<font color="red">Śhrī Rāma married the wife of Rāvaṇa [Śhrī Mandodarī] to Vibhīṣhaṇa: She was a widow.</font><br />
So this was not a custom.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> This was started later on just to suppressed women.<br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0426 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Public Program, House of Carla Mottino, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysi</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"There were so many stories about Sadāśhiva giving a eh-eh ... blessing to people, even to Rāvaṇa, which is a very interesting story about Rāvaṇa. That Rāvaṇa did lots of penance.<br />
I don't know what he did, how much he must have starved with his ten heads, [as laughter starts:] and what [laughs], I mean, if one mouth is there you feel so hungry, with [as laughter starts:] ten mouths, you see! [Smiles.] I don't know what he must have done to-oo do that kind of a penance that Śh-śhiva just got fed up, you see.<br />
His Compassion is so great, He thought, 'Let this man have whatever he likes.'<br />
So, Rāvaṇa went to Śhiva, and the Śhiva said, "What do you want? Why are you doing all this to yourself?" So, he said that uh: "I want to have a blessing." He said, "What blessing?" "First You promise, that, whatever I ask for, you will give me." He said, "Of course. If it is in My power, I'll give."<br />
It's a very interesting story.<br />
So, he said, "I want to have Your wife." Because he knew His wife is Ādi Śhakti. And, if he gets the Ādi Śhakti as a partner with him, he can do wonders. So he asked that, "I should get Your wife as my partner."<br />
Now, it was very difficult, you see, for Him [laughing:] to take such a decision: to give in to this devil. But in compassion, He did it.<br />
And all these events, you see, really show that how His Compassion works out things.<br />
As a result, ah-ah-ah-oh it was decided that the His wife, Pārvatī, had to go with this horrible fellow.<br />
But Pārvatī's sister [brother] was Śhrī Vi... Viṣhṇu, that is, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, and He said uh-uh-uh to Himself: that, 'I can't allow My sister to go with this devil. I must do something about it.'<br />
The most mischievous one is Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa.<br />
So what He did: was to make him feel like going for the bathroom. So he felt shy, He put the Lady on one side, and he went to the bathroom.<br />
Now, uh-uh-uh Śhiva had warned him: that, "You'd better be careful because this Mother Earth is the Mother of this Lady, and never put Her on the Mother Earth. You must uh carry Him [Her] all the time on your back."<br />
So when he reached uh-uh-uh certain point this Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa created a mischief, and he felt like going. So he put Her down. As soon as he put Her down, the Mother Earth sucked Her in, and he ... he didn't know what to do.<br />
Second time again he tried. And eoh ... he again went to Śhiva and he said, "See now: this is what You have promised, and this is what is doing." So He said, "I'd warned you: that it ... Her brother is a very mischievous fellow, and He'll, some or other, manage, so you'd better be careful. This time you don't listen to Him. Don't put Her on the ground, whatever it may be."<br />
So this time, he did another uh-uh-uh try, we can say, and carried Her on his back. Suddenly, he found a little boy -- It was Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Himself -- uh laughing at him. She [he] said, "Why are You laughing at me?" "Oh my! Why are you carrying this old woman on your bo... back? She has no ornaments." He said, "She's the Goddess." He said, "No! She has no ornaments. She's wearing nothing. How can She be the Goddess?"<br />
So, you see, in India that's a ... uh-uh-uh proverb we use. Somebody, some lady who has, who lives without any ornaments or anything, that she's like the Lanka Pārvatī.<br />
So he was carrying Her to Lanka. And the ... when he looked at Her up, he saw a very old woman without any teeth, you know, laughing at him. He got such a fright, he threw Her away. [Laughter.]<br />
That's Mahāmāyā! [More laughter.]<br />
<font color="red">Then the, third situation was, he went and told: that, "You'd better tell Your wife that She's not to listen to anybody, and You'd better see that You give me Your wife Itself." He said: "All right. She'll be born in Lanka, and you can marry Her."<br />
And's, Her name was Mandodarī.</font><br />
Now the great story goes on like that.<br />
<font color="red">But this Mandodarī was the great worshiper of Viṣhṇu. And at the time when Rāma came, you see, to kill him, all this was organized by Mandodarī Herself. Because She know ... knew that, if Śhrī Rāma kills Rāvaṇa, he will get his uh liberation from these ideas about women. The way he was running after uh-uh-uh Sītā and doing all these things, She actually wanted that something should happen that he should take another birth, and he should get rid of these uh-uh-uh notions of uh-uh-uh looking after beautiful women, and the way he brought Sītājī there. She was against it completely, but he would not listen.</font><br />
So the war took place. And in the war, he was killed by Śhrī Rāma.<br />
All this episode came because of the unlimited compassion of Śhrī Śhiva.<br />
His Compassion is, to look at, looks very illogical sometimes. But there's a big logic behind it. The logic is that: whatever He does, brings forth a uh-uh-uh kind of a solution of the problem."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0226 Śhivarātri Pūjā, How to Get Detached and Ascend, Castle Mountain Camp, 256 Webbs Creek Road, Wisemans Ferry (78 kms NNW of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
"Seeing a widow was considered to be ominous. Ritualistic people do not eat food cooked by a widow.<br />
Our society is unaware of the fact that our Scriptures do not allow such things.<br />
<font color="red">After the death of Rāvaṇa, Śhrī Rāma married Mandodarī, the wife of Rāvaṇa, to Vibhīṣhaṇa.</font><br />
But people say that, 'Śhrī Rāma was all right, yet widows cannot marry.'<br />
Just imagine your own mother, sister or daughter in such a miserable condition! May God save from such a society! It is better not to have such a society and if at all some society is made everyone should have the right to live peacefully in it."<br />
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
To add to this there is a belief that, 'Even seeing a widow would bring bad luck. Must not eat food cooked by a widow.'<br />
This society of ours does not know that this has not been written in any of the Scriptures.<br />
<font color="red">Śhrī Rāma got Mandodarī married to Vibhīṣhaṇa. There are innumerable examples. Śhrī Rāma did this. After the death of Rāvaṇa, Śhrī Rāma got Mandodarī married to Vibhīṣhaṇa.</font><br />
But people say that, 'Up to that it was all right. But other widows cannot marry again.'<br />
Now just think, that if your mother, sister or daughter is pushed into such a circumstance, then God save us from such a samāj [society]. Better there is not any samāj at all. And if there is, then everyone has the right to live a happy and peaceful life.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0407 Śhrī Bhūmī Devī Pūjā (Hindi), Inauguration of the H.H. Śhrī Mātājī Nirmalā Devī Foundation, Nirmal Dham, Behind BSF Camp Chhawala, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">During the Tretā Yuga, at the time of Śhrī Rāma, Ādi Śhakti incarnated in three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
&emsp;1. Sītā [Jānakī] (Mahālakṣhmī) as the daughter of Rāja Janaka</font><br />
&emsp;&emsp;This was the first absolute human form (<i>Laukik</i>)"<br />
&emsp;2. Satī Anasūyā (Mahāsaraswatī) as the wife of a Great Saint<br />
&emsp;<font color="red">3. Mandodarī (Mahākālī) as the wife of the demon Rāvaṇa</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play, Page 20</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">At the time of Rāma's Incarnation Ādi Śhakti existed in three persons: Mahālakṣhmī, as Sītā, His wife; Mahāsaraswatī, as Satī Anasūyā who gave birth to Dattātreya, the Primordial Master; and Mahākālī as Mandodarī, the wife of the demon Rāvaṇa.</font><br />
Ādi Viṣhṇu's eighth form was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa during the Dwāpara Yuga, and again Ādi Śhakti took three forms. Mahākālī lived for a very short time as Viṣhṇumāyā, the infant sister of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. She was actually born as the daughter of Yeśhodā, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's foster mother, and was killed by the demon Kaṃsa. She later took birth as Draupadī, wife of the Pāṇḍavas."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 34</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Mandodari" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ REṆUKĀ DEVĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1108" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ REṆUKĀ DEVĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Renuka_Devi</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/1108"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />
"<font color="red">But some people are also strange, such as one lady has come and said, "I believe in [worship] Reṇukā Devī." Now, particularly, we should not believe in [worship] Reṇukā Devī's Incarnation.</font><br />
And people believe in these kind of insane things. Some people simply believe in who we believe as Incarnations."<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />
"<font color="red">Now, there was one lady who said, "Mother, I worship Reṇukā Devī," so, you should not consider Reṇukā Devī as an Incarnation specifically.</font><br />
People do many such things but normally if you ask about the very well-known Incarnations, this will happen immediately."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0325 Pūjā (Hindi + English), Chit ke Gaharai (Depth of Your Attention), Seminar, Day 2, Camp, Bordi, Maharashtra, India}\label{1979-0325 Pūjā (Hindi + English), Chit ke Gaharai (Depth of Your Attention), Seminar, Day 2, Camp, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"You know how much we did last time, how many names? Two thousand and ... two thousand, one-hundred and eight. Thousand of uh Saraswatī and thousand of Reṇukā Devī, and [a] hundred and eight of the Mahākālī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0118 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (Vināyaka Chaturthī Day), House of Dr. Ramesh Adinath Saṃghavī, B.N-1, Sapt Shrung, Krishnanagar Housing Society, Saharanpur Road, Nasik, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Where is Reṇukā Devī [Reṇukā Mātā Maṃdira] situated?<br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi replies:] Mānorī, we went there."</font><br />
[After a Sahaja Yogi replies something:] We have been to many places like this.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0114 Makar Saṅkrānti Pūjā (English + Marathi), Advice about the Growth within, House of Madhukar Bhikobā Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now the second one [of the three and a half energies] is Mahāsaraswatī, is at Māhūra Gaḍa -- we always sing 'Māhūra Gaḍāvarī' song, that is the one -- is Mahāsaraswatī, which is ... also called as Reṇukā Devī. That's the right-sided Mahāsaraswatī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1221 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (Hindi + English), Hall, Kolhapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Maharashtra there are Aṣhṭavināyak, then we have Three Goddesses, that is, Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī, Śhrī Mahāsaraswatī and Śhrī Mahākālī, I don't have to tell you, though all of this is there. <font color="red">Still we remember Jejurīchā Khaṇḍobā [Khaṇḍobā of Jejurī or Mārtāṇḍa Bhairava, most popular family Deity in Maharashtra], then we remember Reṇukā Devī.</font><br />
Everybody knows everything in Maharashtra, which place is holy and which is not. We are aware of everything because Maharashtra State is like a temple.<br />
You go anywhere in Maharashtra, there will be a jāgṛut sthāna."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1221 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English + Hindi + Marathi), Jayasiṅgapura (37 kms E of Kolhapur), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />
"Same is the situation of Hindu religion. In Hindu religion, there are different Real Gurus, for example Śhrī Ādi Guru Dattātreya, the Nāth Pānth. There are different Incarnations and different swayambhus. They have different religious books.<br />
But in Christian religion, they have only Bible. They can be fundamentalists. Muslims and Jews can be fundamentalists. All these are interrelated. 'This is written in the Books.'<br />
But this is not the case of Hinduism. <font color="red">When one is worshiping Mahālakṣhmī, the other is worshiping Reṇukā Devī.</font> So each family is different. They believe in Incarnations and books."<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />
The same is the case with Hindu religion. In Hindu religion you cannot be communal at all. Because your various Gurus, Real Gurus like Dattātreya, etc., and Nāth Pānthis, are your many Incarnations and your swayambhus are many. You don't have one book. You have [a] number of books.<br />
Only Jesus and Bible, they can be fundamentalists. And they can be Yahūdīs [Jews] also. And all the three are related to each other. It is written in Books.<br />
But a Hindu can never be communal. Because some have some guru and others a different guru. <font color="red">Some adore Mahālakṣhmī, others Reṇukā Devī, some to Kṛiṣhṇa.</font> So, every person, every family individually adore [some] Incarnation, books. As such there is no book which can be called as Holy Bible.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-1225 Christmas Pūjā (Hindi + English), Get Rid of Ritualism and Ego or You Have To Be Loving, Affectionate, Kind and Disciplined (Love Everyone and Apart from Love There Is No Remedy), Gaṇapatīpuḷe, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Renuka Devi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ RĀMA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0817-c" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ RĀMA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Rama</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0817-c"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Rāma is the Embodiment of All the Good Qualities in a man like saṅkoch. You see there is a saṅkoch, like not sort of to go to somebody's house and then to start demanding this and that. Rather you should be worried how far to go with a person, how far to talk to a person, how far to go with your wife, with your children. You see, all that is saṅkoch. Saṅkoch means restraint in a wise way, enlightened restraint -- how far to go is the question."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 Quote on Saṅkocha, Seminar, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The Raja Yoga is a derivation of Hathayoga. In this style the of practices the Gurus led a life like kings. They wore clothes like royal personalities and ruled the people. Raja Janaka an incarnation of Primordial Guru was the father of Seeta. In their inner life they were yogis but they led royal life without any attachment. They did not practice Asanas or Pranayamas but they worshiped God by different styles of bowing.<br />
Prophet Mohomed [Muhammad] was the incarnation of the same Primordial Master. He was married four times but in his inner life he was completely detached.<br />
Shri Rama[']s incarnation also took place on the same channel and enlightened the path of Divine Kingship."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Haṭha Yoga related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As Shri Rama, Vishnu came to enlighten human social and political consciousness as the true model of what Plato, thousands of year[s] later[,] will call it the philosopher king. He settled for human beings the rules of socio-political right action (Samaj Tatha Rajkakaran Dharma). He expressed God's aspcets of majesty and order within kingship and institutions. He had a life of an ideal human King (Maryada Purushottama)[.] This was witnessed by multitudes resulting in a mass awareness for the first time among human beings."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Viṣhṇu's Central Path related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"On the right side on the right channel of Adi Pingla [Piṅgalā], a part of the cardia[c] center extends in this part resides the deity of Rama + Seeta who are the evolved forms of Shri Vishnu."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on the Incarnations of Viṣhṇu and Higher Chakras</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"New Moon pray to Śhrī Śhiva, Full Moon pray to Śhrī Sītā Rāma."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1908-0000 Advices Given to Dr. Madhur Rai, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[Answer to the question, "When this knowledge come to Toy?":] <font color="red">"I knew about it since I was born. I knew about Myself. If I have done anything it is to understand human beings. What's their problem? They follow Christ, they follow Muhammad Sāhab, they follow Rāma, they follow Kṛiṣhṇa, and they follow everything but nothing inside. What is the matter? Nothing penetrates, that was the thing. I thought they were not connected. They are to be connected to all this. Only what I have done is to work out the permutation and combination of human beings. That's not difficult because there are mainly seven chakras one has to work out and how you can raise the Kuṇḍalinī to break the Sahasrāra."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1972-0200 Conversation with Chaṃdūbhāī Jhaverī, Bordi or Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (could be also end of January)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Ah, the name is like this, a man like Tulasīdās, who wrote such a big Rāmāyaṇa, used to take the name. Raghuvīr Himself came to him three times and they planted tīḷa, sandalwood, and did not recognize Him."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1972-0409 Public Program (Marathi), Dhule, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Apart from this, the greatest problem of the jet age is this: that before the Advent of Rāma, Rāvaṇa was bon ... born. And that's why Rāma had to come. Before the Advent of Christ, Herod was born. Before Kṛiṣhṇa, actually Kṛiṣhṇa got His birth because Kaṃsa was there. And Bhagavatī took Her forms always to kill some demons. But I tell you, this killing has helped us not much, because all of them are back again, in their seat. This Kṛiṣhṇa Haraṇa Śhakti has only killed their bodies, again all of them are back on these banners, as if they are the godmen.<br />
......<br />
In the jet age, Rāma if He comes, He will be [considered] absolutely useless, good for nothing man: He cannot even look at other women."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0324 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Jet Age, Seminar, Day 2, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>
<p>
<font color="red">"This is the Land of Yoga and therefore here Great Personalities or Deities took their birth. And in this land only, on this topic for thousands of years, means if Kṛiṣhṇa came six thousand years ago, Rām must have come eleven thousand years ago and even before them many thousands of years ago in Vedas, etc. Historians may not believe Me, but for thousands of years in Bhāratvarṣha, Saints, Seers worked a lot on Self-realization."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0916 Public Program (Marathi), Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"In the word Rām, rā means energy and m means Maheśha, that is Śhrī Śhiva. Maheśha is Śhiva, the God who resides in our heart. When rā is united with m it becomes Rām.<br />
To make the people cross the Void (Bhavasāgara) He has to make some arrangement. So the Great Power like Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha was created and They were placed in the Area of Dharma.<br />
......<br />
After that Śhrī Rāma incarnated in this world but He forgot that He was an Incarnation. He remained in this world as a human being, not as an Incarnation, so that you could rise above the Bhavasāgara. He was a perfect human being. During His Incarnation a few seekers could get their Realization, there is no doubt about it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Sītājī was Śhrī Rāma's wife. Was married. The injustice that was done to Her by the society, made Her leave the house, by accusing Her falsely, disgraced Her. Why back then these great people had a blindfold on? Why didn't they said, that, 'She is our Mother? You are asking Her to leave the house?' She already had passed the test, bypassing the fire, why were they dumbfounded then? What happened to their vigor [light] back then? All were so-called very great then. Nobody raised any point on that.<br />
To teach them a lesson Rādhājī did not marry Kṛiṣhṇa under the societal norms. But still, the whole world knows Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa as Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa. But for Him, the formal marriage is important, that's why there was no child."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Shia word has been derived from Siyā. The word which come from Siyā became Shia -- Siyā means Sītājī. If you go to UP [Uttar Pradesh, India] then nobody says Sītājī, they say Siyājī, 'Siyā var Rām[a]chandra ki jay.' Everyone takes the name Siyā. She was Sītājī, Ādi Śhakti Herself.<br />
......<br />
And these people have achieved many siddhis [achievements]. This is work of our Bhole Śhaṅkarjī, what to do? They [demons] have achieved many siddhis.<br />
As He gave one siddhi to Rāvaṇ that when he used to speak and give lectures then something used to happen on Nābhī chakra [of a listener] that a bhūt would sit there. Thousands of people were overwhelmed listening to his speeches. Even to this extent that nobody was ready to fight against Rāma [as] he convinced all of them."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0120 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Kṣham Ki Śhakti Ka Mahatav (Power of Forgiveness) or Dharm va Adharm (Dharma and Adharma), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I bless you with all my heart that Dr. Ramlingam has good vibrations[,] Shri Rama [Śhrī Rāma] in him would have wisdom to understand the ways of God Almighty."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0000 Letter to Dr. Raul, 2, Parklands, Ice House Wood, Hurst Green, Oxted, Surrey, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"We have come to a place which we call as Brahmapuri here, called, perhaps, maybe because here Śhrī Rāmadāsa, the Guru of Śhivajī Mahārās [Mahārāj], in these deep waters found the statue of Śhrī Rāma, Sītā, Lakṣhmaṇa and Hanumāna together.<br />
Then they were carried from here and put in a temple called Chāphaḷ, the place where I saw that, also.<br />
......<br />
Also we have some miraculous things about Christ and His Mother, that we ... they found a statue of Mother Mary and Christ in one of the shores of Bombay [Mumbai] City, ca...  and  ... called as Worli [locality in central Mumbai and one of the 4 peninsulas], the fisherman found it in their net.<br />
Like Rāmadāsa when He jumped inside this he found it in the river, in the same way.<br />
......<br />
Now today, I am telling you this because Rāmadāsa was the Guru of Śhivajī. And He was the man who was very detached, He was Hanumāna Himself. And once He came to Śhivajī's place and Śhivajī was so fed up with this people and with the whole administration, and the way the things were. He had made a chit, saying that: ``Mh... O, my Guru, I give You all my property, all my lands, all my kingdom, everything at Your Feet and You better look after it." And he [laughing:] put that chit in the ... uh-uh-uh we have the choḷī, you see, in the cloth sort of a thing.<br />
So He stood in the door and read it and he said, ``What? [Laughing:] You've given Me everything?" He said, ``I am a saṃnyāsī, and I don't know administration. But you can do everything ... uh-uh-uh the same way as you have been doing, but be detached about it. And to show that you are detached you must use a ... a ... waist under's ... under dhotī stuff we call it, in a triangular manner, it is made. You see, that thing, with the ... uh saffron color showing that you are detached and you are a saṃnyāsī."<br />
That's how this flag came into being.<br />
So the entry of the politics has been in this country ... uh entry into politics by uh-uh-uh sākṣhātkāri people or by Incarnation has been there.<br />
Most of the Incarnations have been kings. Like uh we have got Buddha, he was a king, Mahāvīra was a prince. Both were prince. Then we have got Rāma who was a king. Then we have got Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who became a king.<br />
So the aiśhwarya, the king-ness, has to be there. Has to be a royal family. Has to be, Incarnation should be from a royal family. In India it is, that is the concept."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-1220 Pūjā (English + Marathi), Garden, little House, Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1110 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi) (Diwālī Pāḍavā Day), Honesty and Patriotism, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"His channel is the evolutionary path, and His Ten Incarnations of the Virāṭa have helped mankind to evolve:<br />
......<br />
&emsp;<i>vii. Benevolent \&amp; Perfect King</i> Rāma Avatāra<br />"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"During the Tretā Yuga, at the time of Śhrī Rāma, Ādi Śhakti incarnated in three separate human personalities, expressing Her three aspects:<br />
&emsp;1. Sītā [Jānakī] (Mahālakṣhmī) as the daughter of Rāja Janaka<br />
&emsp;&emsp;This was the first absolute human form (<i>Laukik</i>)"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 1: Creation, the Eternal Play</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This spiritual awakening in man grew very strong and was again challenged by the evil forces who incarnated to disturb their search through penance (<i>yagonya</i>). At this time, much before the seventh Incarnation of Śhrī Viṣhṇu as Lord Rāma, the Primordial Mother incarnated as the Goddess Durgā, Mother of the Universe. She incarnated from the Primordial Heart Center (Ādi Anāhata Chakra) called the Sacred heart in the Virāṭa. There have been one hundred and eight main Incarnations of the Goddess Durgā to save seekers from the evil of satanic forces.<br />
Maheśha (Śhiva), Viṣhṇu and Brahmadeva form the Trinity which incarnated as one teacher God, the Primordial Master, Dattātreya. He came onto this Earth to teach people the secrets of the Divine, to reveal God, and to help them cross the Ocean of Illusion themselves within their own identity. Evolution could not go further in the hands of human beings who were in the bondage of ignorance, so they were given guidance through this Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) again and again in different lives. He was created as the three-headed child, Dattātreya, by Ādi Śhakti who appeared on Earth during the Tretā Yuga as Satī Anasūyā, wife of the Sage Atreya. He was born as Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara] who founded Jainism -- one of the oldest religions. Then he was born as Rāja Janaka, father of Jānakī also called Sītā, Rāma's wife. She was an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis. Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya.<br />
It is very important to understand that until the animal stage there was no need for animals to solve the problem of life, as animals were under the complete command of God. At the human stage, however, as we learn from the history of Adam and Eve, they were given the choice and freedom to solve the problem of life. That was how evolution was to go a step further. Without such freedom human beings were not equipped to learn the secrets of Divine Power.<br />
Ādi Viṣhṇu Himself took His seventh Incarnation during the Tretā Yuga as Lord Rāma, a human being who crossed the Ocean of Illusion and touched a new dimension of awareness. As Śhrī Rāma, Ādi Viṣhṇu came to enlighten human social and political consciousness as the true model of what Plato, thousand of years later, would call 'the philosopher king'. He settled for human beings the rules of socio-political correct action (<i>samāj tatha rājkaraṇ dharma</i>). He also expressed God's aspect of majesty and order within kingship and institutions, and led a life of an ideal human being (<i>Maryādā Puruṣhottama</i>). This was witnessed by multitudes, resulting in a mass awareness for the first time among human beings. Śhrī Rāma was the ideal King for all kings, and <i>Rām Rājya</i>, His kingdom, was the ideal kingdom.<br />
He reached a point in the Primordial Heart Chakra (Ādi Anāhata Chakra) crossing the Void along the central path (Ādi Suṣhumṇā Nāḍī). His wife Sītā was an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. The <i>Rāmāyaṇa</i>, the epic about Lord Rāma's exploits written by Vālmīki, tells how Lord Rāma was made to forget that He was the Reincarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu for some time, because it was desired that He should act absolutely like a human being, to make them feel absolutely free with him. He gave them a human leadership. Later on, when Sītā disappeared back into the Mother Earth, Lord Rāma remembered His divinity.<br />
At the time of Rāma's Incarnation Ādi Śhakti existed in three persons: Mahālakṣhmī, as Sītā, His wife; Mahāsaraswatī, as Satī Anasūyā who gave birth to Dattātreya, the Primordial Master; and Mahākālī as Mandodarī, the wife of the demon Rāvaṇa.<br />
......<br />
Whilst Dattātreya's Incarnation was created in the Void, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's was at a much higher point, higher than even the Primordial Heart Chakra on which Lord Rāma took Incarnation. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's seat in the body of the Virāṭa is the Ādi Viśhuddhi Chakra, and is placed at the base of the neck inside the spinal cord. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was in fact the Complete Incarnation of the Virāṭa whose form (<i>swarūpa</i>) He showed in a vision to His disciple Arjuna. His teachings to Arjuna are compiled in the <i>Śhrī Bhagavad Gītā</i>. As the Embodiment of the Witness State He killed many male and female evil geniuses (rākṣhasas and rākṣhasīs), as Lord Rāma had done. These entities have to be killed and destroyed again and again whenever they come in the way of human evolution. Ādi Śhakti's Incarnations are also mostly to kill demons. <br />
The Incarnations of Rādhā show how the ideas of human beings gradually changed. The life as Rādhā was definitely a peg above in social advancement in the dogmatic thinking of society, compared to the time of Sītā. She was not married to Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa in a formal human way (<i>laukika</i>). Their wedding was divine (<i>alaukika</i>), and was performed spiritually and socially in the presence of many people by Brahmadeva. Earlier, as Sītā, although formally married to Rāma in a wedding ceremony that was collectively sanctioned, She was still condemned by society. Kṛiṣhṇa's love and adoration of Rādhā brought Her glory without marriage, while Sītā was denied that public acceptance even though She was the legal wife of Rāma.<br />
Princess Sītā was married to King Rāma in a very traditional way. When He went into exile, Rāvaṇa the rākṣhasa, Satan disguised as an ascetic, appeared before Her and took Her away to the capital of his kingdom in Lanka. Rāma fought a war with Rāvaṇa to rescue His wife, who was secluded by Rāvaṇa in the core of his island kingdom. Rāma defeated His enemy and brought Sītā back to His kingdom, Ayodhyā. Although She was the purest of the pure, and the holiest of the holy, She was treated with suspicion by the citizens of Ayodhyā, Rāma's capital city. They would not accept Her as queen, blaming Her for having been abducted by force by Rāvaṇa. The suspicious citizens questioned Her chastity, and committed collective sin by rejecting Her. Although She was pregnant Rāma was forced to forsake Her. She lived with the Saint Vālmīki in the jungles of Bihar State where She gave birth to twin boys, Lava and Kuśha. They were absolutely human personalities but of very great spiritual heritage from previous births. Sītā taught them the divine way of life. They were later born again in Bihar as Gautama, known as Lord Buddha, and as Śhrī Mahāvīra, the leader of the great religion, Jainism. This all happened 500 years before the birth of Christ. Internally they reached a very great height through these births. They preached the doctrine of nonviolence (<i>ahiṃsā</i>) which was later developed into an extreme form of vegetarianism. They took birth in the warrior caste (<i>Kṣhatriya</i>) rather than as fanatical Brahmins in order to keep away from the extremes of vegetarian abstinences, and to stay more balanced. Still their disciples carried their teachings to the extreme of abstinence and vegetarianism. They confused inner asceticism (<i>saṃnyāsa</i>) with organized institutions of asceticism, and nonviolence with vegetarianism. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was later very much criticized by the so-called vegetarian followers of Buddha and Mahāvīra.<br />
......<br />
When one takes the name of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa one has to take the name of Rādhā first, so a seeker recites the mantra to the Virāṭa as 'Rādhā-Kṛiṣhṇa'. Similarly Sītā's name has to be taken before Rāma's for the mantra 'Sītā-Rāma'. Even the Virgin Mary (<i>Kanyā</i>) who was so quiet and potential at the time of Christ, was recognized later on by His disciples as the Power behind Him. She was worshiped for many years after Her death by early Christians. In modern times human beings who are satanic personalities are challenging the validity of the Primordial Mother's virginity and the Virgin Birth in particular. Mary has clearly shown the power of virginity that can raise a mother to such an exalted powerful position that she can conceive a child by desire alone. She had reached that high stage of evolution when by Her Divine Will, She could immaculately conceive. There are other such instances in Hindu purāṇik literature when Kuntī, by the wish of the Mantra, gave birth to the Pāṇḍavas and to Karṇa immaculately."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Tāntrikas controlled their spirits individually or in groups, and gave them mantras as code-names. One mantra for example, `{\it Auṃ Aim Hrīm Klīm Chāmuṇḍāya Vichai namaḥ}', is properly used to awaken Ādi Śhakti as Jagadambā or Chāmuṇḍā. This beautiful and powerful mantra should only be used by a realized Soul under the guidance of an evolved guru. But the same mantra was used by tāntrikas in such a way that each syllable was instrumental in summoning a group of dead spirits to be tamed and used by them. It is the same principle as giving your servant the name of a Deity, such as Rāma, which is quite a common usage in India. When you want your servant you call out the name of Rāma, and he is available at your beck and call. But God is not similarly available to every Tom, Dick or Harry. One has to be a realized Soul and have an authority to call God. Those who call Him without such authority will only succeed in summoning the services of dead spirits as slaves. Such dead beings will respond to a call for Rāma, if that was their name in earthly life. God however does not need the homage of such slaves."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 6: Tantrism</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Rāja Yoga is a derivation of Haṭha Yoga. In this style of practice the gurus led lives like kings. They wore robes like royal personalities and ruled over the people. Rāja Janaka, another Incarnation of Dattātreya, was one such Rāja Yogi. In their inner life they were Yogis, but externally they led a royal existence, yet without attachment. They did not practice āsanas or Prāṇāyāmas, but they worshiped God through different styles of bowing. The Prophet Muhammad was the Incarnation of the same Primordial Master. He was married four times, but in His inner life He was completely detached. Śhrī Rāma's Incarnation also took place on the same channel and enlightened the path of Divine Kingship."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7: Haṭha Yoga and Rāja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Emotional seekers who show off their love of seeking with many tears and much repentance, and who sing sad songs of separation, do not recognize God even when He stands before them. The great poet Tulasīdās, author of the Rāmāyaṇa, was unable to recognize Śhrī Rāma who appeared before him on three separate occasions."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 8: Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"<br />
......<br />
The other Deities remain on their different centers:<br />
&emsp;1. <i>Sahasrāra chakra</i> &#8211; Ādi Śhakti Herself<br />
&emsp;2. <i>Āgñyā chakra</i> &#8211; Jesus Christ + His Mother Mary<br />
&emsp;3. <i>Viśhuddhi chakra</i> &#8211; Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa + Śhrī Rādhā<br />
&emsp;4. <i>Anāhat chakra</i> &#8211; Śhrī Rāma + Śhrī Sītā (right side) Śhrī Śhiva + Śhrī Pārvatī (left side), Śhrī Jagadambā (Durgā) in the center<br />
......<br />
The dangling chakra moves in a circle around the Nābhī chakra, creating an area called the Ocean of Illusion (Bhavasāgara) or the Void. Lord Viṣhṇu, through His ten Incarnations which represent the ten stages of the evolution of the Primordial Being (Virāṭa), crosses this Void. His seventh Incarnation was as Śhrī Rāma who resides on the right side of the Heart chakra with His Power, Śhrī Sītā. Rāma incarnated as the representation of a personality who was the perfect male human being (<i>Maryādā Puruṣhottama</i>). Lord Viṣhṇu's eighth Incarnation was as Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa who, with His Power Rādhā, resides on the Viśhuddhi chakra. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was the ultimate expression of the Primordial Being (Virāṭa) in human form, and taught us to regard the Creation as a play (<i>Līlā</i>) of the Divine Power."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The Heart Center has three parts:<br />
<br />
&emsp;1. On the left side of the Chakra, Pārvatī resides with Her husband, Lord Śhiva. He governs the left side channel of Iḍā nāḍī.<br />
&emsp;2. On the right side of the Chakra is the seat of Lord Rāma, an Incarnation of Ādi Viṣhṇu, and His wife, Sītā, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
&emsp;3. Pārvatī enters alone into the central part of the Chakra as Durgā or Jagadambā, Mother of the World. When Ādi Viṣhṇu incarnated as Lord Rāma, this central part was vacated by Durgā who, in Her role as wife, rejoined Lord Śhiva in the left chamber whilst Lord Rāma with Sītā occupied the central chamber.<br />
......<br />
<b>The fourth center of Anāhat</b><br />
<br />
Is governed by Ādi Śhakti (the Goddess) as Durgā or Jagadambā whose sustenance is Universal Motherly Love. The left part of this Chakra governed by Śhiva and Pārvatī has the sustenance of existence, of innocence, simplicity and steadfastness. The right part of the Chakra is governed by Śhrī Rāma and His dedicated wife, Sītā, and has the sustenance of majesty, and His perfect political leadership. This couple symbolizes the steadfast love between husband and wife."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 10: The Central Path of Sustenance</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Those people who do not respect their parents and their elders always have a weak Mūlādhāra chakra when they come to Sahaja Yoga. They also have a very weak right Heart center (Anāhata chakra) where Śhrī Rāma resides with His wife, Sītā. If they are particularly unkind to their mothers, then the center and right Heart gets very weak. We must therefore understand just how important our parents are, and how the spiritual link is held in the inner being of personality. Our parents have their roots in the Primordial Parents, and marriage has its roots in their primordial and eternal loving relationship. Those who do not respect their marriage, or enjoy the glory of their chastity, also suffer from a very weak Heart center and Mūlādhāra chakra. In such shameless, sex-obsessed people the Kuṇḍalinī just does not rise."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 12: Mūlādhāra Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Seeta Ram"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Appendix: Additional Figures by Śhrī Mātājī, Figure 21</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Despite the chaotic conditions of the world, these are special times. Sahaja Yoga can be called as Mahā Yoga because it's working on such a mass scale. At the time of Śhrī Rāma only one, Nachiketa, got his Realization, but today there are thousands and thousands who have mastered Sahaja Yoga."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0700 Book 'Sahaja Yoga', Chapter 1: Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Later on Śhrī Rāma who was one of the Incarnations on this Earth, showed in his own life that he respected people for their aptitude. For example when Śhrī Rāma was exiled and went to a forest, he met there a poor old woman called Śhabarī who was of tribal caste. She offered some berries to Śhrī Rāma with great affection and devotion. She said: ``Please eat them because they are not at all sour. I have already tasted them." The food or fruits tasted by somebody else are not to be eaten (uttiṣhṭa). If someone has bitten off even a part of a fruit, that fruit is no longer pure and cannot be offered to another person, certainly not to an Incarnation. But Śhrī Rāma was greatly moved by the love of the old lady. He accepted the berries with much joy and ate them. He praised their taste and gave some to his wife, Sītā. His brother Lakṣhmaṇ, felt rather jealous and asked for some berries for himself. There are many incidents where Śhrī Rām gets very friendly with people who were not of very high castes. Also his own Rāmāyaṇa, his life story, was written by a fisherman who was a dacoit. This fisherman was transformed into a Saint by another heavenly minstrel called Nārada. Of course an ordinary fisherman who was also a dacoit had such respect for Śhrī Rāma that he wrote this beautiful epic, the Rāmāyaṇa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Rama" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Vishnu" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ LAKṢHMAṆA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0817-a" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ LAKṢHMAṆA in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Lakshmana</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0817-a"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Tomorrow you come to My house. The kumkum that I['ll] give, with that draw a line outside the door of your māmā's house; this will be like Lakṣhmaṇ Rekhā</font> [line meant to Śhrī Sītā and protect drawn by Śhrī Lakṣhmaṇa around the dwelling He shares with Śhrī Rāma and Śhrī Sītā at Panchavati in the forest of Dandakaranya, now part of Nasik]<font color="red">. As a result of that your māmī will not be able to throw your māmā out of the house. Otherwise, your māmī will kill your māmā, she is a rākṣhasī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-0000 Conversation with Venu Narayan Phaḍake and His Māmā (Marathi), House of Śhrī Mātājī, Gurudev Cooperative Housing Society, Prabhadevi Sea Face, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"How was Śhrī Lakṣhmaṇa, he only used to see the Feet of Śhrī Sītā.<br />
Keep the eyes low. Gradually all these baddhas will go away spontaneously."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1221 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Apanī aur Dṛuṣhṭi Rakhe (Keep the Attention on Yourself), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0322 Public Program, Questions and Answers, Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-1025 Diwālī Pūjā (6th day after Diwālī Day), Expression of Love, Pal Sports Complex, Novi Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Rāma has many special qualities. He was very powerful and a perfect archer. You might have heard about what He did in Sītā Swayaṃwara.<br />
The same Śhrī Rāma killed the Rāvaṇa when He came to it. Tulasīdās has described His bow very very beautifully. Śhrī Rāma was aiming at Rāvaṇa's head with His arrow. Out of ten head's of Rāvaṇa one will fall down, but again it will assume its place. Lakṣhmaṇa suggested Śhrī Rāma to shoot an arrow in the heart of Rāvaṇa, without which he will not die. "Hit him in the heart." Śhrī Rāma was a very humble person. Though He was very powerful yet hH said to Lakṣhmaṇa that, "Rāvaṇa has placed My Sītā in his heart, therefore, I cannot hit him in the heart. Again and again when I chop off his heads, his attention will be diverted from the heart. Only then shall I shoot him in the heart."<br />
What an example of the love of a husband for His Wife! Ocean of Power, how He was full of love! "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0331 Śhrī Hanumāna Pūjā (Hindi), Krishna Sundar Garden, Amit Gaikwad Mala, Erandwane, Mhatre Bridge, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"So, at that time, Śhrī Rāma's mother-in-law, I should say, who was the wife of Daśharatha, she said ... she used to s... she's r... like a big uh-uh-uh ... Sādhunī, and she said that: "From today, two marriages are not allowed, only one."<br />
So among Hindus there's only one marriage. They don't have two marriages. And regard it as a very sinful to have another woman, according to Indian culture. There are some people who do it, but is wrong. Is not Indian.<br />
The father-in-law passed the law, because he has, he suffered -- he had two wives. And one of them tried to send Śhrī Rām to the jungle. She was so cruel, because she wanted her son to become the king. And, as it was the mistake of the father, that he had promish... promised that he will give her a boon [twp boons], because she had saved him in war. And so now, she asked him to send Śhrī Rām to the vanavas [vanam], to the-uh jungle. By-ee-eeh second one [boon], she asked to give the kingdom to her son, who was Lakṣhmaṇa.<br />
But when Lakṣhmaṇa came he didn't want. He said, "I don't want to take Śhrī Rāma's ... uah-uah-uah seat because it is his right."<br />
So he went to Śhrī Rām, in the jungle, requested him: "To You must come! You must come to Ayodhyā, to the capital city, and You should be crowned." Śhrī Rām said, "I can't do it. I have to fulfill my father's wish."<br />
But, at that moment,, the father said that,  "In India nobody will have second marriage." Because of two wives the whole family suffered! So, him ... he said, "Only we can have one wife, and no two wives."<br />
Very surprising, that even till today, in India they believe that you should have only one wife.<br />
But uh-uh-uh what you find in another countries, that people may not have another wife, but they have affairs and they do not respect their wives. This is very sad! And the this makes the country suffering. Because if the women are treated like that, the women suffer, and if the mother suffers the children suffer.<br />
So he made a law: that, 'Nobody will marry twice.' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2007-1021 Navarātri Pūjā (Dussehra Day), Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Later on Śhrī Rāma who was one of the Incarnations on this Earth, showed in his own life that he respected people for their aptitude. For example when Śhrī Rāma was exiled and went to a forest, he met there a poor old woman called Śhabarī who was of tribal caste. She offered some berries to Śhrī Rāma with great affection and devotion. She said: "Please eat them because they are not at all sour. I have already tasted them." The food or fruits tasted by somebody else are not to be eaten (uttiṣhṭa). If someone has bitten off even a part of a fruit, that fruit is no longer pure and cannot be offered to another person, certainly not to an Incarnation. But Śhrī Rāma was greatly moved by the love of the old lady. He accepted the berries with much joy and ate them. He praised their taste and gave some to his wife, Sītā. His brother Lakṣhmaṇ, felt rather jealous and asked for some berries for himself. There are many incidents where Śhrī Rām gets very friendly with people who were not of very high castes. Also his own Rāmāyaṇa, his life story, was written by a fisherman who was a dacoit. This fisherman was transformed into a Saint by another heavenly minstrel called Nārada. Of course an ordinary fisherman who was also a dacoit had such respect for Śhrī Rāma that he wrote this beautiful epic, the Rāmāyaṇa."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Lakshmana" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ HASAN and ŚHRĪ HUSAYN in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0817-b" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ HASAN and ŚHRĪ HUSAYN in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Hasan_Husayn</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0817-b"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now, what can I say, you would be surprised, that the Shia sect that started after Muhammad Sāhab, His daughter was Fāṭimah, She was also Ādi Śhakti.<br />
And Her two children were, Hasan and Husayn, back then, when They saw even after the annihilation of the world, the human beings did not understand, then They were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra and They brought the non-violence as religion, and attempted that, 'Maybe with the establishment of non-violence people will achieve Self-realization.' But couldn't do it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"After the birth of the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab, as I talked yesterday also, there was beginning of the caste Shia in Islam.<br />
Shia word has been derived from Siyā. The word which come from Siyā became Shia -- Siyā means Sītājī. If you go to UP [Uttar Pradesh, India] then nobody says Sītājī, they say Siyājī, 'Siyā var Rām[a]chandra ki jay.' Everyone takes the name Siyā. She was Sītājī, Ādi Śhakti Herself.<br />
And Her two sons, who were Hasan and Husayn, destroyed many evils. When They ultimately died after getting tried, then in the next birth they thought of establishment of nonviolence, violence led them nowhere.<br />
They were [re]born as Mahāvīr and Buddha to make a new experiment. Experiments do happen. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And His daughter Fāṭimah was nobody else but Sītā Jānakī Herself.<br />
And Her two sons, Hasan and Husayn, were nobody else but Lava and Kuśha. They were born again and again: They were born as Mahāvīra and Buddha, and then They were born as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
It is only possible through Sahaja Yoga to realize that this is the Truth, this is the fact. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now, beyond that is God's Realization.<br />
There are three stages to that also, but just now I have told this: the Sat-chit-ānand State.<br />
The God's Realization is the state in which Gautam Buddha and Mahāvīra only rose, and They are settled down here in our brains, both of Them are here, Christ is here.<br />
And these two were not Incarnations: They were born as human beings. They were born to Sītā, as Lav and Kuśh. Then they were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra. Then Ādi Śhakti was Their mother again. Then they were born to Fāṭimah Bi as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
They are both placed here, in your head.<br />
And They are the two milestones you have got, by which you can know what a human being can rise up to that now today They are like Incarnations. Incarnations are beyond, but maybe the gap can be bri... bridged."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now in this Void we have two great entities as well which we know as Chandra [Moon] and Sūrya [Sun]. Moon and Sun are such chakras which reside on these nāḍīs here and here.<br />
On these chakras there are two very great personalities who have been appointed. They are complete embodiment of human beings. They are like humans, in fact are humans. Out of these one is Buddha and one is Mahāvīra.<br />
But if you listen to the whole history of Their lives, then these are two sons which Śhrī Sītā had as Lav and Kuśha who is completely in human form. And after They evolved to the level that They are here as Buddha and Mahāvīra. There also they thought They have reached an extreme of nonviolence because the supports of nonviolence came in and started protecting even mosquitoes and bugs.<br />
Then They again took birth and came at the time of Muhammad. Muhammad was an Incarnation of Śhrī Janaka and His daughter Fāṭimah Bi was also Incarnation of Śhrī Sītā.<br />
Then, as Their sons as Hasan and Husayn, They gave Their life in Karbalāʾ to prove that no kind of extreme is good.<br />
And this thing is Truth or not you can see on your vibrations. If [one thinks that] I am lying, then through your vibrations you would know that not even one single word is a lie here that I am telling you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0131 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Void, Heart, Viśhuddhi, Channels, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"They are all connected. Because Hazarat ʿAlī was the son-in-law of Prophet Muhammad and Prophet Muhammad was the Incarnation of King Janaka. His sons Hasan and Husayn, who were killed in the battle of Karbalā, were no one else but Sītājī's sons Lav and Kuśh, who were later incarnated as Mahāvīr and Buddha."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0201 Public Program (Hindi), Brahma kā Gyān (Knowledge of Brahma) or Mūlādhāra to Viśhuddhi, Āgñyā, and Sahasrāra, 9 Raisina Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Zen and Void, Part 1, First Western Seminar, Day 2, Session 2 (during and after tea and coffee), Conference Center, East Hampstead Park (near Wokingham, 60 kms W of London), Berkshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-1112 Public Program, Day 2, Auditorium, Hotel Karim (now closed), Route Touristique Raouad, Gammarth (21 kms NE of Tunis), Tunisia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Specially, these are the days of your marty[rdo]m. And I know about it, everything, what had happened to Hasan and Husayn. You all have done lot of penance for Them, and are still doing it. But now the time has come for all of you to know that Their sacrifice, Their kurbānī, has been completely fulfilled. After all, what did They want? They wanted whatever Their father, ʿAlī, wanted Them to do, also Their mother Fāṭimah. But we don't know, 'Who They were? What Incarnations They were? What was Their job?'<br />
......<br />
No need to feel guilty. You are not the ones who killed Hasan and Husayn, and still, if you feel that Hasan and Husayn should have lived, They can live through your lives. Only thing you have to know: how to become personality, make your personality of Their level. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0528 Persian Public Program, Iman Cultural Center, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Later They were born in Arabia as Hasan and Husayn, the two sons of Fāṭimah, daughter of Muhammad Sāhib. They were murdered in a very violent war at Karbalāʾ. Their death signifies a great sacrifice in the name of religion. It is an indication how people who are extreme in nature take to fanaticism and, in their blindness, kill the very essence of religion that is born in flesh and blood as an Incarnation. This awakening gave a rude shock to the mass of religious human beings of the land, and there ensued a phenomenon of mass repentance. In this way people were made to realize that there can be no attachment to war for a realized Soul. Violence and nonviolence are attributes of mind but awareness is beyond these extremes. In defense of righteousness one has to go to war, but when one becomes the witness one only sees the play of war without taking any credit or discredit for it, or being disturbed by its aggression.<br />
After Fāṭimah, the Reincarnation of Sītā, died, sectarian war broke out among the Muslims. One side, the Shiya sect, was founded by Her; in Indian dialect Sītā is pronounced 'Shiya'. They are known today as Shiites. Shiya women are regarded as fair, innocent and beautiful because of their motherly expressions; in the same way the women of Janakapur, Sītā's birthplace in India, are similarly blessed by Mahālakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Hussain Hasan<br />
sons of Fatima<br />
daughter of Moha"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Appendix: Additional Figures by Śhrī Mātājī, Figure 21</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Hasan" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Husayn" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ LAV and ŚHRĪ KUŚH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0816" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ LAV and ŚHRĪ KUŚH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Lav_Shri_Kush</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0816"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And His daughter Fāṭimah was nobody else but Sītā Jānakī Herself.<br />
And Her two sons, Hasan and Husayn, were nobody else but Lava and Kuśha. They were born again and again: They were born as Mahāvīra and Buddha, and then They were born as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
It is only possible through Sahaja Yoga to realize that this is the Truth, this is the fact."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now, beyond that is God's Realization.<br />
There are three stages to that also, but just now I have told this: the Sat-chit-ānand State.<br />
The God's Realization is the state in which Gautam Buddha and Mahāvīra only rose, and They are settled down here in our brains, both of Them are here, Christ is here.<br />
And these two were not Incarnations: They were born as human beings. They were born to Sītā, as Lav and Kuśh. Then they were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra. Then Ādi Śhakti was Their mother again. Then they were born to Fāṭimah Bi as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
They are both placed here, in your head.<br />
And They are the two milestones you have got, by which you can know what a human being can rise up to that now today They are like Incarnations. Incarnations are beyond, but maybe the gap can be bri... bridged."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now in this Void we have two great entities as well which we know as Chandra [Moon] and Sūrya [Sun]. Moon and Sun are such chakras which reside on these nāḍīs here and here.<br />
On these chakras there are two very great personalities who have been appointed. They are complete embodiment of human beings. They are like humans, in fact are humans. Out of these one is Buddha and one is Mahāvīra.<br />
But if you listen to the whole history of Their lives, then these are two sons which Śhrī Sītā had as Lav and Kuśha who is completely in human form. And after They evolved to the level that They are here as Buddha and Mahāvīra. There also they thought They have reached an extreme of nonviolence because the supports of nonviolence came in and started protecting even mosquitoes and bugs.<br />
Then They again took birth and came at the time of Muhammad. Muhammad was an Incarnation of Śhrī Janaka and His daughter Fāṭimah Bi was also Incarnation of Śhrī Sītā.<br />
Then, as Their sons as Hasan and Husayn, They gave Their life in Karbalāʾ to prove that no kind of extreme is good.<br />
And this thing is Truth or not you can see on your vibrations. If [one thinks that] I am lying, then through your vibrations you would know that not even one single word is a lie here that I am telling you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0131 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Void, Heart, Viśhuddhi, Channels, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"They are all connected. Because Hazarat ʿAlī was the son-in-law of Prophet Muhammad and Prophet Muhammad was the Incarnation of King Janaka. His sons Hasan and Husayn, who were killed in the battle of Karbalā, were no one else but Sītājī's sons Lav and Kuśh, who were later incarnated as Mahāvīr and Buddha."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0201 Public Program (Hindi), Brahma kā Gyān (Knowledge of Brahma) or Mūlādhāra to Viśhuddhi, Āgñyā, and Sahasrāra, 9 Raisina Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Those who are here and Buddha and Mahāvīr are here, sitting on our foreheads. Buddha and Mahāvīr are not someone else, [but] Luv and Kuśh, whom you call, Their names are Luv and Kuśh. They are the ones who take birth in Their world multiple times. They came into the world under the names of Buddha and Mahāvīr.<br />
Consider Them as Incarnations only. They are a special being who take incarnation from humans."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0117 Public Program (Hindi), Day 4, Chakroṃ para Upasthita Devatā (Deities on All Chakras), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Also here Two Great Incarnations reside on the forehead: one is Buddha and the other is Mahāvīra.<br />
These are both very special, for guidance to human beings. These both are Luv and Kuśh. Luv and Kuśh took birth as Buddha and Mahāvīra, both have the same mother. Both these Luv and Kuśh were born when work was being done on Nābhī chakra along with Chandra nāḍī and Sūrya nāḍī.<br />
This I am telling you the subtle side of it, you may check this when your Kuṇḍalinī is awakened."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0311 Public Program (English + Hindi), Day 2, Session 2 (evening), On Gāndhī and Collective Consciousness, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Śhrī Rām was the ideal husband where as Śhrī Sītājī was an ideal wife and the children born to Them, known as Lav and Kuśha, were also the ideal sons."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-0405 Śhrī Rāma Pūjā (Rāma Navamī), House, Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Princess Sītā was married to King Rāma in a very traditional way. When He went into exile, Rāvaṇa the rākṣhasa, Satan disguised as an ascetic, appeared before Her and took Her away to the capital of his kingdom in Lanka. Rāma fought a war with Rāvaṇa to rescue His wife, who was secluded by Rāvaṇa in the core of his island kingdom. Rāma defeated His enemy and brought Sītā back to His kingdom, Ayodhyā. Although She was the purest of the pure, and the holiest of the holy, She was treated with suspicion by the citizens of Ayodhyā, Rāma's capital city. They would not accept Her as queen, blaming Her for having been abducted by force by Rāvaṇa. The suspicious citizens questioned Her chastity, and committed collective sin by rejecting Her. Although She was pregnant Rāma was forced to forsake Her. She lived with the Saint Vālmīki in the jungles of Bihar State where She gave birth to twin boys, Lava and Kuśha. They were absolutely human personalities but of very great spiritual heritage from previous births. Sītā taught them the divine way of life. They were later born again in Bihar as Gautama, known as Lord Buddha, and as Śhrī Mahāvīra, the leader of the great religion, Jainism. This all happened 500 years before the birth of Christ. Internally they reached a very great height through these births. They preached the doctrine of nonviolence (<i>ahiṃsā</i>) which was later developed into an extreme form of vegetarianism. They took birth in the warrior caste (<i>Kṣhatriya</i>) rather than as fanatical Brahmins in order to keep away from the extremes of vegetarian abstinences, and to stay more balanced. Still their disciples carried their teachings to the extreme of abstinence and vegetarianism. They confused inner asceticism (<i>saṃnyāsa</i>) with organized institutions of asceticism, and nonviolence with vegetarianism. Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa was later very much criticized by the so-called vegetarian followers of Buddha and Mahāvīra. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Hussain Hasan<br />
sons of Fatima<br />
daughter of Moha"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Appendix: Additional Figures by Śhrī Mātājī, Figure 21</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Lav" /><category term="crimson @ Shri Kush" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ FĀṬIMAH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0815" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ FĀṬIMAH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/QIT_Shri_Fatimah</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2024/0815"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Fāṭimah, the daughter of Muhammad Sāheb, was the same who became daughter of King Janaka.<br />
Whom are you fighting? Think over it. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now, what can I say, you would be surprised, that the Shia sect that started after Muhammad Sāhab, His daughter was Fāṭimah, She was also Ādi Śhakti.<br />
And Her two children were, Hasan and Husayn, back then, when They saw even after the annihilation of the world, the human beings did not understand, then They were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra and They brought the non-violence as religion, and attempted that, 'Maybe with the establishment of non-violence people will achieve Self-realization.' But couldn't do it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"After the birth of the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab, as I talked yesterday also, there was beginning of the caste Shia in Islam.<br />
Shia word has been derived from Siyā. The word which come from Siyā became Shia -- Siyā means Sītājī. If you go to UP [Uttar Pradesh, India] then nobody says Sītājī, they say Siyājī, 'Siyā var Rām[a]chandra ki jay.' Everyone takes the name Siyā. She was Sītājī, Ādi Śhakti Herself.<br />
And Her two sons, who were Hasan and Husayn, destroyed many evils. When They ultimately died after getting tried, then in the next birth they thought of establishment of nonviolence, violence led them nowhere.<br />
They were [re]born as Mahāvīr and Buddha to make a new experiment. Experiments do happen. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And His daughter Fāṭimah was nobody else but Sītā Jānakī Herself.<br />
And Her two sons, Hasan and Husayn, were nobody else but Lava and Kuśha. They were born again and again: They were born as Mahāvīra and Buddha, and then They were born as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
It is only possible through Sahaja Yoga to realize that this is the Truth, this is the fact. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now, beyond that is God's Realization.<br />
There are three stages to that also, but just now I have told this: the Sat-chit-ānand State.<br />
The God's Realization is the state in which Gautam Buddha and Mahāvīra only rose, and They are settled down here in our brains, both of Them are here, Christ is here.<br />
And these two were not Incarnations: They were born as human beings. They were born to Sītā, as Lav and Kuśh. Then they were born as Buddha and Mahāvīra. Then Ādi Śhakti was Their mother again. Then they were born to Fāṭimah Bi as Hasan and Husayn.<br />
They are both placed here, in your head.<br />
And They are the two milestones you have got, by which you can know what a human being can rise up to that now today They are like Incarnations. Incarnations are beyond, but maybe the gap can be bri... bridged."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi + English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Now in this Void we have two great entities as well which we know as Chandra [Moon] and Sūrya [Sun]. Moon and Sun are such chakras which reside on these nāḍīs here and here.<br />
On these chakras there are two very great personalities who have been appointed. They are complete embodiment of human beings. They are like humans, in fact are humans. Out of these one is Buddha and one is Mahāvīra.<br />
But if you listen to the whole history of Their lives, then these are two sons which Śhrī Sītā had as Lav and Kuśha who is completely in human form. And after They evolved to the level that They are here as Buddha and Mahāvīra. There also they thought They have reached an extreme of nonviolence because the supports of nonviolence came in and started protecting even mosquitoes and bugs.<br />
Then They again took birth and came at the time of Muhammad. Muhammad was an Incarnation of Śhrī Janaka and His daughter Fāṭimah Bi was also Incarnation of Śhrī Sītā.<br />
Then, as Their sons as Hasan and Husayn, They gave Their life in Karbalāʾ to prove that no kind of extreme is good.<br />
And this thing is Truth or not you can see on your vibrations. If [one thinks that] I am lying, then through your vibrations you would know that not even one single word is a lie here that I am telling you. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0131 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Void, Heart, Viśhuddhi, Channels, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0117 Public Program (Hindi), Day 4, Chakroṃ para Upasthita Devatā (Deities on All Chakras), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Although after Realization you go beyond religion, you do not have any religion left.<br />
When you believe in Muhammad Sāhab also, also in Nāṇak Sāhab, and in Hazarat ʿAlī also, in Fāṭimah Bi also, and in Sītājī also, also in Jesus Christ, and also in Gaṇeśhjī, then how can you sit in these small compartments of religions?"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0318 Public Program (Hindi), Day 9, Sahasrāra Chakra, Śhāmiyānā, Garden, Pataudi House, 10 Ashoka Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And those gurus who know about it, they know that on our left, at the place of Swādhiṣhṭhān, we have to take the name of Hazarat ʿAlī and Fāṭimah."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"So He [Lord Buddha] was to be born again as one of the sons of Fāṭimah Bi, who was the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab. Then again He was to be born as Mārkaṇḍeya, and again as Śhaṅkarāchārya: just to neutralize what He has been preaching."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0611 Public Program, How Aspects of God Are Expressed within Us, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0617 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Bala Kanayson's House, Rosemary Road, Tamworth (31 kms NE of Birmingham), Staffordshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0207 Public Program, Day 3, Introduction to Nābhī and Void, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-1029 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Honesty and Money, Suite, Hotel, Cairo, Egypt</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Specially, these are the days of your marty[rdo]m. And I know about it, everything, what had happened to Hasan and Husayn. You all have done lot of penance for Them, and are still doing it. But now the time has come for all of you to know that Their sacrifice, Their kurbānī, has been completely fulfilled. After all, what did They want? They wanted whatever Their father, ʿAlī, wanted Them to do, also Their mother Fāṭimah. But we don't know, 'Who They were? What Incarnations They were? What was Their job?' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0528 Persian Public Program, Iman Cultural Center, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[The DVD contains a saying of Muhammad Sāhib from the Hadith: "Paradise is under the Feet of the Mother." Śhrī Mātājī reads it on the screen.] <font color="red">"Really? Muhammad said this?</font> [Looking with a different view:] <font color="red">Yes, Fāṭimah is that Mother."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2006-1014 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, about Morocco, London, UK}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis. Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya.<br />
Later They were born in Arabia as Hasan and Husayn, the two sons of Fāṭimah, daughter of Muhammad Sāhib. They were murdered in a very violent war at Karbalāʾ. Their death signifies a great sacrifice in the name of religion. It is an indication how people who are extreme in nature take to fanaticism and, in their blindness, kill the very essence of religion that is born in flesh and blood as an Incarnation. This awakening gave a rude shock to the mass of religious human beings of the land, and there ensued a phenomenon of mass repentance. In this way people were made to realize that there can be no attachment to war for a realized Soul. Violence and nonviolence are attributes of mind but awareness is beyond these extremes. In defense of righteousness one has to go to war, but when one becomes the witness one only sees the play of war without taking any credit or discredit for it, or being disturbed by its aggression.<br />
After Fāṭimah, the Reincarnation of Sītā, died, sectarian war broke out among the Muslims. One side, the Shiya sect, was founded by Her; in Indian dialect Sītā is pronounced 'Shiya'. They are known today as Shiites. Shiya women are regarded as fair, innocent and beautiful because of their motherly expressions; in the same way the women of Janakapur, Sītā's birthplace in India, are similarly blessed by Mahālakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Brahmadeva represents that aspect of God Almighty which manifests as the Creator of both the subtle side (esthetics), and of the gross side of material creation. Brahmadeva looks like an ascetic, a saintly personality, with a beard and mustache. He has four heads and all the hair on His heads is tied up in a top-knot. His body is thin with His most prominent feature being bulging and very large eyes. Brahmadeva rarely incarnates but He has incarnated once as Hazarat ʿAlī, husband of Fāṭimah and son-in-law of Muhammad Sāhib. Some ancient Sages tried to explain the meaning of His four heads as the expression of creation into four <i>Vedas</i>. The meaning of His heads is much wider and deeper, though. Brahmadeva is the symbol of the Creative Power of the Supreme, the Īśhwara, Brahma, God. This creative power is expressed through the plane of matter in this universe. All material things have three dimensions but there is a fourth dimension which only human beings can see and feel. This fourth dimension is the esthetic dimension created by balanced harmonies and the integration of different textures, forms and lines. Animals have no sense of beauty; only human beings can feel the esthetics of a composition of different colors, or the movement of lines and the melting of forms. The feelings of joy acquired through this esthetic sense create a <i>Rasa</i> (a secretion of the essence or juice of a feeling). This Rasa gives one a stimulative feeling that sets in motion waves of esthetic joy within the Inner Self. These joys are of different frequencies and vibrations. One does not need to dissect them but as I look at the different petals of this chakra, I shall try to explain the kinds of joys present in the realm of creativity expressed through divine enlightenment. "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 13: Swādhiṣhṭhān Chakra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Hussain Hasan<br />
sons of Fatima<br />
daughter of Moha"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Appendix: Additional Figures by Śhrī Mātājī, Figure 21</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Fatimah" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Gruhalakshmi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>