<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-06T17:39:50-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/quotes.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Quotes</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ MACCHINDRANĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0630" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ MACCHINDRANĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Macchindranath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0630"><![CDATA[<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Macchinder Nath an incarnation of Primordial Guru started Nath Pantha.</font> Even after some decades these were very few real Gurus (Avadhuta[s)] left in this cult. The deterioration started. Tankrikas [tantrikas] who imposed themselves as Gurus took charge of the cult in Many places."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Haṭha Yoga related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now about this power ... in our country many people knew about this for ages and they were called true Masters (Sadguru). These people had attained this knowledge through very hard penance.<br />
A power named as Kuṇḍalinī resides in our triangular bone. And we call it Kuṇḍalinī because it's [it] sits in the shape of three and a half coil. It is very surprising that even Greeks knew about this. Because the triangular bone where Kuṇḍalinī resides, they call it sacrum bone. It means there is this sacred bone within us. Not sure, if many of these things they adopted from us or they attained this knowledge themselves in sahaja way.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">In our country, experimentations to achieve Self-realization have been going on for ages. In Maharashtra [India] there have been people belonging to Nāth sect like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, etc., these people were all into this.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1907-0000 Interview (Hindi) with a Lady for a TV Program Directed by Ashok Agarwal, Ardhamātrā Volume 2, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To make the people cross the Void (Bhavasāgara) He has to make some arrangement. So the Great Power like Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha was created and They were placed in the Area of Dharma.<br />
Dattātreya and Ādi Gurus incarnated in this world many a times. He incarnated as King Janaka who was like the father of Ādi Śhakti. <font color="DarkRed">After that He incarnated in Iran as Zoroaster, then as Macchindranāth, then as Muhammad Sāheb and Nāṇak Sāheb.</font><br />
No one fought with each other. See what type of darkness you are in?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Śhrī Dattātreya's Incarnations are numerous. Firstly He came as King Janaka. Śhrī Sītājī was His daughter, who was the embodiment of Śhakti Herself. <font color="DarkRed">Then He came as Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, and Muhammad Sāhab, who were a completely different type of human being.</font><br />
They trialed out lots of different things.<br />
Śhrī Datta, the Primordial Masters firstly in this world educated us about the symbolic forms within us. And then also said that, "You people got entangled in symbolism, in idol worshiping." Their meaning was to go beyond and recognize the Śhakti within these idols. That's why They talked about the idols."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The same Śhrī Dattā incarnated many a times on the Earth.<br />
As I told you yesterday, King Janaka was one of Them. King Janaka was the father of Jānakī [Śhrī Sītā]. He was none other than the Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Thereafter, Macchindranāth, most have you must have heard His name, was also His Incarnation.</font><br />
After that Zoroaster who came three times on the Earth, He was also His Incarnation.<br />
After that Muhammad Sāhab, who was His Incarnation.<br />
And when He was asked that, "Bhāī [Brother], there must have been others also before You," then He replied, "Yes, there [was] a Muhammad." Then again He was asked who was before Him. He replied, "There was one Muhammad."<br />
Muhammad means Praise, the One who is praised, the One who deserves to be praised and is the One who is Redeemer of the world.<br />
They were all Muhammads, They were all Dattātreyas, who came on Earth regularly.<br />
After that [was] Nāṇaka, Guru Nāṇaka. If you ever read His teachings, if you read His talks then you will be surprised that He has always talked in a Sahaja. He has said, "Sahaja Samādhi lago." He has said, "Kāhe re ban khojan jāe, Sarab nivāsī sadā alepā tohī saṃg[a] samāī, Puṣhpamadhya jo bāsa basata hai mukara māhī jaise chhāī, Taise hī harī base niraṃtara ghaṭa hī khojo bhāī." ["Why to go to forest to find Him, He is always there with you just like there is a fragrance in a flower and just as the reflection is there in a mirror, in the same way God is residing in you eternally, seek Him within."] He is just inside, achieve Him just inside. We are just singing poem, singing songs, we are just cramming His prescription.<br />
The talk of seeking this Absolute Principle, residing just inside the heart, has been made since ancient times by these Ādi Gurus, who are incarnated on this Earth again and again.<br />
......<br />
Now just look at Gaganagaḍ Mahārāj, it is true that he cured many people, but the problem is that his fingers moved inside like a telescope and those of feet also. The poor man lives on a tree or moves on a lion. Apart from this he cannot move anywhere. But when I reached to him, these people were with Me, he quickly recognized Me. There is no doubt about it. He has not yet seen Me in this lifetime. But from many years he knew about Me. He is elder to Me. He began to say, "Mother, I have been waiting for you for many years. Today I am so fortunate that you have come here." <font color="DarkRed">He is a Nāth Pānthi, so he is just like Macchindranāth and a very great person.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, we have had great Saints in our country, no doubt.<br />
Even a person like Gyāneśhwara, was a great Saint we have [had]. <font color="DarkRed">And He was in the same line as Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, then Gyānināth, and then His father [brother] there was Nivṛuttināth, and He initiated Him. And we had a Great Guru paramparā, Guru tradition in a ... that Nāth Pānthis.</font><br />
Even He, Gyāneśhwara, who was a realized Soul, no doubt, and His brother was really a very great Saint. Even He, when He writes about [the] Kuṇḍalinī awakening, He doesn't do the way you Sahaja Yogis [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
That I wish you could read Marathi, I could make you understand now.<br />
And how He has raised the Kuṇḍalinī, what happens: He could give Realization to two people in His lifetime. See?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0527 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, TM, False Gurus, Industrial Revolution, Christ, Go Slowly with New People, Seminar, Day 1, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Dattātreya is the innocence of all these Three Powers.<br />
And this Guru uh was the One whose ... who then had a big tradition of Gurus.<br />
In the same tradition, we had many Gurus in our country. And, specially, in the area near Bombay [Mumbai], which is called as Maharashtra, they came as Nāth. They are, they were called as Nāth.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">So the first one was Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], then ahh Dattātreya, then Macchindranāth, then Gorakhnāth, like that a tradition of these Gurus came.</font><br />
But all Their knowledge was kept as a guarded secret. It was a Gupta Vidyā. Is absolutely guarded secret: secret knowledge about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
They never talked about it, they never told about it. Because they thought: that, 'Just now, let us experiment with it fully, and then we will give some idea about it to people.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0107 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), Jñāneśhvarasāgar (Mulā Dharaṇa or Mula Dam), Bārāgāva Nāṃdūra (near Rāhurī), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0106 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English + Marathi + English), Ascent Is the Main Attention, Sangli, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0125 Pūjā, Why We Have Failed in Our Pursuit of God (The Whole System Has to Be Changed), Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1221 Pūjā (Marathi + English + Marathi + English), Become Beautiful Vessels of Vibrations and Attention on Quality, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">[We had many Yogis who started work on the middle path of human ascent like Gorakhnāth, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], Macchindranāth. They worked on the problem of human beings and how to make this ascent possible. They discovered in human beings in the triangular bone sacrum a residual power.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1018 Public Talk, 1st World Conference on Yoga Organized by the Soviet Ministry of Health, Moscow University, Moscow, Russia (other date 1019)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0212 Public Program, Day 1, Chowdia Memorial Hall, Town Hall, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, the tradition is, that: we had a group, we should say, we called them as Nāth Pānthis, in India, who were working on the central path, which is called as Suṣhumṇā. But the tradition was that only one guru c[o]uld have only one disciple. That was the tradition, for ages together.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And the we had this-s Gorakhnāth, and you must have heard about the Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], all these people.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0413 Public Program, National Press Club, Canberra, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />  
"In early tradition, it was accustomed to have one guru per student.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">It was like this in Nāth Pānthi. One path was devotion (Bhakti Mārg) and the other path was to read about lok [mankind, world] or ved [knowledge]. But as far as Self-realization was concerned, Nāth Pānthi introduced [it] in Maharashtra, like Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth. At that time also there was a custom to have one guru per student.</font>"
<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />  
"Earlier, it was a custom that one guru should have only one disciple only.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">This was the custom in Nāth Pānthi also. On one side, they were very ignorant, and on the other side, people were reading Vedas, etc. But when it was the question of Self-realization, it was Nāth Pānthis who said it was in Maharashtra. Like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth. At that time, it was a custom that one master should have only one disciple.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1216 Public Program (Hindi + Marathi), Day 1, Kuṇḍalinī Eka Mahāna Śhakti (Kuṇḍalinī Is a Great Power), Grounds, New English School, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0115 Public Program, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0118 Public Program, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1001 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between 7th Day and 8th Day), You Must Project Your Depth and Not Reflect, Hangar, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1008 Śhrī Śhakti Devī Pūjā, We Have to Understand Our Own Responsibility (Sense of Responsibility and the Main Quality of Viśhuddhi Chakra is Responsibility) and The Greatest Problem of America is Mister Ego (Surrender your ego and Ego Must Be Controlled), Camp Vacamas, 256 Macopin Road, West Milford, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1028 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi + Hindi + English), after Concert, the day before Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi) (5th day after Diwālī Day), Nargol, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-1030 Diwālī Pūjā (Hindi + English) (6th day after Diwālī Day), Sahajyog Ke Suruvat (How Sahaja Yoga Started), Nargol, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0219 Public Address to Doctors, Inauguration, International Sahaja Yoga Research and Health Center, Plot No. 1, Sector 8, H.H. Śhrī Nirmalā Devī Mārg, C.B.D. Belapur, Navi Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0721 Public Program, CSCA Stadium, Povitroflots'kyi prospect 2, Kiev, Ukraine</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0919 Public Program, Convocation Hall, University of Toronto, 31 King's College Circle, Toronto, ON, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But I was surprised that in Kiev, which is the capital of Ukraine, I went to see the museum: is full of paintings of Kuṇḍalinī and of the chakras, different chakras. I was amazed: 'How could it be?'<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And then they said that, "Two thousand before Christ [2000 B.C.], two S-Saints came from India," and they told Me the name and I was a... amazed how they knew the names of those people: Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth.</font><br />
That time I think America didn't exist, otherwise they would have come here also. [Laughter.]<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And these two people went there. And they taught them all about Kuṇḍalinī, but they said, "We didn't know how to raise, we didn't know how to achieve it. So, we just knew it, but we didn't know how to do it.</font>"<br />
Same in India: Gyāneśhwara has written about it.<br />
But much before that, thirteen thousand years back, another Saint, Mārkaṇḍeya, has written about it.<br />
Then in the sixth century, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has written about it.<br />
And it has been written by many people. In the sixteenth century, so many Saints have written about.<br />
In the Bible also it is there, that, "I'll appear before you like tongues of flames," and these are the chakras that you see."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0924 Public Program, The Olympic Collection, Grand Ballroom, 3rd Floor, 11301 W. Olympic Boulevard, 204, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0927 Public Program, Auditorium, New York Society for Ethical Culture, 2 West 64th Street, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0406 Public Talk to Doctors, Conference "The Art of Healing and 'Sahaja Yoga' -- A Special Session on Alternative Medicine", Indian Medical Association, FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0622 Public Program, Convocation Hall, University of Toronto, 31 King's College Circle, Toronto, ON, Canada</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Those who went into the research of this in India were called as Nāth Pānthis. Nāth means master and paṇṭh[an] means way, that is, way or road of mastery. Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth were two of these Saints thousands of years ago. These two and others traveled extensively. They had visited the land which is now Ukraine because in the museum you can find ancient pottery with paintings of these chakras."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1997-0827 Written (Presented) Talk, Russian Folk Medicine Conference, Russia (other date 0901)}</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1998-1218 Public Program (Hindi), Naitikatā aura Deśhabhakti (Ethics and Patriotism), Rāmlīlā Maidān, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, after the Evening Program, Friday before Navarātri Pūjā (6th Day), Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0305 Śhivarātri Pūjā (English + Hindi + Marathi), Stadium, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0325 Public Program (Hindi), Hamārī Ātmā Kyā Chīja Hai (What Is Our Spirit), Rāmlīlā Maidān, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0408 Public Address to I.A.S. Officers' Wives Association, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Africa, I was surprised: that they have talked about Kuṇḍalinī. They have! And I have seen some of the maps, old maps, of Africa, they have made the picture of Kuṇḍalinī also, all over.<br />
Even in a place like Bolivia, which is so far away, and the somebody went to Bolivia, from Italy, and he said, "Mother they know everything about Kuṇḍalinī!" I said, "Really?" "Yes, they know, but they don't know how to awaken It."<br />
And sprea... Sahaja Yoga has spread so much in Bolivia: the Minister from there came to see Me.<br />
And who told them? I said, "Who told them?" They said, "There were two Saints who came from India."<br />
Even in Ukraine, I was surprised, they said, "There were two Saints who came here from India, they told us about Kuṇḍalinī."<br />
Chinese people, they believe that there is a treasure of spirituality in India, but they don't know what it is, you see.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">But these two, I don't know, there were two Saints known as Macchindranāth and Gorakhnāth who have been traveling all over the world. But I don't know if they went all the way [smiling:] over there.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>2000-0927 Public Program, Day 2, Hall, Holland Park School, Airlie Gardens, Campden Hill Rd, London W8 7AF, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis.</font> Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Macchindranāth, an Incarnation of Dattātreya, the Primordial Master, started {\it Nāth Pāntha}.</font> There were some very feared gurus ({\it Avadhūtas}) of this cult even decades later. Its deterioration started, though, when tāntrikas imposed themselves as gurus, and took over the cult in many places. These fake gurus were criticized by the great Saint Kabīr Dās in His poems."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7: Haṭha Yoga and Rāja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In this Void is placed the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) formed from Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva). This Primordial Master is also known as Dattātreya. <font color="DarkRed">He has taken many human births as a Prophet and teacher, such as Rāja Janaka, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, Guru Nāṇaka, and Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.</font> This Deity helps human beings to seek their salvation by crossing the Void or Ocean of Illusion within themselves."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Ramadas Swami" /><category term="hotpink @ Angels" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA["Macchinder Nath an incarnation of Primordial Guru started Nath Pantha. Even after some decades these were very few real Gurus (Avadhuta[s)] left in this cult. The deterioration started. Tankrikas [tantrikas] who imposed themselves as Gurus took charge of the cult in Many places." 1902-0000 Handwritten Note on Haṭha Yoga related to The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 7]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ ĀDINĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0317" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ ĀDINĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri%20Adinath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0317"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Likewise Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], who came before Māhavīr, was also an Incarnation of Dattātreya."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Dattātreya is the innocence of all these Three Powers.<br />
And this Guru uh was the One whose ... who then had a big tradition of Gurus.<br />
In the same tradition, we had many Gurus in our country. And, specially, in the area near Bombay [Mumbai], which is called as Maharashtra, they came as Nāth. They are, they were called as Nāth.<br />
<font color="red">So the first one was Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], then ahh Dattātreya, then Macchindranāth, then Gorakhnāth, like that a tradition of these Gurus came.</font><br />
But all their knowledge was kept as a guarded secret. It was a Gupta Vidyā. Is absolutely guarded secret: secret knowledge about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
They never talked about it, they never told about it. Because they thought: that, 'Just now, let us experiment with it fully, and then we will give some idea about it to people.' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Like Muhammad Sāhab and all these Gurus, all these Great Incarnations of the Primordial Master who was Ādi Dattātreya, Ādinātha, They taught you how to maintain your religion, your sustainance [sustenance], your balance."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0616 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Bala Kanayson's House, Rosemary Road, Tamworth (31 kms NE of Birmingham), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"For example, we can say the gree... green thing is the one that represents the water, water element. This center the ... in the stomach is the water element within us. It is called as Nābhī chakra, and around it is called as the Bhavasāgara, you can say the Void, or you can say the Gap, or whatever you may say, the whole world as such, within us. So, the people who were born on this center, around this center, were born out of water element.<br />
<font color="red">In this Bhavasāgara -- oc... Bhavasāgara means the ocean of this world -- were born, through this ocean of the world, were born all the Primordial Masters, one after another. We can say Abraham, Moses, we had Janaka, were Ādināth, and Socrates, and so many others like that, Nāṇaka, and also very recently, we had about hundred years back, a very great Saint born in India known as Sāī Nāth.<br />
They all represent the same element that is the water element. Being responsible or being born out of that, They are anxious to maintain water element as the one which is within us for sustaining ourselves. We su... we are sustained by water, so They help us to sustain ourselves. They are the sustainers: They tell us how to sustain us as a human being.<br />
And all of Them have tried to establish religion within us.</font><br />
A religion doesn't mean outside, but the religion as a man: means the capacity of a man, or you can say the quality of a man. What a human being should be like, what is the way to know if he is a human being or not, which is described in al... in the Ten Commandments."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0421 Public Program, What Is Second Birth, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To normalize you, all these Great Saints were born on this Earth, in this Void of the Big Primordial Being. And they exist within us, though they are not awakened as yet.<br />
We have had mainly Ten of Them. <font color="red">In India, we can call Them, from a very long time, as Ādināth, who was thousands of year[s] back.</font> I have told you Socrates, Moses, Abraham, then Rāja Janaka. Then we had, later on, Muhammad Sāhab, then Nāṇaka. Then the last, one of Them, was Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. He was another Primordial Master, a great man.<br />
They are the Incarnations of the One Personality! They said the same thing and same thing and same thing: how to sustain yourself. Their job was not to give you Realization, but to sustain you: to make you capable of your Realization, to make you a proper recipient of God's blessings as realized Souls."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0613 Public Program, Something within Us which Makes Us Seek Something Beyond, Stratford, East London, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, all the Gurus, all the Gurus who came, say from ... we can start from Socrates, then Abraham, Moses, this is the Guru Tattwa, is the Principle of Master, Primordial Masters. The Principle is born again and again.<br />
<font color="red">In India we can say the Ādināth, we had one Ādināth, the Guru long time back.</font> Then we had Dattātreya, we had uh Janaka, Nāṇaka, Sāī Nāth.<br />
We had in the Middle East Muhammad Sāhab, Lao Tze in China, Confucius.<br />
All these Great Principles of Gurus who were born, They had one job to do is to establish your dharma. Their job was not to give you Realization."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0728 Public Program, The Principle of Guru (Moderation Is the Way We Really Solve the Problem and The Innocence Is in the Center), Sea is the Guru (The Sea Is to Be Worshiped and So Much to Learn from the Sea) and Your Dharma Is the Way Your Attention Is (Dharma Is Balancing), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But with you I have to request you to think about it and to put your attention to it. And you'll be amazed, when you will know about it, that how much a chastity of a woman is important and graceful and energy-giving to her and to the whole society, to her own brother, to her own father, mother and everyone, to her children, because she is the one, really, who is the śhakti. And if she starts frittering away her śhakti like this, then the śhakti of the whole community, the whole country disappears.<br />
<font color="red">And that is why all the Gurus, right from Ādināth, or you can say Ādi Guru, up to, you can say, Moses and [A]braham and Muhammad Sāhab and all these people, have been so particular on this poaint ... point that even Muhammad Sāhab said, "Supposing there are too many women, then you can marry four times."</font> Doesn't mean that every Muslim should marry. But it was [laughing:] meaning that there were too many women on those days, so He said, "All right, but marry them!" "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0826 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Rakṣhābandhan Day), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Sahaja Yoga today is the Last Judgment. Today. Sahaja Yoga is spontaneous, as always Realization has been spontaneous, whether in the time of Ādināth, of Buddha, of Christ. [Sahaja Yoga aujourd'hui est le Jugement Dernier. Aujourd'hui. Sahaja Yoga est spontané, comme toujours la Réalisation a été spontanée, que ce soit au temps d'Ādināth, de Bouddha, du Christ.]"</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0507 Interview with Michel Sadashiva Cherney for the Sahaja Yoga Magazaine in French L'Attention, Issue 4, Pages 32 to 37, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And that is what is dharma: is the ten valences within us. These ten valances are nothing but dharma, which was preached by all the Great Saints. <font color="red">We can start it from Ādināth, we can say Lao Tze, we can say Confucius, we can say Zoroaster, we can say Muhammad Sāhab, we can say Nāṇak Sāhab, we can say Janaka, we can say the, all of Them are the representation or manifestation of Dattātreya, which we know very well in Maharashtra what is Dattātreya.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-1205 Public Program (English+Marathi), Day 2, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Here [turning and pointing towards the Chakra Chart:] the Guru Tattwa is expressed in the Void, there, where the Ten Gurus actually incarnated basically and they re-incarnated. <font color="red">Say we can start uh-uh from Ādināth.</font> Then we can come to ... other ones, uh-uh-uh ... like Nāṇaka, Janaka. Janaka was-ss much earlier. Then we can say Abraham, Moses-s-s. All these were Guru Tattwa, Socrates. All these were Guru Tattwa people: the people who came as Prophets. The ones who came on this Earth to teach us balance, to teach us the Code of Life.<br />
That was also important part. But that was forgot[ten]!<br /> 
'Why? Why the code? Why the religion?' Religion is for the ascent, to build you up."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1128 Public Program (Śhrī William Blake's Birthday), Building the New Jerusalem, Hammersmith Town Hall, 1 Riverside Gardens, Hammersmith, London W6 9LE, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">The authority with which Moses talked, authority with which Socrates talked, authority with which Lao Tze talked ... All these great Ādi Gurus, from Ādināth to Sāī Nāth, They didn't say, 'If you do this way will be good,' or, 'That way would be good.' No! "This is what it is, you better do it!"</font><br />
This is what it is!"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0706 Guru Pūjā, Cosmic Consciousness, Hall, Kongresshaus Toscana, Toscanapark und Ruhe, Johann Orth-Allee 23, Gmunden (75 kms E of Salzburg), Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As we had very great people ... uh ... on this Earth, I have given you the names, as we said there are, there have been Ten Gurus, uh ... starting from Ādināth, we had Confucius, we had Socrates, and later on we had Abraham, Moses and also up to Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, we had about Ten Great Gurus, now we have so many here sitting down. They are all gurus, and They have to behave like gurus and They have to the ... do the job of Great Gurus."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0731 Guru Pūjā, The First Principle of the Guru Is the Gravity (First Thing and Foremost Thing Is that We Must Have Gravity in Temperament and Value System of a Balance and You Have to Become the Fruits of Sahaja Yoga), Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"And in the stomach, in the Void as you say, are the all the Guru Tattwa where all the Great Gurus uh-uh from Ādināth, Muhammad Sāhab and others up to, we can say, Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, all of Them are the Guru Principle which we worshiped last time when we were in Andorra."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0806 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, The Witness State (Taṭasth), Lawn, Āśhram, Garlate (40 kms E of Como), Italy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">[We had many Yogis who started work on the middle path of human ascent like Gorakhnāth, Ādināth, Macchindranāth. They worked on the problem of human beings and how to make this ascent possible. They discovered in human beings in the triangular bone sacrum a residual power.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-1018 Public Talk, 1st World Conference on Yoga Organized by the Soviet Ministry of Health, Moscow University, Moscow, Russia (other date 1019)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"This, the central path was for, actually, redemption and for awakening the Kuṇḍalinī, which was done by mostly the Nāth Pānthis, like Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, Ādināth, these people did it."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0212 Public Program, Day 1, Chowdia Memorial Hall, Town Hall, Bengaluru, Karnataka, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In the early days-s-s, thousands of years back, all over the world there were realized Souls. You can start right from Abraham, to Moses, to Confucius. <font color="red">In India there were many great Saints: Ādināth, from that, Nāth Pānthis they were called as.</font><br />
Their job was just to give awakening to people."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0315 Public Program, Department of Religious Studies, University, Sydney, New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Then ... then of course, of course after Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, who took the lead was Christ. And He started talking about spirituality.<br />
Even, you will be surprised, that Abraham or Moses did not talk of spirituality. They talked of God, but not of spirituality.<br />
Till Christ came, nobody said that, "You are to be born-again," even in the ... on the other side of the world. Only Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa said this thing.<br />
Śhrī Rāma was taught by His guru: that, 'He should be born-again.' In the sense that: what is the Kuṇḍalinī and all that. Not that He should be born-again, but He ... He had become a human being, as I told you. So he taught Him about Kuṇḍalinī, he told Him about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
<font color="red">But it was a very secret science, followed by only very ... Nāth Pānthis we call them, is the Ādināth and all that.</font> Very few people were given Realization.<br />
In Rāma's time just we know upon Nachiketa. And His father-in-law was a realized Soul."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-0819 Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Hallowtree Scout Campsite, Nacton, Ipswich IP10 0JP, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, the tradition is, that: we had a group, we should say, we called them as Nāth Pānthis, in India, who were working on the central path, which is called as Suṣhumṇā. But the tradition was that only one guru c[o]uld have only one disciple. That was the tradition, for ages together. <font color="red">And the we had this-s Gorakhnāth, and you must have heard about the Macchindranāth, Gorakhnāth, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], all these people.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0413 Public Program, National Press Club, Canberra, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I didn't tell you about the third kind of movement we had in our country, is of Nāth Pānthis.<br />
<font color="red">Jains have Ādināth, and a deviation started from that: ah ... one guru was supposed to give knowledge to only one person.</font> Like Janaka had only Nachiketa.<br />
Till the time of Gyāneśhwara, that's in the twelfth century.<br />
Gyāneśhwara was the disciple of His own brother, Nivṛuttināth. And They suffered a lot. And He asked Nivṛuttināth for one permission: that, "Let Me open the Truth to the public. Just I'll tell about it! I'll not do anything, I'll just tell about it."<br />
Because thirteen, fourteen thousand years back Mārkaṇḍeya has described about Kuṇḍalinī. Then came ... Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has described about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
But all in Sanskrit language. And Sanskrital knowledge was not available to the common public. And those who knew Sanskrit nalguage ... language didn't want to get into Self-knowledge.<br />
Thus this knowledge was kept a secret all the time."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1206 Public Program, Day 1, Narada Gana Sabha, 254 Mowbrays Road, Alwarpet, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"But in the center we had another great movement which is called as Nāth, Nāth Pānthis. They say it came from Śhiva, but whatever it is: it came from Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], and these people, and got diverted into many types."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0628 Public Program, Myths Are Unreal, Royal Albert Hall, Kensington Gore, London SW7, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Maheśha (Śhiva), Viṣhṇu and Brahmadeva form the Trinity which incarnated as one teacher God, the Primordial Master, Dattātreya. He came onto this Earth to teach people the secrets of the Divine, to reveal God, and to help them cross the Ocean of Illusion themselves within their own identity. Evolution could not go further in the hands of human beings who were in the bondage of ignorance, so they were given guidance through this Incarnation of the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) again and again in different lives. He was created as the three-headed child, Dattātreya, by Ādi Śhakti who appeared on Earth during the Tretā Yuga as Satī Anasūyā, wife of the Sage Atreya. <font color="red">He was born as Ādināth who founded Jainism -- one of the oldest religions.</font> Then he was born as Rāja Janaka, father of Jānakī also called Sītā, Rāma's wife. She was an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti.<br />
The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis. Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Pages 32 and 33</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In this Void is placed the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) formed from Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva). This Primordial Master is also known as Dattātreya. <font color="red">He has taken many human births as a Prophet and teacher, such as Rāja Janaka, Ādināth, Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, Guru Nāṇaka, and Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.</font> This Deity helps human beings to seek their salvation by crossing the Void or Ocean of Illusion within themselves."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings, Pages 124 and 125</b></font>
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Adinath" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Adi Guru" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ RĀMADĀS SWĀMĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0224" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ RĀMADĀS SWĀMĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Ramadas_Swami</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0224"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
[And he was given full freedom. He was given the ego and superego. In his ego he started behaving in whatever way he liked. <font color="DarkRed">In order to control him, several Saints like Sant Jñāneśhwar, Sant Tukārām, Sant Rāmadās, Sant Eknāth, etc., by their behavior tried to show him several ways of turning his attention towards God.</font> Ṛiṣhis and Munis, through their austerities, tried to show him the way to God. The Saints wrote several books explaining to man their experiences, but all these people were unable to make others experience what they had experienced.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1900-0000 The Story of Creation (Marathi), House of Śhrī Mātājī, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Afterwards in sixteenth century there have been many Saints in Maharashtra like Śhrī Rāmadāsjī, who was the Guru of Śhivajī Mahārāj. Someone questioned Him, 'How Kuṇḍalinī awakens?' On this His response was, "It happens spontaneously. But there has to be a deserving receiver [disciple] and an able Granter [Guru]." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1907-0000 Interview (Hindi) with a Lady for a TV Program Directed by Ashok Agarwal, Ardhamātrā Volume 2, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"It was said about Guru Rāmadās Swāmī that make only such a person your guru who himself is Paras [touchstone], and who just by touching others does not make them into gold but makes them elixir [touchstone]. He makes others like himself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-0715 Public Program (Hindi) (Guru Pūrṇimā), Sahaja Yoga a New Discovery, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other possible dates 1974-0704, 1975-0723, or 1976-0711)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"By Grace of Almighty few Great Saints have been there and they also wrote something. However, they did not publish anything themselves but later their scripts were published, for example Kabīr Dāsjī, Guru Nāṇak, Rāmadās Swāmī, Tukārām. In ancient times, we had Sage Vālmīki, Yog Vāsiṣhṭha and many other Saints."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0215 Public Program (Hindi+English), Day 2, Sat-chit-ānanda, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Rāmadās Swāmī has told that, "In this world there are some people whose name is paḍhat mūrkh [reading fool/stupid]." Padhat mūrkh means who keeps reading and reading and becomes great fool (mahāmūrkh), who Kabīr Dāsjī has called, "Padhī, padhī paṇḍit mūrkha bhaye" [by reading and reading a learned man can become stupid]."</font><br />
<br />
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Ramadas Swami said, "There are some people in this world who are called paḍhat mūrkh," those who read a lot and become idiots. The same thing poet Kabīr Dās said, "Padhī, padhī paṇḍit mūrkha bhaye" (a scholar who reads a lot becomes an idiot)."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0323 Public Program (Hindi), Prem Dharma (Dharma of Love), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But you think that, 'We will do something and show.' <font color="DarkRed">Rāmadās Swāmī has said, "Alpa dhāriṣhṭa paye." You want to do something, go ahead, do it.</font> Then when you stumble and fumble down, get hurt, then you blame God, that, 'We did so much effort, so much we called God, then why did this mistake happen?' Who had asked you to do so much effort?' It is better to sit in one place silently that to bang yourself here and there like a blind. And then put down your hand and come and tell Me, 'Mother, how could this happen?' "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0311 Public Program (English+Hindi), Day 2, Session 2 (evening), On Gāndhī and Collective Consciousness, Gāndhī Bhawan, Delhi University, North Campus, GC Narang Road, Timarpur, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Variant 1:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">Śhrī Rāmadās Swāmī has mentioned about the background of our real job. If you have read Dāsbodh, then there is no need to explain to you anything. He has explained everything and that is true."</font><br /> 
<b>Variant 2:</b><br />
<font color="DarkRed">"Śhrī Rāmadās has explained the background for our work. If you have read Dāsbodh, then we do not have to tell you anything. He has explained everything and that is the truth."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0922 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī and Śhrī Gaṇeśha Principle, Navarātri Celebrations (1st Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"After that Budhha came, Mahāvīr came. Nāṇak, Kabīr, all of these came. Great Saints, Hermits like Gyāneśha took birth in Maharashtra. There are several others Saints like Them such as Nāmadeo, Eknāth, Tukārām. <font color="DarkRed">Great Saint Rāmadās Swāmī was also one of Them.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Paḍhatamūrkh is a very sharp expression in our Marathi language. Rāmadās must have seen several educated idiots that is why He has referred to them as paḍhatamūrkh. With these paḍhatamūrkh it will not happen.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0115 Public Program (Marathi), Akurdi, Piṃparī Chiṃchavaḍa (18 kms NNW of Pune), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1230 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Tales of Śhivajī Mahārāj, Rāmdās Temple, Sātārā, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0104 Śhrī Gaṇeśha Pūjā, What Are You Here for, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"This needs to be found out, hence everyone has [been] told that, 'Everybody should find their own Spirit.' If one of them has told, then it should be described (varṇana). But whoever has become great, they have told us that, 'You need to find your own Spirit within. You should find your God within yourself.' <font color="DarkRed">This has been told by all Seers and Saints: Rāmadās has told this, before Him Mārkaṇḍeya has told this, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has told this, Christ has told this, Muhammad has told this, Buddha has told this, Mahāvīra has told this, everyone has told this, that, 'We need to find the Spirit within ourselves.'</font> "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0104 Public Talk (Marathi+English), Rotary Club, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0331 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Birthday Felicitations Program, Birla Matushri Sabhagar, New Marine Lines, Churchgate, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In India, there are many who believe in fasting, penance, etc., many of them only suffer from disease and nothing else.<br />
Jew don't believe in Christ because Christ said that, "I will suck all your sins in Me," which is true because when your Āgñyā chakra opens the sins are sucked out by Him. However, they will not believe in Christ.<br />
In addition, they believe that, 'Man should accept suffering to achieve God.' They think that, 'If a Saint is suffering then it is fine for he will get God.'<br />
We made Gyāneśhwar suffer. <font color="DarkRed">We did not follow Rāmadās Swāmī.</font> We troubled Tukārām. Similarly, in the case of Nāṇak, Kabīr Dās, [They] were troubled.<br />
To say you are a Saint, you cannot get angry. [<font color="orange">unclear</font>]. As if we are entitled to all the anger and they are supposed to accept and suffer everything."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0504 Public Program (Hindi), Sane Gurujī Vidyālaya (English Medium) School, Bhikoba Waman Pathare Mārg, Near Dadar Catering College, Shivaji Park, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>{1983-1101 Public Program, What Is the Purpose of Our Life, Hampstead Town Hall Centre, 213 Haverstock Hill, London NW3 4QP, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-1105 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Diwālī Pāḍavā), Money, Sleep, Bhūts, Lethargy, Bonfire Night and Sitar Recital by Debu Chaudhuri, Āśhram, 102 Ditton Road, Surbiton, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0213 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, What Is Expected of Sahaja Yogis and Where Are We, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="DarkRed">Only Swāmī Rāmadāsa did not do Prapañcha. But in [His Marathi book] Dāsbodha, Prapañcha is flowing in every page. "Leaving Prapañcha, you cannot find God." He said this many times.</font><br />
To find God by leaving Prapañcha has been the imagination of people of our country since ancient times.<br />
......<br />
But I tell you that Maharashtra's background is very great.<br />
They forget everything and don't study or understand. Now, how much knowledge of music they have in Maharashtra. There is lot of literature of Saints in Marathi language. But who reads such books now?<br />
They purchase dirty books from the street and read. Very superficial things ... not going deeper but floating on top. This is the condition of Yuva [young] generation.<br />
If it continues then they all will be lost. They will become useless.<br />
Ask Me! I went to America and there are sixty-five percent jobless people. There they are afraid of a disease called AIDS. All young generation is dying and can't understand how to escape from it.<br />
Its reason is, 'What's wrong?' <font color="DarkRed">'There might have been Saint Rāmadāsa, what are we going to do with Him? Keep this all with you, we are becoming modern now.'</font><br />
This stupid modernity! Where those modern Americans are going? You go to those countries once, what is the condition of those modern people?<br />
The writers here keep writing about those countries sitting here. Go there and see what's happening in those modern countries!<br />
The elders there keep thinking day and night that how to commit suicide. They have only one thought and that is suicide. This is the only way left with them."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-1126 Public Program (Marathi), Prapañcha and Sahaja Yoga, Dr. Antonio De Silva High School, Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"All the renowned Saints have written about this knowledge in all the known Scriptures of the world. <font color="DarkRed">If you read what Rāmdās Swāmī has written that, "Nothing you will gain by reading something over and again."</font> Our very famous Kabīr Dās has written, "Padhī, padhī paṇḍit mūrkha bhaye." He has written it so clearly. Many more things are written by these Saints so clearly."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-1204 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">[Śhrī Mātājī explains about Samartha Rāmdās. Rāmdās was an Incarnation of Śhrī Hanumān and She explains how He looked and what He used to do. She says He was short in height and had a powerful personality. He had a long beard, a very strong appearance and a kamaṇḍalu -- water pot (ewer). He was a strong saintly person.] This is the real Guru [of Śhivajī Mahārāj], not that fake one.<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī explains that Rāmdās was Hanumān, and Hanumān took his birth at An̄janerī, a place near Trimbakeśhwar in Maharashtra, and She visited that place. Śhrī Mātājī explains that near there is where Śhrī Hanumān fell when he tried to catch the Sun.]</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-011x Quote, Talk to New People, House of Saundankars, Nasik, Maharashtra, India (other month 12)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0129 Pūjā (English+Marathi), Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India}\label{1985-0129 Pūjā (English+Marathi), Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0207 Pūjā, The Culture of Universal Religion, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0208 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, during the Evening Program after Marriages, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Rāmdās Swāmī was Himself a Brahmin but a type, if Māravāṛi were there who were Kṣhatriyas. But He said Marāṭhā to Himself because Marāṭhā is 'one who knows God'. He said, "Such a brave person is one who knows his own religion."</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Swāmī Rāmdās has said in Marathi,</font> "[<font color="orange">unclear</font>]," <font color="DarkRed">that if you see anything from the corner of your eyes, you cannot see any man."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0215 Public Program (English+Hindi), Day 4, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0603 Public Program, Day 1, The Bayard Rustin High School for the Humanities, 351 W 18th Street, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0704 Interview with Theologian Dr. Reender Kranenborg for 'Trouw' ('Fidelity') Newspaper, Conferentieoord Overvoorde, van Vredenburchweg 170, Rijswijk (6 kms SSE of The Hague), Netherlands</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0920 Public Program, Memorial Hall, City Hall, Sheffield, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0921 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The English are Scholars, Seminar, Totley Hall Training College, Sheffield, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1217 Pūjā (English+Marathi+English), Right Type of Conduct and The Establishment of Our Dharma Is Very Important, House of Dr. Ramesh Adinath Saṃghavī, B.N-1, Sapt Shrung, Krishnanagar Housing Society, Saharanpur Road, Nasik, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">" "Yeṛyā gabāḷyāche kāma nohe" [Śhivacharitramālā bhāga 25 of Tukārām: It is not the work of the mediocres/lousy], specially in this Sātārā district, where our very great Śhrī Rāmadās Swāmī stayed.<br />
And if you take any of His sentences, these are the absolute descriptions of God Almighty. He has written such stories and descriptions, through which He scolds the low level people. This was something only He could accomplish. We consider Him [as] Śhrī Hanumān. We consider Him at the highest level but in our Maharashtra whatever we hear is not enough.</font><br />
There we call this a saintly place where great saints were born. Great people have enlightened this nation, that is really Maharashtra, there is no doubt about this. Although now we have made it muddy, that's another thing, but this is really Maharashtra."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1226 Public Program (Marathi), Parameśhwara Chā Gaurav (The Pride of God), Sātārā, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0120 Public Program, Day 1, Attention Should Be on God, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Here many marketers also used to go to war. But these marketers won't be able to walk in the battle of Sahaja Yoga.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">As Rāmadās Swāmī has said, "Tyala pahijet jātīche." It needs the one who is strong! It's the work of the brave. This is not the work of fools, weak and egoists. This should be understood.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0223 Public Program (Hindi), Day 4, Dharm kī Āvaśhyakatā aur Ātma kī Prāpti (The Need of Religion and the Realization of the Spirit), Sir Shankarlal Concert Hall, Modern School, Bara Khamba Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Śhivajī Mahārāj was a self-realized personality. According to Me, he was pure Indian. He said that, "One should know the meaning of freedom."<br />
<font color="DarkRed">His Guru was Śhrī Rāmadās Swāmī. He had told Śhrī Śhivajī Mahārāj that, "Till the time we all realize our duties and responsibilities towards our country, we cannot enrich our country. We are unable to understand our duties and discharge them properly."</font> This is so in respect of all nations and countries."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0401 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Ghanaśhyām das Birla Sabhaghar, 29 Ashutosh Choudhry Avenue, Near Birla Mandir, Ballygunge, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Śhivajī Mahārāj, who was a realized Soul, who was a true Indian, said that, "One needs to understand the inner working of the soul and the Spirit."<br />
<font color="DarkRed">His Guru, Śhrī Rāmadās, said to him that, "Unless and until the Innate Religion is not established in this country, till then this country won't be benevolent." </font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1011 Public Program (Hindi) (8th Day of Navarātri), Sahajyog ke Anubhav (Experience of Sahaja Yoga), Ice Skating Ring, Kolkata, West Bengal, India (place and date not sure)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Once Śhrī Śhivajī Mahārāj asked Śhrī Rāmadās Swāmī, "How much time does it take for the awakening of the Kuṇḍalinī?" He said, "That moment, in that moment it happens." "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1013 Public Program (Hindi), Ice Skating Ring, Kolkata, West Bengal, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1104 Public Program (English+Hindi), Balance is for Ascent and Everything Emerges into the Ocean of Love of God (Dharma Is only of One Viśhwa Dharm Paramātma and that Dharma Is to Achieve God), Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1227 Pūjā (English+Marathi), by the Kṛiṣhṇa's River, Pandal, Brahmapuri, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Seeing the work of Sahaja Yoga in Sātārā district, I am feeling extremely joyous. It has also been a very great work of establishing fifteen centers in Sātārā district.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">This is the land of Śhrī Rāmdās, who was the Incarnation of Śhrī Hanumān. The fruits of His flowerlike work are seen now in the fact that there are fifteen centers over here.</font><br />
......<br />
Also, all the Saints have talked against the people who take money from you and misguide you in the name of God. They have even used abuses at times to describe what exactly these people are.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Saint Rāmdās says, "Mahisha mardila chandane tyala pujite." This means that some people brought a buffalo, rubbed chandan [sandalwood powder] over it and started doing Pūjā to it as it was covered with chandan. He has said so clearly about the level of blind faith in our country and how we fall prey to it. If one person goes then another is ready to take his place.</font><br />
Without Sahaja Yoga, you won't recognize who is true and who is false."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1229 Public Program (Marathi), Art, Commerce, and Science, Rahimatpur (22 kms SE of Sātārā), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Hence whatever first we need to tell people, it should be explained in their language, in their way.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Secondly, as we have the guidance of Nāmdeo [Nāmadev], Tukārām, Gora Kumbhar, Janābāi, Muktābāī, Dyaneśhwar and Rāmadās, after reading their books we should examine what all is written in the poetic verses written in those books. Means what they have written about the people engrossed in the misconceptions and who fast and perform religious ceremonies.</font><br />
Dyaneśhwa Himself has clearly written in His book Amṛutānubhav that after reading His book, one should simply contemplate and think, 'What this is all about?', not merely continue reading. You will be surprised that He has stipulated in it more clearly what I am emphasizing.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Rāmadās Swāmī and Tukārām have sweared at such people severely, still these vagabonds [are] misguiding others.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-1231 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (Marathi+English), Sangli, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Ramadas Swami" /><category term="hotpink @ Angels" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ NĀṆAKĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0212" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ NĀṆAKĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Nanaki</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0212"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"The Nāṇakī of Guru Nāṇaka was none else but Jānakī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Muhammad Sāhab was the same, Dattātreya's Incarnation, and the same Incarnation was King Janaka. The same Incarnation was Nāṇaka, whose sister Nāṇakī, was the same Ādi Śhakti. She was Sītājī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"He was born as Nāṇaka. And Nāṇakī was nobody else but Jānakī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0205 Public Program (Vasant Pañchamī), Day 2, Description of Kuṇḍalinī, after Śhrī Viṣhnu Havan, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"So we have to understand that if we are committing this kind of foolish thing, also can be forgiven by God because He is the Ocean of Forgiveness. She is Guru Nāṇakī. She is Dayā Sāgar [Ocean of Compassion]. He has to do it because He has to complete His creation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0328 Public Address, Inauguration of The Advent (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 5--12</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Is ʿAlī.<br />
And His wife, that was later on, His wife was also the same Mahālakṣhmī personified: the daughter of Nārāyaṇa [Muhammad]. She incarnated also like that.<br />
So the, in the main, They are worshiped as three persons in India, as I told you: as first as Sītā, and then as Rādhā, and then as Mary. In ... in India, Mary, Female, is worshiped also, three, three persons.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">But, otherwise, She incar-nated as Fāṭimah. And She also uh ... incarnated as Nāṇaka's sister, as Nāṇakī.<br />
But because They were at a potential level, They were potential at that time, so, people do not know much about Them.</font><br />
Even Mary was potential energy: She was not kinetic."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-1029 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Creation, Original Sin, and Incarnations, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Leukemia comes from left Nābhī, when your Gṛuhalakṣhmī is ruined.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">The Deity of Gṛuhalakṣhmī is Fāṭimah Bi, the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab. While the daughter of ... the sister of Nāṇak Sāhab is on the left Nā... left Viśhuddhi. You'll see that. Nāṇakī.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0131 Public Program, Day 2, The Nābhī Chakra, N.D.M.C. Park, Hanumān Road, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Also, at the time of the Prophets, Mahālakṣhmī incarnates as a pure relationship with Them. Like Rāja Janaka's daughter was Jānakī, means Sītā, uh uh uh ... then She came on this Earth as the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab, and then She came on this Earth as Nāṇakī, the sister of Nāṇaka. So, She ... She resides as a pure relationship of these Gurus.<br />
Thus, the Mahālakṣhmī's greatest ... greatness is that: through Her Power only the Suṣhumṇā is covered by Kuṇḍalinī. She is the power of our evolution. And by Her Power only, we have risen to be human beings, and by Her Son's Power, we are going to become higher people.<br />
Thus the importance of Mahālakṣhmī is very great for all the Sahaja Yogis. Because She guides our Viṣhṇu Tattwa to its culmination, to its completion, which is the Principle of our Evolution. Thus She is a Giver of Dharma, She gives us the dharma, and She is the Giver of the Truth. She's the One who relates us to our brain. The whole brain's system is Mahālakṣhmī's system. So, it is She who exposes the whole of the knowledge as truth to us, on our central nervous system.<br />
But at the State of Virāṭa, when Śhrī Kṛiṣh... uh ... when Viṣhṇu becomes the Virāṭa, the Great Primordial Being, then She is called as Virāṭaṅganā, as His Power.<br />
So these are the Incarnations, of Mahālakṣhmī, about which I have told you."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0908 Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Münich, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In no Incarnation a male has come without a female. Christ came, He had His Mother. When Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came, He had to have Rādhā. When Rāma came, Sītā was there. <font color="DarkRed">When Nāṇaka came, there had to be Nāṇakī.</font> When Janaka came, He had to have Jānakī, as His daughter. When Muhammad Sāhab came, He had to have His daughter, Fāṭimah. They could not do without the Power because they are just the kinetic energy.<br />
But when the Goddess came, She came alone. Because She has a Power to contain within Herself all the Powers."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0601 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Role of Women in America, Tent, Backyard, House of Judy Gaddy, 442 Liberty Road, Englewood, NJ, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now this sisterly relationship existed in other Incarnations also. Like Muhammad Sāhab had a sisterly relationship ... uh-uh-uh ... with, actually, what we have to say, that: His sister as such was ʿAlī's wife, but She was born to Him as a daughter.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">So, They can be born as a daughter or as the sister. She was born as Nāṇaka's sister, Nāṇakī. She was born as the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab. So, it could be a sister or could be the daughter of an Incarnation.</font><br />
But daughter and sister are innocent, pure chastity.<br />
Now think of it: that those people who cannot understand the importance of chastity, how can they talk of any laws whatsoever? Because laws means maryādās. And it has the proper sense through the Power of Viṣhṇumāyā."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0901 Śhrī Viṣhṇumāyā Pūjā, Southlands College, University of Roehampton, Wimbledon, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So when we read about the Devī, about Her Incarnations -- how She came on this Earth to save Her bhaktas, people who were trying to ascend, to cross this Bhavasāgara, how She worked hard, how She fought the devils, how She cough... She killed the demons, single-handed -- She took upon Herself the responsibility of making the people cross the Bhavasāgara.<br />
Guru gave you the strength to have dharma but She is the One who brought you out. Even those who were dhārmik could not do it because of the demonic pressure. She's the One who fought, single-handed, with Her Powers of destruction. In Her Love for you She fought. She brought you to this level.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">And then She took a milder form of Incarnation. Even during the time of all the Gurus, She took the Form of, as you know: Jānakī was the daughter of Janaka, then Fāṭimah was the daughter of Muhammad Sāhab, and Nāṇakī was the sister of Nāṇaka. In those Forms, these Powers s... sustained and nourished the Guru Tattwa. And later on, or sometimes simultaneously, They incarn-ated in milder forms to help human beings to rise.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1019 Navarātri Pūjā (cusp between the 6th Day and 7th Day), Complete Dedication, Gymnasium, Weggis (19 kms E of Luzern on Luzern Lake), Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Now let us see how many Incarnations we've had of Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī. Firstly, the Principle of Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī is very close with a Guru ... a relation of plenty of love and purity. Now if we see from the beginning with all the Ādi Gurus, She was born to them as a daughter or as a sister. Like the daughter of Janaka was Śhrī Sītā: She was the form of Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī, was the Principle of Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī. Sītā was Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī, and She was the daughter of Janaka. Then the sister of Śhrī Nāṇaka, Nāṇakī, She was Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī. Her relation was of sister. In the same way, the daughter of Muhammad Sāhib, Fāṭimah, She was Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī. After Her, Rādhā: Rādhā was the form of Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī. After Her, Mary: Mary was Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī, and Her relation was of purity. She was so pure that with Her purity She gave birth to Śhrī Christ. So She was a form of complete pure Virgin. And as She was a form of Virgin, because of Her purity She got a Son pure as Christ. So She was also Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1986-0106 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Marathi+English), Ascent Is the Main Attention, Sangli, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā)."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Nanaki" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Mahalakshmi" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ GUĀNYĪN in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0203" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ GUĀNYĪN in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-02-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri_Guanyin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0203"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"While they searched back into the history of China, and they found out: the Ādi Śhakti lived many years back there as Quānyīn [Guānyīn]. And that's how Quānyīn [Guānyīn] was established as a Goddess for many Buddhist[s]."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0526 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, Brighton Center, Brighton, East Sussex, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> The Goddess Kuan Yen [Guānyīn], Śhrī Mātājī, ...<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Yes.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> ... can You tell us something about it [Her]?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed"> Kuan Yin [Guānyīn]?</font><br />
<b>Another Sahaja Yogi:</b> Kuan Yin [Guānyīn]!<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Yes? You want to know about Her?<br />
That's an Incarnation of one of the ... yuh ... I mean in the Chinese mythology you find the Incarnation described of Kuan Yin [Guānyīn]. And actually, She is the One, who is the Vṛuddhā, is described as Vṛuddhā, She is the One, is the Aged One. Uh-uh-uh because uh Kuan Yin [Guānyīn] was born to a king. She was the daughter of a king. And She was the Virgin Form of the Goddess, and She would not marry. So Her father got very angry with Her, that She is not marrying. And he threatened Her, because he had arranged Her ... His marri... uh marriage with some great king, you see. And when the marriage took pla... mariage did not take place, father was so angry and annoyed and felt very humiliated. So, he-ee took Her to a hillside and got ... said ... threatened [Her] that, "I will throw You down." And actually She was thrown down from the hillside into a valley, and he thought, 'She must have been dead.'<br />
But there was a tiger, which held Her, and he carried Her along, and then he looked after Her. And when She grew very old, quite old, then She came out of Her hermitage. And She started prea... treating people. And many people got cured by Her.<br />
But She was quite old, then the father recognized Her. Because father was sick. She went and treated the father also. And She started curing people.<br />
And that's the Kuan Yin [Guānyīn].<br />
Uh-uh-uh if you go to Hong Kong, you can see Her statue: the face is very much like Mine, absolutely. But She is older looking, and Her uh shoulders are bent, quite bent.<br />
But She came much before Christ.<br />
And the uh-uh-uh ... the Buddhist felt that, 'People wouldn't give Her up, because She was so much regarded as the Mother of Mercy.' So, they included Her in the Buddha uh-uh-uh thing.</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0502 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Nirānanda, Āśhram, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> We have Chinese also who are very wise. And the ... they are known to be people of deep understanding. But they are not like Indians.<br />
So, what is lacking in all these people is: the depth of awareness. <font color="DarkRed">Because-ss, though in China also Mother of Mercy came, and She really uh-uh-uh bestowed blessings upon them, and China rose also, afterwards, into her own glory and became quite a good industrial, I mean developed country, we can say, very powerful, but still, that kind of regimentation could not be borne. Because, after all, Mother Mercy was there.</font><br />
<font color="DarkRed"><font color="DarkRed">Do you know last -- you have one Mother Mercy to give ... you have given Me ...</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Ahh?<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Or Kuan Yin [Guānyīn], same thing. Kuan Yin [Guānyīn] -- and She's the same thing, called as Mother of Mercy.</font><br />
And the second one was given by Grégoire recently.<br />
And you see what's happening in China now.<br />
So the effects of these Deities which existed in different countries at different times, are felt only in Kali Yuga in the best way.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1989-0524 Śhrī Pallas Athena Pūjā, The Origins and Role of Greece, House of Stamatis Boudouris, Athens, Greece</b></font>
&lt;/p&gt;

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">" 'Mother, are You Kwun Yin [Guānyīn]?' "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1990-1110 Public Program, Day 3, Auditorium, Chientan Overseas Youth Activity Center, No. 16, Section 4, Zhongshan N Rd, Shilin District, Taipei City, Taiwan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> And Bodhisattva is the one when you are realized, you have found the Truth, you have to give it to the society, you have to give it to the public, you have to go all out to give it. That's Sahaja Yoga.<br />
So Buddhism, at that stage, was: achieving your Self, alone.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Oh, I see.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Or your little group.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Now, today, it is Bodhisattva.<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Because the Buddhists, a lot of them believed in the Goddess of Mercy, ...<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> What?<br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Goddess of Mercy, Quānyīn [Guānyīn].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Quānyīn [Guānyīn], they believed.</font><br /> 
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Yes, Goddess of Mercy.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">[In] Quānyīn [Guānyīn] they believed.</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Yes.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">She looks like Me very much.</font> [Laughter, smiles.]<br /> 
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> But I try to talk to them like that, and some of them, because of the barrier of uh races and nationality: "Oh, no, no, no! Look at this picture: is not!", and this and that. Is so hard to convince them.<br />
And my's ... my-my real desire, I like to talk to these people, especially in my area, there are lots of them are Quānyīns [Guānyīns].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">But you should say, 'Now, there is no Quānyīn [Guānyīn].'<br />
And when She lived, nobody recognized Her.<br />
Who, Her own father wanted to throw Her away. And a tiger came and saved Her. And She actually appeared on the scene when She was about, I think, ninety years She [was], something like that, very old.</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So, nothing much was done.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">But they could recognize that She was the Goddess.</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">Now She is no more.</font><br /> 
<b>Sahaja Yoginī:</b> History.<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> It's Me here. [Smiles.]<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0213 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Questions and Answers during Picnic, Black Mountain Peninsula, Canberra, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Also, Buddha has talked about it. <font color="DarkRed">Also, this Mother Mercy that they worship, Chinese, they too have, s... to describe about it, like Tao.</font> Like Tao has talked about it. Tao means Kuṇḍalinī! Can you s... imagine? Tao means Kuṇḍalinī. Zen system has talked about Kuṇḍalinī."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0426 Public Program, PJ Civic Hall, Jalan Yong Shook Lin, Pj New Town, 46200 Petaling Jaya, Selangor, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> <font color="DarkRed">But even before Buddha you had a tradition of the Mother Mercy. I do not know how far the Japanese accepted this, but in the eastern part of China and other places they worshiped Mother Mercy, Quānyīn [Guānyīn].<br />
I don't know if even Japanese worshiped Her or not. They did?</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> [<font color="orange">unclear</font>].<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> So, this is [has] come from ancient times."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0301 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Zen System or Sahaja Yoga is also Zen, before Public Program, Four Seasons Hotel, Tokyo, Japan</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"After Her Incarnation as Sītā She was born and lived in China as Kuan Yin [Guānyīn], the Mother of Mercy, as a virgin."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"In China they also worship Mother Mercy, Kuan Yin [Guānyīn], who was a Chinese Incarnation."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>
</font></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Guanyin" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Adi Shakti" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ SOPĀNDEV in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0127" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ SOPĀNDEV in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Shri%20Sopandev</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0127"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"Even Muhammad Sāhab has described His son-in-law in many ways. And He is the only One, or there's another Incarnation, of Brahmadeva, who came on this Earth, ʿAlī, came on this Earth. He was the Incarnation of Brahmadeva and His another Incarnation was Sopāndev, which ... you can go to Poona [Pune], you can see the temple of Sopāndev there."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0814 Śhrī Fāṭimah Pūjā, Saint-George (40 kms W of Lausanne), Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Sometimes I feel, all these Incarnations have created a chaos for Me. If they had not done all this nonsense with these ignorant people, it would have been a much better world, you know.<br />
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> So why did They come, Śhrī Mātājī?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Huh?
<b>Dr. Rustom Burjorjee:</b> Why did They come?<br />
<font color="DarkRed"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> They came to bring you to make the sopān [ladder] as this, what you call a, is the step by which you have to rise.<br />
But everybody seems to be completely disobeyed.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1994-0711 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, On Islam and Around a Letter from Ayatollah Dr. Mehdi Rouhani, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1 :</b>
I mean to say that the Sopānamārga, which is Suṣhumṇā Path, the central path, is the Path of Lord Viṣhṇu. Through this path we attain the Śhiva Tattwa. So Śhiva Tattwa is the destination and the Path is made by Lord Viṣhṇu.<br />
This central path is the creation of Lord Viṣhṇu and the Ādi Śhakti. Lord Śhiva has no role in it: He sits comfortably in His Seat, without bothering for anybody. If someone wishes to come, may come.<br />
To attain Śhiv Tattwa we should go through this Viṣhṇu Path and correct all the centers that are created on it. When the centers are cleansed, the Viṣhṇu Path opens up and our ascent begins.<br />
<br />
<b>Version 2 :</b>
"Meaning that the Sopānamārga which has been created, which we call as Suṣhumṇā nāḍī, which is central path, is the Path of Lord Viṣhṇu. And through this Path we attain the Śhiva Tattwa. So Śhiva Tattwa is the destination to Śhiva, and the Path is made by Lord Viṣhṇu.<br />
To create this Path, Viṣhṇujī and Ādi Śhakti have taken efforts. Lord Shiva has no role in it: He sits comfortably in His Seat, not bothering about anyone who comes or doesn't come.<br />
So, to attain this Śhiv Tattwa, we should go through this Viṣhṇu Path."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1999-0214 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi+English), Principle of Śhiva Is in Your Heart, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Sopandev" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Brahmadeva" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ NIVṚITTINĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0120" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ NIVṚITTINĀTH in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2023-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/QIT_Niv%E1%B9%9Bittin%C4%81th</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2023/0120"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I didn't tell you about the third kind of movement we had in our country, is of Nāth Pānthis.<br />
Jains have Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], and a deviation started from that: ah ... one guru was supposed to give knowledge to only one person. Like Janaka had only Nachiketa.<br />
Till the time of Gyāneśhwara, that's in the twelfth century.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Gyāneśhwara was the disciple of His own brother, Nivṛuttināth. And They suffered a lot. And He asked Nivṛuttināth for one permission: that, "Let Me open the Truth to the public. Just I'll tell about it! I'll not do anything, I'll just tell about it."</font><br />
Because thirteen, fourteen thousand years back Mārkaṇḍeya has described about Kuṇḍalinī. Then came ... Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya has described about Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
But all in Sanskrit language. And Sanskrital knowledge was not available to the common public. And those who knew Sanskrit nalguage ... language didn't want to get into Self-knowledge.<br />
Thus this knowledge was kept a secret all the time."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-1206 Public Program, Day 1, Narada Gana Sabha, 254 Mowbrays Road, Alwarpet, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"One master would have one disciple, chosen for this.<br />
Thus, it continued till the twelfth century, when a very great poet called Gyāneśhwara, He started ...<br />
[Aside:] It's all right. [Laughs.] It's all right. [Drinks water.]<br />
He started, in a way, writing about Gītā.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">He requested His brother, who was His Guru, Nivṛittināth, that, "Please allow Me to write about Kuṇḍalinī because in the Gītā it is not mentioned. We must write about it!" So He allowed.</font><br />
And He wrote it in the sixth chapter of that Gyāneśhwarī.<br />
But people said ... the people who were in charge of the religion, that time, said: "This chapter is something to be condemned." Because they didn't know how to awaken the Kuṇḍalinī. "This has to be absolutely condemned, and nobody should read this one." Niṣhiddha is the word, is not so bad as it's condemned, but niṣhiddha: is not to be read.<br />
Thus, all this knowledge, of the inner be-ing, was kept in the darkness. And this knowledge of the inner being, not known to us, created the problem."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1014 Public Program, Masur Auditorium, National Institute of Health, Clinical Center (Building 10), 9,000 Rockville Pike, Bethesda, MD, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">But in the twelfth century, Gyāneśhwara asked His Guru, who was His brother, Nivṛittināth. He asked Him: that, ``You just allow Me to write about this Kuṇḍalinī." Because He wrote Gyāneśhwarī. And in Gyāneśhwarī, He wanted to write about this Kuṇḍalinī, just to little talk about this secret power within us. His Guru allowed Him, and then He wrote it."</font>
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1016 Public Program (2nd Day of Navarātri), Auditorium, New York Society for Ethical Culture, 2 West 64 Street, Manhattan, New York City, NY, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="DarkRed">"But in the twelfth century, Gyāneśhwara took permission from His brother who was His Guru as well, that, ``Please allow Me to at least write about it! This much permission I need!" And when He wrote about it, in His book Gyāneśhwarī, in the sixth chapter, He has described beautifully that, ``Due to this Kuṇḍalinī only we achieve our enlightenment." He has stated it very clearly."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1203 Public Program (Hindi), Kidwai Nagar, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But in the center we had another great movement which is called as Nāth, Nāth Pānthis. They say it came from Śhiva, but whatever it is: it came from Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], and these people, and got diverted into many types.<br />
But those who remained in the middle, one of them was, we should say, was called Gahinināth. <font color="DarkRed">And his disciple was Nivṛuttināth, the elder brother of Gyānadeva.</font><br />
It is amazing, if you read anything about them, they know all about chakras, they know all about these, all three channels. Everything they new thousands of years back.<br />
Then somehow or other, they didn't tell people. They kept the knowledge to themselves.<br />
I can't say why they did it but they did.<br />
<font color="DarkRed">Ultimately, Gyānadeva took permission of His Guru, Nivṛittināth, and said that, "I, let Me tell you ... at least let Me tell others. You allow Me. Because people should know what works it out." So He wrote about Kuṇḍalinī.</font><br />
But if you read these ancient books, you will be amazed that the whole thing was described in those books: how you get your Realization, and how then we have those centers, which are to be enlightened, what problems come in.<br />
But the method they employed, [laughing:] for achieving it, was really hazardous again.<br />
I don't know why they had to do it but they did it.<br />
They were all unmarried people and very strict with themselves and they had to lead a life very secluded from the society.<br />
This was really a very difficult type of ascent they had.<br />
When I read about them I'm really is ... feel very, extremely sad, that all these great people who were seeking had to go through such horrible strenuous turmoil for days together, and then s-s-some of them got Realization."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0628 Public Program, Myths Are Unreal, Royal Albert Hall, Kensington Gore, London SW7, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Nivrittinath" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ ZOROASTER in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0714-d" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ ZOROASTER in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri_Zoroaster</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0714-d"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To make the people cross the Void (Bhavasāgara) He has to make some arrangement. So the Great Power like Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha was created and They were placed in the Area of Dharma.<br />
<font color="red">Dattātreya and Ādi Gurus incarnated in this world many a times. He incarnated as King Janaka who was like the father of Ādi Śhakti. After that He incarnated in Iran as Zoroaster, then as Macchindranāth, then as Muhammad Sāheb and Nāṇak Sāheb.</font><br />
No one fought with each other. See what type of darkness you are in?<br />
Fāṭimah, the daughter of Muhammad Sāheb was the same who became daughter of King Janaka.<br />
Whom are you fighting? Think over it.<br />
The Nāṇakī of Guru Nāṇaka was none else but Jānakī.<br />
Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth was also an Ādi Guru.<br />
<font color="red">They are the Masters of all.<br />
Also, They are My Gurus. These Ādi Gurus taught Me all this Knowledge. In different Incarnations They kept Me teaching.<br /> 
Ultimately I had to come and do His work. They could not do it and now They are placing Me as a Guru so that I take up the job of a Guru.<br />
There was an age when no one was willing to accept a woman as a Guru but in Kali Yuga only Mother could do His work: it is beyond the power of men.</font><br />
This work could not be done by force, only the love of a Mother could do it because already there is so much pressure, tension in this world. The day it is forced upon the human being they will break down. So, love is the only way out.<br />
So this Gurudom was given to Me. Everything is acceptable to Me.<br />
But I didn't know the qualities of a Guru.<br />
Gurus maintain distance but mother does not keep distance with the children. Children sit on her head.<br />
So, you people also could take liberty with Me and enjoy. Be with Me with full freedom, you will neither be afraid nor be embarrassed. There is no problem, you could come and talk to Me boldly about your problems. You could complain to Me as you do to your mother. I am freely available to you.<br />
Freedom was needed, religion was required to be discussed openly, there is no secret, no secret about it. Ultimately everything has to be explained very clearly. All the secrets are to be told about, everything could not be said everywhere."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But before reaching the Heart chakra, the gap I showed you, is all the Bhavasāgara. In the center is the seat of Śhrī Viṣhṇu, and on it Śhrī Brahmadeva creates the whole universe. He made this Bhavasāgara.<br />
After creating the Bhavasāgara, the question was, 'How to cross it over? The human being was created, but how to make him realize it? How to make human beings recognize it? In him, how to activate the Brahma Tattwa?' Meaning, 'How to get the Union of Śhiva and Śhakti within him? How would the connection be established?'<br />
For this, a special personality was created in this world. This was created by the combined essence of Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, and Maheśh, who we acknowledge as Śhrī Dattātreya. Śhrī Dattātreya is none other than Ādi Guru.<br />
He is My Guru. He has mentored Me all His past lives.<br />
If you hear about His birth and all His previous lives you would be amazed. We have forgotten such a great thing.<br />
Śhrī Dattātreya's Incarnations are numerous. Firstly He came as King Janaka. Śhrī Sītājī was His daughter, who was the embodiment of Śhakti Herself. <font color="red">Then He came as Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, and Muhammad Sāhab, who were a completely different type of human being.<br />
They trialed out lots of different things.</font><br /> 
Śhrī Datta, the Primordial Masters firstly in this world educated us about the symbolic forms within us. And then also said that, "You people got entangled in symbolism, in idol worshiping." Their meaning was to go beyond and recognize the Śhakti within these idols. That's why They talked about the idols.<br />
<font color="red">For example, there is a flower, and to describe the honey within the flower, They talked about the flower first, from which the people would taste the honey. But people got stuck to flower. So Then they took Incarnations and talked about the honey.<br />
In that, They talked about God in the abstract. They deliberately didn't talk about the reincarnation of life.</font><br />
Because as soon as you talk about past lives, people ask Me, "Mātājī, tell me about my past lives." The life that has passed, why do you want to know that? Whether you were a king or a pauper, what difference it will make?<br />
<font color="red">That's why They did not discuss past lives.</font><br />
Muhammad Sāhab was the same, Dattātreya's Incarnation, and the same Incarnation was King Janaka. The same Incarnation was Nāṇaka, whose sister Nāṇakī, was the same Ādi Śhakti. She was Sītājī."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1208 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The same Śhrī Dattā incarnated many a times on the Earth.<br />
As I told you yesterday, King Janaka was one of Them. King Janaka was the father of Jānakī [Śhrī Sītā]. He was none other than the Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya.<br />
Thereafter, Macchindranāth, most have you must have heard His name, was also His Incarnation.<br />
<font color="red">After that Zoroaster who came three times on the Earth, He was also His Incarnation.</font><br />
......<br /> 
<font color="red">They were all Muhammads, They were all Dattātreyas, who came on Earth regularly.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="red">The talk of seeking this Absolute Principle, residing just inside the heart, has been made since ancient times by these Ādi Gurus, who are incarnated on this Earth again and again."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But in some people that stability has to be brought about. No problem. You have obtained that thing, you recognized it, you reached there and there is a complete arrangement for bringing stability.<br />
<font color="red">As soon as that stability is achieved, in Absolute Peace and Joy, you achieve that Witness State described by Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, by Jesus, by all the Scriptures whether by Zoroaster, Socrates, Confucius or any of Dattātreya's Incarnations.</font><br />
Till today, these people who were of a higher state, who would take birth in a higher state, would talk in a manner that others were unable to understand. They could see matters of the tenth floor and others would remain on the first floor and they would just not understand what was being talked about."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Another thing is, here in Bhavasāgar, all Three, Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśhwar, combined to make a child, who is called Ādi Guru, is known as Dattātreya. There were many Incarnations of Him. And His Child Tattwa also took Incarnations. First was Dattātreya, then came Rāja Janak. <font color="red">Like this, many Incarnations came, Rāja Janak, Nāṇak, Zarathustra, Muhammad Sāhab, Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.<br />
They are all one. Are They or not?</font> You can witness it after Self-realization. If you believe in one Guru, like Nāṇak, then you have no right not to accept Muhammad Sāhab. If you get Muhammad Sāhab and not Nāṇak, then you have no authority as well.<br />
You will be surprised, most of the cancer disease comes from the imbalance of Bhavasāgar, you follow one but not the other. Cancer also comes when we don't follow Them.<br />
Like He forbade two things, like not to smoke a cigarette and not to consume alcohol.<br />
Alcohol is entirely not allowed. Here, in Sahaja Yoga, if someone is habituated to drink alcohol, they will leave it. If they don't leave alcohol, it will [not] be in moderation because both of these things go against Guru Tattwa.<br />
If Guru Tattwa is not established within us, we cannot have our evolution. Guru Tattwa is essential. Guru Tattwa is one destiny for all religions. There is one flow from all the religions."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-032x Public Program (Hindi), Day y, Advertised as 'Kuṇḍalinī Awakening', New Delhi, India (date to be confirmed)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"I wish all of you a very-very happy New Year today because it is Navroz, and Navroz is the day when Zartosht [Zoroaster in Urdu] started His work on this world. He was a great Sahaja Yogi. He was an Incarnation of Dattātreya Himself."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Road, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"This type of an organization [doubt] keeps going on. <font color="red">Even if it is the Age of Jesus Christ, even if it is the Age of Gyāneśhwarjī, even if it is the Age of Śhaṅkarāchārya, Age of Zartosht, these people who think of themselves as special and overly smart (ati śhahāṇe), think of themselves to be special type, think themselves as very high scholarly, have always been there and will be there.</font> They will all the time do these kind of true barricades (āḍ aṇge) and there are precious moments of life, those they will spend in this only. They don't have any treatment (ilāj). [<b>Variant:</b> <font color="red">A doubt of this type lingers on, whether it is during the period of Christ, Gyāneśhwar, Śhaṅkarāchārya or Zartosht.</font> Anytime! Those who think they are very helpful, special people, those who think they are scholars existed and will always be there. They will always create obstacles and spend priceless moments in such activity. There is no cure for it.]"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0323 Public Program (Hindi), Prem Dharma (Dharma of Love), Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So the dharma that has been established in us by God Almighty because if we want to go to the Kingdom of God, then in our freedom we must desire to get to God. If someone tries to pressurize us and says, 'You must ask for God,' then it is of no use, it is not an evaluation. That is why to reach in this state, a person has to seek the God as per his own independent sweet will and not due to any pressure, or any disease or any hardships or any sorrow, but only because of the fact and realizing that, 'It is the only motive of our life to seek God.'<br />
<font color="red">That is why, when we desire for this Divine Gift, then the doors of God Almighty's Divine Blessings open for you, and around the center is a place of Ten Primordial Gurus. These are the Main Gurus which are the Incarnation[s] of Śhri Dattātreya. They are: Socrates, Moses, Muhammad Sāhab, Guru Nāṇak, Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, and Zoroaster. They are all Incarnation[s] of one Incarnation.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"You can see how difficult it was for Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. He came to Vṛundāvan from Mathura, stayed there as a common cowherd, took all the troubles onto Himself. Demons used to come again and again to kill Him. How He used His powers of destruction, how He fought with the Kāliya snake, you know about all His life.<br />
<font color="red">You know about Śhrī Rām's life, you know about Christ's life, you know about Muhammad Sāhab's life, you know about Zoroaster's life, how many problems They had to face? How people tortured Them and troubled Them?</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0325 Pūjā (Hindi+English), Chit ke Gaharai (Depth of Your Attention), Seminar, Day 2, Camp, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"This is the only country in the whole world which is Yoga-oriented! Do you understand the importance of this country? Not only that it is Yoga-oriented, but also, also it is a Puṇya Bhūmi, here all the Great Saints have come and [<font color="orange">unclear</font> lived].<br />
<font color="red">Even Zoroaster, whom Parsis worship, is nothing but an Incarnation of Dattātreya, and you know how we worship Him in our Sahaja Yoga, how we worship Muhammad Sāhab in our Sahaja Yoga, how we understand where He stands within us!</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0929 Public Address, Joy (Poverty), Public Felicitation and Advent Seminar (8th Day of Navarātri), Sunderbhai Hall, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> [Mentions that Her forefathers ruled in Rāhurī and that the Nāth Pānthis worked there.]<br />
<b>Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ:</b> [Asks who were the Nāth Pānthis.]<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> I have so far told you how the evolution was led by Viṣhṇu and His Incarnations on the Earth.<br />
Apart from this there was a unique Incarnation of the Primordial Master, Ādi Guru, in the Void or Bhavasāgara. He incarnated many a times to guide humanity to cross the Void.<br />
These Masters evolved new personalities endowed with the Principles of Disciples or Śhiṣhya Tattwa, who manifested as Great Disciples of this Ādi Guru. The disciples created by Ādi Guru were human beings but they achieved salvation with the help of their Gurus or their own efforts. They were not Divine Incarnations and are known as Avadhūts.<br />
<font color="red">They incarnated on this Earth as other personalities: Solomon, David, Guru Vasiṣhṭha, John the Baptist, second and third Zoroaster, Mārkaṇḍeya, Gaganagaḍ Mahārāj and the Nine Nāths.</font><br />
The Nav Nāths knew that Kuṇḍalinī awakening is the only way you can get your Self-realization. Their attention was enlightened, and they could just put it on matter or anything and it would work.<br />
For instance, Chāṅgadev would put his attention on heat and cook on it!<br />
They had the True Knowledge of the Kuṇḍalinī and went as far as Bolivia and Ukraine to bestow Kuṇḍalinī awakening.<br />
<b>Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ:</b> Are they to be worshiped?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Only Deities are to be worshiped.<br />
<b>Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ:</b> Are there any Avadhūts born in India?<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Now Sahaja Yoga has created the environment for many great Souls to take their birth.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-1229 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, House of Madhukar Bhikājī Dhumāḷ, near Railway Station, Rāhurī, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In the same way, Sahaja Yoga is the Ocean. You cannot name it. Do not try to find its identifity ... identity with other things.<br />
If you start doing that, then your mind will start becoming that small little cup.<br />
And moreover, if you are coming from some organized religions, it's very important to understand: that organized religions make your cup even stronger, it doesn't dissolve.<br />
If it is a disorganized religion, then it's a cup of earthenware, which can dissolve into this Ocean.<br />
But if it is a solid, nice porcelain [soft laughter], Meissen, then there is no possibility. Then you are adhering to all that conditioning, all that solidness, and then it's very difficult. <font color="red">All the time you have to bring in Christ, or you have to bring in Muhammad, or you have to bring in Zoroaster, or someone like that, who should be there to guide you.</font><br />
Now, your guidance is your Spirit, which is unlimited. So you don't have to bring any one of Them: They are all within you, They are part and parcel of you.<br />
But to stick on to one person is again a sign that you are not expanding."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0926 Śhrī Durgā Pūjā, Mind Is just like a Donkey, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font> <font color="red">Ah-ah the old Persian which was before, uh I mean after Zoroaster, is definitely Sanskrit, very much, no doubt.</font><br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Mh-hm.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī</b></font> But this uh it is modern Persian that you see is Arabic.<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0927 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, House of Grégoire de Kalbermatten, Sternwartestrasse 62, Vienna, Austria</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Today only, we had somebody who had a uh Kuṇḍalinī which was just pulsating at the base.<br />
<br /> If there is no way of getting out, It pulsates, poor thing. You know, It just ... some people have such Kuṇḍalinī that just goes on tossing that, 'Oh God, when I am going to give birth to My child?'<br />
And then, if you can smooth it out, bring it out [snaps Her right fingers], It just comes up. And then you feel a Cool Breeze coming out of your head. Which is not possible medically, is it possible? You feel a Cool Breeze coming out of your head, you feel a Cool Breeze blowing into your hands. Then, this is the Power, which is the All-pervading Power, the Brahma Tattwa, which you can use, which is all integrated.<br />
In Sahaja Yoga lung... language we call it Mahākālī, Mahālakṣhmī, Mahāsaraswatī.<br />
<font color="red">Then you understand what was Muhammad Sāhab, what was Zoroaster, what was Christ, who They are, everything we understand. They are all integrated, we are the only people fighting among ourselves.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0104 Public Talk, Sholapur Brunch of Indian Medical Association, Sholapur, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As I told you before, that: we had Ten Gurus who came on this Earth, and They represented the innocence of the three Brahma, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha of Dattātreya. And one of Them was Zoroaster, another was Muhammad Sāhab, and all these Gurus represent those qualities of innocence of these Three Personalities called as Dattātreya.<br />
And also told you how by understanding these different Gurus we can produce the effects even on our physical health."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0317 Public Program, Day 5, Āgñyā Chakra, Mavlankar Hall, Constitution Club of India, Vithal Bhai Patel House, Rafi Mārg, Sansad Mārg Area, Behind Reserve Bank of India, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So [that] the Ātmā, the Spirit, has to be found out, is said even by Muhammad Sāhab! He said, "You have to become the Pīr."<br />
<font color="red">Is said by Zoroaster, is said by Lao Tze, is also said by Zen.</font> Buddha has said it, Mahāvīra has said it, every one of Them have said it.<br />
So many religions have started, in the name of God, without going to the Truth, that, "You have to be born-again." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-0622 Public Program, The Experience of Truth, Part I, Polytechnic of the South Bank (now London South Bank University), 103 Borough Road, Newington, Southwark, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And that is what is dharma: is the ten valences within us. <font color="red">These ten valances are nothing but dharma, which was preached by all the Great Saints. We can start it from Ādināth, we can say Lao Tze, we can say Confucius, we can say Zoroaster, we can say Muhammad Sāhab, we can say Nāṇak Sāhab, we can say Janaka, we can say the, all of Them are the representation or manifestation of Dattātreya, which we know very well in Maharashtra what is Dattātreya.</font><br />
But despite all that, we do not know: we'll worship Dattātreya, and we will not follow Him.<br />
This is the only problem we have. That: we have all the ideals, we have all the capacity to understand that this is something great, but we have no power to follow it. Because we are not Samartha, we are not equal to the meaning of a human being."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1984-1205 Public Program (English+Marathi), Day 2, Pune, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, when we seek also the Truth, we try to get to a new method all the time. And I think the evil[s] that came uh in forms of wrong type of gurus are the product of this kind of demand.<br />
Only seventy to hundred years back, I should say, in India, suddenly a new wave of some new ideas about the knowledge of the roots started.<br />
<font color="red">Some things that they talk of are not written in the Vedas, nor in the Purāṇas, nor in any books of uh uh ori-ental knowledge, nor in any books that are uh written after Christ, like the Bible, or Qur'ān after Muhammad Sāhab, and also uh the writings of Zoroaster. It has no relationship whatsoever to the ancient findings about the roots.</font><br />
So, we had a problem about the religion in the same manner."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0611 Public Program, Day 1, The Truth Has Two Sides, Geneva, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now when I'm talking to you about the mechanism that is built within us for our last breakthrough, you need not believe Me. <br />
In our country also, this knowledge was kept a secret for thousands of years. Though we can say people like Mārkaṇḍeya, whose dates could be fourteen thousand [years ago], or later on, up to Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, people did write about the Kuṇḍalinī.<br />
And at the time of Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, He very clearly talked about it. That was the tradition of evolution described in all these great Scriptures.<br />
Even in the Bible, you find the Tree of Fire. It says: "I will appear before you as tongues of flames." <br />
Even Muhammad Sāhab, who came much later, very clearly, very, very clearly, and elaborately, at length, talked about the Resurrection Day. He said: "At the Time of Resurrection, your hands will speak."<br />
But everybody missed the point.<br />
<font color="red">Zoroaster talked about it thousands of years back.</font> Confucius, Lao Tze, everyone talked about it: that, 'We have to be the Spirit.'<br />
Christ clearly said: "You are to be born-again!" Then Nicodemus asked Him: "Do you mean to say, I should enter into the womb of my mother?" "No," He said, "whatever is born of the flesh is the flesh. You are to be born of the Holy Ghost." "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0703 Public Program, Day 1, Nederlands Congresgebouw (now World Forum), Churchillplein 10, The Hague, Netherlands</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But when you have your Self-realization, you start feeling it on your c-c-central nervous system the All-pervading Power of God as Cool Breeze.<br />
Now this is described in all the Śhāstras [Scriptures].<br />
[Repeats for the translator:] It is described in all the Śhāstras.<br />
It is described in ... uh by Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya as, "Salī-laṃ, Salī-laṃ," means the Cool, Cool Breeze. Is described in the Bible as the Cool Breeze of the Holy Ghost. Is described in the Qur'ān as 'Asas. <font color="red">Is described in Sikh religion, in the Zoroaster's, that, 'The God's All-pervading Power is like a Cool Breeze.'<br />
Also, we know that when we say, 'You become a Christian,' you are [touching repeatedly the top of Her head with the right fingers:] baptized here. That much they know, in the church.<br /> 
Even the Hindus have a kind of ceremony that you are born-again. And the Muslims and the Jews, all of them have.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-1009 Public Program, Grand Hotel Krasnopolski, Dam 9, Amsterdam, Netherlands</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Sahaja Yoga is your own religion. Within yourself you have a Kuṇḍalinī: you have this Power within yourself which is to be awakened. About which even Saint Thomas has said, about which Muhammad Sāheb has said, about which Zoroaster has said, about which Christ has said, about which of course, Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa has said, in a way."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0000 Public Program, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"For example, in the Arabic countries, Zoroaster took birth five times, and later many Ādi Gurus took birth, like Abraham, Moses, and last of all Śhrī Muhammad Sāhib also took birth there. Because it was very necessary, and that is why these Gurus took birth to accomplish some definite work."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0101 New Year Pūjā (Hindi+English), Mukand Steel Factory, Kalwa, Thane, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Like in the Indian Scriptures, we have the Primordial Master. Then we have, this Master incarnates.<br />
<font color="red">Like in Iran, you had Zoroaster. According to Sahaj Yog, Zoroaster was the same. He c... five Zoroasters came there to preach about God and religion.</font><br />
These were the people who are now in India, who ran away from there, we call them Iranians, you see. They ran away. This is Parsepolis [Persepolis], you know that where S... Shiraz, near Shiraz, where the whole uh-uh-uh ... capital was there, at that time."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-0915 Public Talk to a Group of about 20 Iranians, Āśhram, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Muslims, Hindus, Christians, we do not accept. For us, we are all Sahaja Yogis, and we have faith in all the religion[s]. Not a samabhāv [sympathy, like nature]! We have faith in everyone. As well as we worship Rāma, we worship Muhammad Sāhab also. Same way! No less! <font color="red">As we worship Brahmadeva, or as we worship, let's say, Dattātreya, we worship Zoroaster. There's no difference at all. Same way!</font><br />
There's a big difference in having just the same ... uh-uh-uh, uh what you call, the same uh respect. Is not that! But we worship the same way.<br />
So there's no question of differentiating each other, nor on countrywise, nothing."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1992-1230 Śhrī Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā (English+Marathi+Hindi+English), The Universal Love, Kalwa, Thane, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, I think Iran is a very old country of great culture.<br />
<font color="red">And before it became Islamic, it had Zoroastrians living there, who had great philosophy also.</font><br />
Then these Islamic people also took to Islam in a very serious way.<br />
I don't know but, before Islam came, the people used to make art with human figures. And after that they started making things of this kind, where there were only flowers, or cubes, or geometrical drawings.<br />
<font color="red">It happened that I went to Shiraz, and I went to Metropolis [Persepolis] also. Saw all the places: is full of Divine Vibrations. That means: there have been, even before Muhammad, five times Zoroaster came.</font><br />
And then came Hazarat Muhammad, who did such a lot of work for all of us."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1993-1009 Iranian Public Program, 11301 Olympic Boulevard, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In every religion there is some sort of a stupid stuff pushed forward, in every. Nobody could really stop it. Because those people who are in charge of religion have no enlightenment, they have nothing to k... do with it, anywhere.<br />
And that's how, I have seen, people, say, in Japan, they follow one religion, and in uh-uh-uh China they follow another religion, both are just the same: one is Zen, another is Tao. But the misunderstanding is that they think, 'We are ex-xu-xu-xclusive [exclusive].' They are not! None of them are exclusive!.<br />
Muhammad Sāhab described all of Them: from Abraham to Moses, to Christ, to the Mother of Christ. And He said, :There have been more than one lākh Nabīs on this Earth."<br />
But now, why to feel that we are exclusive? This exclusiveness comes from where?<br />
With Christ also, He described all of Them!<br />
Ta-o, the one religion that they follow in China, is nothing but Sahaja Yoga: Ta-o is Kuṇḍalinī. <font color="red">Zen is nothing [laughing:] but Sahaja. Zoroaster, everyone.</font><br />
But this exclusiveness has brought this problem, and they are fighting among each other."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0321 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Birthday Felicitations, Nizamuddin Scouts Grounds, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Because as I went to Boston, the TV people asked Me: "How many Rolls-Royces You have?" [As laughter starts:] I said, "I haven't any. I'm sorry. My husband has one single car, that's all. That's sufficient for us!" So they said, "You mean You are not in the business?" I said, "No." [Laughter.] "So we are not interested!"<br />
How can you talk of spirituality when you have this mentality towards spirituality?<br />
How much did you pay to Christ, again? How much did you pay to Kṛiṣhṇa? <font color="red">Or how much did you pay to Zoroaster, or to Moses?</font><br />
Anybody who talks of spirituality cannot be purchased! And this is what one has to understand."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1996-0924 Public Program, The Olympic Collection, Grand Ballroom, 3rd Floor, 11301 W. Olympic Boulevard, 204, Los Angeles, CA, U.S.A.</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis.</font> Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 33</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In this Void is placed the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) formed from Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva). This Primordial Master is also known as Dattātreya. <font color="red">He has taken many human births as a Prophet and teacher, such as Rāja Janaka, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, Guru Nāṇaka, and Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.</font> This Deity helps human beings to seek their salvation by crossing the Void or Ocean of Illusion within themselves."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings, Pages 124 and 125</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The material energy of sound becomes absolutely divine only when a realized Soul creates it by percussion or by vocal means. For example, chanting mantras or talking to Deities by non-realized souls creates barriers for their communication with these Deities, who become very angry with such unauthorized practices. Human beings must understand that there is a protocol for approaching the Divine; ignorance of it is no excuse. For example, if a non-realized soul continues to chant the name of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, he may get throat problems, and ultimately even throat cancer. Sounds that are used for invoking Deities in temples, or in the worship of God by realized Souls or Yogis, are the sounds which carry or reflect Divine Vibrations. Mantras are divine sounds, and the poetic language of the Scriptures is based on the complete divine expression of the sound element. The Lord's Prayer and <i>Namāz</i> are pure mantras. <font color="red">The Parsi <i>Avestha</i> Scriptures (of the followers of Zoroaster) and the Sanskrit <i>śhlokas</i> of the Hindus are all divine words which carry Divine Vibrations.</font> If these words are uttered by non-realized people, they have no meaning and give no connection to God. If they are uttered by unholy people, these can fall victims to the anger of the Deities. Such individuals may fall into the subconscious or supraconscious realms. The Divine Power, the integrated energy, is expressed as the Word, also known as the Auṃ or Logos or <i>Anahalk</i>."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 14: The Powers of Ādi Śhakti and the Three Guṇas, Pages 207 and 208</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Japan we had another great Master whose name was Viditama. He was the disciple of Lord Buddha and he went to Japan and started the Zen system. Zen means meditation -- dhyāna -- and he wanted people to become "thoughtlessly aware". He found out many ways of making people "thoughtlessly aware" -- the tea ceremony and the temples that they have, are all meant to create thoughtless awareness. I was amazed that none of the Japanese knew what the purpose of these gardens were. There is one garden which has some moss on top of a hill in a very small area and it is very interesting. You have to see the flowers and other foliage there through a magnifying glass. All this should amaze a person and one should become thoughtlessly aware. That was the idea of Zen, but surprisingly, few understood Zen. <font color="red">Then there was a Prophet, Zoroaster, who was born five times in His country, Persia.</font> Ultimately Muhammad Sāhib had to come to say something very clearly about religion. <font color="red">But the people who followed Muhammad Sāhib, never realized the oneness of His preaching or that of Zoroaster, and they made all the Persians run away to all the other countries and so many of them came to India.</font><br />
Muhammad Sāhib has talked about Abraham, Moses, Christ in a series as They came one after the other. He has talked about the Mother of Christ especially with great respect. In the Bible She is not given so much respect because of Paul who edited the Bible. She is just called "the woman". But Prophet Muhammad says that anyone who talks against this Holy Lady will be punished, or something to that effect. So one can see that Muhammad Sāhib never talked of an exclusive religion called "Islam" (i.e., I surrender to God Almighty). But so many followers of Islam are fighting the followers of other religions and even amongst themselves."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 8: World Peace</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"As the Kuṇḍalinī rises into the third part, next to the Nābhī chakra, we become absolutely righteous. This area, which we call as the Ocean of Illusion, is enlightened by Ten Principles of Mastery. The Great Masters have created these ten centers of commandments which are enlightened and we become holy. There is no need to be strict in one's behavior. We automatically become really spiritual. Like an egg becomes the bird, we are born twice. In Sanskrit a Yogi or the one who knows Brahma, meaning the All-pervading Power, is called dvija and a bird is also called dvija, meaning twice-born. There were Abraham and Moses and all the Ten Primordial Masters who have been born again and again on this Earth. <font color="red">Zoroaster has been born five times and also so many of these were born in different places in different countries to guide the people to take to religious life to establish the necessary balance for the ascent.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 11: The Subtle System</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Zoroaster" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Adi Guru" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ SOCRATES in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0714-g" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ SOCRATES in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri_Socrates</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0714-g"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But in some people that stability has to be brought about. No problem. You have obtained that thing, you recognized it, you reached there and there is a complete arrangement for bringing stability.<br />
<font color="red">As soon as that stability is achieved, in Absolute Peace and Joy, you achieve that Witness State described by Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, by Jesus, by all the Scriptures whether by Zoroaster, Socrates, Confucius or any of Dattātreya's Incarnations.</font><br />
Till today, these people who were of a higher state, who would take birth in a higher state, would talk in a manner that others were unable to understand. They could see matters of the tenth floor and others would remain on the first floor and they would just not understand what was being talked about."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"It has been since ages, one simple question: "How to reach the Infinite through this finite mind, through this rationality, which God has given us?" <font color="red">This is the eternal problem which has been there from the times of Socrates, Confucius.</font> Kant, Hegel, all these great philosophers have been only asking this question in all their findings and search: "How to reach the Infinite through this finite?" "<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0319 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, It Is a Spontaneous Growth of Your Being into that Infinite Realm of God's Grace and The Articulation of Your Personality, Seminar, Day 1, Session 2 (evening), Cowasji Jehangir Hall, 15, Madam Cama Rd, Mantralaya, Fort, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Otherwise, so far, you see, anywhere, great men were born.<br />
Socrates see: just, what happened to [Him]? And what did He do? I mean, just think of it! He did not do anything wrong!<br />
Galileo, anybody!</font><br />
Because never Truth was accepted by people who were not realized! They cannot, because they do not have that power to bear the Truth."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0701 Guru Pūjā (Guru Pūrṇimā Day) (first more formal Pūjā in the West), Self-realization, Living Room, Gavin Brown's Geological Institute (Terrace House), 160 North Gower Street, 2nd Floor, Euston, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now we have got Ten Dharmas within us which we have to keep all right. These are the main Ten Commandments.<br />
<font color="red">These Ten Commandments we have to look after, and these are looked after by the people who are these, the Primordial Masters, as you call Them Incarnations Divinely: like Rāja Janaka, like Moses, like Socrates, like Nāṇaka, the last one was the Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. This is the Principle is there, is the Primordial Master.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Zen and Void, Part 1, First Western Seminar, Day 2, Session 2 (during and after tea and coffee), Conference Center, East Hampstead Park (near Workingham, 60 kms W of London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Any Saint, you can say, Kabīra Dās or it bring say Nāṇaka, any Saint you ... you read, uh Khalil Gibran or any Saint, whosoever has lived, you ask him, 'How do you do it? How it is?', he said [will say], 'I cannot say. You see, I've become dumb.'<br />
How do you ask a dumb person what is the taste of the mhh jaggery [made from sugarcane and date palm] or of the's sugar? How can a dumb person say?<br />
'I've become dumb.'<br />
Because the thing is, it's a happening! It happens within you. You cannot describe it. But it just happens within you, you can see it happen.<br />
<font color="red">This is the breakthrough which was historically, was described from the time of Socrates it started. He said that, "You have to become."</font><br />
Everyone has said!<br />
And today the time has come: is to happen."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1030 Public Program, Sahaja Yoga as a Hypothesis, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK (very likely)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Not only that, everything that is written in our Scriptures, not only in Hindu Scriptures but the Scriptures of the whole world, about things even those written by Lao Tze, by Socrates, whatever is written, because They all stood for the Truth and the same Truth. There are no two truths."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0114 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Satya kā Anveṣhaṇa (Exploration of Truth), Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"After that there is Nābhī center. For Nābhī center you know that whatever has happened in the evolution from fish to human being, everything has happened here.<br />
<font color="red">For helping in it many Big Gurus have Incarnated inside us, whom you know from Socrates to Confucius, Moses, Rāja Janak, Muhammad Sāhab, Nāṇak Sāhab, Kabīr, all these Big Gurus, all of Them have worked hard on it and made dharma of human beings. It is the dharma of human beings inside, in the stomach, not outside.</font><br />
Like dharma of this gold is that it does not get spoiled, it is untarnishable.<br />
In the same way Ten Dharma[s] of human beings are formed inside the stomach."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0312 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Session 2 (evening), Mūlādhāra Chakra or Realization of Divine and Spirit, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So the dharma that has been established in us by God Almighty because if we want to go to the Kingdom of God, then in our freedom we must desire to get to God. If someone tries to pressurize us and says, 'You must ask for God,' then it is of no use, it is not an evaluation. That is why to reach in this state, a person has to seek the God as per his own independent sweet will and not due to any pressure, or any disease or any hardships or any sorrow, but only because of the fact and realizing that, 'It is the only motive of our life to seek God.'<br />
<font color="red">That is why, when we desire for this Divine Gift, then the doors of God Almighty's Divine Blessings open for you, and around the center is a place of Ten Primordial Gurus. These are the Main Gurus which are the Incarnation[s] of Śhri Dattātreya. They are: Socrates, Moses, Muhammad Sāhab, Guru Nāṇak, Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, and Zoroaster. They are all Incarnation[s] of one Incarnation.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Or Greeks can ask: 'Was Socrates an Incarnation of Primordial Master?'<br />
His birthday was celebrated the other day. And that day I was so very happy, you don't know, and it was extremely hot weather. Then I said ... I said, "All right, have any drops from flowers to the leaves," and they said, "Today is His birthday." And I was so happy today, all the time.<br />
'Was He the Incarnation of our sustainance [sustenance]?' 'And is He within us?'<br />
He looks after our sustainance [sustenance].<br />
He was not the property of Greeks, He was everybody's property which is within us, on this green Void, as you call it. He exists there.</font><br />
Ask such questions: these can be answered only on vibratory awareness.<br />
......<br />
They ... they want to, you see, even the Christ, even Christ, they don't think much of Him, they never thought much of Him. Now, I don't know what, they think because He's no more! What did you think of Him? You see, not one educated person went to Him, not one!<br />
[After 10 seconds:] <font color="red">As a person they don't think much of Socrates, now what to do?<br />
Every word that Socrates has said is Absolute Truth.<br />
And these are the human beings who, who are evaluating Him! What is your measure?</font><br />
And then they crucified Christ, very nicely, thinking that they have done the greatest ... job."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0524 Public Program, Seeking and Rationality, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Now, it is being said, not only by Me! What I say I have a complete historical background. You can go to Socrates and you can come up to Christ, everywhere you will find what I say is written down there.</font><br />
I do not have to quarrel with Them at all: They are My own, They are with Me.<br />
But I am here to convince you that whatever They have said is the Truth. Not by preaching about it, not by brainwashing, not by writing books about it, but by giving you the experience of your be-ing, actualizing it, what They have said, that, "There is a Spirit within us and we have to be born of the Spirit." And what is that Spirit is, and how do we become that, that is what we are going to experience."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0531 Public Program, Hall in City Center, Birmingham, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">Whatever I'm saying, whatever I'm explaining, has been explained right from Socrates, Christ, Muhammad Sāhab, all of Them have said this.</font><br />
And I would request you to be humble about it, and take your gift which is for you."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0625 Public Program, Seeking the Life Beyond, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Only in the human stage, it is said that, "You will become aware of it." Is said in all the Scriptures: like Qur'ān, like Bible, like Vedas, like uh Gītā which is a part of Veda, you can say. <font color="red">Also, Great Sages, all over the world, right from Moses, Abraham, Socrates, Lao Tze, in India, Janaka, Nāṇaka, Vasiṣhṭha, later on, people like, we can say, in the history, about sixth century, we had a very Great Saint or a great personality or an Incarnation like Śhaṅkarāchārya, all these people have been talking about your Second Birth.</font> That you are to be born-again.<br />
Unless and until you are born-again, you are not a Christian, you are not a Hindu, you are not a Muslim.<br />
Keep it one name. There are ten names, to one thing, for twice-born."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1203 Public Program, Session 1 (morning), Realization Is Not of the Intellect, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Apart from that, there is [a] third type of Incarnations which worked [pointing to the Void on the Chakra Chart:] in this gap: to sustain us. These are Ten Pri... Primordial Masters, the Ādi Guru. These people incarnated on this Earth to give us our sustainance [sustenance], our religion as they call it. They gave us those Ten Religions or sustainance [sustenance] which is important for a human being.<br />
This Principle of Primordial Master incarnated as Abraham, as Moses, as Muhammad Sāhab, as Janaka, as Nāṇaka, and recently, till recently, the One who is no more a now, is Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth.<br />
[During the translation helps with the enumeration:] Muh... mhh. <font color="red">Socrates.</font> Nāṇaka.<br />
Yes.<br />
<font color="red">Now, these people are Incarnation[s] of the one Principle, that is Primordial Master.<br /> 
The energy or the power with which They work[ed] is either a sister or a daughter: is a very pure relationships.<br /> 
If you read Their teachings you will find [that] They are saying the same things. Because They were worried about our sustainance [sustenance].</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0419 Public Program, Day 4, Spiritual Evolution of Man, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"For example, we can say the gree... green thing is the one that represents the water, water element. This center the ... in the stomach is the water element within us. It is called as Nābhī chakra, and around it is called as the Bhavasāgara, you can say the Void, or you can say the Gap, or whatever you may say, the whole world as such, within us. So, the people who were born on this center, around this center, were born out of water element.<br />
<font color="red">In this Bhavasāgara -- oc... Bhavasāgara means the ocean of this world -- were born, through this ocean of the world, were born all the Primordial Masters, one after another. We can say Abraham, Moses, we had Janaka, were Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], and Socrates, and so many others like that, Nāṇaka, and also very recently, we had about hundred years back, a very great Saint born in India known as Sāī Nāth.<br />
They all represent the same element that is the water element. Being responsible or being born out of that, They are anxious to maintain water element as the one which is within us for sustaining ourselves. We su... we are sustained by water, so They help us to sustain ourselves. They are the sustainers: They tell us how to sustain us as a human being.<br />
And all of Them have tried to establish religion within us.</font><br />
A religion doesn't mean outside, but the religion as a man: means the capacity of a man, or you can say the quality of a man. What a human being should be like, what is the way to know if he is a human being or not, which is described in al... in the Ten Commandments."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0421 Public Program, What Is Second Birth, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And these Ten Sustainances [Sustenances] are represented by Great Prophets. The Principle is called as Ādi Guru, in Sanskrit language, the Primordial Master. <font color="red">He had incarnated on this Earth as Abraham, Moses, as Lao Tze, as Confucius, as Socrates.</font> Recently, He has been as Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī, not the other fellow, and other great people have been like Nāṇaka, Janaka.<br />
All these Great Saints can ... came on this Earth to tell us: how to keep in the center, how to keep our sustenance, how to be human beings.<br />
As carbon has got four valances, we too have got ten valances. We have to maintain those ten valances within us! That's what they came to tell us."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0325 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 2, Mūlādhāra and Swādhiṣhṭhāna Chakras, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Moses, Abraham, Confucius, Socrates, Muhammad, Nāṇak, Janak, Lao Tze, these are the Primordial Masters, the Principle of Primordial Masters, the Ādi Gurus, who incarnated on this Earth to teach us how to keep our sustainance [sustenance]. They taught against all alcohols and strong things."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0402 Public Program, Day 1, The Pure Power of Desire or Aim of Seeking, Royal Exhibition Building, Carlton Gardens, 9 Nicholson Street, Melbourne, Victoria, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> Is not only that, I'm saying on the whole, a shee ... worship is a tradition which has come to us from great Seers and ancient Sages. <font color="red">Anybody, even, say, Moses, you can say Socrates, you can say Dattātreya, or Mārkaṇḍeya, or any one of these people, have found out the ways and methods how to tune our instruments to the Divine to achieve the maximum joy.</font><br />
'How to please the Deities,'' that's the main point is, how to please the Deities. But it's a crude word pleases, but how to ... [laughing:] I don't know what should I say, innovation they say, or what do you call that? How to spark them, ...<br />
<b>Sahaja Yogi:</b> Invoke.<br />
<font color="red"><b>Śhrī Mātājī:</b></font> ... invoke, invoke them. Invoke them: that they give you complete blessings.<br />
And the trick of the trade one has to learn, one has to educate. There's nothing wrong in getting educated.<br />
So we know that we have to educate ourself, first point, and secondly, we have to know, that for that, we have to be humble. The humility should be such: that, 'I have to learn. I have to learn. I have to educate. Nothing ... nothing wrong in it.'<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1982-0321 Birthday Pūjā, Āśhram, 44 Chelsham Road, Clapham, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>[<font color="orange">WARNING: Quotes for the period 1980-04 to 2001-12 will follow in due time.</font>]</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">But Socrates and Confucius, who were such ancient people, have talked about these Gods. That, 'We have to keep Them pleased,' and you have to keep Them all right. But those realized Souls, perhaps did not know, that's not easy to convince human beings, who are not realized Souls, about these Deities being within you.</font><br />
And They are all just waiting there.<br />
As soon as the Kuṇḍalinī rises, you start manifesting your grandeur, your great personality that awaits you. This is something not fantastic to Me, because I have seen thousands of people getting Realization, thousands of them feeling the Cool Breeze, thousands of them transforming."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0302 Public Program, Day 1, Town Hall, Hay Street and Barrack Street, Perth, WA, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now when this center is illumined, around it is illumined your sustainance [sustenance]. That's your Inner Religion.<br />
The ... we call it Ten Incarnations of the Primordial Master. There are many who came, but the Ones who came in India was called as Brahmadeva uh ... was called as Dattātreya, Janaka, Rāja Janaka, the father of Sītā. In China, Lao Tze, Confucius. In uh, in the Bible, Abraham and Moses. And later on, in the uh form of uh Muhammad Sāhab. And then Janaka. No, no, Nāṇaka, I'm sorry, Nāṇaka. Nāṇak Sāhab. <font color="red">And in Greece, it was Socrates.</font> They took birth on all these places. In the end, about fifty years back, or hundred years back, was born Great Primordial Master, in India, in Śhirḍī.<br />
[Helping with the translation:] In Śhirḍī."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0831 Public Program, Day 3, Geneva, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"They have described that, 'Through the ascent of the Kuṇḍalinī only you can reach your Spirit.' All the Upaniṣhadas, which are the second part of the Vedas, all of them have described the Kuṇḍalinī. Only thing, the difference is: that some said, 'By doing this, by doing that,' 'By uh abstinence,' some said, 'By accepting uh the right part, the central part,' 'By building up your balance,' all these different, different style of things to modulate a human being to lead a moderate life, they have built up their own literature.<br />
But every one of them exist: exist because they want to talk about your ascent to be the Spirit. There's nothing else but that! That's the basic point!<br />
And Kuṇḍalinī is the Fundamental Power which has to be awakened: all of them have the same.<br />
But it happens: that a person who is more extrovert, always tries to go to something new. [Drinks water.] And when he tries to go to something new, he forgets that: 'There has been a tradition of that for ages! And why should we suddenly accept a new idea?'<br />
<font color="red">Confucius, Socrates, Abraham, Moses, later on Christ, all of Them have talked about the Spirit.</font><br />
Muhammad Sāhab has talked about the Kuṇḍalinī, calling It a 'Asas.<br />
And the word Kuṇḍalinī also is ... has a meaning that it is a coiled-up energy."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0508 Public Program, Day 1, This Is the Knowledge of the Roots, Deutsches Museum, Münich, Germany</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">When they talked, say, about the flowers, say, they talked that they are Gods, like Socrates talked about Gods, like Confucius talked about Gods. When they talked, 'We have to please our Gods,' we started doubting. 'What Gods He's talking about?' Whatever They saw we could not see. All right.<br />
Then they thought, "No use talking about Gods. If you talk about Gods, then it becomes a, sort of a worship of something that is a flower. We talk about flower, then we think, 'We have become God.' And we talk about flower all the time!" "</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-0920 Public Program, Memorial Hall, City Hall, Sheffield, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Here [turning and pointing towards the Chakra Chart:] the Guru Tattwa is expressed in the Void, there, where the Ten Gurus actually incarnated basically and they re-incarnated. Say we can start uh-uh from Ādināth. Then we can come to ... other ones, uh-uh-uh ... like Nāṇaka, Janaka. Janaka was-ss much earlier. Then we can say Abraham, Moses-s-s. <font color="red">All these were Guru Tattwa, Socrates.</font> All these were Guru Tattwa people: the people who came as Prophets. The ones who came on this Earth to teach us balance, to teach us the Code of Life.<br />
That was also important part. But that was forgot[ten]!<br /> 
'Why? Why the code? Why the religion?' Religion is for the ascent, to build you up."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1985-1128 Public Program (Śhrī William Blake's Birthday), Building the New Jerusalem, Hammersmith Town Hall, 1 Riverside Gardens, Hammersmith, London W6 9LE, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"If you go to a temple, every temple has got uh-uh-uh nice uh arrangement for you to get possessed. [Laughter.]<br />
Or even a church, or a mosque, where God has to reside, you find suddenly you get attacked. and you come out absolutely puzzled about yourself, ending up into lunatic asylums.<br />
So what sort of worshiping places are these, where you go to find God and you get the horrible satanic forces acting on you?<br />
<font color="red">That's why in the modern times, people have become so very confused. We do not find truth in anything: in any ideologies, any philosophies, anything that started, say, Confucius started humanism, Socrates started another thing, Muhammad Sāhab started another thing.</font><br />
Like Muhammad Sāhab said. "Let us not worship God as an idol. Let us worship Him in the Nirākāra," in the Formless God."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1987-0712 Guru Pūjā, Tent, Marque, Back Garden, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As we had very great people ... uh ... on this Earth, I have given you the names, as we said there are, there have been Ten Gurus, uh ... starting from Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], we had Confucius, we had Socrates, and later on we had Abraham, Moses and also up to Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, we had about Ten Great Gurus, now we have so many here sitting down. They are all gurus, and they have to behave like gurus and they have to the ... do the job of great gurus."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0731 Guru Pūjā, The First Principle of the Guru Is the Gravity (First Thing and Foremost Thing Is that We Must Have Gravity in Temperament and Value System of a Balance and You Have to Become the Fruits of Sahaja Yoga), Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis. Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. <font color="red">In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates.</font> He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918. Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 33</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The Brahmachaitanya (All-pervading Power) has Itself become very active as a new type of age called "Kṛita Yuga" has started. It is achieving results and producing miracles. It is not only talk or reading Scriptures, but it is actualization and the proof. Of course, all false people are afraid of facing the Truth, because Sahaja Yoga goes against their interests. They are challenging and opposing violently the spread of Sahaja Yoga. The Satya Yuga has to be established by the Sahaja Yogis. <font color="red">Now they are not alone like Christ our Lord, Muhammad the Prophet, Socrates the Philosopher or other Incarnations, Seers and realized Souls.</font> They are in thousands. They are not in any way hampered by the few people who are trying to harm their collective progress. The Truth will be established and thus the dawn of Satya Yuga (the Kingdom of God) would be seen on the horizon. The message of Sahaja Yoga is that even these negative people have to accept the Truth and enjoy the blessings of the Divine Love."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1991-0700 Book 'Sahaja Yoga', Chapter 1: Sahaja Yoga</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"<font color="red">A benevolent ruler, in the form of a philosopher king (as put forward by Socrates), is the ideal person to be the head of government.</font> Such a person must be an extremely wise, detached personality, without any desires for lust, power and money. There have been such persons in the recent past, people like Mahātmā Gāndhī, Atatürk Kemal Pasha, Anwar el-Sadat, Lal Bahadur Shastri, Ho Chi Minh, Martin Luther King, Nelson Mandela, Dag Hammarksjöld, and Mujibur Rahman.<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">The Socratic ideal of serving the benevolence of the people, does not exist any more. On the contrary, they criticize it by insisting that Socrates was not a practical man. All the great Saints and Prophets were, of course, idealists and not practical people.</font> Most of the democracies of today's world are under the thumb of people who have no honorable or moral ideas whatsoever. They discover very fast that power can give them prosperity and that this money power can whitewash and obliterate all their misdeeds and conceal the dubious business they are up to. Unfortunately for them, this false license has now gone into their heads, like a fixed idea, and they go on behaving immorally, without any fear of the Divine, ruthlessly destroying the entire value system of democracy. They may carry on for years, as they did in Italy, until, by the Law of Polarity or by Divine Retribution, they are exposed. But before this happens, such rulers unfortunately become models for the people whom they govern and gradually moral degradation in day-to-day life begins to create a decadent or dying democratic society."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 3: Democracy</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"World peace can be achieved only when people in charge of world affairs get their Self-realization. They are leaders of different countries and through a Sahaja relation they will respect and love each other. <font color="red">They will be like benevolent kings described by Socrates, who will think of global peace.</font> Today it seems as if the whole world is ablaze with war."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 7: Peace</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Socrates" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Adi Guru" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ŚHRĪ SĀĪ NĀTH of ŚHIRḌĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0714-j" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ŚHRĪ SĀĪ NĀTH of ŚHIRḌĪ in the Words of ŚHRĪ MĀTĀJĪ" /><published>2022-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/QIT_Shri_Sai_Nath</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/quotes/2022/0714-j"><![CDATA[<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"To make the people cross the Void (Bhavasāgara) He has to make some arrangement. So the Great Power like Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśha was created and They were placed in the Area of Dharma.<br />
Dattātreya and Ādi Gurus incarnated in this world many a times. He incarnated as King Janaka who was like the father of Ādi Śhakti. After that He incarnated in Iran as Zoroaster, then as Macchindranāth, then as Muhammad Sāheb and Nāṇak Sāheb.<br />
No one fought with each other. See what type of darkness you are in?<br />
Fāṭimah, the daughter of Muhammad Sāheb was the same who became daughter of King Janaka.<br />
Whom are you fighting? Think over it.<br />
The Nāṇakī of Guru Nāṇaka was none else but Jānakī.<br />
<font color="red">Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth was also an Ādi Guru.</font><br />
<font color="red">They are the Masters of all.<br />
Also, They are My Gurus. These Ādi Gurus taught Me all this Knowledge. In different Incarnations They kept Me teaching.<br /> 
Ultimately I had to come and do His work. They could not do it and now They are placing Me as a Guru so that I take up the job of a Guru.<br />
There was an age when no one was willing to accept a woman as a Guru but in Kali Yuga only Mother could do His work: it is beyond the power of men.</font><br />
This work could not be done by force, only the love of a Mother could do it because already there is so much pressure, tension in this world. The day it is forced upon the human being they will break down. So, love is the only way out.<br />
So this Gurudom was given to Me. Everything is acceptable to Me.<br />
But I didn't know the qualities of a Guru.<br />
Gurus maintain distance but mother does not keep distance with the children. Children sit on her head.<br />
So, you people also could take liberty with Me and enjoy. Be with Me with full freedom, you will neither be afraid nor be embarrassed. There is no problem, you could come and talk to Me boldly about your problems. You could complain to Me as you do to your mother. I am freely available to you.<br />
Freedom was needed, religion was required to be discussed openly, there is no secret, no secret about it. Ultimately everything has to be explained very clearly. All the secrets are to be told about, everything could not be said everywhere."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1125 Public Program (Hindi), Day 7, Pāne ke Bāda: Sāta Chakroṃ ke Devatā (After Getting It: Deities of the Seven Chakras), 4 Duplex Lane, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The same Śhrī Dattā incarnated many a times on the Earth.<br />
As I told you yesterday, King Janaka was one of Them. King Janaka was the father of Jānakī [Śhrī Sītā]. He was none other than the Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya.<br />
Thereafter, Macchindranāth, most have you must have heard His name, was also His Incarnation.<br />
After that Zoroaster who came three times on the Earth, He was also His Incarnation.<br />
After that Muhammad Sāhab, who was His Incarnation.<br />
And when He was asked that, "Bhāī [Brother], there must have been others also before You," then He replied, "Yes, there [was] a Muhammad." Then again He was asked who was before Him. He replied, "There was one Muhammad."<br />
Muhammad means Praise, the One who is praised, the One who deserves to be praised and is the One who is Redeemer of the world.<br /> 
They were all Muhammads, They were all Dattātreyas, who came on Earth regularly.<br />
After that [was] Nāṇaka, Guru Nāṇaka. If you ever read His teachings, if you read His talks then you will be surprised that He has always talked in a Sahaja. He has said, "Sahaja Samādhi lago." He has said, "Kāhe re ban khojan jāe, Sarab nivāsī sadā alepā tohī saṃg[a] samāī, Puṣhpamadhya jo bāsa basata hai mukara māhī jaise chhāī, Taise hī harī base niraṃtara ghaṭa hī khojo bhāī." ["Why to go to forest to find Him, He is always there with you just like there is a fragrance in a flower and just as the reflection is there in a mirror, in the same way God is residing in you eternally, seek Him within."] He is just inside, achieve Him just inside. We are just singing poem, singing songs, we are just cramming His prescription.<br />
The talk of seeking this Absolute Principle, residing just inside the heart, has been made since ancient times by these Ādi Gurus, who are incarnated on this Earth again and again.<br />
......<br />
<font color="red">After Nāṇak Sāhab, around fifty, sixty years ago in our Maharashtra Dattātreya incarnated as Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī.</font> If you want proof of it, then you get your Realization and after that if you put your hand on anyone, then you will get vibration of same kind: from just vibration only you can know about all."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1973-1209 Public Program (Hindi), Day 3, Śhrī Dattātreya Jayanti, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Despite the wealth, property, prosperity, power or position you have, you might [be] kings and queens but you won't get joy unless you stand in the Kingdom of Joy. When you stand in the Kingdom of Joy, then in any case you become kings and queens. No one can purchase you or conquer you. You conquer everything. You become kings.<br />
<font color="red">Such great kings have come and gone in this country. In this Maharashtra, a great personage took birth who lived in a small village in Śhirḍī. People never understood His kingship, in what enjoyment He used to live. In this India, there was another king in Guru Nāṇak. Another was Kabīr. Did They enjoy any royal comforts? Today, the whole world lies at Their Feet.</font><br />
I am present before you today only to bring fulfillment to all Their teachings and Their work. Nothing They said was false. What Jesus said, what Kṛiṣhṇa said, what is written in the Gītā, what is written in the Bible, what is written in the Qur'ān will be proved by Me.<br /> 
In looks, I am just an ordinary lady. All right, the power flowing through Me will prove how the Unconscious is working."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1975-1222 Public Program (Hindi), Day 1, Prabhu ke Prem kā Anubhav (Experiences of Lord's Love), Gita Mandir Hall, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan (3rd floor), 29, Kulapati K.M. Munshi Mārg, Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Another thing is, here in Bhavasāgar, all Three, Brahmā, Viṣhṇu, Maheśhwar, combined to make a child, who is called Ādi Guru, is known as Dattātreya. There were many Incarnations of Him. And His Child Tattwa also took Incarnations. First was Dattātreya, then came Rāja Janak. <font color="red">Like this, many Incarnations came, Rāja Janak, Nāṇak, Zarathustra, Muhammad Sāhab, Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.<br />
They are all one. Are They or not?</font> You can witness it after Self-realization. If you believe in one Guru, like Nāṇak, then you have no right not to accept Muhammad Sāhab. If you get Muhammad Sāhab and not Nāṇak, then you have no authority as well.<br />
You will be surprised, most of the cancer disease comes from the imbalance of Bhavasāgar, you follow one but not the other. Cancer also comes when we don't follow Them.<br />
Like He forbade two things, like not to smoke a cigarette and not to consume alcohol.<br />
Alcohol is entirely not allowed. Here, in Sahaja Yoga, if someone is habituated to drink alcohol, they will leave it. If they don't leave alcohol, it will [not] be in moderation because both of these things go against Guru Tattwa.<br />
If Guru Tattwa is not established within us, we cannot have our evolution. Guru Tattwa is essential. Guru Tattwa is one destiny for all religions. There is one flow from all the religions."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-032x Public Program (Hindi), Day y, Advertised as 'Kuṇḍalinī Awakening', New Delhi, India (date to be confirmed)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Just be silent and be witnesses. As Sāī Bābā has said, "Saburī," patience, it comes in."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0402 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Role of Tongue, Sight and Feet in Spiritual Evolution, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"At this point you are in Sāmīpya Samādhi. Means you feel that Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa is standing next to you. Sometimes you feel that Rādhā is here. <font color="red">Sometimes you see that Śhrī Śhrī Sāī Bābā is sitting in person.</font> But still you are not there where They are. In Sāmīpya State also, you are not there where They all are."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0527 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Sahaja Yoga Baddal Sarvānna Sangaychee Hi Sahajayogyānchi Jababdari Āhe (Responsibility of Sahaja Yoga), Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Maharashtra, some Great Gurus have taken birth, which means we are some special people, that's what I have to say. Land of Maharashtra has something extraordinary. Or you can say that because of that soil, lotus bloomed. Those Gurus were very great.<br />
<font color="red">Before some years back we had Great Guru of Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. No doubt about it, He was an Incarnation of Śhrī Dattātreya. There is no doubt about His Incarnation. He was a Muslim. You recognized Him, that is important.</font><br />
But there now you have built temples, big priests have come there. How they would do Pūjā for Him or worship Him? What authority they have? Who are they? And in front of them you put the money. Means, what is going on? <font color="red">What He taught, what He said?</font><br />
<font color="red">Only going to temple and sitting there, you will say, 'Sāī Bābā [of Śhirḍī] has fulfilled our wishes,' means He has done our work. He does that because He is very kind. Once you surrender to Him, He will do your work. But what you have done for Him?<br />
He is angry because you are taking His name. I have seen so many of His devotees. I have to tell Him, 'Forgive them, they don't know.' We are not qualified to take His name.<br />
He is very great, for Me.</font><br />
I am OK if you have taken My name for so many times, there is no problem. I will not get angry, I am your Mother.<br />
<font color="red">But for Him, to take His name, or to see Him with big eyes, is a big thing.</font><br />
These kinds of Great Saints we had.<br />
When they were alive, then they were tortured, that you have to accept.<br />
Now they are not here. Whatever happened it happened.<br />
But now also, how you are behaving‽ Are we behaving as per them?<br />
In Maharashtra so many Saints were there.<br />
There is one group, Śhiva Senā [Party] is created [on 1966-0619]. Some others are also created. This kind of dirty things we are doing now.<br />
<font color="red">I want to say it means what it's not a political thing, but to envy someone or think bad about others or seeing someone less than you or big than you, etc., these things should not happen by [to] devotees of Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. Let other people do that.<br />
Keeping Sāī's Photo at home and say[ing] that, 'Hindus, Muslims are different'! That kind of thing you can't spread. Admitted that Muslims are bad that they have done something wrong or harassed someone, admitted Hindus are bad [that] they have harassed someone! But when you are keeping His Photo, where you stand? You are at His Feet.</font><br />
But if you are a disciple of anyone, fine.<br />
<font color="red">But if you are a disciple of Sāī, then you are all one. Then you don't have to have different feelings.</font><br />
......<br />
<font color="red">Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth was great.</font><br />
I have seen today's Śhaṅkarāchārya. None of them are realized.<br />
<font color="red">It's different about Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, He and Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth are one.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1976-0531 Public Program (Marathi), Sahajyog Sgalyāṃnā Samagra Karto (Sahaja Yoga Makes Everyone Holistic), Matunga, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The left-hand side, as I told you, is the emotional feeling about things, you see. <br />
<font color="red">Uh-uh-uh-uh you feel tremendous love for others and the sometimes, you know, people ... I would say Sāī ... Sāī Nāth was uh one of them who had uh this left-hand side gift with Him. And He was love personified. And uh-uh-uh. I meam, He was so much uh-uh-uh ... full of love for people that once there was in a woman who was very poor and she couldn't celebrate her uh Diwālī Day and He couldn't bear it. So, He gave her some water and the water became like a oil and she burnt ... lights in that.</font><br />
And it's a fact, you can do that, it's possible.<br />
And with this power, you can increase food, sort of thing, you see. You increase the food stuff, you are going to some, like Christ did it, you see. That's also [using] one [left] side.<br />
So these, all these things come in a personality: uh-uh-uh some people have one more, another has some more, and some people have all these qualities. <br />
Some, those who are Incarnations have everything. They can do everything that They want to. And They will use whatever They want to do and if They don't want use any powers They will not use."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0126 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (28th Republic Day), Day 1, Questions on Chakras, Bordi, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"Some great gurus too like Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī, was also an Incarnation. He smoked a funnel shaped clay pipe for smoking chilam [hookah]. Now everybody started smoking a pipe. Are you Sāī Nāth? He would smoke, so that you do not come in contact with chilam [hookah] at all. He smoked everybody's chilam [hookah] once for all. He would smoke to digest everybody's chilam [hookah]. Have you got the power to smoke chilam [hookah]? He could not be attacked by cancer."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1977-0216 Śhivarātri Pūjā (Hindi), Śhivajī Ke Ūpara Sārā Saṃsāra Nirbhara Hai (The Whole World Is Dependent on Śhivajī), New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"I have told you about Nābhī chakra and also about Void. The Guru Principle resides in this Bhavasāgara [Void] and this Guru Principle establishes the dharma within us. These ten petals here that we have shown are the ones which establishes the Ten Dharmas within us.<br />
It is important to have these Ten Dharmas in a human being otherwise he is not a human being. Even if he has has nine dharmas in him is still [<font color="orange">unclear</font>] a bit and if he does not follow these dharmas that are within him, and when I say dharma I don't mean by Christianity, Islam, Hinduism, and all that, but dharma means the Innate Dharma of humanity within, if one does not keep to those Ten Dharmas, then he turns into a demon [devil].<br />
<font color="red">This Guru Principle (Tattwa) has taken birth in this world in many forms especially it has these Ten Main Incarnations have taken birth like Rāja Janaka, Nāṇak, Muhammad Sāhab, etc. and at the end it was Sāī Nāth from Śhirḍī, who took birth. They tie this Tattwa [Principle] within us because all these Gurus who have taken birth for our evolution are placed within us.</font><br /> 
[<font color="orange">unclear</font>] these Gurus are very subtly placed Deities within us.<br />
Like for these Guru already say, "Don't consume alcohol," then They weren't mad that They said this. Neither They were standing in any elections to win votes that They said that. You can't even say that They had any kind of business that in some competitive feeling He said that thing.<br />
They said, "Child, don't drink alcohol, don't take to cigarettes, don't take any kind of drugs," because the position of our attention within is also placed in the area of Void.<br />
You will be surprised to know that our attention is in our stomach. Actually, to be specific, in liver resides our attention.<br />
They said, "You don't drink alcohol," so your attention does not get spoiled. You know by drinking human awareness gets damaged.<br />
People got the other way by saying, 'OK, if drinking is not allowed then let's not garlic, onions, etc.' Prophet Muhammad used to eat garlic, onions and also Nāṇaka used to eat meat and all that."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-0131 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Void, Heart, Viśhuddhi, Channels, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now we have got Ten Dharmas within us which we have to keep all right. These are the main Ten Commandments.<br />
<font color="red">These Ten Commandments we have to look after, and these are looked after by the people who are these, the Primordial Masters, as you call Them Incarnations Divinely: like Rāja Janaka, like Moses, like Socrates, like Nāṇaka, the last one was the Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth. This is the Principle is there, is the Primordial Master.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1978-1015 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Zen and Void, Part 1, First Western Seminar, Day 2, Session 2 (during and after tea and coffee), Conference Center, East Hampstead Park (near Workingham, 60 kms W of London), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In Delhi there is Hazrat Nizamuddin, he is a realized Soul. He is realized for everyone in the world. He is not the property of someone's father.<br />
<font color="red">Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī was Muslim but He was realized. He was not only realized but Ihe incarnation of Dattātreya.</font><br />
How will you know about it? Till you are not realized, how will you know that you are Muslim or we are Hindu?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0109 Public Program (Hindi), Day 2, Kuṇḍalinī yā Cīja hai aura Usakā Jāgraṃ Kaise Hotā Hai (What is Kuṇḍalinī and How is Its Awakening), Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"It is surprising that there is a gentleman in Rangoon who is an Avadhūta. Not only in India, but they can be found all around the world. Prophet Muhammad was an Avadhūta. King Janaka was an Avadhūta, so was Nāṇak.<br />
Many of them [Avadhūtas] did a lot of work in this Maharashtra. It is only because of their work here did I take My birth in this place.<br />
<font color="red">Sāī Nāth was the last of them from Maharashtra.</font><br />
Their work establishes the dharma. Or more like the dharma settles down in that place. They take their form on this earth only to fulfill that goal.<br />
When the human loses his faith in dharma, 'Why should I do this?', when he starts thinking this ways, then the Avadhūtas take birth on this Earth. And wherever they may be, in forests or mountains, dead or alive, all they do is keep working on giving you the validations of dharma.<br />
If you tell lies and start suffering from its consequences, then realize that there is some Avadhūta, sitting on some mountain in the Himalayas, who is responsible for whatever is happening to you. He is the one putting you all right.<br />
......<br />
But the concepts of dharma, as this world knows it today, are so complicated and twisted, "I don't drink, I don't even consume garlic." "Is it so? OK, you don't drink, you don't eat garlic, onions, etc., you don't do anything, granted. Then why is your Void catching?" Void meaning where Dattā [Śhrī Dattātreya] resides, in the stomach. "But I am a huge opponent of Muslims." That's it: you have lost your quality of Avadhūta. The Avadhūtas have been offended.<br />
<font color="red">These entities, say Muhammad, or Janaka, or Sāī Nāth, do you think any of these belong to any religion, caste or creed?<br />
Say, we keep a Photograph of Sāī Nāth in our home, who was He? Wasn't He a Muslim? Be truthful.</font><br /> 
So if someone becomes a Muslim, he turns bad, how did you form this conclusion? Who was Kabīr Dās? Who was Nāṇak?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0122 Public Program (Marathi), Ātmyālā Miḍavilyāhśivāya Parameśhwar or Avadhūtas, YMCA Hall, New Link Road, D.N. Nagar, Andheri West (14 kms NW of Mumbai), Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In London, I have seen, that you cannot go out without wearing a coat! You have to have a central heated house, otherwise you'll die. You have to struggle all the time.<br /> 
That is the reason people have paid their attention outside to overcome the natural uh problems.<br />
While in this country, there is no need.<br />
<font color="red">That's why in our country only these great people like Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, like Nāṇaka, like Kabīra, like uh-uh-uh recently our Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, and all these people were born because there you can live just in the jungle.</font> You don't have to pay much attention to your well-being here, you can get everything nicely.<br />
This is the reason why Indians are so much religious. Their attention is religious, their traditions are religious, we started religion.<br />
But we have got such a big heritage, but where are we looking forward to? America and to Russia? Just go and see yourself how they are, then you will never look forward to them.<br />
We have to look forward to Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya, we have to look forward to our Nāṇak, and to our great Saints, those who lived in complete joy, peace and happiness. That is our heritage.<br />
We are not to play and go behind these horrible things like casinos and things, that's ... gives no joy, otherwise why are they [foreign seekers] here?<br />
We have to manifest our own, project our own ... our own image, which is actually based on the Self-realization only, nothing else. Let us be proud of it that we have got this heritage.<br />
And they are not going to respect you unthen ... un ... unless and until you are yourself."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0209 Public Talk for Westerners and Westernized Indians, Holiness Is the Basis of Religion and Spirituality (Religion Is Within Not Without), Program Organized by the Government of India, Day 3, Kovalam (18 kms S of Thiruvananthapuram), Kerala, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<b>Version 1:</b><br />
"We are all very thankful to the citizens of Ahmednagar for inviting us so lovingly.<br />
Moreover, Ahmednagar district feels special to Me. This is because work that started in Rāhūrī and spread across makes one realize that there is something especially religious that has happened in this district before.<br />
As is, Maharashtra is a very spiritual environment. Because of that, many Saints have been born here and they have worked here.<br />
<font color="red">At the very end if we recall, Sāī Nāth as you know has done beautiful work in Ahmednagar district.</font><br />
......<br />
Now, living by the dharma doesn't mean making rounds of the temple and reciting the name of God a thousand.<br />
The meaning of dharma has been told by a number of Saints in this country. In this Land of Saints, a number of Gurus have come and have spoken to great lengths about what dharma is, we can't thank Them enough. But we don't follow any of what They have said.<br />
Out of all the Gurus, there have been Ten Important Ones and They have come in this world multiple times. The Prophet Muhammad is an incarnation of Dattātreya. After Muhammad Sāhib, Nāṇak who came on this Earth was an incarnation of Dattātreya too, so was Janak. Likewise Ādināth, who came before Māhavīr, was also an incarnation of Dattātreya. <font color="red">Furthermore, the people of this Ahmednagar are extremely fortunate in the sense that Śhirḍī [84 kms NNW from Ahmadnagar] was the place where Śhrī Sāī Nāth chose to come and stay. He too was an incarnation of Dattātreya.</font> So, it is the same element of the Guru, which keeps reincarnating on this Earth.<br />
They focused on teaching about things pertaining to maintaining the balance of the dharma, They didn't talk much about Self-realization as such, didn't work upon giving knowledge about the Ātmā to people.<br />
The one thing that all of Them had said was to not consume alcohol.<br />
......<br />
And such false people have always been the ones to trouble the Saints. You know, how badly such people have caused misery to Dñyāneśhwar. <font color="red">Then, Sāī Nāth.</font> They have not spared even a single Saint.<br />
Not only that, [but] when Śhaṅkarāchārya wanted to perform the rituals after the death of His mother, these people didn't even allow Him to do those. They said He was not allowed to do them as He was a saṃnyāsī.<br />
So, likewise, such unauthorized people claiming to be higher above others have always insulted the Saints and made their lives miserable. Not only in India, but also elsewhere -- Prophet Muhammad was tortured by such people as well. He and His family were tortured so much more than Dñyāneśhwar, actually."<br /> 
<b>Version 2:</b><br />
"The people of Ahmednagar sent us an invitation with lot of affection, we are all very grateful for that.<br />
And furthermore, I feel Ahmednagar District to be very special. Because the work that began in Rāhūrī and which kept spreading, that made Me realize that there was some special religious work that took place in this District in the past.<br />
Also, Maharashtra is a spiritual region. Hence a lot of Saints have taken birth over here and have done a lot of work.<br />
<font color="red">Finally, to mention as we all know, Śhrī Sāī Nāth has done beautiful work in Ahmednagar District.</font><br />
......<br />
To live with dharma does not mean parroting the name of God in the temples.<br />
The meaning of being religious has been explained by a number of Saints in this country. In this land of Saints, a number of Gurus have come and have spoken to great lengths about what dharma is, we can't thank Them enough. But we don't follow any of what They have said.<br />
Out of all the gurus, there have been Ten Important Ones and They have come in this world multiple times. Of these the Prophet Muhammad is an Incarnation of Dattātreya. After Muhammad Sāhib, Nāṇak who came on this earth was an Incarnation of Dattātreya too, so was Janak. Likewise Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], who came before Mahāvīr, was also an Incarnation of Dattātreya. <font color="red">After this we were really lucky, specially people from Ahmadnagar, that Sāī Nāth who stayed in Śhirḍī [84 kms NNW from Ahmadnagar], He too is an Incarnation of Dattātreya.</font> So, it is the same element of the Guru, which reappears on this Earth.<br />
And They taught several things regarding the balance of dharma. They didn't talk much about giving Realization as such. They did not work too much on giving knowledge on Self-enlightenment to people.<br />
The one thing He said, that all of [Ten of] Them corroborate on, was not to consume alcohol.<br />
......<br />
And such spurious people, they have always tormented the Saints. You know, how badly such people have caused misery to Dñyāneśhwara. <font color="red">Then, Sāī Nāth.</font> They have not spared anyone.<br />
Not only that, when Śhaṅkarāchārya, Ādi Śhaṅkarāchārya went home when his mother died and He wanted to perform the final rituals, these people told him that, "You cannot perform as you are a saṃnyāsī." And nobody turned up for the final rituals. In Kālaṭi village He cut the tree and ignited the banana tree and performed the rituals. And He cursed entire Kerala that, "You would perform the final rituals in front of your homes and bury the dead body there." Even today same thing is happening.<br />
So, likewise, such unauthorized people have insulted all the Saints and monks. Not only in our country, but in most of the countries.<br />
Even during the times of Prophet Muhammad, peace be upon Him, the unauthorized people tortured and persecuted Him immensely. If we describe that we get to know that when compared to Muhammad Sāhib and family, even Dñyāneśhwara was not tortured so much. They tried to destroy Them totally."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0223 Public Program (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti ani Sat Chakra (Kuṇḍalinī Śhakti and the Seven Chakras), Ahmednagar, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So the dharma that has been established in us by God Almighty because if we want to go to the Kingdom of God, then in our freedom we must desire to get to God. If someone tries to pressurize us and says, 'You must ask for God,' then it is of no use, it is not an evaluation. That is why to reach in this state, a person has to seek the God as per his own independent sweet will and not due to any pressure, or any disease or any hardships or any sorrow, but only because of the fact and realizing that, 'It is the only motive of our life to seek God.'<br />
<font color="red">That is why, when we desire for this Divine Gift, then the doors of God Almighty's Divine Blessings open for you, and around the center is a place of Ten Primordial Gurus. These are the Main Gurus which are the Incarnation[s] of Śhri Dattātreya. They are: Socrates, Moses, Muhammad Sāhab, Guru Nāṇak, Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, and Zoroaster. They are all Incarnation[s] of one Incarnation.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0322 Public Program (Hindi), Sahaja Yoga and the Subtle System, Biralā Krīṛā Keṃdra, Chowpatty, Girgaum Chowpatty, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India (other date 0321)</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"About Me also you can ask questions. There are many ways of recognizing because in this life, you have to recognize. You have never recognized an Incarnation so far. You have to recognize.<br />
That is compulsory and that is done through Sahajs Yoga because unless and until you are realized, how are going to recognize Them also?<br />
But even if you have not recognized Them, there was no need for you to crucify Them or to torture.<br />
Then all the Gurus who came on this Earth, the Real Ones -- fakes are never gurus, they are not gurus -- the Real Ones that came on this Earth, say, we can say Moses, Abraham, Nāṇak, Muhammad Sāhib, Kabīr, all these are Incarnations of Primordial Master whom we call as Dattātreya.<br />
If They are or not, if Muhammad Sāhib and Guru Nāṇak are the same personality, same people who came in different times, then what justice are we doing to Them? How are we to find out? How are you to believe Me about it?<br />
I will give you an example. There was a Muslim gentleman from Iran who came to see Me, who was suffering from cancer. He asked Me: "Mother, I want to get cured." I said, "You['re] a Muslim?", he said, "Yes, I only believe in Muhammad Sāhib and nobody else!" I said, "This would be something like that, 'I only believe in my nose, and not in anything else.' "<br />
He was such a fanatic and fanaticism brings about the cancer of Nābhī chakra as we call it, the stomach. You will be amazed fanaticism is sin, sinful. It gives you the cancer of stomach.<br />
I asked him, "Will you worship Nāṇak Sāhib?" He said, "No, why should I? I am a Muslim." I said, "Do you know Muhammad Sāhib Himself is angry with you and you have to worship Nāṇak?"<br />
He would not but it happened for months and then he had to accept.<br />
Any extreme behavior of this kind is prohibited in all the religions.<br />
<font color="red">When Nāṇak came or when even our Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth came, They talked about sadāchār.</font> Even the Goddess's name is Sadāchār Pravartakā [Founder/Source of Good Conduct].<br /> 
Sadāchār is the most important thing. The dhana [treasure] is the most important thing. One has to be in dharma. If you are adharmī, how do you expect Me to give you Realization, you just tell Me?<br />
Today I went to see a tailor of Mine who was saying, "Mother, if I am bad You tell me but why should not I get Realization?" I said, "True, why should not you? All right ask a question, 'Mother, are you Nāṇak?' " He asked Me the question. Normally the vibrations start but would not. He said, "What has happened to me?" I said, "See where is your Surati?"<br />
Nāṇak has described Kuṇḍalinī as Surati.<br />
His Kuṇḍalinī was pulsating at Nābhī. You could see with your naked eye. His friend or his proprietor was also seeing that. It was pulsating there.<br /> 
I said, "You have a liver. Do you drink?" He said, "I drink quite a lot." Then I said, "How do you expect Me to give you Realization in the name of Nāṇak who has prohibited all this?"<br />
When I say this people brand Me as anything."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0328 Public Address, Inauguration of The Advent (Guḍhī Pāḍavā Day), FICCI Auditorium, 1 Tansen Mārg, New Delhi, India from Anant Jeevan, Issue 1 (July 1979), Pages 5--12</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"So, if you think evolution is a religion, then I would say Sahaja Yoga is the religion. If your evolution if you call it as a religion, then Sahaja Yoga is a religion. But is a religion which takes you belo ... beyond your sustenance, beyond your religion, dharmātīt, beyond the dharma.<br />
We have amongst ourselves Hindu[s], Muslims, Christians, all kinds of people, you know that. All these people can feel it within themselves: is the religion in their stomachs, they can feel it. They can find out where is the religion. Because, I say, there, religion in the stomach is looked after by the Deities of Primordial Master whom we call as Dattātreya, in the Sanskrit language.<br />
But does't mean Hinduism. It doesn't mean Hinduism at all. But it is called as Dattātreya in the Sanskrit language, in English is Primordial Master.<br />
<font color="red">He is the same who incarnated on this earth: as Moses, as Abraham, and, say, incarnated as Muhammad Sāhab, as Rāja Janaka, as Nāṇaka, and also as Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth.</font> Can you believe that Muhammad Sāhab is the same as our Nāṇak?"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0507 Public Program, Sahaja Yoga and Christianity, Bharatiya Vidyā Bhavan, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But still, as you can see in the life of Christ, that coming of Christ was declared much before Christ came in by the Prophets who made prophecies. All these Prophets belong to the category of the Gurus I am talking about.<br />
So, all over the world three types of movements were on. For example, the scientist[s] on the right-hand side, we can say, and the left-hand side are the devotees of God who sing the praise of God. And in the center there were people like Moses, like Abraham, who came on this earth just to prophesize, just to protect the devotees of God.<br />
Now this middle movement of evolution, today, has reached its peak. Because all the Incarnations have arrived now, and have done Their job within you. They have occupied Their position within you, in your awareness, on these different centers. <br />
......<br />
So today we are here to know that within us all these Incarnations exist, and the force that really brought forth, really manifested, who live like human beings and work like Gurus, that force which existed in this area, which created religion within us.<br />
Religion, as we understand, organized religion, is not the religion. But the religion means: your sustaining power. You are a human being because there are ten sustaining powers within you.<br />
So, They came to sustain us and to give us full idea about these Ten Powers and to establish us in our religion as a human being.<br />
So these Gurus, who lived in that area, worked out the sustainace [sustenance] and helped us.<br />
And this is one of the greatest forces we have got, which resides within us.<br />
And whatever They have said has a very great meaning.<br />
Actually, we should say the Main Gurus are ten, but there are many other Gurus.<br />
<font color="red">And these Ten Gurus could be described as Rāja Janaka, then Moses, Abraham, and the in modern times you can say Muhammad Sāhab, and even up to Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, in Śhirḍī, that force came in, for a short time, and then He disappeared. Nobody knows how He came there, He lived there and He died.</font> Also, if you know Nāṇaka, He was also the same force, the same Primordial Master, who was born on this Earth.<br />
Now, this is not the time to tell about individual people. But, I think, one day I will talk to you only on this subject of the Gurus.<br />
So, these Gurus first started under the Primordial Master Himself, He was called as Dattātreya.
......<br />
There's one more point I would like to tell you, that they have not yet gone here, but here [], there are the two uh more small uh-uh-uh chakras: one that belongs to, uh uh which we call as the Sūrya -- Sūrya is the-uh-uh uh uh, means the Sun, the Sun center -- and the another as the Moon center on the left-hand side. And these two are uh governed or, we can say, is uh bestowed upon by two great uh-uh-uh people, who are the Disciple Elements.<br />
And They, disciple elements were first, were born to Śhrī Rāma and Śhrī Sītā as the-ee Lav and Kuśh. And then They incarnated many a times on this Earth as disciple. One of Them is, we can say, ah ... was uh Śhaṅkarāchārya, another was Kabīra, uh like that. Then, we can say, later on, uh like, uh before Śhaṅkarāchārya, they came as Buddha and Mahāvīra. Then Śhaṅkarāchārya, and then, uh I told you, which is? Uh after Śhaṅkarāchārya came ... the Advent of Hasan and Husayn, who were the grandsons of Prophet.<br />
So these have been incarnating, and they have been moving from one uh-uh-uh side to another and telling people that, "This is extreme, leave it." "This is the extreme, leave it. Come in the center, and be in the center." That has been Their job. And they are the ones who are, sort of, imparting you that awareness by you become a perfect disciple.<br />
And the ... this is a very important point because it comes, quite often, that uh-uh-uh we do not understand.<br /> 
Like Prophet Muhammad said that: "I am the last Prophet." All right, He did say He was the last Prophet.<br />
Supposing I say, I am the last person to come here. All right I would say just to frighten you that, 'h-oh, you better take to it otherwise this is the last time I am telling you!' [Laughs.]<br />
But it is never that!<br />
Because when He wa... died He found out: that, you see, these people are madcaps. 'I didn't tell them this, what are they doing out of Me?' So, He said, 'I better go back again.'<br />
And He came as Nāṇaka. And He told them, that: "Hindu and Muslims are same people, following the same religion, why are you fighting among yourselves?" See, They came for that unity.<br />
Then as Nāṇaka He came. So, in Nāṇaka's system also the Sikhism came in and they started a warrior class and this and that. I mean imagine, the Sikhism ended up by having wars within Muslims and Hindus.<br />
<font color="red">So, then He came as Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth to teach them.</font><br />
Now, this is not a very important thing that, say Muhammad Sāhab said, "I am the last." Say He is the last, all right, even take that position. Who are you to Him? How are you related? Through what? What is your authority? How do you appropriate Him to yourself? Because you say you are Muslims, so what? How did you become Muslims? Did you get your certificate from God?"<br /> 
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0530 Public Program, A Higher Life, A World of Bliss and Joy (The Three Paths of Evolution), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Around that, is that area where actually it exists in the stomach of God, we can say, this is the Bhavasāgara. This is what we have to cross. You see there's a Void, from there to there is a Void, and this we have to cross. And this is the thing which is crossed by the Kuṇḍalinī awakening.<br />
<font color="red">Now what happens? That around that uh ... that ... water-like thing that you see there, see that is the one where Ten ... the Primordial Masters were born, Gurus, Primordial Gurus. Now They were incarnated of innocence of all this three aspects. And They were incarnated on this Earth, say, from Abraham, Moses, then we had uh-uh-uh ... up to Muhammad Sāhab we can say, then we can say Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, then Nāṇaka, Janaka, all these people incarnated as Gurus.</font><br />
Now what do They do? They, They, They give you sustainance [sustenance]. They give you sustainance [sustenance].<br />
Now, sustenance is ... is ... for human beings is different. For animals is different."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0618 Conversation with Sahaja Yogis, Questions and Answers, Jim Proctor's House, Cookridge (10 kms NW of Leeds), UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"When Śhrī Rām came, people said that they accepted Paraśhurām, when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came they said, they accepted Śhrī Rām, and at the time of Śhrī Nāṇaka, they accepted Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa. When Christ was here they accepted Abraham.<br />
All of Them had taken human form. But it is all the play of buddhi: how interesting it is!<br />
<font color="red">Now, I have come and people are accepting Śhrī Sāī Nāth.<br />
But when He lived here, He did not even get anything to eat. Why was it so? He was also a human being. As long as He was alive, He too was considered useless and tortured. But when He died, He was regarded as Bhagavān.</font><br />
What is the reason of this all? Why has man been like this?<br />
You will have water of the Ganges, where She flows. If She is flowing here, will you say, 'We do not accept Her as the Ganges!'? There may be nothing at the place where She was flowing earlier, or maybe only a nullah [ravine] at present. If you want to take it as the Ganges, you go your way. If the Ganges is flowing at this place, why not accept it?<br />
It is not easy to understand human intellect. It is the most difficult job in the world! It is easy to understand God, because He is what He is. He does not have such double dealings. Man has a variety of qualities, not just double. All animals from snakes and scorpions to elephants, horses and lions are residing in him. You will not understand at all, why his brain is working in this way.<br />
Now when the Ganges is flowing why don't you take water from Her?<br />
Imagine this plug has been connected here. Will you connect in its place a plug which is out of order? It is quite pragmatic.<br />
I cannot understand what hallucination is there on human intellect, that he does not accept the Truth which he is seeing but accepts something that is not seen?
Its reason was understood long back and that is ahaṅkār [ego]. Man has too much of ego.<br />
If you had accepted Śhrī Rāma in His days, He would have told you to get your Kuṇḍalinī awakened and get the Realization and get established in Sahaja Yoga.<br />
Had you recognized Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, He would not have played Sahaja Yoga in Gokul, but would have given you the Realization and told you to practice Sahaja Yoga.<br />
If Śhrī Nāṇak had been accepted, there was no need for Him to break His head telling you to do different things. He would have simply taught Sahaja Yoga, but very few understood Him in His days.<br />
Now, when He is not here, you have built gurudwārās in His name.<br />
When Muhammad is not here mosques have been made, because they think now Muhammad Sāhib is in their hands.<br />
Now Rāma is in their hands, and they can make His temple and say, 'His is our temple, this Rāma is our property. We have authority over Him and whatever you have brought, all money and other things, offer them to this idol.'<br />
You say all this because you think you are the authority of this idol. It is sheer ego because of which man thinks, that he can keep God in his control and for that he is making all the show. Every time the same show was repeated."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0818 Public Program (Hindi), Ātmā and Paramātma, Saradār Patel Vidyalaya (School), Lodi Estate, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, through Sahaja Yoga you will come to know about the problems. How to balance its integrity? How to awaken Ādi Guru Dattātreya within?<br />
Once Dattātreya is awakened within you, then the religion will spontaneously gets awakened. Then it becomes very difficult to do adharma.<br />
The most important thing is that all these Gurus said that, "You should know it."<br />
First thing is that human being should not be addicted to any drug or intoxicant.<br />
<font color="red">They say that Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth used to smoke. He was different.</font><br />
But you don't have to smoke. Any addiction whether it is wine, tobacco, liquor, etc. all are against your Guru Tattwa.<br />
Why you should not drink? Because by drinking, your dharma and Guru Tattwa are damaged."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0924 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Marathi), Kuṇḍalinī, Śhrī Śhivaśhakti and Śhrī Viṣhṇuśhakti, Navarātri Celebrations (3rd Day), Amar Hind Mandal, West Dadar, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Some people degrade the relationship with God to the lowest level. <font color="red">At one place, I observed on an advertisement board: 'Śhrī Sāī Nāth Bidi'. To use the name of God in such filthy manner is an outright insult of Him.</font><br /> 
By relating every petty and mundane things with God, you commit great sins. You should know this.<br /> 
<font color="red">'Sāī Nāth Bidi' or 'Lakṣhmī Hing', advertising like this is an insult of God.</font><br /> 
What do these people gain by doing so? Some people say that, "Mother, this will do us good." What is this good? By that expression they mean they get more money. If a business is carried in this fashion, one or the other day it would surely bring them in trouble. This is the insult of God."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-0927 Talk to Sahaja Yogis (Hindi), Kuṇḍalinī and Lord Jesus Christ, Navarātri Celebrations (6th Day), Hinduja Auditorium, Mumbai, Maharashtra, India</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And the, he had uh ... uh started, you see, doing some sort of tricks which I did feel about him that he had started doing some tricks about uh his Realization. Because that's the only thing one has to be very careful, that one can get into. And the, he had uh sp... gathered spirits, because he got interested in curing too much. I told him not to cure anymore. I said, "You can give My Photograph but don't get into curing part, because if you get the spirits you wouldn't even know and will you be insensitive to it. And then you'll have problems." And then he had such funny spirits in him that those people who came to him, you see, were influenced to give him money by those spirits. And the some people were compelled, I mean they couldn't help it. The only idea that worked into their heads was that they must give money to him.<br />
<font color="red">But uh this was nothing, he started showing My Photograph in the eyes and a Photograph of Sāī Bābā in the eyes and all sorts of nonsensical things.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1008 Public Program, Maintaining Purity of Sahaja Yoga, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"But there is a group of people, still, who have been realized, and who are not, yet, there. Now what is the difference between the two is? In very simple: is the recognition. Those who have not recognized Me, will not be blessed. They'll be going round and round and round. So, it is necessary to recognize.<br />
<font color="red">Now there are some people, like, we ... I'll say, very good example is, Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth's disciples are there. Now He is no more. So they believe in Him. Now where is He?</font><br />
They don't want to believe in the present Incarnation! They want to believe in something that is dead. They believe in Rāma. They'll believe in Christ. Most of the Christians have this problem.<br />
Even they will relate Me only to Christ. If I cannot relate Myself to Christ they cannot be in Sahaja Yoga. Or they'll relate Me, only to Moses, or to someone like that.<br />
You have to live in the present."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1979-1202 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, before and during a Meal after Guru Pūjā, Living Room, Āśhram, 8, Hamilton Road, Dollis Hill, London NW10 1NX, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Apart from that, there is [a] third type of Incarnations which worked [pointing to the Void on the Chakra Chart:] in this gap: to sustain us. These are Ten Pri... Primordial Masters, the Ādi Guru. These people incarnated on this Earth to give us our sustainance [sustenance], our religion as they call it. They gave us those Ten Religions or sustainance [sustenance] which is important for a human being.<br />
<font color="red">This Principle of Primordial Master incarnated as Abraham, as Moses, as Muhammad Sāhab, as Janaka, as Nāṇaka, and recently, till recently, the One who is no more a now, is Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth.</font><br />
[During the translation helps with the enumeration:] Muh... mhh. Socrates. Nāṇaka.<br />
Yes.<br />
<font color="red">Now, these people are Incarnation[s] of the one Principle, that is Primordial Master.<br /> 
The energy or the power with which They work[ed] is either a sister or a daughter: is a very pure relationships.<br /> 
If you read Their teachings you will find [that] They are saying the same things. Because They were worried about our sustainance [sustenance].</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0419 Public Program, Day 4, Spiritual Evolution of Man, Paris, France</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"For example, we can say the gree... green thing is the one that represents the water, water element. This center the ... in the stomach is the water element within us. It is called as Nābhī chakra, and around it is called as the Bhavasāgara, you can say the Void, or you can say the Gap, or whatever you may say, the whole world as such, within us. So, the people who were born on this center, around this center, were born out of water element.<br />
<font color="red">In this Bhavasāgara -- oc... Bhavasāgara means the ocean of this world -- were born, through this ocean of the world, were born all the Primordial Masters, one after another. We can say Abraham, Moses, we had Janaka, were Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], and Socrates, and so many others like that, Nāṇaka, and also very recently, we had about hundred years back, a very great Saint born in India known as Sāī Nāth.<br />
They all represent the same element that is the water element. Being responsible or being born out of that, They are anxious to maintain water element as the one which is within us for sustaining ourselves. We su... we are sustained by water, so They help us to sustain ourselves. They are the sustainers: They tell us how to sustain us as a human being.<br />
And all of Them have tried to establish religion within us.</font><br />
A religion doesn't mean outside, but the religion as a man: means the capacity of a man, or you can say the quality of a man. What a human being should be like, what is the way to know if he is a human being or not, which is described in al... in the Ten Commandments."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0421 Public Program, What Is Second Birth, Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now, all the Gurus, all the Gurus who came, say from ... we can start from Socrates, then Abraham, Moses, this is the Guru Tattwa, is the Principle of Master, Primordial Masters. The Principle is born again and again. In India we can say the Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], we had one Ādināth, the Guru long time back. <font color="red">Then we had Dattātreya, we had uh Janaka, Nāṇaka, Sāī Nāth.</font> We had in the Middle East Muhammad Sāhab, Lao Tze in China, Confucius. <font color="red">All these Great Principles of Gurus who were born, They had one job to do is to establish your dharma. Their job was not to give you Realization.</font><br />
You must understand: everyone has one's own job. See, Mine is a horrible job [laughing:] because I have to do everybody's jobs.<br />
<font color="red">But Their job was just to establish your dharma. They came at that time in those places where it was needed the most.<br />
So, these Ten Principles, as I told you, They established [dharma].</font><br /> 
<font color="red">They are created in the Void.</font><br />
As you see here the Void part, this part is made out of the water element. <font color="red">So, whatever miracles They did, had something to do with water, like They could create water anywhere They wanted to. They would not cure people. All of Them have created water in the desert or in the places where ... like in ... Nāṇaka has created a Pan̄jā Sāhab they call it, or everywhere They have been able to create water. Whatever They touched, They could create water out of it.</font><br />
Water is the life, life force which sustains us. Without water we cannot live! The is the sustainance [sustenance].<br />
<font color="red">But, They actually are symbolized in an ocean, in the ocean, because They give us the salt, the salt of life, which gives us the sustainance [sustenance].</font> If you see the salt, if we do not have salt in our body, we'll have no sustainance [sustenance]."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1980-0728 Public Program, The Principle of Guru (Moderation Is the Way We Really Solve the Problem and The Innocence Is in the Center), Sea is the Guru (The Sea Is to Be Worshiped and So Much to Learn from the Sea) and Your Dharma Is the Way Your Attention Is (Dharma Is Balancing), Caxton Hall, 10 Caxton Street, Westminster, London, UK</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"And these Ten Sustainances [Sustenances] are represented by Great Prophets. The Principle is called as Ādi Guru, in Sanskrit language, the Primordial Master. <font color="red">He had incarnated on this Earth as Abraham, Moses, as Lao Tze, as Confucius, as Socrates.</font> Recently, He has been as Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī, not the other fellow, and other great people have been like Nāṇaka, Janaka.<br />
All these Great Saints can ... came on this Earth to tell us: how to keep in the center, how to keep our sustenance, how to be human beings.<br />
As carbon has got four valances, we too have got ten valances. We have to maintain those ten valances within us! That's what they came to tell us."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1981-0325 Public Program, Cycle 1, Day 2, Mūlādhāra and Swādhiṣhṭhāna Chakras, Maccabean Hall, 146, Darlinghurst Road, Darlinghurst (eastern suburb of Sydney), New South Wales, Australia</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>
<p>[<font color="orange">WARNING: Quotes for the period 1980-01 to 2000-09 will follow in due time.</font>]</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"Now when this center is illumined, around it is illumined your sustainance [sustenance]. That's your Inner Religion.<br />
The ... we call it Ten Incarnations of the Primordial Master. There are many who came, but the Ones who came in India was called as Brahmadeva uh ... was called as Dattātreya, Janaka, Rāja Janaka, the father of Sītā. In China, Lao Tze, Confucius. In uh, in the Bible, Abraham and Moses. And later on, in the uh form of uh Muhammad Sāhab. And then Janaka. No, no, Nāṇaka, I'm sorry, Nāṇaka. Nāṇak Sāhab. And in Greece, it was Socrates. They took birth on all these places. <font color="red">In the end, about fifty years back, or hundred years back, was born Great Primordial Master, in India, in Śhirḍī.<br />
[Helping with the translation:] In Śhirḍī.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1983-0831 Public Program, Day 3, Geneva, Switzerland</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
<font color="red">"As we had very great people ... uh ... on this Earth, I have given you the names, as we said there are, there have been Ten Gurus, uh ... starting from Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], we had Confucius, we had Socrates, and later on we had Abraham, Moses and also up to Śhirḍī Sāī Nāth, we had about Ten Great Gurus, now we have so many here sitting down. They are all gurus, and they have to behave like gurus and they have to the ... do the job of great gurus."</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b>1988-0731 Guru Pūjā, The First Principle of the Guru Is the Gravity (First Thing and Foremost Thing Is that We Must Have Gravity in Temperament and Value System of a Balance and You Have to Become the Fruits of Sahaja Yoga), Tent, Grounds around Annapurna Atiram Aparthotel, Pont d'Ansalonga, Ansalonga, Andorra</b></font>
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">""</font><br />
<font size="+0"><b></b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The Primordial Master was also born as Macchindranāth, and again as Zoroaster who was worshiped by the ancient Persians, and still revered by Parsis. Earlier He had taken birth as Abraham and later as Moses, the Fathers of Judaism. In China He was born as Confucius and as Lao Tze, and in Greece as Socrates. He took a very significant Incarnation as Muhammad Sāhib, the Messenger (Paigambar) and founder of Islam, whose daughter Fāṭimah was Sītā reborn, an Incarnation of Ādi Śhakti. She was the origin of the Shiya sect among the Muslims (in Indian dialect Sītā is called Shiya). Yet again He took birth as Guru Nāṇak, founder of the Sikh religion, whose sister was Nāṇakī (Jānakī, i.e., Sītā). <font color="red">Most recently He was born as Śhrī Sāī Bābā of Śhirḍī in the Indian State of Maharashtra where He died in 1918.</font> Altogether there were ten major Avatāras of Dattātreya."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 2: Divine Incarnations -- Ambassadors of God, Page 33</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"In this Void is placed the Primordial Master (Ādi Guru) formed from Brahmā, Viṣhṇu and Maheśha (Śhiva). This Primordial Master is also known as Dattātreya. <font color="red">He has taken many human births as a Prophet and teacher, such as Rāja Janaka, Ādināth [Ṛiṣhabhadeva, first Tīrthaṅkara in Jainism], Macchindranāth, Zoroaster, Guru Nāṇaka, and Sāī Nāth of Śhirḍī.</font> This Deity helps human beings to seek their salvation by crossing the Void or Ocean of Illusion within themselves."<br />
<font size="+0"><b>The Book of Ādi Śhakti, Chapter 9: The Creation of Kuṇḍalinī in Human Beings, Pages 124 and 125</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p>
"The Sufis in the real sense were realized Souls. In Turkey I met many who are seeking the Truth. The poetry of Yunus Einre is absolutely heavenly. How could he speak about the Global Religion and about Divine Love? He described man as the most elevated creature created by God in His image. <font color="red">In India we had Nizamuddin Auliya, Amīr Khusaro, Moinuddin Chisti, Kabīr Dās, Śhrī Sāī Nāth Śhirḍī, Kāniphanāth, all saying the same Truth about global unity.</font>"<br />
<font size="+0"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 6: Religions</b></font>
</p>

<div class="para-divider"></div>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ Shri Sai Nath" /><category term="hotpink @ Shri Adi Guru" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>