<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/yearly.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-30T18:09:13-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/yearly.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Yearly</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 27</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0925" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 27" /><published>2022-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_27</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0925"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1017_Asha_and_Peter_Brownscombe_Collection.png" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b></b>The Spirit Tells You What Is The Truth<br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"These two have to meet. They are separated. The Spirit within you, and the Holy Ghost within you, have to meet. That is the Yoga, that's the Union.<br />
......<br />
The Spirit Itself is Sat-chit-ānanda. He e... exists in the State of Truth.<br />
Now, we do not know what Truth is. People say, 'God is Love, God is Truth.' Now what is the Truth? <br />
The Truth is this All-pervading Power. And this All-pervading Power is the nature of the Spirit, which gives you the Absolute Knowledge. Now mark it: Absolute Knowledge.<br />
......<br />
So the first thing you are: you are the Truth! The Spirit tells you what is the Truth. It tells you everything about everything. It is the Truth! The Knowledge that is pure is the Truth!  
......<br />
So the Truth is: everything is illusion, except for the Divine Love of God that is all-pervading, which you can feel through your Spirit.<br />
This power has got telecommunication, It has got all that you have created in the science, It can coordinate and cooperates. It has got all the angels and all the great Souls to help It, and to look after you. And the top, topping the whole thing, is the quality that It loves! It loves you.<br />
So It doesn't come to you like a sword. It gives you the time to improve, to judge yourself, to rise, to grow, just as a mother would look after her child, forgive mistakes, see that the child rises, and grows into complete manhood.<br />
So it is Love! And the love that is so powerful is the Truth. And it never fails. It never fails.<br />
......<br />
The second thing: the nature of Spirit is that He's Chitta, He's the attention. He's the attention means: when you become spiritually enlightened, your attention becomes enlightened.<br />
......<br />
Then the third thing happens: is the [laughing:] joy! That you are in joy all the time. You cannot keep serious for more than two minutes. Is very difficult to keep serious.<br /> 
......<br />
May God bless you to blossom into the beauties of your Spirit, so that you glorify your Father, and He feels glorified with His Gracious Love towards you."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1981-1007 Public Program (9th Day of Navarātri), Day 4, The Spirit, Pyramid, Unity (Church of Christianity), 2929 Unity Drive, Houston, TX, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://youtu.be/sK2yxG3t3L8"> youtube</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=R8M2Gk5RSbo"> youtube</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.<br />
20. To counteract through mass spiritual power the destructive forces against spiritualism such as evil spirits, the cult of hypnotism, siddhis and the use of "religion" for the exploitation of the innocent.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 26 on the Birthday of Mother Mary</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0908" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 26 on the Birthday of Mother Mary" /><published>2022-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_26</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0908"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1013_Photo_credit_Colin_Heinsen.png" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Today Is A Great Auspicious Day Where I am Here On The Birthday Of Mother Mary</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"Today is a great auspicious day where I am here on the Birthday of Mother Mary. But today I am going to talk to you about Reality and about Truth.<br />
......<br />
Today specially, on the special day of Christ['s] Mother's birthday, you should not feel guilty and unhappy or melancholic."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1983-0908 Public Program, Day 1, You Are the Spirit, Sala Borromini, Biblioteca Vallicelliana, Piazza della Chiesa Nuova, 18, Rome, Italy</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
"So She incarnated as Mahālakṣhmī when Rāma came on this Earth, first time.<br />
And also, She incarnated as Rādhā when Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa came on this Earth.<br />
And when She came as Mary, it was Mahālakṣhmī who bore the child that is Lord Jesus Christ. So, the child She bore was the great personality of Mahāviṣhṇu."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1984-0908 Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī Pūjā, Münich, Germany</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/435674791"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1984-0908-mahalakshmi-puja"> soundcloud </a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
21. To unite all genuine Seekers of Truth divided by dogmas and ignorance so that Satya Yuga (the Age of Truth) is born out of the present Kali Yuga (the Age of Darkness) rather than complete annihilation. To harness all the human resources to achieve this great task for which mass evolution will be needed.<br />
22. To open, organize and run local centers of the Life Eternal Institution in various parts of India and in foreign countries, the centers being opened on the distinct understanding that meditation is the path of the entire human destiny, and that all barriers of states, nations and races are artificial and irrelevant to Life Eternal.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 25</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0827" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 25" /><published>2022-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_25</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0827"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image1007_Balwant_Kumbhojkar_Collection.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>In Sahaja Yoga You Become Actually The Person Who Is A Vaiṣhṇava</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"But ah this shows that we should understand Sahaja Yoga, that unless and until we are quiet, unless and until we are in thoughtless awareness, we cannot grow. So, all these extreme behaviors cannot take you to the center.<br />
......<br />
But, you see, marriage is a uh-uh-uh thing for Indians, is that is uh-uh, just like having a baby in the house, you see, just like that. It's a part and parcel. So, they never think that, 'All right, my wife has come, she's short or she's uh fair or dark,' nothing, 'Now she's my wife.' Like your child. Like your child comes in, that's it. So, the ... this is what it is a marriage: this is a wife who has come, the husband is there. Husband is supposed to be a husband, wife is supposed to be a wife, finished. That's a part of the family, we all live together. And the-uh husband is supposed to protect the wife, and the wife is supposed to look after the husband and all the family people and everyone.<br />
......<br />
Is a, once you're married, just accept this is the part of your life, is from your destiny, it's your life ... uh previous lives' things, is just accept the fact. Work it out.<br />
And we don't even work out marriages, they just work out.<br />
......<br />
But, you see, in Sahaja Yoga you become actually the person who is a Vaiṣhṇava, is the one who is in the center. Viṣhṇu's Path: you are neither left nor right. You're on Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa's Path.<br />
So, how can you remain left or right? If you are left or right then you are no more [in] Sahaj Yog.<br />
......<br />
And actually in Sahaja Yoga nobody should be right-sided or left-sided. You are all in the center. You are all in the center. Because certain things like shoe-beating is such an embarrassing things, you know, but you have to [laughing:] do it, you can't help it if you have ego.<br />
......<br />
So, tomorrow I'm going to talk about the Master of Masters [Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa], whom I can master also. I can master that Master also. All right?"<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1991-0831 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Marriage and Mastery (Master Everything and First You Master Yourself), after the Evening Program, the day before Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa Pūjā, Tent, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/228445564"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1991-0831-talk-eve-of-shri"> audio</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
9. To create a new generation of self-realized people and to render motherly protection to all such children against evil intentions and to look after their well-being.
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 24 on the Assumption of Mother Mary and the Independence Day of India</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0815" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 24 on the Assumption of Mother Mary and the Independence Day of India" /><published>2022-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0815"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image998_Photo_credit_Michael Markl.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>You Stand For All That</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"After His assumption, Christ descended on this Earth in a hidden place while the Holy Spirit [Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī] stayed back to inspire the faith of the early Christians. After Her assumption She joined Her Son and They lived together for many years in Kashmir. They are buried there."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>The Advent (2002 edition) by Grégoire de Kalbermatten, footnote of Page 251</b></font>
</p>

<p>
"Mahātmā Gāndhī says that ahiṃsā, i.e., nonviolence is the only way we can get rid of war. It is true that Indians fought the British with nonviolent methods to achieve their freedom. But nonviolent methods to gain freedom may sometimes result in the sacrifice of great lives for the country, when the ruling power uses brutal methods. This is what happened in India in several instances. Fortunately by Divine Blessing a Labour Government came into power in the United Kingdom immediately after the end of the Second World War. This Government initiated a process voluntarily which resulted in India's independence. Unfortunately, not all countries have the same good luck. There are numerous instances of dependent countries having to sacrifice a great many precious lives to gain freedom."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 8: World Peace</b></font>
</p>

<p>
"For example today I saw the flag, Independence: when we got [it] we made this flag. I'd seen this flagned [flag] being brought down, and put up when the other flag was brought down [in August 1947]. I cannot tell you what was the feeling that governed Me. Such a feeling, that the Truth has, some or other, overcome the untruth. That justice has been shown over the injustice. That feeling is still so much, I can't even see the flag. If I see it, I remember the whole history, the whole thing: how many people sacrificed, how many martyrs there were, how much people have fought for it, that flag stands for that.<br />
And you stand for all that. You stand for all those ideals, you stand for all those sacrifices, and you stand for all that is to be achieved for bettering human beings.<br />
You have to achieve a great deal for others. You have to work, within yourself, what you can do for others, what you can achieve for others, what is the best way to imbibe those qualities within yeall [you] that you become a[n] absolutely unique personality."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>2001-0321 Birthday Pūjā, New Delhi, India}\label{2001-0321 Birthday Pūjā, New Delhi, India</b></font>
</p>

<p>
[Śhrī Mātājī reminisced about Her time with Gāndhī in his āśhram and said that he was such a simple, disciplined and straightforward man.]<br /> 
[She explained that his khādī movement killed the textile industry in Manchester, England and that they used to even have a song that if we use home spun, the factories will stop. Dr. David Szpiro, who was present at the time, is from Manchester and confirmed that in fact there is no textile industry in Manchester today.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī explained that when Her father was jailed for 6 months during the struggle for independence, She knew true poverty for the first time because he was the primary earner. Her father was the only prominent Christian jailed at the time.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī went on to say that the English were wise to withdraw, but that She still didn't fully understand why because this has never happened before. She said there was no war or conflict and that without this, occupying countries do not leave, so the English had some wisdom.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī said that the Nehru dynasty had not been good for India, and that had Gāndhī become the president, India would be a very different country today.]<br />
<font color="blue"><b>2007-080x Comments on India's Independence, during the period 0730 to 0803, Palazzo Doria, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font>
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/26047803"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/2001-0321-1"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.<br />
20. To counteract through mass spiritual power the destructive forces against spiritualism such as evil spirits, the cult of hypnotism, siddhis and the use of ``religion" for the exploitation of the innocent.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 23</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0806" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 23" /><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_23</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0806"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image997_Balwant_Kumbhojkar_Collection.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Mother Make Me Such That I Suck More Of The Divine</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"So you should not make them attend any Pūjā, minimum, and also seminars I would say. Because seminars are meant for people who are intensively in Sahaja Yoga, to inse ... intensify their awareness, you see, not for people who are half-baked, who are Doubting Thomases, all these kind of people are absolutely useless, you should never bring them to seminar. Whether it's your son, father, brother, mother, sister, husband, wife, nothing doing. You shouldn't bring anybody who is not fully awakened Sahaj Yogi, because seminars are meant for very intensive work.<br />
And what I find, always these people will argue with Me, they are the first to question, they have something to say, [laughing:] they are the ones! [Laughing:] Sahaja Yogis are keeping quiet and receive it. I don't mind even that, but what happens in the seminar, you have to receive more. And they do not receive, their attention is outside, they are disturbing everyone.<br />
So, seminars are even, in a way, more important than an Āśhram, because in Āśhram there's no other problem but to fight them out. But here, in a new place we go, we have to fight out's all surroundings, the place itself has to be cleansed, everything has to be done. On top of that you have these terrible people around you, whom you have to convince. If they are not convinced, why are they here? Why did they spend so much money to come down? Be sure, they have come here to disturb us.<br />
......<br />
So that is for the people who have to have the privilege of this worship. Today is specially a great privilege because it was not so planned, but it worked out, just worked out.<br />
......<br />
So, sucking should be more. Sucking should be more. And just before the Pūjā you should say: `Mother, make me such that I suck more of the Divine!' Just pray that, with sincerity from your heart, just say that. [Twelve seconds of silence.]"<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1982-0801 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, The Privilege of this Worship, Seminar, Day 2, Cowley Manor, Cheltenham, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/31986113"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1982-0801-adi-shakti-puja"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
6. To spread the news of the descent of the Divine Grace, with the help of self-realized disciples of Mātājī.<br />
10. To build and run Ashramas of Sadhakas for their use during Sadhana and to promote all activities expressing the new dimensions of creativity. <br />
22. To open, organize and run local centers of the Life Eternal Institution in various parts of India and in foreign countries, the centers being opened on the distinct understanding that meditation is the path of the entire human destiny, and that all barriers of states, nations and races are artificial and irrelevant to Life Eternal.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 22</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0722" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 22" /><published>2022-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_22</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0722"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image996_Photo_credit_Colin_Heinsen.png" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Have I Become My Own Guru?</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"In Sahaja Yoga, the Guru Pūjā has a very different significant [significance] from any other guru pūjā. When you worship your Guru, you are also worshiping the Guru within you. This is not in any other guru-disciple system, because, in you, the Guru, the Master, has been awakened. And so, when you are worshiping your Guru, then this Master within you is also worshiped, you respect it, you glorify it, you awaken it, and you manifest it.<br />
This, we have to realize: that, in Sahaja Yoga, if you are a Sahaja Yogi.<br />
Now the quality of guru, first and foremost is: that he makes you meet God. Means: he raises the Kuṇḍalinī, and establish the relation between the All-pervading Power.<br />
And, as your Guru is Ādi Śhakti, you make that person meet, also, the Ādi Śhakti.<br />
So you have a double advantage. That, at the same time, when you give them Realization, not only that you make them feel the Union with the Divine Power, but you can make them meet the Divinity Itself, the Source of Divine Power.<br />
So your responsibility as Sahaja Yogis is very great because in you is ... there is the Guru.<br />
Now we in our mantras we say that: 'Mother, I am my own guru.' But, saying that, do we realize, that, "If I am ah ... my own guru, this 'I' and 'my guru', between the two, what have I achieved? Where am I? Can I guide myself? Have I got the light of the Spirit on my attention, so well established and manifested, that I can guide myself and guide others later on?"<br />
First of all, the ... in the Guru Principle it is important, that you see to yourself the introspection: 'Can I be my own guru? Have I become my own guru?'<br />
......<br />
First of all, the quality of a person who has dharma is: that he listens to others, he obeys.<br />
......<br />
The basic thing is humility.<br />
......<br />
Now, for a Guru, as you have seen, that, in My own ... own way, in My own image, you have to come up.<br />
First of all, your life should be absolutely transparent. Transparency is the essence of Sahaja Yoga.<br />
......<br />
So the food part of it is āswāda. You should not have any taste for any special food.<br />
......<br />
So, the eating of good food is a kind of a[n] addiction. It's a kind of an addiction, it's something like drug: that you must have good food.<br />
......<br />
So this is the second point is that: we have to uh-uh-uh give up body k... comfort.<br />
But the third point where I think the Western people falter is uh their materialistic attitude. Materialistic attitude and their fondness of their eyes.<br />
......<br /> 
So this madness of antique has to go away from our minds."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1990-0708 Guru Pūjā, Camp Site, Island in the NW side of Avignon, France</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/583339674"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1990-0708-guru-puja-talk"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
4. To open the minds of people through meetings introducing "thoughtless awareness" which discovers the subtle which at present is lost in gross words, books and dogmas.<br />
5. To introduce the only one internal living religion lying dead and camouflaged under external practices and precepts of religion in all the human beings and for this to organize tours and hold spiritual meetings as per wishes of Mātājī.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 21</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0710" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 21" /><published>2022-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_21</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0710"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image990_Photo_credit_Michael_Markl.jpg" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>The Right Side Movement Is The Collectivity</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"Today is a great day, for all of us, because we are celebrating the Guru Pūjā and remembering all the Great Gurus who came on Earth to teach the world about the Truth. So many of Them were here. And They tried Their level best to explain to humanity what is spirituality.<br />
But is such a disparity that people never understood that spirituality is the most important thing we need, that we have to be one with the Divine Power.<br />
......<br />
That means: Sahaja Yogis can also become right-sided, but like Christ. Otherwise, if they are right-sided: they'll organize, they'll do all kinds of things and have problems of the right side. That's why I want you to avoid the right side.<br />
But once you are fully a left-sided master of Sahaja Yoga, then it's very-very much needed to be a Complete Personality of Spirituality, that you should take to right side movement. And what is the right side movement? Is the collectivity.<br />
......<br />
So, talk about this to everyone, bring them to Sahaja Yoga.<br />
Is a very important day, because, as a Guru Pūjā, they say that a guru canno-t give anything to you. But I can give you the advice, and the advice that you enlarge your heart, you become humble, and try to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility, not with aggressiveness. That is extremely important!<br />
If you can do that, then you'll do full justice to this-s life, which is a spiritual life. Without that you cannot achieve, you cannot achieve, the strength of spirituality. For that, you have to understand that it's very-very important that you should give Sahaja Yoga a full chance, through your wisdom."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>2002-0721 Guru Pūjā, Enlarge Your Heart and Spread Sahaja Yoga with Humility, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/24547969"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/2002-0727-1-guru_puja-1-wav"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
7. To cure people of their physical and mental ailments by blessing them with divine healing touch of Mātājī and other disciples who have developed their Collective Consciousness Self-realization.<br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 20</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0702" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 20" /><published>2022-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_20</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0702"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image989_Balwant_Kumbhojkar_Collection.jpg" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Love Means Sacrifice</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"Why I asked him to talk to arrange a meeting with you people is this: because I've discovered that in Kali Yuga, specially in the West, the problem will be coming from the women.<br />
......<br />
I being a woman, you see, I can come much closer to you people.<br />
And sometimes people start thinking that uh the ladies have a special relationship with Me.<br />
......<br />
And specially in the West, you see, ah with this a woman's lib and all these nonsensical ideas have gone into the heads of even Sahaja Yogis. One of the conditionings they have.<br />
......<br />
Now, in Sahaja Yoga, nobody can dominate you. Because you are the Spirit, and the Spirit cannot be dominated. If you think you are dominated, then know that you are not a Spirit.<br />
So, now, we have to understand: we are women in Sahaja Yoga. And we have to understand our balancing power.<br />
......<br />
But one should be very proud that you are women. I am very proud that I am a woman. Because women can perform so many things which men cannot do. <br />
......<br />
Same, women in Sahaja Yoga are very important for Me. But the first thing they should have is a bearing power.<br />
......<br />
And also they should have lots and lots of love and compassion.<br />
......<br />
The Absolute Womanhood is the climax for you.<br />
......<br />
Love is the best way to control anyone. But love means sacrifice. But after some time you won't feel any sacrifice. Once you start enjoying, giving, then it is no more a sacrifice.<br />
......<br />
Women ha... have been given so many qualities, because their lifestyle is more difficult than that of men.<br />
So, I have to make one request to you: that you must try to make yourself uh-uh into a proper Sahaja Yoginī.<br />
......<br />
No, men are more intelligent, no doubt. But women have intuition. But you don't have to argue! It will happen, the way you have intuition will happen, and they will learn a lesson.<br />
......<br />
So, you see, they ... they ... special quality which is intuition must be developed. All right?<br />
Now see the difference, because you are deep, you are much deeper. In evolution you are higher, no doubt."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1988-0709 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/725081272"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1988-0709-intuition-women"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
8. To give the taste of real joy that is within the Self. ......<br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 19</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0626" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 19" /><published>2022-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_19</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0626"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image988_Asha_Peter_Brownscombe_Collection.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Ocean of Love</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"And today, as a first time, I would say again, to begin with, that I'm talking of Ocean of Love.<br />
If you were so perfect there was no need to have Sahaj Yog. There was no need to do anything. Should have been the simplest job, you see. Anybody could have done it.<br />
Because there are complications and problems, that somebody has to work it out.<br />
......<br />
Now, today we have, in our presence, Mister [Bhaskarrao G.] Pradhan, who is now seventy-six.<br />
And the he came to Me about twelve months ... twelve years back or eleven years back. He belongs to the first batch of Sahaja Yogis.<br /> 
And I've worked on them, about twenty-five of them, for two years. And after two years, only twelve of them got Realization. After two years, can you believe it? He's one of them.<br />
And the he is now going to America, because I'll be going to America so he wants to go and pave way for Me. He has come all the way from India.<br />
He is a lawyer, he's a[n] advocate, and he has held a very great understanding of Sahaja Yoga.<br />
He's helped Me a lot. Last time when I went to America also he came down.<br />
And he is our trustee. For we had to have a trust in India. Uh you cannot even get a hall without a trust. Then we had a trust.<br />
And ... uh-uh-uh, today there's a good news, that somebody has given us donation of one acre of land in Powai Lake area which is a very beautiful area, in addition to what that they had given us.<br />
So, I don't know, maybe that people who want to now have places there, they could come and meditate and sit down. So it's little far away from Bombay [Mumbai], about, say, that is about eight miles or so. That's a very, very quiet area, very quiet area and there's, there are two lakes there. Is [a] very nice place.<br />
And today only I received the message saying that somebody has donated that. I was very happy that they have donated us because we could not buy any, any land, because I said that, "We'll not give any black money or any bribery or anything, and the land has to be proper price. We'll not give extra money, would be public money." But some or other, now we've got some land there."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1981-0625 Public Program, Friends Meeting House, 120 Heath Street, Hampstead, London NW3 1DR, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1981-0625-the-ocean-of-love"> soundcloud</a>
</p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
15. To print, edit and publish journals, books and literature written by Mātājī and her disciples with her approval for conveying the knowledge of truth so that the human beings who are the highest in evolution, rise in their glory, dignity and freedom, as also for publicizing the activities of the institutions run by the Trust.<br />
19. To build sanatoria, hospitals, nursing homes for the sick and invalid.
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</font><br />
<br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 18</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0611" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 18" /><published>2022-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_18</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0611"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image982_Photo_credit_Mark_Taylor.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Tremendous Task Of Creating Virāṭas Out Of Sahaja Yogis and Life For Us Is Nothing But Sahaja Yoga</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"And today what one feels that in America there's more dominance of the left side than of the right. Right side is our attention and the right side of attention is, we can say, is the liver of God Almighty.<br />
So now when we have to talk of the totality, when we are part and parcel of the totality, and now we are awakened to that existence of ours as the part and parcel of the whole, then we have to realize: to become the whole we have to do something about it. Specially in the land of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, we have to work out this tremendous task of creating Virāṭas out of Sahaja Yogis.<br />
After going through the various experiences of American Sahaja Yoga, I've reached the conclusion that we have to talk more frankly about things than we have been talking before: why there's such a failure of Sahaja Yoga in this great country while there are so many seekers.<br />
......<br />
In the same way the Sahaja Yogis of America have to work out because here it's so much superficiality and so much of frivolousness and also no meaning to their lives. They have no meanings at all and they are just frittering away their lives with all nonsensical ideas about their emotions and their love and all those things.<br />
......<br />
That all these souls which have died, I think, have possessed them, and now, today, America is on the left-hand side. The right-hand side of Americans is finished now. They are on the left-hand side: guilty, feeling guilty, they are taking to indulgences.<br />
......<br />
So, to become one part and parcel of the whole, a drop has to become the ocean, you have to become great people, you have to be responsible.<br />
And this lovey-dovey business that you have has to go out of your mind completely, otherwise Sahaja Yoga cannot work out in these two countries. And you'll be cursed one after another.<br />
There are shocks after shocks that are coming to this country as well as to England. But people are not learning any lessons from them. Still it is, 'All right, we get this disease, uh all right, then we glorify it. If ee [we] uh-uh-uh uh are suffering from ecological difference, still we are glorified.' If you are using too much of machinery out of balance, still, 'We are glorified.' Because they just want self-indulgence. Just for self-indulgence they don't want to see the point that what is going wrong with this country is that: that they do not see anything that is reality.<br />
......<br />
So the first thing a Sahaja Yogi has to do: has to make up something of his personality.<br />
......<br />
To become Virāṭa we have to really examine ourselves without any anger, malice or anything, but see for ourselves.<br />
......<br />
So you have to watch within yourself: that we are here for liberation, for complete freedom.<br />
......<br />
So first thing is to build yourself inside as well as outside.<br />
......<br />
But one has to think that: 'We have to change our lifestyle. We have to change our attitudes.'<br />
......<br />
Now, if you have to take to the Sahaj Culture, you have to know that we have to have a discipline in our life. We have to have education, we have to have a place, we have to have a position in the society. Because we are not sitting in the Himalayas, somewhere lost in the Himalayas sitting there and just uh-uh-uh-uh doing our tapasyā.<br />
......<br />
So transformation, of course, means evolution. It also means that whatever basis you had, you have to evolve out of it.<br />
......<br />
And I wish for you that you understand what I am saying today. And I request you, all of you, to be alert and dynamic and work it out. Each single person has to come up.<br />
......<br />
So on one side: the dynamism is to be used for yourself, and the dynamism is to be used for Sahaja Yoga.<br />
......<br />
Same thing is Sahaja Yoga. If you put mathematically, Sahaja Yoga can never be established in America if you add up more and more of this kind of people.<br />
......<br />
So when we believe that we are Sahaja Yogis, we have to know that in a subtle way we are still caught up into the webs of our own understanding about life.<br />
So that we have to change. Life for us is nothing but Sahaja Yoga, and Sahaja Yoga is nothing but enlightening ourselves and others."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1989-0611 Śhrī Virāṭa Pūjā, Camp Wonposet, Lennox Hill Road, Litchfield, CT, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
</p>

<p><br />
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/47834627"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1989-0601-1-shri_virata_puja-1"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p><br /></p>
<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
7. To cure people of their physical and mental ailments by blessing them with divine healing touch of Mātājī and other disciples who have developed their Collective Consciousness Self-realization.<br />
15. To print, edit and publish journals, books and literature written by Mātājī and her disciples with her approval for conveying the knowledge of truth so that the human beings who are the highest in evolution, rise in their glory, dignity and freedom, as also for publicizing the activities of the institutions run by the Trust.<br />
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p><br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>