<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/yearly.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-08-15T17:10:10-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/feed/yearly.xml</id><title type="html">Divine Treasures | Yearly</title><subtitle>personal description</subtitle><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 24 on</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0815" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 24 on" /><published>2022-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_24</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0815"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image998_Photo_credit_Michael Markl.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b></b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"After His assumption, Christ descended on this Earth in a hidden place while the Holy Spirit [Śhrī Mary Mahālakṣhmī] stayed back to inspire the faith of the early Christians. After Her assumption She joined Her Son and They lived together for many years in Kashmir. They are buried there."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>The Advent (2002 edition) by Grégoire de Kalbermatten, footnote of Page 251</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
"Mahātmā Gāndhī says that ahiṃsā, i.e., nonviolence is the only way we can get rid of war. It is true that Indians fought the British with nonviolent methods to achieve their freedom. But nonviolent methods to gain freedom may sometimes result in the sacrifice of great lives for the country, when the ruling power uses brutal methods. This is what happened in India in several instances. Fortunately by Divine Blessing a Labour Government came into power in the United Kingdom immediately after the end of the Second World War. This Government initiated a process voluntarily which resulted in India's independence. Unfortunately, not all countries have the same good luck. There are numerous instances of dependent countries having to sacrifice a great many precious lives to gain freedom."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1995-0929 Meta Modern Era, Chapter 8: World Peace</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
"For example today I saw the flag, Independence: when we got [it] we made this flag. I'd seen this flagned [flag] being brought down, and put up when the other flag was brought down [in August 1947]. I cannot tell you what was the feeling that governed Me. Such a feeling, that the Truth has, some or other, overcome the untruth. That justice has been shown over the injustice. That feeling is still so much, I can't even see the flag. If I see it, I remember the whole history, the whole thing: how many people sacrificed, how many martyrs there were, how much people have fought for it, that flag stands for that.<br />
And you stand for all that. You stand for all those ideals, you stand for all those sacrifices, and you stand for all that is to be achieved for bettering human beings.<br />
You have to achieve a great deal for others. You have to work, within yourself, what you can do for others, what you can achieve for others, what is the best way to imbibe those qualities within yeall [you] that you become a[n] absolutely unique personality."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>2001-0321 Birthday Pūjā, New Delhi, India}\label{2001-0321 Birthday Pūjā, New Delhi, India</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
"[Śhrī Mātājī reminisced about Her time with Gāndhī in his āśhram and said that he was such a simple, disciplined and straightforward man.]<br /> 
[She explained that his khādī movement killed the textile industry in Manchester, England and that they used to even have a song that if we use home spun, the factories will stop. Dr. David Szpiro, who was present at the time, is from Manchester and confirmed that in fact there is no textile industry in Manchester today.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī explained that when Her father was jailed for 6 months during the struggle for independence, She knew true poverty for the first time because he was the primary earner. Her father was the only prominent Christian jailed at the time.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī went on to say that the English were wise to withdraw, but that She still didn't fully understand why because this has never happened before. She said there was no war or conflict and that without this, occupying countries do not leave, so the English had some wisdom.]<br />
[Śhrī Mātājī said that the Nehru dynasty had not been good for India, and that had Gāndhī become the president, India would be a very different country today.]"<br />
<font color="blue"><b>2007-080x Comments on India's Independence, during the period 0730 to 0803, Palazzo Doria, Cabella Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/26047803"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/2001-0321-1"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.<br />
20. To counteract through mass spiritual power the destructive forces against spiritualism such as evil spirits, the cult of hypnotism, siddhis and the use of ``religion" for the exploitation of the innocent.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 23</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0806" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 23" /><published>2022-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-08-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_23</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0806"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image997_Balwant_Kumbhojkar_Collection.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Mother Make Me Such That I Suck More Of The Divine</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"So you should not make them attend any Pūjā, minimum, and also seminars I would say. Because seminars are meant for people who are intensively in Sahaja Yoga, to inse ... intensify their awareness, you see, not for people who are half-baked, who are Doubting Thomases, all these kind of people are absolutely useless, you should never bring them to seminar. Whether it's your son, father, brother, mother, sister, husband, wife, nothing doing. You shouldn't bring anybody who is not fully awakened Sahaj Yogi, because seminars are meant for very intensive work.<br />
And what I find, always these people will argue with Me, they are the first to question, they have something to say, [laughing:] they are the ones! [Laughing:] Sahaja Yogis are keeping quiet and receive it. I don't mind even that, but what happens in the seminar, you have to receive more. And they do not receive, their attention is outside, they are disturbing everyone.<br />
So, seminars are even, in a way, more important than an Āśhram, because in Āśhram there's no other problem but to fight them out. But here, in a new place we go, we have to fight out's all surroundings, the place itself has to be cleansed, everything has to be done. On top of that you have these terrible people around you, whom you have to convince. If they are not convinced, why are they here? Why did they spend so much money to come down? Be sure, they have come here to disturb us.<br />
......<br />
So that is for the people who have to have the privilege of this worship. Today is specially a great privilege because it was not so planned, but it worked out, just worked out.<br />
......<br />
So, sucking should be more. Sucking should be more. And just before the Pūjā you should say: `Mother, make me such that I suck more of the Divine!' Just pray that, with sincerity from your heart, just say that. [Twelve seconds of silence.]"<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1982-0801 Śhrī Ādi Śhakti Pūjā, The Privilege of this Worship, Seminar, Day 2, Cowley Manor, Cheltenham, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/31986113"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1982-0801-adi-shakti-puja"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
6. To spread the news of the descent of the Divine Grace, with the help of self-realized disciples of Mātājī.<br />
10. To build and run Ashramas of Sadhakas for their use during Sadhana and to promote all activities expressing the new dimensions of creativity. <br />
22. To open, organize and run local centers of the Life Eternal Institution in various parts of India and in foreign countries, the centers being opened on the distinct understanding that meditation is the path of the entire human destiny, and that all barriers of states, nations and races are artificial and irrelevant to Life Eternal.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 22</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0722" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 22" /><published>2022-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_22</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0722"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image996_Photo_credit_Colin_Heinsen.png" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Have I Become My Own Guru?</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"In Sahaja Yoga, the Guru Pūjā has a very different significant [significance] from any other guru pūjā. When you worship your Guru, you are also worshiping the Guru within you. This is not in any other guru-disciple system, because, in you, the Guru, the Master, has been awakened. And so, when you are worshiping your Guru, then this Master within you is also worshiped, you respect it, you glorify it, you awaken it, and you manifest it.<br />
This, we have to realize: that, in Sahaja Yoga, if you are a Sahaja Yogi.<br />
Now the quality of guru, first and foremost is: that he makes you meet God. Means: he raises the Kuṇḍalinī, and establish the relation between the All-pervading Power.<br />
And, as your Guru is Ādi Śhakti, you make that person meet, also, the Ādi Śhakti.<br />
So you have a double advantage. That, at the same time, when you give them Realization, not only that you make them feel the Union with the Divine Power, but you can make them meet the Divinity Itself, the Source of Divine Power.<br />
So your responsibility as Sahaja Yogis is very great because in you is ... there is the Guru.<br />
Now we in our mantras we say that: 'Mother, I am my own guru.' But, saying that, do we realize, that, "If I am ah ... my own guru, this 'I' and 'my guru', between the two, what have I achieved? Where am I? Can I guide myself? Have I got the light of the Spirit on my attention, so well established and manifested, that I can guide myself and guide others later on?"<br />
First of all, the ... in the Guru Principle it is important, that you see to yourself the introspection: 'Can I be my own guru? Have I become my own guru?'<br />
......<br />
First of all, the quality of a person who has dharma is: that he listens to others, he obeys.<br />
......<br />
The basic thing is humility.<br />
......<br />
Now, for a Guru, as you have seen, that, in My own ... own way, in My own image, you have to come up.<br />
First of all, your life should be absolutely transparent. Transparency is the essence of Sahaja Yoga.<br />
......<br />
So the food part of it is āswāda. You should not have any taste for any special food.<br />
......<br />
So, the eating of good food is a kind of a[n] addiction. It's a kind of an addiction, it's something like drug: that you must have good food.<br />
......<br />
So this is the second point is that: we have to uh-uh-uh give up body k... comfort.<br />
But the third point where I think the Western people falter is uh their materialistic attitude. Materialistic attitude and their fondness of their eyes.<br />
......<br /> 
So this madness of antique has to go away from our minds."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1990-0708 Guru Pūjā, Camp Site, Island in the NW side of Avignon, France</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/583339674"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1990-0708-guru-puja-talk"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
4. To open the minds of people through meetings introducing "thoughtless awareness" which discovers the subtle which at present is lost in gross words, books and dogmas.<br />
5. To introduce the only one internal living religion lying dead and camouflaged under external practices and precepts of religion in all the human beings and for this to organize tours and hold spiritual meetings as per wishes of Mātājī.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 21</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0710" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 21" /><published>2022-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_21</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0710"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image990_Photo_credit_Michael_Markl.jpg" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>The Right Side Movement Is The Collectivity</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"Today is a great day, for all of us, because we are celebrating the Guru Pūjā and remembering all the Great Gurus who came on Earth to teach the world about the Truth. So many of Them were here. And They tried Their level best to explain to humanity what is spirituality.<br />
But is such a disparity that people never understood that spirituality is the most important thing we need, that we have to be one with the Divine Power.<br />
......<br />
That means: Sahaja Yogis can also become right-sided, but like Christ. Otherwise, if they are right-sided: they'll organize, they'll do all kinds of things and have problems of the right side. That's why I want you to avoid the right side.<br />
But once you are fully a left-sided master of Sahaja Yoga, then it's very-very much needed to be a Complete Personality of Spirituality, that you should take to right side movement. And what is the right side movement? Is the collectivity.<br />
......<br />
So, talk about this to everyone, bring them to Sahaja Yoga.<br />
Is a very important day, because, as a Guru Pūjā, they say that a guru canno-t give anything to you. But I can give you the advice, and the advice that you enlarge your heart, you become humble, and try to spread Sahaja Yoga with humility, not with aggressiveness. That is extremely important!<br />
If you can do that, then you'll do full justice to this-s life, which is a spiritual life. Without that you cannot achieve, you cannot achieve, the strength of spirituality. For that, you have to understand that it's very-very important that you should give Sahaja Yoga a full chance, through your wisdom."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>2002-0721 Guru Pūjā, Enlarge Your Heart and Spread Sahaja Yoga with Humility, Hangar (now Nirmal Temple), Albera Ligure, Alessandria, Italy</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/24547969"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/2002-0727-1-guru_puja-1-wav"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
7. To cure people of their physical and mental ailments by blessing them with divine healing touch of Mātājī and other disciples who have developed their Collective Consciousness Self-realization.<br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</p>

<p>Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 20</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0702" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 20" /><published>2022-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_20</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0702"><![CDATA[<p><br /></p>
<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image989_Balwant_Kumbhojkar_Collection.jpg" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Love Means Sacrifice</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"Why I asked him to talk to arrange a meeting with you people is this: because I've discovered that in Kali Yuga, specially in the West, the problem will be coming from the women.<br />
......<br />
I being a woman, you see, I can come much closer to you people.<br />
And sometimes people start thinking that uh the ladies have a special relationship with Me.<br />
......<br />
And specially in the West, you see, ah with this a woman's lib and all these nonsensical ideas have gone into the heads of even Sahaja Yogis. One of the conditionings they have.<br />
......<br />
Now, in Sahaja Yoga, nobody can dominate you. Because you are the Spirit, and the Spirit cannot be dominated. If you think you are dominated, then know that you are not a Spirit.<br />
So, now, we have to understand: we are women in Sahaja Yoga. And we have to understand our balancing power.<br />
......<br />
But one should be very proud that you are women. I am very proud that I am a woman. Because women can perform so many things which men cannot do. <br />
......<br />
Same, women in Sahaja Yoga are very important for Me. But the first thing they should have is a bearing power.<br />
......<br />
And also they should have lots and lots of love and compassion.<br />
......<br />
The Absolute Womanhood is the climax for you.<br />
......<br />
Love is the best way to control anyone. But love means sacrifice. But after some time you won't feel any sacrifice. Once you start enjoying, giving, then it is no more a sacrifice.<br />
......<br />
Women ha... have been given so many qualities, because their lifestyle is more difficult than that of men.<br />
So, I have to make one request to you: that you must try to make yourself uh-uh into a proper Sahaja Yoginī.<br />
......<br />
No, men are more intelligent, no doubt. But women have intuition. But you don't have to argue! It will happen, the way you have intuition will happen, and they will learn a lesson.<br />
......<br />
So, you see, they ... they ... special quality which is intuition must be developed. All right?<br />
Now see the difference, because you are deep, you are much deeper. In evolution you are higher, no doubt."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1988-0709 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, Āśhram, 9, Allée Du Rocher, Le Raincy (13 kms E of Paris), France</b></font>
</p>

<p>Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/725081272"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1988-0709-intuition-women"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
8. To give the taste of real joy that is within the Self. ......<br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.<br />
</p>

<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p>
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams
</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 19</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0626" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 19" /><published>2022-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_19</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0626"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image988_Asha_Peter_Brownscombe_Collection.png" /></div>

<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Ocean of Love</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"And today, as a first time, I would say again, to begin with, that I'm talking of Ocean of Love.<br />
If you were so perfect there was no need to have Sahaj Yog. There was no need to do anything. Should have been the simplest job, you see. Anybody could have done it.<br />
Because there are complications and problems, that somebody has to work it out.<br />
......<br />
Now, today we have, in our presence, Mister [Bhaskarrao G.] Pradhan, who is now seventy-six.<br />
And the he came to Me about twelve months ... twelve years back or eleven years back. He belongs to the first batch of Sahaja Yogis.<br /> 
And I've worked on them, about twenty-five of them, for two years. And after two years, only twelve of them got Realization. After two years, can you believe it? He's one of them.<br />
And the he is now going to America, because I'll be going to America so he wants to go and pave way for Me. He has come all the way from India.<br />
He is a lawyer, he's a[n] advocate, and he has held a very great understanding of Sahaja Yoga.<br />
He's helped Me a lot. Last time when I went to America also he came down.<br />
And he is our trustee. For we had to have a trust in India. Uh you cannot even get a hall without a trust. Then we had a trust.<br />
And ... uh-uh-uh, today there's a good news, that somebody has given us donation of one acre of land in Powai Lake area which is a very beautiful area, in addition to what that they had given us.<br />
So, I don't know, maybe that people who want to now have places there, they could come and meditate and sit down. So it's little far away from Bombay [Mumbai], about, say, that is about eight miles or so. That's a very, very quiet area, very quiet area and there's, there are two lakes there. Is [a] very nice place.<br />
And today only I received the message saying that somebody has donated that. I was very happy that they have donated us because we could not buy any, any land, because I said that, "We'll not give any black money or any bribery or anything, and the land has to be proper price. We'll not give extra money, would be public money." But some or other, now we've got some land there."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1981-0625 Public Program, Friends Meeting House, 120 Heath Street, Hampstead, London NW3 1DR, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p>
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://soundcloud.com/sahaja-library/1981-0625-the-ocean-of-love"> soundcloud</a>
</p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
15. To print, edit and publish journals, books and literature written by Mātājī and her disciples with her approval for conveying the knowledge of truth so that the human beings who are the highest in evolution, rise in their glory, dignity and freedom, as also for publicizing the activities of the institutions run by the Trust.<br />
19. To build sanatoria, hospitals, nursing homes for the sick and invalid.
</p>

<p>
<font color="red">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!</font><br />
<br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 18</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0611" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 18" /><published>2022-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_18</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0611"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image982_Photo_credit_Mark_Taylor.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Tremendous Task Of Creating Virāṭas Out Of Sahaja Yogis and Life For Us Is Nothing But Sahaja Yoga</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"And today what one feels that in America there's more dominance of the left side than of the right. Right side is our attention and the right side of attention is, we can say, is the liver of God Almighty.<br />
So now when we have to talk of the totality, when we are part and parcel of the totality, and now we are awakened to that existence of ours as the part and parcel of the whole, then we have to realize: to become the whole we have to do something about it. Specially in the land of Śhrī Kṛiṣhṇa, we have to work out this tremendous task of creating Virāṭas out of Sahaja Yogis.<br />
After going through the various experiences of American Sahaja Yoga, I've reached the conclusion that we have to talk more frankly about things than we have been talking before: why there's such a failure of Sahaja Yoga in this great country while there are so many seekers.<br />
......<br />
In the same way the Sahaja Yogis of America have to work out because here it's so much superficiality and so much of frivolousness and also no meaning to their lives. They have no meanings at all and they are just frittering away their lives with all nonsensical ideas about their emotions and their love and all those things.<br />
......<br />
That all these souls which have died, I think, have possessed them, and now, today, America is on the left-hand side. The right-hand side of Americans is finished now. They are on the left-hand side: guilty, feeling guilty, they are taking to indulgences.<br />
......<br />
So, to become one part and parcel of the whole, a drop has to become the ocean, you have to become great people, you have to be responsible.<br />
And this lovey-dovey business that you have has to go out of your mind completely, otherwise Sahaja Yoga cannot work out in these two countries. And you'll be cursed one after another.<br />
There are shocks after shocks that are coming to this country as well as to England. But people are not learning any lessons from them. Still it is, 'All right, we get this disease, uh all right, then we glorify it. If ee [we] uh-uh-uh uh are suffering from ecological difference, still we are glorified.' If you are using too much of machinery out of balance, still, 'We are glorified.' Because they just want self-indulgence. Just for self-indulgence they don't want to see the point that what is going wrong with this country is that: that they do not see anything that is reality.<br />
......<br />
So the first thing a Sahaja Yogi has to do: has to make up something of his personality.<br />
......<br />
To become Virāṭa we have to really examine ourselves without any anger, malice or anything, but see for ourselves.<br />
......<br />
So you have to watch within yourself: that we are here for liberation, for complete freedom.<br />
......<br />
So first thing is to build yourself inside as well as outside.<br />
......<br />
But one has to think that: 'We have to change our lifestyle. We have to change our attitudes.'<br />
......<br />
Now, if you have to take to the Sahaj Culture, you have to know that we have to have a discipline in our life. We have to have education, we have to have a place, we have to have a position in the society. Because we are not sitting in the Himalayas, somewhere lost in the Himalayas sitting there and just uh-uh-uh-uh doing our tapasyā.<br />
......<br />
So transformation, of course, means evolution. It also means that whatever basis you had, you have to evolve out of it.<br />
......<br />
And I wish for you that you understand what I am saying today. And I request you, all of you, to be alert and dynamic and work it out. Each single person has to come up.<br />
......<br />
So on one side: the dynamism is to be used for yourself, and the dynamism is to be used for Sahaja Yoga.<br />
......<br />
Same thing is Sahaja Yoga. If you put mathematically, Sahaja Yoga can never be established in America if you add up more and more of this kind of people.<br />
......<br />
So when we believe that we are Sahaja Yogis, we have to know that in a subtle way we are still caught up into the webs of our own understanding about life.<br />
So that we have to change. Life for us is nothing but Sahaja Yoga, and Sahaja Yoga is nothing but enlightening ourselves and others."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1989-0611 Śhrī Virāṭa Pūjā, Camp Wonposet, Lennox Hill Road, Litchfield, CT, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
</p>

<p><br />
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/47834627"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1989-0601-1-shri_virata_puja-1"> soundcloud</a><br /></p>

<p><br /></p>
<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
7. To cure people of their physical and mental ailments by blessing them with divine healing touch of Mātājī and other disciples who have developed their Collective Consciousness Self-realization.<br />
15. To print, edit and publish journals, books and literature written by Mātājī and her disciples with her approval for conveying the knowledge of truth so that the human beings who are the highest in evolution, rise in their glory, dignity and freedom, as also for publicizing the activities of the institutions run by the Trust.<br />
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p><br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 17</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0604" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 17" /><published>2022-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-06-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_17</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0604"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image981_Photo_credit_Alessandra_Pallini.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Attention Fully On Your Mother</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"Is such a pleasure to be in the Āśhram in San Diego. And it's such a beautiful place, so ek ... much expressing the Love of God, the Divine, the way It wants to help you at every step.<br />
If you want to have an Āśhram, if you want to have a proper place, you want to look after your children well, you want to do God's work, everything is looked after, everything has to be worked out. If it is not worked out, then how will you do your work? So, it all works out.<br />
And is so obvious, the way we have different Āśhrams, such comfortable places, at a very reasonable amount that we ... we can afford, that we can live happily together. This is the abode created by love for you.<br />
......<br />
So the first thing we have to remember: that among ourselves, we should have complete love. <br />
......<br />
We should not trust people who try to ... divide us, who try to give us wrong ideas.<br />
It's very easy to make out a person who is a Sahaja Yogi from the heart. It's very easy to make out. You have to be [a] little more sensitive and you'll find out such a person very easily. Whatever may be the cunning, it can be discovered. Nobody can act against God now, because everything will be discovered and will be found out. <br />
......<br />
This is the point: that we build up our images about Sahaja Yoga also. We cannot build up: it is what it is. We cannot build up our's image. That we think, 'Sahaj Yog should be like this,' 'Sahaj Yog should be like that,' it cannot be. You cannot compromise. You just cannot compromise. It has to be what it is. It cannot be anything that you want it to be. You cannot mold it, because it is fixed long time back.<br />
Now, it is what it is, and that is why it is working out so well, so ... so efficiently. But to make it more efficient, you have to accept its working.<br />
......<br />
And this is the main point where we feel that uh-uh-uh Sahaja Yogis have to learn to accept with joy, with happiness, and not to project nonsensical ideas. Then only you will find your joy will be complete. Otherwise it will not be.<br />
......<br />
So you all people should also understand: 'Don't try new things in Sahaja Yoga.' Sahaja Yoga is a traditionally built thing. 'Don't try anything new in Sahaja Yoga'. Whatever we have is more than sufficient. You don't try anything new. People who tried new things have jumped into problems. So. do not try something new. <br />
......<br />
So be careful! There is no need to try new methods.<br />
Now you have jumped on to that awareness where you have to just be steady. So don't try at this point something new! Just steady yourself! Steady yourself in balance, that's very important."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1985-0531 Śhrī Devī Pūjā, Steady Yourself, Āśhram, San Diego, CA, U.S.A.</b></font><br />
</p>

<p><br />
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/24813422"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/850531-devi-p1-dp"> soundcloud</a><br />
<br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
2. To achieve the evolution described in the foregoing para through the method of "Sahaja Yoga" which means effortless, easy, relaxed method of meditation evolved by Mātājī. To organize meditation centers for this purpose. This completely precludes all the external human efforts like rituals, worships, prayers, recitations, reading, renunciation (i.e. saṃnyāsa), worship of the preceptor (Guru) or any other physical expressions.<br />
10. To build and run Ashramas of Sadhakas for their use during Sadhana and to promote all activities expressing the new dimensions of creativity.
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p><br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 16</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0529" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 16" /><published>2022-05-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_16</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0529"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image980_Balwant_Kumbhojkar_Collection.jpg" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Perfect Knowledge About Sahaja Yoga You Should Have</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"And I told you that we have to understand that this is the greatest moment in the history, while you are born, and you are doing the highest work, that is of God, here. And you are specially chosen for it and how you must know that you are a Saint.<br />
......<br />
And today I find the negativity is also hurting Sahaja Yoga, very much, and Sahaja Yogis, through a very subtle method.<br />
......<br />
So in Sahaja Yoga, you can be misled very much, by so many things.<br />
......<br />
Specially it is very much in Europe, I find, and England and America: the women have become very dominant. And they know how to control men by telling them stories about how to look after the family, how to look after the children, how to do that. Sometimes is amazing! And you get lost with it. <br />
......<br />
Here, the women lack intelligence because they are so aggressive. They do not see the point! They do not understand who I am! They do not understand, `What is our worth?' To them, all nonsensical stupid things are important. Not all of you but some of you.<br />
......<br />
Now women have to understand they are women because they are compassionate, they are forbearing. They are like this Mother Earth.<br />
Their ego is so developed! Be careful about it!<br />
Why America is finished today? Because of their women.<br />
......<br />
This is a very common failing of the West! And I don't know what has happened to the men here, they feel so guilty, that they must become like slaves!<br />
......<br />
You have to be absolutely perfect, in perfect health. And perfect knowledge about Sahaja Yoga you should have!<br />
......<br />
I'm requesting you now, because you are the śhakti. You are the power behind the man. You are the one who are going to make them great. You are the one who are going to build up Sahaja Yoga as a potential energy. <br />
......<br />
In the marriage of Sahaja Yoga, you have given a promise to Me: that you'll work for Sahaja Yoga, and you'll help your husband in doing Sahaja Yoga, you'll help your husband when he's looking after other Sahaja Yogis, and you'll look after other Sahaja Yogis who come to your house. You'll make your house a Sahaja Yoga center, receive the people in your house, and will always try to enhance the collectivity. Under these promises you are married.<br />
So, now, coming to the major problems of the world, we have seen that I am talking about politics quite a lot these days, and maybe one day all of you have to enter into politics when the proper time has come.<br />
......<br /> 
But today the problems are much deeper than what we think of. A kind of a negative force, like a Hitler's force, is rising up through women of all the countries. Through women this horrible Hitler and all his Germans who died are taking birth. They are becoming like ... now, just like Nazis. <br />
......<br />
And I have to specially make a very important request to the women, that, in these modern times, they are the ones who are going to save the world, ot the men! They have done their job before. Now it is for you to save: with your understanding, with your compassion, with your sacrifices, with your wisdom. And the innate love: not only your children, your husband, your family, but the whole world."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1988-0619 Talk to Sahaja Yogis, The Role of Women, Seminar, Day 2, Tent, Marque, Back Garden, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p><br />
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/137315968"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1988-0619-seminar-day-2-shudy"> soundcloud</a><br />
<br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
9. To create a new generation of self-realized people and to render motherly protection to all such children against evil intentions and to look after their well-being.<br />
13. To employ the energy of love to overcome hatred that is the cause of wars, disintegration and destruction by publishing and relating the spiritual experiences of Sadhakas which prove the universal laws of love.
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p><br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 15</title><link href="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0520" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrating 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects, Post 15" /><published>2022-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-05-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/2022_Yearly_50_LET_15</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://seven-teams.github.io/yearly/2022/0520"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align: left"><img src="/images/Celebrating50YearsLET.png" width="350" /></div>
<p><br /></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="/images/image979_Photo_credit_Colin_Heinsen.png" /></div>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:DarkGreen; text-align:center">
<font size="+2"><b>Tapaḥ Means Meditation</b><br /></font>
</p>

<p>
"So just think, under what circumstances you got your Realization: without sacrificing anything, without giving up anything, without working out any one of these tapasyās, penances.<br />
Because Buddha is a Tapaḥ. These three Deities on your Āgñyā chakra: Christ, Mahāvīra and Buddha, three of Them are Tapaḥ. Tapaḥ means penance. You have to do penance.<br />
And penance now in Sahaja Yoga doesn't mean that you give up your wife or give up your husband, give up your children, give up your family life, but here Tapaḥ means meditation. And for meditation, you must know when to get up, that should be the most important thing for a Sahaja Yogi. The rest of the thing automatically will work out, and you'll understand: to grow your depth you have to meditate. Is a[n] absolutely simple thing: you don't have to shave your head, you don't have to starve yourself, you don't have to walk bare feet. You can sing, you can dance, I mean, you can entertain yourself with music.<br />
......<br />
But while you people look like really roses, beautifully, all of you are enjoying life, and everything is there, ut still one has to know that we have to have that Principle of Buddha within ourselves. And what is that Principle of Buddha? Is that we have to do Tapaḥ.<br />
......<br />
For example, some of you are like this, 'That I belong to this nationality, to that nationality. I am this, I am that. We are very proud of that. We cannot mix up with other people, we are too high for the other people,' or something like that. You are now become a Universal Being. So, you, how can you have these stupid limitations which are mythical again?<br />
Now, as it is, we can see there is light within us, what happens that we start seeing what's wrong with us and we just drop it out. But even when you see that, if you cannot drop it out, then must know that you need more of power. Then you must learn how to raise your Kuṇḍalinī, how to be connected with the uh Divine Power all the time, so that you are in thoughtless awareness and that you grow within yourself in a depth.<br />
......<br />
An enlightened attention reacts in a very different manner than a stupid attention or a confused attention, or the attention which is full of negativity. So, one has to judge how you react.<br />
Without coming to the collective, without being collective, you can never understand the value of collectivity. It is so great. It gives you so many powers, it gives you so much satisfaction and joy that one must in Sahaja Yoga first pay attention to collectivity.<br />
......<br />
If you can just pay attention to yourself as far as the defects are concerned, then I'm sure you will become much more collective than when you start seeing the defects in other people. And no use, I mean no use seeing.<br />
......<br />
So, with all these powers, with all these understandings, with all this compassionate love, you have to be sure about yourself and know that you are all the time protected, guided, looked after, nourished, and helped to grow by this Divine Power, which is all-pervading."<br />
<font color="blue"><b>1992-0531 Śhrī Buddha Pūjā, The Search for the Absolute, Śhuddhi Camp (now The Hall, Shudy Camps Park), Shudy Camps, Cambridgeshire, UK</b></font><br />
</p>

<p><br />
Links to suggested talk: <a href="https://vimeo.com/137191600"> vimeo</a>, <a href="https://soundcloud.com/nirmala-vidya-portal/1992-0531-shri-buddha-puja"> soundcloud</a><br />
<br /></p>

<p>
<b>Objectives:</b><br />
8. To give the taste of real joy that is within the Self. To practice different methods of meditation evolved by Mātājī and to hold meditation camps.<br />
22. To open, organize and run local centers of the Life Eternal Institution in various parts of India and in foreign countries, the centers being opened on the distinct understanding that meditation is the path of the entire human destiny, and that all barriers of states, nations and races are artificial and irrelevant to Life Eternal.
</p>

<p><br /></p>
<p style="color:red;">Jay Śhrī Mātājī!<br /></p>

<p><br />
Comprehensive Compilations and Yearly Topics Teams</p>]]></content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;avatar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bio&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;location&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;employer&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pubmed&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;googlescholar&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;researchgate&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;uri&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;bitbucket&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;codepen&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;dribbble&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;flickr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;facebook&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;foursquare&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;github&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;google_plus&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;keybase&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;instagram&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;impactstory&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;lastfm&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;linkedin&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;orcid&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;pinterest&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;soundcloud&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;stackoverflow&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;steam&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;tumblr&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;vine&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;weibo&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;xing&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;youtube&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;wikipedia&quot;=&gt;nil}</name></author><category term="crimson @ 50 Years of Life Eternal Trust and its Objects" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>